<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E7F59445A3A4A3CB1B860B9F1830FB4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8899 IH: Digital Asset Protection, Accountability, Regulation, Innovation, Taxation, and Yields Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8899</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the tax treatment of digital assets.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2D80C76A1184B448B5DD53FFE7AC45E" style="OLC"><section id="H74A28D46B3434BAA9A0114A92E572AAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Digital Asset Protection, Accountability, Regulation, Innovation, Taxation, and Yields Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Digital Asset PARITY Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H986E2A20208346F4ABDD0FDF854F1CDE" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax treatment of regulated payment stablecoin transactions</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67A5FD4C0049466084DB40FA25BA86BE" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part III of subchapter O of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 1045 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3267D9DA4B7E43AFB1FF91E908E7C266"><section id="H5F7A827DC26A482C9CA4BA8B60F1D166" commented="no"><enum>1046.</enum><header>Regulated payment stablecoin transactions</header><subsection id="H13545D0D531946EC9D98E4E3B4A09D67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale of regulated payment stablecoin</header><paragraph id="H02A6AA6136DB4417BF7D3250211E3CF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any sale or exchange of a regulated payment stablecoin, no gain or loss shall be recognized on such sale or exchange unless the taxpayer’s basis in such stablecoin is less than 99 percent of the redemption value of such stablecoin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52CE3CD6028F456B9AE6A2685F8EBEB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Redemption value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>redemption value</quote> means the dollar amount for which the issuer is obligated to redeem such stablecoin.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04B54E0F420545E98A88085D69ABF1B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exchange of regulated payment stablecoin</header><text>In the case of any exchange of a regulated payment stablecoin, the acquirer’s basis in such stablecoin shall be deemed to be $1.</text></subsection><subsection id="H90704971EBF24B94AD51EBB4643586C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transaction costs not included in basis</header><text>Amounts paid or incurred to facilitate the sale or exchange of a regulated payment stablecoin shall not be included in the calculation of the basis of such stablecoin.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02DFD2FE87AD4F25BF5A2A9315547DBA" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulated payment stablecoin</header><paragraph id="HF15349B535644D7EA5A50027B3105781" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>regulated payment stablecoin</quote> means a digital asset—</text><subparagraph id="H00C900C08BE64E299054B772B7BAD69E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is a payment stablecoin issued by a permitted payment stablecoin issuer,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AF98BFEE22147CFB64F7D35285C46F4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which the issuer is obligated to convert, redeem, or repurchase the payment stablecoin for a fixed amount of United States dollars, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H565E1267F949422FBE335B8FF88096F7" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>which was acquired by the taxpayer for a price within 1 percent of $1.00.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H270E8295167F461F8354B5982E74CFCB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The terms <quote>payment stablecoin</quote> and <quote>permitted payment stablecoin issuer</quote> have the meaning given those terms, respectively, in section 2 of the GENIUS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5901">12 U.S.C. 5901</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D1B42C1699F49D9BDC72CABE1AC89E2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Dealers and traders</header><text>This section shall not apply to the sale or exchange of any regulated payment stablecoin by a taxpayer who is a dealer or trader in securities or commodities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCEF1E34678974E2C823AF7AF7C75F62E" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out this section, including to prevent the avoidance of tax under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC722767765ED47D785521AB893A8C09D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter O of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1045 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6D320D9132034D47A508DBEBD37C011C"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H5F7A827DC26A482C9CA4BA8B60F1D166">Sec. 1046. Regulated payment stablecoin transactions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF10304CDED794F53B2ECD6FCEE99BB2A" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC348A477A1484E2E8C8DFB56DB22422A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Digital asset trading safe harbor</header><subsection id="HE53A12624070419E90F3E502F21B12EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/864">section 864(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D) and by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80236C7FDDC94B19A99428F776CAB64E"><subparagraph id="HEFCB602F7E7549AAB9E54D839FED2A7C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Traded digital assets</header><clause id="HAFFFB0064FCA4B179752E5C366E667D3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Trading in traded digital assets through a resident broker, commission agent, custodian, or other independent agent.</text></clause><clause id="H6DD94483AB0246B487DFDD61F99A87A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Trading for taxpayer’s own account</header><text>Trading in traded digital assets for the taxpayer’s own account, whether by the taxpayer or the taxpayer’s employees or through a resident broker, commission agent, custodian, digital asset exchange, or other agent, and whether or not any such employee or agent has discretionary authority to make decisions in effecting the transactions. This clause shall not apply in the case of a dealer in digital assets.</text></clause><clause id="H93B9672CDA18466B96C116A922B8439E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This subparagraph shall apply only if the digital assets are of a kind customarily dealt in on a digital asset exchange.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7EF9096FF64F46A3B1E970E3565B76FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Subparagraph (D) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/864">section 864(b)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended by striking <quote>(A)(i) and (B)(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>(A)(i), (B)(i), and (C)(i)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0566017DB7F84110ADEDBBC3A163C39F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H35DA4C2701DF4A90A9BD80450DF1CBF9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Tax treatment of digital asset lending agreements and related matters</header><subsection id="H07C33A299445411CA28568650E94DC28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1058">section 1058</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>, or eligible digital assets</quote> after <quote>(as defined in section 1236(c))</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H26D4F83C752E41ABB7FEF86414E997B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Basis</header><text>Subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1058">section 1058</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In the case of a basis adjustment to securities or eligible digital assets with respect to which an agreement is in place which meets the requirements of subsection (b), such adjustment shall be made by factoring in the return to the transferor of securities identical to the securities transferred.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB8B24DD45C2C4A3184C92DFE90D48B19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Substitute payments</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1058">Section 1058</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2AD15882700B4CC18054A270CE6F551B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3B3A0126936F4782AEDA73F16538E54D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Substitute payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any payment made to a lender pursuant to an agreement described in subsection (b) in lieu of staking rewards, transaction fees, protocol distributions, or other amounts that would otherwise be payable with respect to a lent digital asset shall be included in the gross income of the lender in the same manner as if such amounts had been received directly by the lender.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H066054E8AD3940A59AB38AB11EBE0D27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section, or any amendments made by this section, shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the classification of any digital asset as a security under the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77a">15 U.S.C. 77a et seq.</external-xref>) or the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC803B65688CD4C35A7EA01E41089313C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) may adopt rules to implement the amendments made by this section, including the application of the amendments made by this section to forks, airdrops, and similar subsidiary value.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDAEAFA53A76C414AA7781FC4F2CB2993"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to exchanges in taxable years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFE4CB8CBE8484CDF9778C5375A213195"><enum>5.</enum><header>Application of wash sale rules to digital assets</header><subsection id="H0064E3711211462DBACF6ADC06A25C79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1091">Section 1091</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><paragraph id="H84D6CDDF86634A65B2183979583EC84B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>stock or securities</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>specified assets</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88B600C9D9EE4557A81532988CD6553C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shares of</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF7D4A2315004BB5857940A755E4738C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified asset</header><text>Section 1091 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H93A06A62A9F44C0E9B150A27B4B78D43" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HE206FA20089F4C7BBAC979DA2A443D9B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Specified asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H642B6BFD68C64A4C965D817B0B4023B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>specified asset</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H60CD44F1524F46AF961601A8883ADBAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any stock or security, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29E7868C2E6B42689139C5C0678E209B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any digital asset.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6037DBE5A504CAEA55A2D2F3B7BA184" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts and options</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in regulations, the term <quote>specified asset</quote> shall include any contract or option to acquire or sell any specified asset described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2935863973394B87A7D8C87BE0584195"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Treatment of certain assets as substantially identical</header><paragraph id="HCB27D6A590ED4633B6B78FFE52579189"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of determining whether an asset is substantially identical to any digital asset under this section, except to the extent provided by regulations prescribed by the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="HCDF965B0C80D4178B658C8C75F414735"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the determination of whether an asset is substantially identical to any other asset shall be made on the basis of the economic exposure of the asset,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04F89B1322FC4E4CB1B533E486E7C7C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the mere fact that an asset may have different or no voting rights shall not prevent the asset from being substantially identical to any other asset,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7763966622A8402A88E85CCD949871E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the mere fact that an asset may trade on a different exchange (or no exchange) or a different blockchain (or no blockchain) shall not be taken into account, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H796E269A64DE45D4824A77296EAD93CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any asset that would not otherwise be treated as substantially identical to another asset shall not be so treated merely because the asset is based on the same or substantially similar protocol or computer code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A037CFE5027486EB797162A58C48982"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No inference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall create any inference as to whether any property is substantially identical to any property that is not a digital asset or as to whether any property was substantially identical to any digital asset before the effective date of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4FFC2D5816C04C1A822436ACD7C3F047"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H4EE9463A4BEB4B1EADF0597198A0FC2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sections 312(f)(1), 1256(f)(5), and 6045(g)(2)(B)(ii) are each amended by striking <quote>stock or securities</quote> and inserting <quote>specified assets</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63F65AE4210A4621A3BE09D8419F4815"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1091(a) is amended by striking the last sentence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7932C605DCF846849D43194A11D48E78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 1091(e) (as amended by subsection (a)) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD29FCF7B6D1541A3893537FD95A49A5C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H2629AAB3A4134FD2914AB3FF47C96A3C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certain short sales of specified assets and specified asset futures contracts To sell</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of subsection (a) shall apply to any loss realized on the closing of a short sale of (or the sale, exchange, or termination of a specified asset futures contract to sell) specified assets if, within a period beginning 30 days before the date of such closing and ending 30 days after such date—</text><paragraph id="H0673708DA22A447FA8F32F0A64744FEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>substantially identical specified assets were sold, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E7313BE105A441A932A73E3D0295561"><enum>(2)</enum><text>another short sale of (or specified asset futures contracts to sell) substantially identical specified assets was entered into.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">For purposes of
                                this subsection, the term <quote>specified asset futures
                                    contract</quote> has the meaning provided by section
 1234B(c).</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F58ECF9D8624805AF38D2A2478C2C30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The heading of section 1091 is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">stock or securities</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">specified assets</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59A9425F2D494B9F85F098B329FE9F15"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The headings of subsections (b), (c), and (d) of section 1091 are each amended by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Stock</header-in-text></quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Specified Assets</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50A268C110A84F77A9CB1EB179451268"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The item relating to section 1091 in the table of sections for part VII of subchapter O of chapter 1 is amended by striking <quote>stock or securities</quote> and inserting <quote>specified assets</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7ABA492A3DF7453C838D8595AB4B2A5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to sales, dispositions, and terminations after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53945E87B46A478089440938FBF85869"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mark-to-market election</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8052C252EAFF4CB3905FF3295EA82405"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/475">Section 475</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h) and by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7ED11257323940E9BA536CE7F1B4FACE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H1F630487455B425FB02F3E2DF6EA5E14"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Election of mark To market for dealers and traders in actively-Traded digital assets</header><paragraph id="H63358FB1E979422C924826A429B5EE1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dealer in digital assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a dealer in actively-traded digital assets who elects the application of this subsection, this section shall apply to digital assets held by such dealer in the same manner as this section applies to securities held by a dealer in securities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AED25094D8B4377AC4F310D7F819CDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trader in digital assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a person who is engaged in a trade or business as a trader in actively traded digital assets, and who elects to have this paragraph apply to such trade or business as a trader in actively traded digital assets, subsection (f)(1) shall apply to digital assets held by the trader in connection with such trade or business in the same manner as such subsection applies to securities held by a trader in securities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F0E9C0724C9422A9BFDA9C75E7E165D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An election under this section shall only apply to digital assets treated as actively traded (as defined by the Secretary).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF95CF9956654417E9E10BCEAA4A1F7C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations and guidance as are necessary to carry out the provisions of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70097379022F40AB93D1D4EDF75A33B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H747452DB656A464A9F0BDCD0DC7DB717"><enum>7.</enum><header>Application of constructive sale rules to digital assets</header><subsection id="H63727BE290514351AE5CBB4D4C77A9B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1259 is amended by inserting <quote>digital asset,</quote> after <quote>debt instrument,</quote> each place it appears.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9EEDB3CD721C4C6A8057014885E2EB86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply to constructive sales after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE24F6853B07447628C3CDB46C987C872" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Treatment of digital assets acquired through validation activities</header><subsection id="H8375BA638AB34C40A1A30794B3AD3A56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 1 is amended by inserting after subchapter V the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAF53AB662704C76B15FFC1136408F17"><subchapter id="HDD80545491E34F84AD2412CD4A7B673C"><enum>W</enum><header>Digital assets acquired through validation activities</header><toc container-level="subchapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" idref="HDD80545491E34F84AD2412CD4A7B673C"><toc-entry level="section" idref="H97DDE9BF94834F60BF2D0C9707C43774">Sec. 1400W–1. Inclusion in gross income; expenses not capitalized.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA24B9C90217947AAB64F53FCED120F13">Sec. 1400W–2. Election to defer inclusion of income and capitalize expenses.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H53AFDF6D8F354F249671DC723FBC19FB">Sec. 1400W–3. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc><section id="H97DDE9BF94834F60BF2D0C9707C43774"><enum>1400W–1.</enum><header>Inclusion in gross income; expenses not capitalized</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of the acquisition of any newly created digital asset by a taxpayer which is a specified taxpayer during any taxable year—</text><paragraph id="H577B5F346A6D4EFDA33ACF09EB0E3DCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the fair market value of such asset shall be included in such taxpayer’s gross income as ordinary income for such taxable year, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3B9FF14AB0B49D0B3A6653C27E9EBDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the taxpayer’s basis in such asset shall be increased by the amount included in gross income under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA24B9C90217947AAB64F53FCED120F13"><enum>1400W–2.</enum><header>Election to defer inclusion of income and capitalize
 expenses</header><subsection id="H5A830A46AE934FD6BBDBACA25282763C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxpayer which is a specified taxpayer for any taxable year to which an election under subsection (c) applies—</text><paragraph id="HDB38BFDDB81C406B9DB0E58B86DB0CC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any newly created digital asset acquired by such taxpayer during such taxable year shall not be included in the taxpayer’s gross income,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD57AD448C6406E93016231F3637555"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specified transaction costs paid or incurred during such taxable year shall be chargeable to capital account and no deduction shall otherwise be allowed under this subtitle with respect to such costs, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17056E6ED20D423393BF2E3EBB6E0295"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 1400W–1 shall not apply.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9941C8C58B714A7E8C7FE8FC6EA03D3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Gain and loss on disposition during election period treated as ordinary</header><text>In the case of the disposition of any newly created digital asset to which subsection (a)(1) applies—</text><paragraph id="H5CD7B1C28E1C4286914E6423135EDE03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><subparagraph id="HA0062041BDFB449A9CE5E1A79240E8E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount realized (in the case of a sale or exchange) or the fair market value of such asset (in the case of any other disposition), over</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEBF44A6BBBE4869A757A98B2668A37D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the adjusted basis of such asset,</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">shall be treated as gain which is ordinary income (and such gain shall be recognized notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle), and</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46ED892570BA45CF99D6FC3ED46F66C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of the amount described in paragraph (1)(B) over the amount described in paragraph (1)(A) shall be treated as loss which is ordinary loss.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8F9FF46C8B2487680E0063798524300"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Election</header><paragraph id="HB9DB2B4A313D41CD896DDE36A210958C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An election under this section shall apply for the taxable year for which made and each of the four successive taxable years thereafter unless revoked by the taxpayer. Such election shall be made at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAAA5B4EBCA14DF7B4786CDB1BCD2A0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to partnerships and S corporations</header><text>In the case of any partnership or S corporation, the election under this section shall be made at the partnership or S corporation level.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFBAF6FD57204550BCDFEA460C76C2B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Gains and losses on disposition after election
 period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the sale, exchange, or other disposition of a digital asset with respect to which an election was in effect under subsection (b) for a prior taxable year, gains and losses with respect to such asset shall be treated as long-term capital gains or long-term capital losses, as the case may be.</text></subsection></section><section id="H53AFDF6D8F354F249671DC723FBC19FB"><enum>1400W–3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this subchapter—</text><paragraph id="HF1A4AE2CF0364BA4A6CD3F9DB8DEEB79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Newly created digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>newly created digital asset</quote> means any digital asset—</text><subparagraph id="H177C2B49A4944FBFA5CF22C807379D38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not previously owned by any person other than the validator, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2725056468DB492B84D18A696B23F2B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is issued in connection with the validation of digital asset transactions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA042D5BE97BE4371887359BDE32E22A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified taxpayer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specified taxpayer</quote> means, with respect to the acquisition of any newly created digital asset that is issued in connection with the validation of digital asset transactions, a taxpayer who is the person who validated the digital asset transactions in connection with which such digital asset was issued.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04C6BE4890FE4849AFF41B8387DDFE57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specified transaction costs</header><text>The term <quote>specified transaction costs</quote> means any amount paid or incurred in validating any digital asset transaction if, at the time such amount is paid or incurred there is a reasonable possibility that the taxpayer will acquire a newly created digital asset in connection with such validation, including amounts to—</text><subparagraph id="HA6C795ECA21E496A812588845DEC6FED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>claim or withdraw such asset from a staking pool, validator, or protocol,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H103DFA2A474D483D9B143DB7E9CE61F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>execute a smart contract function to receive such asset, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00548E749FDD42DE87B80D7D84102257"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transfer such asset to a wallet or account controlled by the taxpayer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1C6907C047BC4346850A272152458763"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of subchapters for chapter 1 is amended by inserting after the item relating to subchapter V the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84BC746ABDE249519F4D540842FF9D25"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" idref="HAAF53AB662704C76B15FFC1136408F17"><toc-entry level="subchapter" idref="HDD80545491E34F84AD2412CD4A7B673C">Subchapter W—Digital assets acquired through validation activities</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3C16106C15DE4A168B0EF047300102A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to assets acquired in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H122ECFA381F04E5481E7C9C0D4252356"><enum>9.</enum><header>Charitable contributions and qualified appraisals</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4013AB4CE1FA4C1CA40D2D39E0477ED7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">Section 170(f)(11)(A)(ii)(I)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>actively traded digital assets,</quote> before <quote>and any qualified vehicle</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D3B49409BF740188C4D53ECDDE6408C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of application to qualified appraisals</header><text>Section 170(f)(11)(B) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following sentence: <quote>The requirements of this subparagraph shall not apply to contributions of actively traded digital assets.</quote></text></subsection><subsection id="H186A9CC5E93D45E9809BD9BDF999A754"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Substantiation and valuation requirements</header><text>Section 170(f) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDB74F1ABCB4D49168AEFE07262E6D794" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE4C8823EA56649A9B63965A75D6FB0DF"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Infrequently traded digital assets</header><subparagraph id="H279896C5D6CA4A16A17E0BFC87E3C9B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a contribution of a digital asset which is not an actively traded digital asset the claimed value of which exceeds $500—</text><clause id="H61CDD84E4B0D456FAA8ECEFFD810A08B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (8) shall not apply and no deduction shall be allowed under subsection (a) for such contribution unless the taxpayer substantiates the contribution by a contemporaneous written acknowledgment of the contribution by the donee organization that meets the requirements of subparagraph (B) and includes the acknowledgment with the taxpayer's return of tax which includes the deduction, and</text></clause><clause id="HF092460625A748FDA6414A1C064FE39E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the organization sells such asset, the amount of the deduction allowed under subsection (a) shall not exceed the gross proceeds received from such sale.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73EBB3B1FE724044AE0EDA5244872019"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Content of acknowledgment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An acknowledgment meets the requirements of this subparagraph if it includes the following information:</text><clause id="HD17278BE4DEB4BFAB8E95653E3186D02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The name and taxpayer identification number of the donor.</text></clause><clause id="H6FD230EA2CBE4C1684933D3859BC68E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Details of the transfer of the digital asset contribution, including—</text><subclause id="H4CDEC66B0BA94658AD0755D6EB34C50F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>specific addresses involved in the contribution,</text></subclause><subclause id="HB7E56284FFAD4199A752E9400DC1264C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of the digital asset contributed, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H15177698A1B5488F8AA8CD30FBF827DE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the date of the contribution.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1CE2D946169B4D83AF1464E342EA478F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A certification that the digital asset was sold in an arm’s length transaction between unrelated parties.</text></clause><clause id="HA85D5895E5644AE7A4402EA5538066D4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The amount of gross proceeds from the sale described in clause (iii).</text></clause><clause id="H9659EA1BA0904B24942E41A1AE4FA270"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A statement that the deductible amount may not exceed the amount the gross proceeds described in clause (iv).</text></clause><clause id="H5EBC49DC672F427EBA394D24E7741384"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Whether the donee organization provided any goods or services in consideration, in whole or in part, for the digital asset.</text></clause><clause id="H5E5CFF5391334FE89F220778CF999624"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A description and good faith estimate of the value of any goods or services referred to in clause (vi), or if such goods or services consist solely of intangible religious benefits (as defined in 170(f)(8)(B)), a statement to that effect.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56E27FEC00624382BF53D93A015FD21E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contemporaneous acknowledgement; Information to Secretary</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subparagraphs (C)(i) and (D) of paragraph (12) shall apply.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H61036B8856C74D39850942D18BB9D2E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalty for fraudulent acknowledgment</header><paragraph id="HF0B5EF10318B42B2A1A36A3879377477"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part I of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/68">chapter 68</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HACF895F1B4C44D46BD47391C6EAADB64" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HB85D6CB5D4834347BC039175AD3095BD"><enum>6720D.</enum><header>Fraudulent acknowledgments with respect to donations of digital assets</header><subsection id="H806FDA2071044D9DA1DFB11E60D2BD13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any donee organization required under section 170(f)(20)(A) to furnish a contemporaneous written acknowledgment to a donor which knowingly furnishes a false or fraudulent acknowledgment, or which knowingly fails to furnish such acknowledgment in the manner, at the time, and showing the information required under section 170(f)(20), or regulations prescribed thereunder, shall for each such act, or for each such failure, be subject to a penalty equal to the greater of—</text><paragraph id="H1BDB4B69B021491B9AC8352C7A1C22AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the product of the highest rate of tax specified in section 1 and the sales price stated on the acknowledgment, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB31E8DDB5CB40C58135F18ACB551636"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the gross proceeds from the sale of such digital asset.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H489B94B93CF34141B01249C83A731D8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H217F23ECEEBC43FDA459350DDA42EDD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections of part I of subchapter B of chapter 68 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section"><quote>Sec. 6720D. Fraudulent acknowledgments with respect to donations of digital assets.</quote></toc-entry></toc></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7B16AD63322429DBD08BD4FD833CC62"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to contributions and acknowledgments made in taxable years beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC821C931B32946288CA130350B0B7FCB"><enum>10.</enum><header>Tax treatment of certain digital asset activities</header><subsection id="H34E70FE85A454CE78064532085447841"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">Section 7701</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (p) as subsection (q) and by inserting after subsection (o) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9EA35EB0DA38400A9B835B2B0AEC1AEC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H806BFA4DA57B4E1683ACEFBB6BAE0D90"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Tax treatment of certain digital asset activities</header><paragraph id="H5BFA96B505854D199C96DD34CDF4A0DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Passive staking not a trade or business</header><subparagraph id="HA741E35A7FED46639571502401CDD3A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Passive staking shall not constitute a trade or business, including for purposes of sections 512 and 864.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35506A4B9D294A7FA6D33E3F93AA9077"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Passive staking</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><clause id="H50AE13C175D3457C8C09EC61FA754856"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>passive staking</quote> means staking by an individual or entity that is a passive validator.</text></clause><clause id="HD4A027BB2C4043C1AB0F644FF4459313"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Passive validator</header><text>The term <quote>passive validator</quote> means, with respect to the acquisition of any newly created digital asset (as defined in section 1400W–3)—</text><subclause id="H709D1BF85F3E47AD910FE86384F7A9B2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the person who validated the digital asset transactions in connection with which such digital asset was issued, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA4C5D522F9104B2EA310EC33289F6C3A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to which there are no deductible business expenses relating to such validation activity.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H14CE64AA7EBA4CDF8E34EE2D9CF09D6A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital assets in investment trusts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title, in the case of a digital asset investment trust formed to hold digital assets—</text><subparagraph id="H7542EA1666394DBEB1B01B064BC1AD62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any power held by the trustee to stake or unstake digital assets, whether directly or through delegation to another party, and to perform any related acts to exercise such power to stake, including the retention of staking rewards, shall not be treated as a power under such trust agreement to vary the investment of the certificate holders of such trust and shall not otherwise disqualify an entity from characterization as an investment trust that is not classified as a business entity under this section,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H413682E52301402590811F9DD48EF266"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discretionary powers held by a trustee to use other measures, including a borrowing facility, to manage the trust’s potential need for assets available to satisfy redemptions shall not be treated as a power under the applicable trust agreement to vary the investment of the certificate holders of such trust, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69E4E3D08D124C348093B3ECF6AC258C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>discretionary powers held by a trustee to act in response to changes to technology supporting the digital assets held by the trust, including with regard to staking, shall not be treated as a power under the applicable trust agreement to vary the investment of the certificate holders of such trust.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3422AEA2D37C4AFC80A4E8F410143DC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE434543F475D45D7A8E953C9F4216E3D" commented="no"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">Section 7701</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by this Act, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF58D0029CB324BB2A2D5B205A2AFC617" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (q) as subsection (r), and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE150D8EBAB564960A58DFF6F7A6E7E5A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (p) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98BA0136F1E34737ACFA6E62886E008B"><subsection id="H42C057AEA1AD4FCD80F05D3257AAA226" commented="no"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Definitions related to digital assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title—</text><paragraph id="H49A1F1A5F7C1454095537A624D60447E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>digital asset</quote> means a digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger or any similar technology as specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEFAFE64D5214606BDC706BD15CBA0B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital asset exchange</header><text>The term <term>digital asset exchange</term> means a platform which facilitates the transfer of digital assets by taking custody of, or exercising control over, such assets on behalf of users.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2693A995E8284D2F854805F700D100E4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Actively traded digital asset</header><subparagraph id="H4A3D62E9BC6D44D88AD764B14CEC58A6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>actively traded digital asset</quote> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, any digital asset—</text><clause id="H8D89119DC6694F1389D2110D4CD0397F" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is fungible,</text></clause><clause id="H014567E4A90F43A5AF96A0C512305643" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with a minimum trading volume of $50,000,000 for the two calendar years immediately preceding the sale or exchange of such asset,</text></clause><clause id="H31936B7E99A34DE6B1B5EDC1278E1CB3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with a minimum yearly market capitalization of $10,000,000,000 for the three calendar years immediately preceding the sale or exchange of such asset, and</text></clause><clause id="H41BA86B3F9B74C088F7BA751EEA33D90" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with respect to which the taxpayer and the related parties of the taxpayer hold no more than 5 percent by value or units of such asset.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E55FA9DE091435B8DE529B586A9A164" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any calendar year after 2025, each of the dollar amounts in subparagraph (A) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="HD003789A07EE41438F156BD482A865AE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="HBD8334854FED41269445FC19CC7F37CA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2024</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">Any increase determined under the preceding sentence which is not a multiple of $100,000 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD30D1324B5BA4EE0AD070A4488F8D450" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible digital asset</header><text>The term <quote>eligible digital asset</quote> means a digital asset that—</text><subparagraph id="HE933E78619AF4990967326310D7B1FA7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is fungible,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CE8E9FFFF2B480A85757AE09AFB55FB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is of a type for which a market price is readily ascertainable based on publicly available quotations on a digital asset exchange,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A0DDE5202D24172BC3D5EC80CD3B891" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not represent or confer any ownership interest, equity interest, debt obligation, or other financial or property right in any entity, asset, commodity, or enterprise, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE305987C4E3F4CFCAF1EBEA1678FEF56" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is designed and functions as a medium of exchange, store of value, or unit of account, and is recorded and transferred through distributed ledger or blockchain technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A0B5C3834424053B428E149DA1F9237"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Traded digital asset</header><text>The term <term>traded digital asset</term> means a digital representation of value that—</text><subparagraph id="HA6C001797C034FAD9C0D07BAF87C4DA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designed and functions as a medium of exchange, store of value, or unit of account,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9D78DE45FA0481A946B064904DE1550"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is recorded and transferred through distributed ledger or blockchain technology,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1426A8FFB7404CC5BA099450A03F4CF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not represent or confer any ownership interest, equity interest, debt obligation, or other financial or property right in any entity, asset, commodity, or enterprise, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H640BEA4DF02F4BC09CDEB58D89813297"><enum>(D)</enum><text>does not derive its value from, or represent a claim on, any fiat currency, commodity, security, or other financial instrument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FCD5E9EA74B44FE961734D34474EF56"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Validation activity</header><text>The term <quote>validation activity</quote> means staking, mining, or similar activities in support of the validation of digital asset transactions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84B0970059814414B0A3CDC79F819941"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Mining</header><text>The term <quote>mining</quote>, when used in connection with a digital asset, means—</text><subparagraph id="H600B9793BD254F6BA92E8AE582EE8E90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performing computations, or making available computing power, in support of the validation of digital asset transactions, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B08D335113D4D25A958A5B65CCDA7D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any substantially similar activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9661E7285F44ADE8B1ACEFC25B81AB0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Staking</header><text>The term <quote>staking</quote>, when used in connection with a digital asset, means—</text><subparagraph id="HD1AA26090A974F52AD9B44707F4AC24F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making such asset available in support of the validation of digital asset transactions by pledging, deploying, immobilizing, or locking to support validation of transactions on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE60208FAE71D4E24A5F332C083CC6000" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any substantially similar activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H73A71F4C94BC43379D38D0522D9B3484"><enum>12.</enum><header>Study and report on relief for digital asset consumer transactions</header><subsection id="HC4091C0C24244ACC9EC9306700AE5A6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text><paragraph id="H456A8AD6C4A345159A822D5BBBEB8D75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the estimated compliance burden currently imposed on taxpayers by gain recognition requirements for small digital asset transactions, expressed in aggregate hours and dollars, and disaggregated by income level,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87FCFB3FB89B4162A3B74379828E7A91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which information reporting under section 6045 captures digital asset transactions of $200 or less, including the gap attributable to transactions conducted without a broker intermediary,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31ABCDCB4B4B4DFF9B3867706C53599C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the administrative and technological requirements necessary for the Internal Revenue Service to verify taxpayer eligibility for a de minimis exclusion within existing appropriations,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17192CC4284D4A1E92DAD984F9ECEA4D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the potential for abuse of a de minimis exclusion, including through transaction fragmentation, the use of multiple accounts or wallets, and the mischaracterization of investment dispositions as consumer transactions, and the mechanisms available to detect and deter such abuse without imposing additional taxpayer reporting burdens,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H247C089FB2934B83B75B7A6037939E9B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the extent to which any de minimis exclusion could be implemented in a manner that maintains consistency between taxpayer reporting and third-party information reporting under section 6045,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAB5ABE0FFEC48FDA3081EBB7A92C397"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any disparities in reporting, compliance, or enforcement between custodial and non-custodial digital asset transactions that would arise from a de minimis exclusion,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF87CF89F8959446CA5291BEB5A85443A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recommended legislative or regulatory approaches, if any, that would provide meaningful consumer relief while remaining administrable by the Internal Revenue Service within existing resources,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC0155AAE5174078B70CFBD60312DDDC"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of additional resources that would enable the Internal Revenue Service to fully enforce existing laws concerning digital assets,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF69E2C86FF694F98A819377AB41484C4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the extent to which tax reporting, compliance, or enforcement does not meet Crypto Asset Reporting Framework (CARF) standards, with recommended legislative or regulatory approaches, if any, that would bring the United States into compliance with CARF, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0A0088F360D431C9381F474D35FF3FF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the extent of tax avoidance risks associated with digital asset transactions, including through noncompliance, offshore activity, or structuring techniques, and the feasibility of establishing a voluntary disclosure program to facilitate taxpayer compliance with respect to such transactions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25300856806B478795F5A4A60C94BCC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue guidance identifying categories of digital asset transactions for which relief from gain or loss recognition may be provided under existing authority, including where—</text><paragraph id="H8C4570CDE9E14E6FBF387F4BDDCE0C0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compliance burdens are disproportionate relative to potential tax liability, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83FCEFFB17A148E0B6C6DCB36E47F5D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such relief can be administered without undermining information reporting or return matching.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3CA9BFFD6E214F61B8A393861AC4E6E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H7C771C86B0EB40EB85D3D07AC021D541"><enum>(1)</enum><text>taxpayers should not be subject to undue compliance burdens for low-value digital asset transactions undertaken for personal consumption,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF7FFB212AC14794A3F179E785EDCFA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any de minimis exclusion should be designed to provide meaningful relief to users while maintaining the integrity of the Federal tax system, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9398DD74E97943BAB86CC98EB5FF1782"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such relief should be implemented only in a manner that is administrable within existing Internal Revenue Service resources.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1727D1500A9D4B07BEBFCDD9588B878A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="HE8FFE9A878C54E86A1B2F1C46CCE8CF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create or imply the existence of a de minimis exclusion for digital asset transactions, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80FA2B0EAE2D422AA165BEB48EACD953"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide independent authority to the Secretary to implement such an exclusion except to the extent otherwise authorized under existing law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF68EDBF29DA14F8F8ED9CD41414D4610"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s delegate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

