<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7F7A4BB0C09483687FDF159CAC488AA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6633 IH: High-Capacity Grid Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6633</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000482">Mrs. Fedorchak</sponsor> introduced the following bill;
                which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy
                    and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a best-available transmission conductor standard for certain transmission projects under the Federal Power Act and to provide for presumptions regarding cost recovery for such conductors.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F538D0B9D274E5CA662126A16AFA656" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF6486BCD3C29452087FAC101DF85E0A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>High-Capacity Grid Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDCBC699733A24686B70492DCD6AF547A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Best-available transmission conductor standard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 205 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824d">16 U.S.C. 824d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H85822B7B1A2B45C59C05C6D74B58090D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HE5A4F390BCBC4E07964FACF800145116">
          <enum>(h)</enum>
          <header>Best-Available transmission conductor standard</header>
          <paragraph id="H6FD265D6FE89433FB24FDF53DC6871FB">
            <enum>(1)</enum>
            <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HC259841F9FDD4F69BDB1D964224F5CC3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>Best-available transmission conductor</header> <text>The term <term>best-available transmission conductor</term> means a transmission conductor that, as determined by the Commission by rule under paragraph (5)—</text>
              <clause id="HDB83C9F00F154CF3B8AC70BBC159E8A5">
                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>provides the greatest feasible and commercially available energy-carrying capacity at a given voltage level;</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="HB66A5198D71B4A25ABE6CFC1A6B038B6">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>provides the highest feasible and commercially available electrical efficiency at that voltage level; and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H7AB67E4E63594E978220D98D31C5BAF6">
                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>mitigates thermal sag at the maximum rated transmission-carrying capacity of the facility.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H39EA7B2F64084F24BF67FF8423D1B80D">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
              <header>Covered project</header>
 <text>The term <term>covered project</term> means—</text> <clause id="HCF6462077AD34013A48409BA7716393E"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>the construction of a new transmission facility subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission under section 201(b); and</text>
              </clause>
              <clause id="H62A366B9A3624277A6D82D49A0A5320E">
                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>any modification, upgrade, replacement, or reconductoring of an existing transmission line subject to such jurisdiction.</text>
              </clause>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H7A01049C059849D5B2794BF64A399C49">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
            <header>Presumption of prudence for best-available transmission conductors</header>
 <text>In any filing seeking to recover the cost of a transmission conductor for a covered project, and in any proceeding to determine whether such cost may be recovered through rates, the Commission shall presume that the use of a best-available transmission conductor is a prudent practice and that the associated costs are just and reasonable.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H3E9C891BF97746E58349A52654F29ECA">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
            <header>Presumption against recovery of costs for non-best-available conductors</header>
 <text>In any filing seeking to recover the cost of a transmission conductor for a covered project, and in any proceeding to determine whether such cost may be recovered through rates, the Commission shall presume that the use of a transmission conductor that is not a best-available transmission conductor is not prudent and that the associated costs are not just and reasonable.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCFC38D75F1E14CA2A9FD9B38576E6C3A">
            <enum>(4)</enum>
            <header>Applicability</header>
 <text>The requirements of this subsection apply only to public utilities and only with respect to covered projects that are subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission under section 201(b).</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="H400F31EDE83E438FBA958ACA1A7F2C05">
            <enum>(5)</enum>
            <header>Rulemaking</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Commission shall promulgate regulations to implement this subsection. In promulgating such regulations, the Commission shall—</text>
            <subparagraph id="H18217DA522A14760A8B34DA2EB6C175E">
              <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>establish a methodology for determining whether a transmission conductor is a best-available transmission conductor for purposes of this subsection;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H641274FEED524031A4ECD594FB226CF5">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>ensure that such methodology is consistent with the criteria set forth in paragraph (1)(A); and</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H24ACBFEBF6A34372A2B904BC1CC58C34">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>provide for periodic review and updating of the methodology to reflect improvements in technology, materials, and system performance.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
        </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

