<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF7E9FDCD91D84E548B9546B825ADA306" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5973 IH: Stop Excessive Force in Immigration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5973</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish certain limitations on Federal immigration enforcement personnel.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0867448CE07F4DBAB13FD8D7E6F9445D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB7F13B2662D24B1C82E1ED73278B2D27" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Excessive Force in Immigration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H7895C5ADDBD84B1BA1892EF7A52E3CB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H515D1026D6234CDCABB24F1332342836"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to use force is a serious responsibility that shall be exercised judiciously and with respect for human rights and dignity and for the sanctity of every human life. Every person has a right to be free from excessive use of force by law enforcement acting under color of law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB5B13A828F34D9483395B0940894BA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It is the responsibility of all law enforcement, Federal, State, and local, to promote and further public safety.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0476E78EFFFA4223B7E8D0B0DAF8C5A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Federal immigration enforcement personnel should conduct interior enforcement operations with the intention of creating minimal community disruption and furthering public safety.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61D72604F4DF4634BB9B37C4A742B12E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of force manual of the Department of Justice states that reducing the need for force allows officers to secure their own safety, as well as the safety of the public.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76B2A797AF3E485D932C2802A957FABD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 287.8 of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations, requires that designated immigration personnel shall at the time of the arrest identify themselves as an immigration officer and provide the reason for a person’s arrest as soon as it is practical and safe to do so.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC82B34F260E46AFBEF1409558CDA5A9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The First Amendment prevents Federal immigration enforcement personnel from using force against, or to impede the work of journalists who are properly identified and acting lawfully.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB2886955BC84CD8911261C41F66832D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The First Amendment protects freedom of speech and prevents Federal immigration enforcement personnel from using force against protesters or bystanders acting lawfully.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29C26017B4C046C9BE8B2FC2C5FF8B2C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel are to refuse orders they believe to be blatantly illegal or create an unnecessary risk to public safety.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D100DA6B5F847C7B619B53E93073198"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress condemns violence and threats directed against law enforcement personnel.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H50771CBBAB6C490D9E516636E7F63879"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement limits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act is amended by inserting after section 287 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4B387DFA96D8497EAF8F98EF23CEF991" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H247C047688BD4859B34893FC6DE7DB55"><enum>287A.</enum><header>Federal immigration enforcement</header> <subsection id="H1543FD4665FB4779BE7CE5DAC93AEF25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of force</header> <paragraph id="H5EB12DF4351B4443B5E241E7EA7D7D0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall be subject to the following requirements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H93228882680C4F0ABD87336197DD58FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of force standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel may use non-deadly force as follows:</text> <clause id="HE004A9DE084B460FB8D8A5B0261200C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No reasonably effective, safe, and feasible alternative appears to exist to bring an unlawful situation safely and effectively under control, and the level of force used is proportional to the seriousness of the actual or threatened resistance.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE0E44B1ECB7641A4A63734C84E677734" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agents shall account for factors such as age, injury, disability, and size of the subject when assessing reasonableness.</text></clause> <clause id="H8E591BA67A744E75B64DA9F13A1B76EF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <quote>reasonableness</quote> of a particular use of force must be judged from the perspective of a reasonable officer on the scene, and its calculus must account for the fact that law enforcement personnel are often forced to make split-second decisions, in circumstances that are tense, uncertain, and rapidly evolving, about the amount of force necessary in a particular situation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H25AC59BD0AB84D27B61545AC4C90B567" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel who make or attempt to make an arrest need not retreat or desist from their efforts by reason of the resistance or threatened resistance of the person being arrested. Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall not be deemed an aggressor or lose the right to self-defense by the use of force when no reasonably effective, safe, and feasible alternative appears to exist, in compliance with clause (i), to effect the arrest or to prevent escape or to overcome resistance. For the purposes of this section, <quote>retreat</quote> does not mean tactical repositioning or other de-escalation tactics.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E7F4FB06EC44346A324FC58BBE0E238"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimization of risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall minimize the risk of injury to a third person when using non-deadly force.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C72292A86FC4546A7F848BC0AD9046C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deescalation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall make all reasonable efforts to de-escalate tensions prior to using force.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80D9804AF9DF4F0DA4D934D91DB3555E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Affirmative duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall have an affirmative duty to intervene to prevent or stop, as appropriate, any other Federal immigration enforcement personnel from engaging in excessive force or any other use of force that violates the Constitution, other Federal laws, or policies on the reasonable use of force. Such personnel who witness excessive use of force shall also have a duty to report it to their chain of command or the Department of Homeland Security’s Office of the Inspector General. Such personnel shall recognize and act upon the affirmative duty to request and, as appropriate, render medical aid, if needed.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E57B9E9BCDD4D3BB783F9AD9CECEF9A"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Masks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall limit the use of masks or face coverings, except in the case that a supervisory officer provides written approval for such use in one of the following instances:</text> <clause id="HB3BBCF02AB224351BAAD12250A8565D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The target poses a national security threat.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBD014E624D984D60A9A7DA5C9736C7CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a high likelihood that the personnel needs to maintain anonymity for future covert operations.</text></clause> <clause id="H64744FF55CB943488D1112FD3A119BAC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Masks are necessary to protect personnel’s health from environmental hazards.</text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D4218ACD0AA4FE79CD5FF2E166D5F32"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Identification</header> 
<clause id="H0722E89E655649788A5B805D35C99379"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall wear a uniform or identification clearly displaying their agency or that they are Federal immigration enforcement personnel, unless—</text> <subclause id="H5FC03281E934464C9BB98232123F09B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the target poses a public safety or national security threat;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H46A970417A8748AAB14CA6AE4F6875FB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not wearing identification is necessary to safely carry out the operation; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H876745ACD5CF48539041C3FCFD45DC59"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the personnel receives prior written approval from a supervisory officer.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H117CA4EF58B44E589FDC9D959C14D668"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>No uniform of Federal immigration enforcement personnel may use the title <quote>Police</quote> or any other identifier that may result in them being misidentified as local police officers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A6BDA871C56475290D46644CDE92E10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restricted equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel are prohibited from being equipped with or using noise flash diversionary devices (also known as flash bangs), rubber bullets, pepper balls, and tear gas, except for the following immigration enforcement operations purposes:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED7E5CBEC0BB444EB3233A15AA501959"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An immigration enforcement operation involving the arrest of a person in the presence or view of Federal immigration enforcement personnel who is entering or attempting to enter the United States in violation of any law.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F6FC553F29C480BBDC6BFEA73BC9245"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An immigration enforcement operation with respect to an enforcement target presenting a public safety or national security threat. To qualify for this exception, personnel are required to complete a tactical action plan, to be approved by their supervisor, outlining the equipment they plan to use in the operation and provide justification for the need for this equipment. Personnel may also complete a tactical action plan, to be approved by their supervisor, to provide them with the contingent authority to appropriately use restricted equipment in specified operations targeting national security or public safety threats in the event personnel unexpectedly encounter their target and do not have time to seek additional approval without jeopardizing apprehension of the target.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE059EBBE4265450F946FC88BE9E954E0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exceptions under this paragraph shall only apply in the case of Federal immigration enforcement personnel who are trained and certified for the use of the specified equipment.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEFD487144AD4A3FB933B7BD71DAF522"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Backup team</header> <subparagraph id="H4B1643DA238A401B8EC5BF26490917E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any operation not qualifying for an exception under paragraph (2), such operation may maintain a trained and certified backup team equipped with restricted nondeadly equipment that can be deployed when the safety of the primary Federal immigration enforcement personnel, or others, is at risk.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1AF5F6EA326499A997467E4571759FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>First Amendment activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The safety of Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall not be determined to be at risk solely due to lawful protest or other protected First Amendment activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAFC51A34BED4B0EB5C7ADEAE73FE9D6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Discipline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security and the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall be required to investigate and, if necessary, discipline any Federal immigration enforcement personnel, within their primary jurisdiction, who violates this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF801CAA12A024544A01BA621D41B91C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Body and vehicle Camera requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HF0D522BB57884C4C9959600CCAAD6C8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop and disseminate a Department-wide directive requiring the use of—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE5F587A89324D80A83A262B7907BDB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">body-worn cameras by all Federal immigration enforcement personnel; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66F26CE2DF4747ECB2AB6E797DB83287"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dashboard cameras for all vehicles being used in Federal immigration enforcement operations and associated recording protocols.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E6C5E360A854EEF8927DA0959F1DD1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Principles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the directive required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3ABCE5E6C054409280444C2C7858B4D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Benchmarks for implementation of the use of body-worn cameras by Federal immigration enforcement personnel and dashboard cameras for vehicles being used for Federal immigration enforcement to conform with a standard that cameras are on by default and may only be turned off in certain circumstances.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB599AE578F1404F8CC55170453BF0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training requirements, procedures, and best practices for the use of body-worn cameras and dashboard cameras.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA852AD6E52CC4E42B36A9086D8E476B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Plans to publicize the directive and the requirements set forth in this section to ensure Federal immigration enforcement personnel and other impacted individuals are notified of new policies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF63BE00B5564E50B3F4BC804FE09748"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The directive required under paragraph (1) shall not apply to any personnel who operate in a location where the Secretary carries out redundant video-monitoring or video-surveillance that is maintained in good working order and that provides video footage of a quality that is the same or better than that which would be captured by a body-worn camera or dashboard camera.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9734EC23CF54EE8A380A2D0108711AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Retention of footage</header> 
<subparagraph id="H52071AA4D0164AD38A5B27000875EC7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Body camera and dashboard camera video footage shall be retained by the Department of Homeland Security for 1 year after the date on which it was recorded, after which time such footage shall be permanently deleted.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBE9745402C34B5D9ACFFDC7681E97B8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional retention requirements</header><text>Notwithstanding the retention and deletion requirements in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="HF1B4535FEB9441FF8583FAD856526D4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such video footage shall be automatically retained for not less than three years if the video footage captures an interaction or event involving—</text> <subclause id="H26E451A016514299B61F7F250FAD0985"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any use of force; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC10A2B0685B549E0BCB110AE22732415"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an encounter involving a registered complaint by a subject of the video footage;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1CE05F41BC2E4225AF30C5DA7118E23F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such video footage shall be retained for not less than three years if a longer retention period is voluntarily requested by—</text> 
<subclause id="H1B4B0273CC234BE398E62D3492275EBF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal immigration enforcement personnel whose body camera recorded the video footage, if that personnel reasonably asserts the video footage has evidentiary or exculpatory value in an ongoing investigation or is a subject of the video footage, if the personnel reasonably asserts the video footage has evidentiary or exculpatory value;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE7730815CBA845E5A96BFD70B7075E80"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any superior officer of the personnel whose body camera recorded the video footage or who is a subject of the video footage, if that superior officer reasonably asserts the video footage has evidentiary or exculpatory value;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7E540C174C9A40DF99B294FD9E68996E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any uniformed law enforcement officer, if the video footage is being retained solely and exclusively for enforcement training purposes;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H00BAA93BC5F84442A78330C73DBC7FDB"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any member of the public who is a subject of the video footage;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H73103E568AFB425B9D3EEBB5075D339D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any parent or legal guardian of a minor who is a subject of the video footage; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8D8F49CE2196480D9A72084181709E2B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a spouse of a deceased subject, next of kin, or legally authorized designee; or</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HA92B6070461C4D8698C190367A40B220"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">footage may not be discarded until the conclusion of any investigation or lawsuit to which the footage is relevant.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05B557D53C324D0C9E223FD3FC9D0A8F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Right to inspect</header><text>During the retention periods described in paragraph (4), the following individuals shall have the right to inspect, but not retain or in any matter alter, the body camera footage:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7F846CC2AA6B45919117A13B0C72CB31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any individual who is a subject of body camera video footage, and their designated legal counsel.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H659349B7530D4CB9AC77102F9A2DCB32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A parent of a minor subject of body camera video footage, and their designated legal counsel.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5B7A26E60D624E479FB1025944A5734E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The spouse, next of kin, or legally authorized designee of a deceased subject of body camera video footage, and their designated legal counsel.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0B47A11BFE54D94A804263B85ADDC6B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel whose body camera recorded the video footage, and their designated legal counsel, subject to the limitations and restrictions in this part.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3F2DF32674649E5A9EC0EE677F99D82"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The superior officer of the personnel whose body camera recorded the video footage, subject to the limitations and restrictions in this part.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE36D9E1A2E5482BA7F4991288CD82C7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any defense counsel who claims, pursuant to a written affidavit, to have a reasonable basis for believing a video may contain evidence that exculpates a client.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5417E66CC8BA496CB2A5F6B4C69190AE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any Member of Congress representing the district in which the operation in the video took place.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H264C6312BCB04922870ACA2C3ED08EED"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Member of Congress who sits on a relevant Committee of jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2389490C0AAA4894BAE58882D7097ECB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall receive training, at least annually—</text> <paragraph id="HC06284BB694543F8BC7F718D798AE7D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on use of force policy and related legal updates; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCA88DDDB3514B8DAFB74A5DC4ECA9F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to—</text> <subparagraph id="HA4093A7912504034B2A54D5F37DCFC6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinforce the appropriate exercise of discretion and judgment in using non-deadly and deadly force;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1BABC53AF3E4223B3FAEE8AEE9964BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide techniques for the use of and reinforce the importance of de-escalation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC709EC29EC2428297237C2A6D9255C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>comply with the First Amendment’s protections for journalists, protesters, and those who assemble;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2795CCA36164403866E14B58807E46A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>comply with the Fourth Amendment’s protections against unreasonable searches and seizures;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4CF861DDAB374A70BA5D0E044E72F8B1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reinforce the illegality of determining immigration enforcement targets primarily based on race;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9EA15B5E08924EAFA861FF2DCF3D3A6F"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinforce the affirmative duty to intervene to prevent or stop, as appropriate, any officer from engaging in excessive force or any other use of force that violates the Constitution, other Federal laws, or policies on the reasonable use of force;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF47EBFCE6CF44A84B03F162E77ED88A4"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinforce the affirmative duty to request and/or render medical aid, as appropriate, where needed; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48C92FEAA93A424097DE51E914F4DE7B"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">document and keep records of practice for immigration enforcement operations.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E5B0C760F0E45CDBCFA5C5480D631A7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requiring notification for local law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement shall notify local law enforcement of impending operations in their jurisdiction.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H755D9392FF064508A6B3B0449945330E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>DHS reporting requirements</header><text>Beginning not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress the following reports on the criteria Federal immigration enforcement personnel use to determine whether an immigrant poses a public safety or national security threat:</text> <paragraph id="H809D24EBBA3C41C0BA7DF6802ADB8270"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report every 6 months detailing instances where non-deadly force was used, the level of public safety or national security threat the target posed, for what reason non-deadly force was administered, specific instances where non-deadly force was improperly administered, and the measures the Department took to ensure accountability for improper use of force.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA1C6A3057604B7BA5ADEAF587FDD12D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress a report every 6 months detailing instances of assaults against Federal immigration enforcement personnel. The report shall include the total number of personnel involved in immigration enforcement operations, the number of assaults against Federal immigration enforcement personnel, and details on the severity of those instances.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5D5698B1C974DEE9E2D94EBC9E43227"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall send a classified report to Congress every 6 months detailing instances in which Federal immigration enforcement personnel operated without identification.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H119BC4E91B7C425F942DD4349137C213"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to Congress every 6 months on the frequency of Federal immigration enforcement personnel using facial coverings.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H12737936E67849A898A463E0DF46E302" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>DOJ reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress every 6 months on the number and circumstances of incidents of individuals falsely impersonating a Federal immigration enforcement personnel, the public safety impact of individuals posing as immigration enforcement, and how the Department of Justice is combating impersonations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7C62B2F18584D498F1B8A0007C83309"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Database</header> 
<paragraph id="H4712DC7CCA034F9BBBDDC5AE5C39C1F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall maintain a database accessible to supervisors of Federal immigration enforcement personnel with proof of certification and training for all Federal immigration enforcement personnel who will use equipment restricted under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB63F5785BB894BE9A9FB076F98B9BEE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <subparagraph id="H7E3C5DFB710744A5964AC05ED5A33722"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Supervisor responsibility</header><text>Each supervisor shall be responsible and held accountable if Federal immigration enforcement personnel without proper training and certification use restricted equipment under subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83F05747AC824103A6F245304C5DA43C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Improper approvals</header><text>Each supervisor shall also be responsible and held accountable for clearly improper approval of the authority under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E72A6459D2F4DB2B90EBD1946AC74C7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall create a searchable and organizable database, including all reports from Federal immigration enforcement personnel, for the following systems:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB1CF0B07BA754722AB1570778B105D17" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Use of Force Incident Reporting System, which is mandatory for all deployments of force.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8DD0265098D4AAFB8C984FC1A27EAA8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Significant Incident Reports, which is mandatory for all operational anomalies or escalations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19219395AB224349AD28A05477C852DD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Civil Rights and Civil Liberties reporting, which is mandatory for all allegations of abuse or misconduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DD588321E4C4610B70A0A0C190E8F27" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability</header> <subparagraph id="H4C136BA73A8A4F17AF4FBFE90D525A20"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unredacted availability</header><text>Entries from the database described in paragraph (3) shall be accessible to—</text> 
<clause id="HE5E6E30D1F604379878383AC9F5FC9F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each Member of Congress representing the district in which the area of operation is located; or</text></clause> <clause id="HED436D6F44C24BA3A7ADE42E90DA5612"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Member of Congress who sits on a relevant committee of jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6AE2C0FF41DD47B2800E859298A1F8B8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Redacted availability</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall make available to the public a version of the database that redacts any sensitive, personal information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC466F0139F3447FCB90F7474F828445B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE861AA6FEC884A72A55AFFEB2A19C916"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal immigration enforcement personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal immigration enforcement personnel</term> includes any immigration agent or officer who is using the authority to conduct arrests or enforcement actions under sections 236 and 287 or provides support to personnel conducting an enforcement action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB4397236C0B4AA2AC6D5F625BC43085"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National security threat</header><text>The term <quote>national security threat</quote> means any threat, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security, posed by transnational criminal organizations, cartels, human trafficking organizations, foreign terrorist organizations, and gangs with a demonstrated international reach.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70E75CAC6B19403C9C58DE62157B6F7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public safety threat</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public safety threat</quote> means an imminent and substantial threat, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security, to the safety of others posed by an individual.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H9C92CC9F778149A4A2E05FB2E38A3508"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA2B862BA14CE4F0A9770411105D073CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide Federal immigration enforcement personnel additional authority to exercise deadly force;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A13E57DA64B4A96819071FDFA9DEDDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent Federal immigration enforcement personnel from taking action necessary to ensure the safety of themselves, other personnel, or bystanders; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47218ACC9B144A0B9B724FD600011317"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require State and local law enforcement to assist or be involved in Federal immigration enforcement activities.</text></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

