<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H36FDBE7983A04E88848A998576CF2C64" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7963 IH: No Lifeline for the Dead Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7963</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to promulgate regulations to improve the Lifeline program of the Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H01A354A58AE04975AE954E667A9582DB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H57B8883D14FA47C28F32A95F4FC8FF63" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Lifeline for the Dead Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H78F1C3660A1444A4926229AE379716EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Lifeline program improvement</header> 
<subsection id="H65C44D99D150467087DB536018576A69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall promulgate regulations with respect to the Lifeline program to provide for the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD8B893F5D3554E338377F2ACE8445744"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The eligibility of a consumer for assistance under such program shall be determined using the National Lifeline Eligibility Verifier and the National Lifeline Accountability Database, without any option for opting out of such Verifier or such Database on the basis of a State or other system related to eligibility determinations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF86512B8B8E4D899DBA0575372CC4FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, any consumer whose eligibility for assistance under such program was determined without use of the National Lifeline Eligibility Verifier and the National Lifeline Accountability Database—</text> <subparagraph id="H434CA4506FE14620957141B36F2CB8EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall have the eligibility of such consumer for assistance under such program reexamined and determined using such Verifier and such Database; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC64646C4FC6B4DB19A59E35FBFF31F43"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be no longer eligible for assistance under such program if determined ineligible pursuant to a reexamination under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE4B29EEDE3F40E29FD23D3CA099A2F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Only a consumer who is a citizen of the United States or a qualified alien shall be eligible for assistance under such program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEE25216485645F281BE7FFD89EA62E5">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Only a consumer who provides, as part of the application process for assistance under such program, the Social Security number (or a Tribal identifier) of such consumer shall be eligible for assistance under such program.</text>
        </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HEAB6E05EC143464CBF3035FA11160D87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB6E4E5D6EC104B6FBE89CC389E9655D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lifeline program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Lifeline program</term> means the Lifeline program of the Federal Communications Commission, set forth in subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55B0BA730CF64E97BBDDB4747A5C5739"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Lifeline Accountability Database</header><text>The term <term>National Lifeline Accountability Database</term> has the meaning given such term in section 54.400 of subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H200EA967F3704FC083F9F50A48DFC9B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Lifeline Eligibility Verifier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>National Lifeline Eligibility Verifier</term> has the meaning given such term in section 54.400 of subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC6656BF48D348A881EF90ADA8486AB5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified alien</term> has the meaning given such term in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

