<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9C3B343539894EB6B6E3A3312269B5B9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6163 IH: Determination of NEPA Adequacy Streamlining Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to allow Federal agencies to rely on certain previously completed environmental assessments and environmental impact statements to satisfy the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50708FE515F54028ADBF916C1CCCFEAE" style="OLC"><section id="H7C8061E37EE5445A835DEF6E585B7F72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Determination of NEPA Adequacy Streamlining Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFC51E160358D40EFB7F862FF11830F88"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reliance on previously completed environmental assessments and environmental impact statements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 108 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4336b">42 U.S.C. 4336b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1EFFF487E02C4508B8F4AD6A2E209DA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Programmatic environmental document</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Programmatic Environmental Documents and Reliance on Previously Completed Environmental Documents</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F519D1B76C245B9AC224C8F7669812B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>When an agency prepares</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H204669A1FB594C0EAE0BC37DDA61025A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H6081A7A4A13243B8A2909B12BD4667C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Programmatic environmental documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When an agency prepares</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H03841FEA761B470FA31A35325DA855C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6F89534027FB48199E9DC9DA99E67953" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H4339859FD5324DA2B6E06F9F4C2C9389"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reliance on Previously Completed Environmental Documents</header><paragraph id="HAA165CB2B97145B48CAA4F41CF565FEE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions that are substantially the same</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A lead agency may satisfy the requirements of this Act with respect to a new major Federal action by relying on an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement that the lead agency, another Federal agency, or a project sponsor under the supervision of a Federal agency completed for another major Federal action if the lead agency determines that—</text><subparagraph id="H23FE1F0EFD56430395C3F49E54E9D608" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the new major Federal action is substantially the same as the other major Federal action or an alternative analyzed in such environmental assessment or environmental impact statement; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC053B3C9CAB84D778D6F73364EAEC323"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effects of the new major Federal action are substantially the same as the effects analyzed in such environmental assessment or environmental impact statement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD341CF8B740A48209F3FA19DC144DD64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions that are not substantially the same</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a new major Federal action is not substantially the same as another major Federal action or an alternative analyzed in an environmental assessment or environmental impact statement completed by the lead agency, another Federal agency, or a project sponsor under the supervision of a Federal agency, the lead agency may modify any such previously completed environmental assessment or environmental impact statement as necessary to satisfy the requirements of this Act with respect to the new major Federal action. The lead agency shall make such modified environmental assessment or environmental impact statement publicly available as a new environmental assessment or environmental impact statement.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

