<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON26390-0VD-H5-S4J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S4889 IS: Supporting Our Direct Care Workforce and Family Caregivers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4889</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To award grants for the creation, recruitment, training and education, retention, and advancement of the direct care workforce and to award grants to support family caregivers.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Our Direct Care Workforce and Family Caregivers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idB731FACC0D984B0DBB292338AA65C375"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id65651facc66a45c5874d02a76fee11ca"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>apprenticeship program</term> means an apprenticeship program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), including any requirement, standard, or rule promulgated under such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idD85A7D46D793490AA28B9D4ED46C8F55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community college</header><text>The term <term>community college</term> means a public institution of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree, including Tribal Colleges or Universities receiving grants under section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>) that offer a 2-year program for completion of such degree and State public institutions of higher education that offer such a 2-year program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44043ab5b969444eb5f63c79a9ab5260"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Direct care professional</header><text>The term <term>direct care professional</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id48a5359ba9b54baca48dc597da8b8772"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual who, in exchange for compensation, provides services to a person with a disability or an older individual that promotes the independence of such person or individual, including—</text><clause id="id8ADF458DFA35472692555627591F3A91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>services that enhance the independence and community inclusion for such person or individual, including traveling with such person or individual or attending and assisting such person or individual while visiting friends and family, shopping, or socializing;</text></clause><clause id="idF191A05BF8C949BEA8757E9901984DCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>services such as coaching and supporting such person or individual in communicating needs, achieving self-expression, pursuing personal goals, living independently, and participating actively in employment or voluntary roles in the community;</text></clause><clause id="id28AA2B139F4C4757A29D9544194977BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>services such as providing assistance with activities of daily living (such as feeding, bathing, toileting, and ambulation) and with tasks such as meal preparation, shopping, light housekeeping, and laundry;</text></clause><clause id="idAD6CA8EED89541F09D5A2E580A00AE59"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>services that support such person or individual at home, work, school, or in any other community setting; or</text></clause><clause id="id685620e095174441ae101a18e2755e48"><enum>(v)</enum><text>services that promote health and wellness, including scheduling and taking such person or individual to health care appointments, communicating with health and allied health professionals, administering medications, implementing health and behavioral health interventions and treatment plans, and monitoring and recording health status and progress; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd37611813f0e41ab949a0be58373aa0a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include—</text><clause id="ida91eff8ba3e34c8ebb1506ee0d941d9f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a direct support professional supporting people with intellectual and developmental disabilities;</text></clause><clause id="id78abc847b2644d85ac421c25ee096fc4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a home and community-based services manager or direct support professional manager;</text></clause><clause id="id98d972e5656144c6ba76973fd4b76a0a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a self-directed care worker;</text></clause><clause id="id524d5b28cb1b46c1bd3814d9339b12bd"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a personal care service worker;</text></clause><clause id="id2cf7e3e928b34ce4b2d4ca7b81b34754"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a direct care worker, as defined in section 799B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295p">42 U.S.C. 295p</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="id47ee9ccce6674cc1a193f93db2e5200a"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other position or job related to the home care or direct care workforce, such as positions or jobs in respite care or palliative care, as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the Secretary of Labor.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4053F2BAFE5B49138C868776BBDCEA1B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Direct care workforce</header><text>The term <term>direct care workforce</term> means the broad workforce of direct care professionals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id26EDCC4DCA764A348DCC4E7E629B6276"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Family caregiver</header><text>The term <term>family caregiver</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the RAISE Family Caregivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3030s">42 U.S.C. 3030s</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/119">Public Law 115–119</external-xref>) and includes paid and unpaid family caregivers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE71874D7C4DD47C6AA91435E52218CD0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity—</text><subparagraph id="id7397354830a64561afc7937f502a9357"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is—</text><clause id="id26E15AF65F3144669253CA94ECD3CC1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State;</text></clause><clause id="id3fef2ff6afde4d0dbe90b1d84035f34f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a labor organization, joint labor-management organization, or employer of direct care professionals;</text></clause><clause id="id0b052ea51fe54c059ce9cc33441be266"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a nonprofit entity with experience in aging, disability, or supporting the rights and interests of, training of, or educating direct care professionals or family caregivers;</text></clause><clause id="ide5641ee465c7452e8359735b4041c2e7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe, Tribal organization, or Urban Indian organization;</text></clause><clause id="id2a67a899c6ef4e91bf2005d0332640df"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a community college or other institution of higher education; or</text></clause><clause id="idCADDBE3E15A14DFCB16E51C38DD332AB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a consortium of entities listed in any of clauses (i) through (v);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5A1A03EEBD114A4ABBE0D29CFF94500F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that agrees to include, as applicable with respect to the type of grant the entity is seeking under this Act and the activities supported through such grant, older individuals, people with disabilities, direct care professionals, and family caregivers, as advisors and trainers in such activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ca7900267f44f40a2d7e921ec944969"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that agrees to consult with the State Medicaid agency of the State (or each State) served by the grant on the grant activities, to the extent that such agency (or each such agency) is not the eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4BF11248E4734C7998F8E79AB4A690B5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Employ; employer</header><text>The terms <term>employ</term> and <term>employer</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id798A30EFC312411590F2830CBB68D602"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3202d54740cb4814b33d890c8c9489b3"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id7FE16457BFB2405F9A955F652B098751"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE9341BAAEED34211A31794299F542FCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an institution of higher education defined in section 102(a)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0555624C7FF04ED4875DE45C10C022FD"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Older individual</header><text>The term <term>older individual</term> means an individual who is 60 years of age or older.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id39CE9F76064E4A9D8A0B9499C8A5ECA9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Person with a disability</header><text>The term <term>person with disability</term> means an individual with a disability, as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCDDD05EB7CF84DF195969969584D1A93"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Project participant</header><text>The term <term>project participant</term> means an individual participating in a project or activity assisted with a grant under this Act, including (as applicable for the category of the grant) a direct care professional, or an individual training to be such a professional, or a family caregiver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5060b5c3e49740c89a7bb289156aaa52"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator for Community Living.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idA4F576D935A248A3986964B97CC4DC45"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Self-directed care professional</header><text>The term <term>self-directed care professional</term> means a direct care professional who is employed by an individual who is an older individual, a person with a disability, or a representative of such older individual or person with a disability, and such older individual or person with a disability has the decision-making authority over certain supports and services provided by the direct care professional and takes direct responsibility to manage those supports and services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b30bc8fecac4d54af6d469d9b86fcdd"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Supportive services</header><text>The term <term>supportive services</term> means services that are necessary to enable an individual to participate in activities assisted with a grant under this Act, such as transportation, child care, dependent care, housing, workplace accommodations, employee benefits such as paid sick leave and child care, workplace health and safety protections, wages and overtime pay, and needs-related payments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4706e957f8c04451acdf45a9d5bbc642"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Urban indian organization</header><text>The term <term>urban Indian organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id37e8c3f35eda4f01a825103489d408a8"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Workforce innovation and opportunity act terms</header><text>The terms <term>career pathway</term>, <term>career planning</term>, <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term>, <term>individual with a barrier to employment</term>, <term>local board</term>, <term>on-the-job training</term>, <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term>, <term>region</term>, and <term>State board</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd01048191b3477388bdf6d2d1269368"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Work-based learning</header><text>The term <term>work-based learning</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idb117b6dea2d846bea454382c0da63000"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority to establish a technical assistance center for building the direct care workforce</header><subsection id="ide0e51a6bebbc464d9001e3e7f4ddebcc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a national technical assistance center (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>) for, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Education, the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, and the heads of other entities as necessary—</text><paragraph id="id7AA9845F739B42ACAFE434425A42D7E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting direct care workforce creation, training and education, recruitment, retention, and advancement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7090A8128D8741DD9220F8B09BA4A1BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supporting family caregivers and activities of family caregivers as a critical part of the support team for older individuals or people with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idef1925312c3b4e43a8813a4ce0c83db0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The Secretary shall convene an advisory council to provide recommendations to the Center with respect to the duties of the Center under this section and may engage individuals and entities described in paragraphs (3)(B), and (12), of section 5(b) (without regard to a specific project described in such paragraphs) for service on the advisory council.</text></subsection><subsection id="iddffa3acd207940e0a973ad4ef4be5123"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Center may—</text><paragraph id="idd8cb934325fe4be88b4ddfed179b8981"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop recommendations for training and education curricula for direct care professionals, which such recommendations may include recommendations for curricula for higher education, postsecondary credentials, and programs with community colleges;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a609c45216d48ff987cb94c881aacb7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop learning and dissemination strategies to—</text><subparagraph id="idEC127734E495468F8446117ADD387847"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engage States and other entities in activities supported under this Act and best practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id293CF4E4ED38481B9FBA2F0F3B92BE49"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distribute findings from activities supported by grants under this Act;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id55a24cf88c6344a290da372ddabb2043"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop recommendations for training and education curricula and other strategies for supporting family caregivers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8add12e0161346578bdcaad0ad27aa32"><enum>(4)</enum><text>explore the national data gaps, workforce shortage areas, and data collection strategies for direct care professionals and make recommendations to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget for an occupation category in the Standard Occupational Classification system for direct support professionals as a healthcare support occupation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfedec19d10594c6ea18f61b758c371ad"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommend career development and advancement opportunities for direct care professionals, which may include occupational frameworks, national standards, recruitment campaigns, pre-apprenticeship and on-the-job training opportunities, apprenticeship programs, career ladders or pathways, specializations or certifications, or other activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6875d9bbfe74d91bbbae32afde78124"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop strategies for assisting with reporting and evaluation of grant activities under section 7.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idE1315A8FC3834D20B3D30094DCA9E133"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authority to award grants</header><subsection id="id5B140C6770884A7186A03D8598F2A714"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><paragraph id="id7a4d00a084c34956a615c88944d0a547"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Education, shall award grants described in paragraph (2) to eligible entities. A grant awarded under this section may be in more than 1 category described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7E24CCB55AE84533BD83E4EA18515365"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Categories of grants</header><text>The categories of grants described in this paragraph are each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id497fd12a2866498fa928860a43bbd379"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Direct care professional grants</header><text>Grants to eligible entities to create and carry out projects for the purposes of recruiting, retaining, or providing advancement opportunities for direct care professionals who are not described in subparagraph (B) or (C), including through education or training programs for such professionals or individuals seeking to become such professionals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2b814d1b0567417fa421379dbde08b63"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Direct care professional managers grants</header><text>Grants to eligible entities to create and carry out projects for the purposes of recruiting, retaining, or providing advancement opportunities for direct care professionals who are managers or supervisory staff that have coaching, training, managerial, supervisory, or other oversight responsibilities, including through education or training programs for such professionals or individuals seeking to become such professionals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd204f17923304701b13f7a196209a59a"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Self-directed care professionals grants</header><text>Grants to eligible entities to create and carry out projects for the purposes of recruiting, retaining, or providing advancement opportunities for self-directed care professionals, including through education or training programs for such professionals or individuals seeking to become such professionals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddfb1d1f933dc44739f16b21a7fbbf4ea"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Family caregiver grants</header><text>Grants to eligible entities to create and carry out projects for providing support to paid or unpaid family caregivers through educational, training, or other resources, including resources for caregiver self-care or educational or training resources for individuals newly in a caregiving role or seeking additional support in the role of a family caregiver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0D397064F3994FF480B22C9C6228FE10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Projects for advancement opportunities</header><text>Not less than 30 percent of projects assisted with grants under this Act shall be projects to provide career pathways that offer opportunities for professional development and advancement opportunities to direct care professionals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6DAF0EF6248B4B91B3CBEDCF00BCF265"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of continuation activities</header><text>An eligible entity that carries out activities described in subsection (a)(2) prior to receipt of a grant under this Act may use such grant to continue carrying out such activities, and, in using such grant to continue such activities, shall be treated as an eligible entity carrying out a project through a grant under this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id068F3C20312D48E787509935960700C8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Project plans</header><subsection id="id91266a008f7e42208f9710bfec339548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this Act shall submit to the Secretary a project plan for each project to be developed and carried out (including for activities to be continued as described in section 4(b)) with the grant at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2bcad98ecf124e019cf11c2b8d474747"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A project plan submitted by an eligible entity under subsection (a) shall include a description of information determined relevant by the Secretary for purposes of the category of the grant and the activities to be carried out through the grant. Such information may include (as applicable) the following:</text><paragraph id="id27161ea42d0e4f7f8c7f7f162b62a252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Demographic information regarding the population in the State or relevant geographic area, including a description of the populations likely to need long-term care services, such as people with disabilities and older individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id576bf8d729a641ddbda20fa376a01bab"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Projections of unmet need for services provided by direct care professionals based on enrollment waiting lists under home and community-based waivers under section 1115 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315">42 U.S.C. 1315</external-xref>) or section 1915(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396n">42 U.S.C. 1396n(c)</external-xref>) and other relevant data to the extent practicable and feasible, such as direct care workforce vacancy rates, crude separation rates, and the number of direct care professionals, including such professionals who are managers or supervisors, in the region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79caa10d5f214b9fb37b17bdc7830bcd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An advisory committee to advise the eligible entity on activities to be carried out through the grant. Such advisory committee—</text><subparagraph id="idFEE5E1E4DA404CDEA9E8DD35E020CB85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be comprised of entities listed in paragraph (12); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd92232a1eb224f79bd18bd1c82ec7aec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include—</text><clause id="id37E0A536576B4555A292479C8BC7276C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>older individuals or persons with a disability;</text></clause><clause id="idDF52E7901FCF43B7B0E3DCD153559A12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>organizations representing the rights and interests of people receiving services by the direct care professionals or family caregivers targeted by the project;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id7870282A098F4AE0BCA21086C6BE1A8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>individuals who are direct care professionals or family caregivers targeted by the project and organizations representing the rights and interests of direct care professionals or family caregivers;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id85568302809048DB9121ADB9E980D564"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>as applicable, employers of individuals described in clause (iii) and labor organizations representing such individuals;</text></clause><clause id="id85D459F31F084AA29D4717366A05665C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>representatives of the State Medicaid agency, the State agency defined in section 102 of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3002">42 U.S.C. 3002</external-xref>), the State developmental disabilities office, and the State mental health agency, in the State (or each State) to be served by the project; and</text></clause><clause id="id9BCBC903B46C494480B68EBEA1B31A44"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>representatives reflecting diverse racial, cultural, ethnic, geographic, socioeconomic, and gender identity and sexual orientation perspectives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id65d35c4f2ab84766b38b243bbb14b3e9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Current or projected job openings for, or relevant labor market information related to, the direct care professionals targeted by the project in the State or region to be served by the project, and the geographic scope of the workforce to be served by the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c235b8127234598a3c6a7affdbfecd6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Specific efforts and strategies that the project will undertake to reduce barriers to recruitment, retention, or advancement of the direct care professionals targeted by the project, including an assurance that such efforts will include—</text><subparagraph id="id74ca69f38b6a4d1594e5095387b13b2d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the wages or other compensation or benefits necessary to recruit and retain the direct care professionals targeted by the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfb464b70639b40d2b26e3d7af317435d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the project’s projected compensation or benefits for the direct care professionals targeted by the project at the State or local level, including a comparison of such projected compensation or benefits to regional and national compensation or benefits and a description of how wages and benefits received by project participants will be impacted by the participation in and completion of the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39ff0b44ca4d425799b8fa6ced03ce18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the projected impact of workplace safety issues on the recruitment and retention of direct care professionals targeted by the project, including the availability of personal protective equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id09519055224c4f7998a9cc897410522d"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In the case of a project offering an education or training program for direct care professionals, a description of such program (including how the core competencies identified by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services will be incorporated, curricula, models, and standards used under the program, and any associated recognized postsecondary credentials for which the program provides preparation, as applicable), which shall include an assurance that such program will provide to each project participant in such program—</text><subparagraph id="id375e891e8dc144b18cc8ab3046627d48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant training regarding the rights of recipients of home and community based services, including their rights to—</text><clause id="id79402476abd847939f048828fe98a7a1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receive services in integrated settings that provide access to the broader community;</text></clause><clause id="id9F611B8354024B40A088740AD85CEBA0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exercise self-determination;</text></clause><clause id="id222a994768f0415f8bb338bb0a204cbd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be free from all forms of abuse, neglect, or exploitation; and</text></clause><clause id="id61824f0d2ab4496d86b404f671494e44"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>person-centered planning and practices, including participation in planning activities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87f29a7604774bfaaa2dc4b4897a126c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relevant training to ensure that each project participant has the necessary skills to recognize abuse and understand their obligations with regard to reporting and responding to abuse appropriately in accordance with relevant Federal and State law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbbf28c0734094610a4004b714a780b89"><enum>(C)</enum><text>relevant training regarding the provision of culturally competent and disability competent supports to recipients of services provided by the direct care professionals targeted by the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0c62b3a9a7df4d409bd9848d217d533a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an apprenticeship program, work-based learning, or on-the-job training opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8fda268fa0fa4a71bb3ac2cfecac6230"><enum>(E)</enum><text>supervision or mentoring; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1db21e18b96a4542b51be00468bb1d4d"><enum>(F)</enum><text>for any on-the-job training portion of the program, a progressively increasing, clearly defined schedule of wages to be paid to each such participant that—</text><clause id="ida23751c9dd13499f948bcb42684371b2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is consistent with skill gains or attainment of a recognized postsecondary credential received as a result of participation in or completion of such program; and</text></clause><clause id="id83e9e999d177481ba9a692d5372e9b76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensures the entry wage is not less than the greater of—</text><subclause id="idd1c0a13b01d544b78025c2cb28a0d183"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the minimum wage required under section 6(a) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206(a)</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause id="id16bc137205664ff2ac48b4488d43327b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the applicable wage required by other applicable Federal or State law, or a collective bargaining agreement.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id14d12c3b887048be9ba81f19d0e140e3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other innovative models or processes the eligible entity will implement to support the retention and career advancement of the direct care professionals targeted by the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd737bcd95c4a44baae3a2c93b8f962c5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The supportive services and benefits to be provided to the project participants in order to support the employment, retention, or career advancement of the direct care professionals targeted by the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id166c20231f1043f5a517c3cdd97f4725"><enum>(9)</enum><text>How the eligible entity will make use of career planning to support the identification of advancement opportunities and career pathways for the direct care professionals in the State or region to be served by the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a9ebed5ca494cd1a2c3fd67a0be6137"><enum>(10)</enum><text>How the eligible entity will collect and submit to the Secretary workforce data and outcomes of the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6ee1881689647f187ed4b36b8b2635a"><enum>(11)</enum><text>How the project—</text><subparagraph id="id2AE8BE6AF1744CC2AE6B2BBB1EE44442"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will—</text><clause id="id9a4a73bc4fdf4d149cb23751c52118de"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide adequate and safe equipment and facilities for training and supervision, including a safe work environment free from discrimination, which may include the provision of personal protective equipment and other necessary equipment to prevent the spread of infectious disease among the direct care professionals targeted by the project and recipients of services provided by such professionals;</text></clause><clause id="id105394b3b2fc41c8bb691539fc955a66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incorporate remote training and education opportunities or technology-supported opportunities;</text></clause><clause id="idc511893df7d8415ba5f275a7d9b2a2ef"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for training and education curricula, incorporate evidenced-supported practices for adult learners and universal design for learning and ensure recipients of services provided by the direct care professionals or family caregivers targeted by the project participate in the development and implementation of such training and education curricula;</text></clause><clause id="id379be8c208224ea4a9f7102a36066dc3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>use outreach, recruitment, and retention strategies designed to reach and retain a diverse workforce;</text></clause><clause id="id9511564942e34ef3b2733eb655a3035c"><enum>(v)</enum><text>incorporate methods to monitor satisfaction with project activities for project participants and individuals receiving services from such participants;</text></clause><clause id="id40b4d7eb91ff4c6d9ca99e418fccbff5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>incorporate evidence-supported practices for family caregiver engagement; and</text></clause><clause id="ida20703ccfbf94bb9b9c385aa0795c3d9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>incorporate core competencies identified by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a4aa8feaf2948bb8eda52063c423ca3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may incorporate continuing education programs and specialty training, with a specific focus on—</text><clause id="id0D65384D1ADF4F7291839B4F199BD7FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>trauma-informed care;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id6F4FCCC004044A94B7C37304D0FDF9D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>behavioral health, including co-occurring behavioral health conditions and intellectual or developmental disabilities;</text></clause><clause id="idF95A58D9735A45E8A56ACFA3ACF68A92"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Alzheimer’s and dementia care;</text></clause><clause id="idD44DBB9FD8744AE88C90E0F72397DA34"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>chronic disease management; and</text></clause><clause id="id8ECC8B6BAE7045C6B9A5B86DFAFBEA40"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the use of supportive or assistive technology.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0af6236b7ea6443c9068a28b8abb0aee"><enum>(12)</enum><text>How the eligible entity will consult on the implementation of the project, or coordinate the project with, each of the following entities, to the extent that each such entity is not the eligible entity:</text><subparagraph id="idb0a5203d60ef4728a5d5cbb96f647c40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The State Medicaid agency, State agency defined in section 102 of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3002">42 U.S.C. 3002</external-xref>), and the State developmental disabilities office for the State (or each State) to be served by the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2720a2ace2e2443eb5b5383503595af6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The local board and State board for each region, or State, to be served by the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id411ff4c40c2a484fb34f8465b585e157"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In the case of a project that carries out an education or training program, a nonprofit organization with demonstrated experience in the development or delivery of curricula or coursework.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb799bdbad3dc4f1a9cd4b87b6e673810"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization, including a labor organization, that fosters the professional development and collective engagement of the direct care professionals targeted by the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e5bb19348824b259c5d747697205166"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Area agencies on aging, as defined in section 102 of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3002">42 U.S.C. 3002</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB0E5804B19EC44ED8F427282149571F7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Centers for independent living, as described in part C of title VII of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/796f">29 U.S.C. 796f et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31e977c7c383420fbafa75a0db18ed95"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The State Council on Developmental Disabilities (as such term is used in subtitle B of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15021">42 U.S.C. 15021 et seq.</external-xref>)) for the State (or each State) to be served by the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f74096eb86246628dda36906be2df44"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Aging and Disability Resource Centers (as defined in section 102 of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3002">42 U.S.C. 3002</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33a3fab8aa4d4d159fa258ace552e73a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A nonprofit State provider association that represents providers who employ the direct care professionals targeted by the project, where such associations exist.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id624528365cc14c2dbe64a5c9fa87a472"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An entity that employs the direct care professionals targeted by the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37df6eb22f9344b8bbba761708379f7f"><enum>(K)</enum><text>University Centers for Excellence in Developmental Disabilities Education, Research, and Service supported under subtitle D of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15061">42 U.S.C. 15061 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f7e03e3e1b54d9f94f2f5ab65e26aef"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The State protection and advocacy system described in section 143 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15043">42 U.S.C. 15043</external-xref>) of the State (or each State) to be served by the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2fd0507241e24d15b2edd29cee088837"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Direct care professionals or direct care workforce organizations representing underserved communities, including communities of color.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2b5c56a99c244c7a534057b2b2efdf6"><enum>(13)</enum><text>How the eligible entity will consult throughout the project with—</text><subparagraph id="id49F983F23274408495958ECCEB18575D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals employed or working as the direct care professionals or family caregivers targeted by the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id889D77743B754EE5B5134D2DFE382413"><enum>(B)</enum><text>representatives of such professionals or caregivers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF5E53DCAF7B24BBA90E92338F0C5FAA4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individuals assisted by such professionals or caregivers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDB72FE6F80F1492C9EF2BAFEB2D3D979"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the families of such professionals or caregivers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDB397770FBA2404888E629F44D3D5C4B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>individuals receiving education or training to become such professionals or caregivers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ce7acd3e6e049959b3de0c7d55d9247"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Outreach efforts to individuals for participation in such project, including targeted outreach efforts to—</text><subparagraph id="idd1b00cdb529b402baf38d039f8ee1970"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals who are recipients of assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) or individuals who are eligible for such assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5502b6cf1eab4f4189170bff34e0e154"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals with barriers to employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id913D44285D994EE68EC8D0167267C6D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In selecting eligible entities to receive a grant under this Act, the Secretary shall ensure—</text><paragraph id="id18c5f43a7ea543b8b5ff08b4fdc637bc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>equitable geographic and demographic diversity, including by selecting recipients serving rural areas and selecting recipients serving urban areas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id667adcfed8b54ca3bc18ac378dc3caf4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that selected eligible entities will serve areas where the occupation of direct care professional, or a related occupation, is an in-demand industry sector or occupation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idC7F270DB54DF4870BC54D0A877FC3E6E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Uses of funds; supplement, not supplant</header><subsection id="id42daa199ba46452c93907e4c6cc311fa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><paragraph id="id5da1350aefbb4b7aad1e7c097726485d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall use the funds of such grant to carry out at least 1 project described in section 4(a)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd92cd82320ac4c5c980eda9417912725"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall not use more than 5 percent of the funds of such grant for costs associated with the administration of activities under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53395fea02a14a0980fd7472434d979f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Direct support</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act (except for a grant described in section 4(a)(2)(D)) shall use not less than 5 percent of the funds of such grant to provide direct financial benefits or supportive services to direct care professionals to support the financial needs of such participants during the duration of the project activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id573d24c15cc842d98704bdf848f78e68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall use such grant only to supplement, and not supplant, the amount of funds that, in the absence of such grant, would be available to address the recruitment, training and education, retention, and advancement of direct care professionals or provide support for family caregivers, in the State or region served by the eligible entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="idaa08ea0880714ba3b7b0d80b7e526c84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No amounts made available under this Act may be used for any activity that is subject to the reporting requirements set forth in section 203(a) of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/433">29 U.S.C. 433(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="id8236B70BE5504BB195C04420E0329298"><enum>7.</enum><header>Evaluations and reports; technical assistance</header><subsection id="id2348629f2a614b97b1902beede4e1b04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirements by grant recipients</header><paragraph id="id2CA324DB4BE947028B6DD8D9194226C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this Act shall cooperate with the Secretary and annually provide a report to the Secretary that includes any relevant data requested by the Secretary in a manner specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id65E40847AF3C450A8E5554A588B0FE56"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The data requested by the Secretary for an annual report may include any of the following (as determined relevant by the Secretary with respect to the category of the grant and each project supported through the grant):</text><subparagraph id="id1b41330bda2140bebbc83513a5295cc6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of individuals and the demographics of these individuals served by each project supported by the grant, including—</text><clause id="id022e3bb2442649c29292644e04852920"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of individuals recruited through each such project to be employed as a direct care professional;</text></clause><clause id="id40ef2b5b6bc64ab6bb443371050106c2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of individuals who through each such project attained employment as a direct care professional; and</text></clause><clause id="id052979c0bdac4afaa57b6f8d2eac5265"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of individuals who enrolled in each such project and withdrew or were terminated from each such project without completing training or attaining employment as a direct care professional.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6AE917CD73D8423087AAFB75D13B5A45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of family caregivers participating in an education or training program through each project supported by the grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77166FCF748C42A2B8CAD789A4083241"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The number of project participants who through each such project participated in and completed—</text><clause id="id1e5c32aecf4a49cbb18d4735b7a0749b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>work-based learning;</text></clause><clause id="id6b3471eb50d842a68bbffa693e2375e3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on-the-job training;</text></clause><clause id="id443bb4cbaaac4d1db6fee16a19d889bd"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an apprenticeship program; or</text></clause><clause id="idd9c6efdc0d5344fca41181c27e3f7a47"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a professional development or mentoring program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c7897ae76da4b67997e6719a6b9f87a"> <enum>(D)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6D69409DE6D74725B303505E35524CB2"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>Other services, benefits, or supports (other than the services, benefits, or supports described in subparagraph (C)) provided through each such project to assist in the recruitment, retention, or advancement of direct care professionals (including through education or training for such professionals or individuals seeking to become such professionals);</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id3B9AD30BA68643CC925638998CA8E8A9" indent="up1">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the number of individuals who accessed such services, benefits, or supports; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause indent="up1" id="id84E55CAF051244B0973AC59E490A5D35">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the impact of such services, benefits, or supports.</text> </clause> </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8d0e0cb93ed343729bc9c43228ab98f6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The crude separation and vacancy rates of direct care professionals, and such rates for those professionals who are managers or supervisors, in the geographic region for a number of years before the grant was awarded, as determined by the Secretary, and annually thereafter for the duration of the grant period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB40A4A2147294E708D6A582B2A4A570A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>How each project supported by the grant assessed satisfaction with respect to—</text><clause id="id665d0afc9f9e4e5399bca8bf8e87d857"><enum>(i)</enum><text>project participants assisted by the project;</text></clause><clause id="id038ca208b9764aee9969ff5432e26389"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>individuals receiving services delivered by project participants, including—</text><subclause id="idf2932cf502814dc5b24bc0e48a87d7c1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any impact on the health or health outcomes of such individuals; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id1ed4112e1ba345219b1275bc849cfbb0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any impact on the ability of individuals to transition to or remain in the community in an environment that meets the criteria established in the section 441.301(c)(4) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id93297f3a37a24040bd0694d1619fa535"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employers of such project participants.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42711BB0C21F43E0AD3CB10B8DE2C9A6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The performance of the eligible entity with respect to unsubsidized employment, median earnings, credential attainment, measurable skill gains, and employer satisfaction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id27e1eea49c7e42cc8d8947f32a827e38"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Any other information with respect to outcomes of the project as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id265a13fb8c0849578f5ca0bb4aff4418"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress by Secretary</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter until all projects supported through a grant under this Act are completed, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress an annual report on the progress of each project supported through a grant under this Act and the activities of the technical assistance center established under section 3.</text></subsection><subsection id="id59e4ae1c68574fe299552ecfd22b74e4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which all projects supported through a grant under this Act are completed, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit to Congress a report including—</text><paragraph id="ideb60bd37779242f0817fe457593bdf84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of how the technical assistance center established under section 3 and the projects supported through a grant under this Act assisted in the creation, recruitment, training and education, retention, and advancement of the direct care workforce or in providing support for family caregivers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ffd8191062745dca3afb28a6ecd11ce"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for such legislative or administrative actions needed for improving the assistance described in paragraph (1), as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id5b2a9acf6a3144deb7311be84f6b5bc8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Independent evaluations</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall enter into a contract with an independent entity to provide independent evaluations of activities supported by grants under this Act and activities of the technical assistance center established under section 3.</text></subsection></section><section id="id1F997E31B67442008414B09DD861B00F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="idAA78F7AA67ED4EDA86E79AD1606A7B7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="iddac0723352714cfa919cf4256bbe2844"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the establishment and activities of the technical assistance center under section 3, $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idCB9BD02AD297400D862EA7AAD2FE9E19"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for grants under section 4, $1,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id892ec468488e45ff9ffaca2af72370d6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts made available under this Act shall remain available until September 30, 2036.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

