<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H406C615F1BFD42D29AA24D9E058D7B7D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 3074 EH: Common Cents Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3074</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to stop minting the penny, to permit cash transactions to be rounded up or down to the nearest five cents, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H245652B765084785907C42BA845782B3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H528B451E792940DB967A711EC35C8340" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Common Cents Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0D846FBAE49C460DA70073FE007C6936" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Specifications of 5-cent coins and ceasing production of one-cent coins</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5112 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3FACE38163B64AA8A7C0D6FADB3B546D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4FA403B0C57B42B49888B78FC22F0DF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>weighs 5 grams.</quote> and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H49825B14C4E64EE69DDD97EC7E6C144D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">weighs—</text> <subparagraph id="HB93AC9DD6C0F4414980B081B3CE801D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5 grams, with respect to such coin that is an alloy of copper and nickel; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H856B51941B9245DBB5FD8C0A605FDBEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">between 4 and 6 grams, with respect to such coin as described in subsection (c).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB48983416B7478E921B77E260488E21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text> 
<clause id="HC066B3A1D8644ACB8FC0BDB4E3FBE260"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>except as provided under subsection (c) of this section,</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9B14ACBA8749460CB4FEB742F69F36D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and weighs 3.11 grams</quote>; </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H252CC4935652466F81F20106E5E88302"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H62AFBA7164544BF897B2CA87FBBEB539"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the sixth sentence—</text> 
<clause id="HE3CC2D02CB5647E8A6A7326549F91B5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>either</quote> before <quote>an alloy</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD8F45CEE3C2E483696FF9B9C52090EAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or a composition described in subsection (c)</quote> before the period; </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4CFED08F648949A982E74956342A3C5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>with respect to such coins that are an alloy of copper and nickel</quote> after <quote>nickel required</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6800D9F82C71478D9FFD7E6D352FECCC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except</quote> through <quote>zinc</quote> and inserting <quote>The one-cent coin is composed of copper and zinc</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA73FBF810030475898928C16038E5462"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H789E056161BE4A66A8863A4978F351AB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H13CAF86A32194D558F2F8558705E7C69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>5-cent coin</header> <paragraph id="H51CBFA11CC7441858F9D08498CE10CD7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The 5-cent coin may be a coin with an inner layer of zinc and an outer layer of nickel.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BE8E4BF418F4443A398FEA76FA941EC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may prescribe the composition of zinc and nickel in the 5-cent coin, subject to testing and evaluation that such composition—</text> <subparagraph id="H7C3DC751ED4E47B780592D119BC7E974"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduces the cost incurred to produce such coin; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD4ACE5A530F40EAB63D499793042559"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the greatest extent practicable, has a minimal adverse impact on machines designed to accept coins.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H560B24DC9FB64C788B04B17EA52387A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HE531E6DA31CA4444BC89741906C02B04" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HA4CA6CB041C14145A86DC8448FE526CF"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Ceasing production of one-cent coin</header> 
<paragraph id="HA9AF19BB57874942BC3A6C265BCE88BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall cease production of one-cent coins for general circulation, but may continue to produce and issue one-cent coins for sale as numismatic items.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H533BE63C98374D1BA7FAE5F937592A1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on legal tender</header><text>Any one-cent coin that is minted and issued on any date before the date of the enactment of this subsection shall remain legal tender for all debts, public charges, taxes, and dues. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA39798B65D0A4252819A928A4949A8BA" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cash transaction rounding</header> 
<subsection id="H3FC796ECDC044AEA969DF88B6F8E4806"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person, including a financial institution, selling goods or services in a cash transaction or entering into any other transaction that results in a payment or transfer of cash between the parties to the transaction may, if exact change cannot be provided at that time of such transaction, round the covered amount in the following manner:</text> <paragraph id="H7554045C3AD84C199BD37B29310B63E6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rounding down</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2)(B), in any case in which the covered amount ends with 1 cent, 2 cents, 6 cents, or 7 cents as the final digit, the amount of cents in the sum may be rounded down to the nearest amount divisible by 5 for any person seeking to make payment with cash.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9995E128C5A412FABD4B7B0CCD1C1E6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rounding up</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5C3BE9402D8C499D97229BC74DFEE464" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the covered amount ends with 3 cents, 4 cents, 8 cents, or 9 cents as the final digit, the amount of cents in the sum may be rounded up to the nearest amount divisible by 5 for any person seeking to make payment with cash.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD74D02E068A84794A298914F1344CBF3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the covered amount totals $0.01 or $0.02, such amount may be rounded up to $.05 for any person seeking to make payment with cash.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H205864DF48C149B2B257FEA20F10F895" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional authority to round</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a person, including a financial institution, conducting a cash transaction with a customer of the person, the amount of cents in the sum of the transaction may be rounded, if such rounding is in favor of the customer, as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HA0E152C6998641428DF92717FF31CE95"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Up to the nearest amount divisible by 5, if the person is paying the customer in cash.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C967C76539643879ED267ACD5B9EE83"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Down to the nearest amount divisible by 5, if the customer is paying the person in cash.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H73A8ADAB255B4DFBB16DA88871B10346" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employer payments to employees</header> <paragraph id="H22C5FF0DFFE84240A96C0850CC52169D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an employer providing a cash payment to an employee in an amount that is not divisible by 5 cents, if the employer chooses to round the amount of cents in such payment, the employer shall round the amount of cents in such payment up to the nearest amount divisible by 5 cents.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79065B7B8F424BA0B351FFAC056867AB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No rounding requirement</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to require rounding by an employer described in paragraph (1) who provides a cash payment to an employee in an exact amount.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCD5E12C7CB046F4BF4B86D7312BA38B" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall not apply to any transaction for which payment is made by any demand or negotiable instrument, electronic fund transfer, check, gift card, money order, credit card, or other like instrument or method.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD5CFF3961B4F4271A192EDD73645865F" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to require any person to round a payment as described in subsections (a) or (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC828F351CBDE4394AABF18AD0F9DE9B6" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered amount defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered amount</quote> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2C2FD7B2BEDF427288D2AFAB75C92509" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the total transaction amount, including taxes; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D2BD7A325AF4985BB0A066BB47443BB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a person selling goods or services in a cash transaction or entering into any other transaction that results in a payment or transfer of cash between the parties to the transaction, the amount of change due to the customer if the customer provides a cash payment that exceeds the total transaction amount, including taxes.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H96B3F7063B554A5087558A8ABCA67C16"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of Federal, State, and Tribal law with respect to cash transaction rounding</header> 
<subsection id="H427251881C9A4D828E0B48FC5259EADB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person selling goods or services in a cash transaction, including a financial institution, entering into any other transaction that results in a payment or transfer of cash between the parties to the transaction shall not be in violation of any Federal requirement, law, regulation, or standard based on the adherence to the cash rounding provisions described in section 3.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HF49C8C181D404F32A9FD1D27C20FE582"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State and Tribal law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person selling goods or services in a cash transaction, including a financial institution, entering into any other transaction that results in a payment or transfer of cash between the parties to the transaction shall not be in violation of any requirement, law, regulation, or standard of a State, Tribe, or a political subdivision of a State based on the adherence to the cash rounding provisions described in section 3.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFF1243563D5947A9AFB38B7B1C860F62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or of any order thereunder shall excuse noncompliance with any Federal, State, Tribal, or local law, regulation, ordinance, or requirement establishing a minimum wage, providing for overtime pay requirements, or providing for paid leave.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H06717D04A50C4168BE2C83D129295163"><enum>5.</enum><header>Strategic plan and report on coin terminal operations and coin distribution stability</header> <subsection id="H971B7D9242DB45A8ACBFDAF1E9E75C3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategic Plan and Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall submit to the covered committees and make publicly available a report that outlines a strategic plan for the acceptance of penny orders and deposits at commercial coin terminals providing services under agreements with the Federal reserve banks nationwide, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H027EF6319DA24FEA988E27B898894291"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the Board’s approach to limiting disruptions in penny supply and maintaining the stability of and efficiency of the coin distribution system, to the greatest extent practicable;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7236CC269D4F48A188B77F24BCB613E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of such coin terminals where the Federal reserve banks no longer accept penny deposits or penny orders;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80405ED79A484406A0877E1AE66B2327"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of whether processing penny deposits or penny orders at such coin terminals could mitigate any challenges related to ceasing the production of the penny, including challenges related to the implementation of rounding practices;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBD061BFE3084AA9AF3C1D6F8BF5DE4A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment by the Secretary of the Treasury, which the Secretary shall conduct and deliver to the Board not less than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H90BAB77874F64DE2B1FA8398EB50DDF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the impact of penny supply and demand disruptions, and rounding practices for check cashing, on low-income communities, older consumers, debanked, unbanked, and underbanked individuals, including feedback from State or local entities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDA57DDBAD8049EF9827DB2946429E39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that includes recommendations to the Congress to address any adverse impacts identified under subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FA9870838E04359989257B60EBE5A33"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any additional considerations the Board determines relevant to maintaining penny distribution stability.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD4A40604CF0B4C04BE0FDB8AB6BC4791"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <paragraph id="HA4C01B1992E747DABD83CF39082C70A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after submission of the report required under subsection (a), the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall submit to the covered committees and make publicly available a report that evaluates the progress of implementing the strategic plan described in subsection (a), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCB19402E37C2489F867B2CC0187B8C7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any material changes to the plan; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D4585492C5347F68BEA2983CD1E452F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any identified or emerging stress in the penny distribution system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A5DD3A785994AE4B09F7893BDC6F82C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Successive reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall submit to the covered committees and make publicly available 2 additional reports that evaluate the progress described in paragraph (1) on dates that are not later than—</text> <subparagraph id="H5999E47F3DA0486F9BA79E103DEE4CDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>18 months after the submission of the report required under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D286EC5FB914DCFAF65188D236CECAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>30 months after the submission of the report required under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H148C66EDC8CC4120AE60F43B920571B4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H13CC8B0ED2054840A2403B8486CB1503"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered committees</header><text>The term <quote>covered committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H2743585747214FC097AA5B695CCD73A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H788585B5F37747E382A7D4B717630BA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3AF6C7D50D141DF952FC6E904CFCC8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <quote>financial institution</quote> means any person, other than an individual, the business of which is engaging in financial activities in section 4(k) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1843">12 U.S.C. 1843(k)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260714" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 14, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> 
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> 
</bill> 


