<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BFA01DB366446F89C2080C8E210444C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9059 IH: National Police Athletic/Activities League Youth Enrichment Reauthorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9059</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Assistant Attorney General to award grants to the National Police Athletic/Activities League to improve academic and social outcomes for youth and reduce both juvenile crime and the risk that youth will become victims of crime by providing productive activities conducted by law enforcement personnel during non-school hours.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8EF0968F40DB4A65B1DCD4CB955CD936" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0DEE448A405C4150A1212FBA5E71F021" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Police Athletic/Activities League Youth Enrichment Reauthorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H0C516E031EC04B0A97F8D393C4E3B823"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HF7B0BCC4E96244BAA3C8B4259EC811EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The goals of the National Police Athletic/Activities League and its member chapters are to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC23694B4DDCD473C868C17876A123DBA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the academic success of youth participants in Police Athletic/Activities League programs, including in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87243DF7EE73426FA6513560E3903AE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote a safe, healthy environment for youth under the supervision of law enforcement personnel where mutual trust and respect can be built;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H034AC4D321D3470EA9B9FC7D56B2EF39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop life-enhancing character and leadership skills in young people;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DAB27A846BA41C5BEC2D05B5CC878C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increase school attendance by providing alternatives to suspensions and expulsions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB008AFA5A1204A06B750DBB33820EEC8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reduce the juvenile crime rate in participating designated communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC067B0DE1ABB4D0E922D2FE9D70A025B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>reduce the number of police calls involving juveniles during non-school hours;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEEF1085B927E4D2AB452FACCA232CAE8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>teach youth protection skills, particularly those geared to the online world;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDDDA227824184E74B26380E8C3F7FFD4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>provide youths with alternatives to drugs, alcohol, tobacco, gangs, and other activity that is harmful to such youths and their communities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEBC86147ABA4387AD866A8D279EB17A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>create positive communication and interaction between youth and law enforcement personnel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15EC442C8E9C46C5858B3815FC422020"><enum>(J)</enum><text>prepare youth for the workplace; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5CF6AC2FBE741E8A96D301B54125425"><enum>(K)</enum><text>strengthen neighborhoods by bringing youth, families, and law enforcement together around shared programs and goals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0AF23FB21D44EB09B52B085FC3C57D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Police Athletic/Activities League and its member chapters, during its over 85-year history as a national organization, has proven to be a positive force in the communities it serves.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9378168B49E949998C42C48D95B80DD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Police Athletic/Activities League has over 200 chartered Police Athletic/Activities League chapters throughout the United States, including the United States Virgin Islands, serving 2,000,000 youths, ages 5 to 18, nationwide.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12734B621AF9415DA72434533F5F07EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on National Police Athletic/Activities League chapter demographics, approximately 75 percent of the youths who benefit from Police Athletic/Activities League programs live in inner cities and urban areas.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8571A9D7B82B4441BB8D8620FB55F6AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">National Police Athletic/Activities League chapters are locally operated, volunteer-driven organizations. Although most Police Athletic/Activities League chapters are sponsored by a law enforcement agency, National Police Athletic/Activities League chapters rarely receive funding from law enforcement agencies and are dependent in large part on support from the private sector, such as individuals, business leaders, corporations, and foundations. National Police Athletic/Activities League chapters have been exceptionally successful in balancing public funds with private sector donations and maximizing community involvement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37C98ED87EBA411693B120B9710622EC"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Today’s youth face far greater risks than did their parents and grandparents. Law enforcement statistics demonstrate that youth between the ages of 12 and 18 are at risk of committing violent acts and being victims of violent acts after school hours, between the hours of 3 p.m. and 8 p.m.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF870C618AEA433AA93E2EEA35DC6214"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Greater numbers of students are dropping out of school and failing in school, even though the consequences of academic failure are more dire in 2026 than ever before.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8717C10B35C84485BFD2AE169FC5E0AF"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Police Athletic/Activities League is the premier model for modern community policing and connecting cops to kids, based on the belief that young people, if reached early enough, are more likely to become productive adults and agents of change. It is dedicated to fostering positive relationships between law enforcement and youth through recreational, educational, and mentorship programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H28D973A668044FCEA15CF0B539435C66"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many distressed areas in the United States are still underserved by Police Athletic/Activities League chapters.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0EB5D4F527EB4A95A5395E18235531E1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to provide adequate resources in the form of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H629414A5D5FA4F37A67ADB5D8BB0107B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance for the 200 established National Police Athletic/Activities League chapters to increase services to the communities they are serving;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H559A66E6F942432B88DF5E68794D8947"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seed money for the establishment of 250 (50 per year over a 5-year period) additional local Police Athletic/Activities League chapters in public housing projects and other distressed areas, including distressed areas with a majority population of Native Americans, by not later than fiscal year 2032; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F29F2ED181B48B5966F441298BF65EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support of an annual gathering of Police Athletic/Activities League chapters and designated youth leaders from such chapters to participate in a 3-day conference that addresses national and local issues impacting the youth of America and includes educational sessions to advance character and leadership skills.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HE02BBFF569CC4690AAA326277B7E39DB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <subsection id="H1C18CF096E784A7AB28BCC4658BEB5F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2028 through 2032, the Assistant Attorney General shall award a grant to the National Police Athletic/Activities League to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6CCBD7939EE84C33981E82FBAC549342"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish PAL chapters to serve public housing projects and other distressed areas; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC84D6AC0BB4B481C87D8B50B2CDFDAFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expand existing PAL chapters to serve additional youths.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7FFF7388EE1B49678F1E070D21DFEE76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="HBB63C7AEE8EF49E8ABDD7FD0C7AB2D4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the National Police Athletic/Activities League shall submit to the Assistant Attorney General an application, which shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4CAD92333BC44978A7CCD41DBE8F086"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a long-term strategy to establish 250 additional PAL chapters and a detailed summary of those areas in which such new PAL chapters will be established, or in which existing chapters will be expanded to serve additional youths, during the next fiscal year;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA4A7D9CD11C4163AD5C16A1E8E9AB94"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to ensure that there are not fewer than 500 PAL chapters in operation by January 1, 2032;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8034342AF0D9407CAFE77435D92FA849"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a certification that there will be appropriate coordination between new PAL chapters and those communities where such new PAL chapters will be located; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4CF4836404B84652A51C1510EFA741A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how new PAL chapters will operate without additional Federal financial assistance once assistance under this Act is discontinued.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3006166BF4374BF6A7BF702C22EF05BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of submission of an application under paragraph (1), the Assistant Attorney General shall take action on such application.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6D4AFB0828D44B8D9E4059CED60EA5EF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<subsection id="H76E86E5F9355410D9477459651ABECA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Police Athletic/Activities League shall use grant funds awarded under this Act to provide funding for—</text> <paragraph id="H89E2B33F68374C2FAFB5DE2171838103"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the establishment of PAL chapters serving public housing projects and other distressed areas; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0769B49BBB34E66BCF969A95918B0B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the expansion of existing PAL chapters.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H56584C774B0946F99208C49C99FECD09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each PAL chapter assisted under paragraph (1) shall carry out not less than 2 programs during non-school hours, of which—</text> 
<paragraph id="H99D838B8059C44CEA789D4C273D0AD6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 1 program shall provide—</text> <subparagraph id="H5190D8FB4BDD4683BA13D50BF021E038"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mentorship assistance and opportunities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA808B1327E9E49C2BA84A0F7AC09B141"><enum>(B)</enum><text>academic assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D2A2FE3C2E24F55BB485C979D8497E6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recreational and athletic activities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF4D428F09CD4932AC780F3539ACD449"><enum>(D)</enum><text>technology training; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3279AF59D9A4290A1AC343E8FE27BD8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>character development and leadership training; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4BEC75A2E3340DFB97E64947BE263F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any remaining programs shall provide—</text> <subparagraph id="H919217FA4300499E93CBA689A643B4C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>activities to prevent use of drugs and alcohol and participation in gangs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97C8DF417EB44CD6BF66AAC5D032AF8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>health and nutrition counseling;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96C5C5B3C49D433EA8AE882C32CBD1D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>cultural and social programs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H14E4ABAA7BF7421FAF16CC47C259456A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conflict resolution training, anger management, and peer pressure resistance training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF8FB23ADF994664B5AF7FE80DE94A63"><enum>(E)</enum><text>job skill preparation activities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27DAB30349B44A62959DF44306B5D075"><enum>(F)</enum><text>safety skills conveying; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61200E018E8945E0A8E785491B0FF10E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Youth Police Athletic League Conferences or Youth Forums.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC496B9B569CA4F57A9C1EE7E9BC6F4CC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the programs required under subsection (b), a PAL chapter shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</text> <paragraph id="H0619FFF4EC294B57BDC5AF2F08B1E0D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recruit volunteers from businesses, academic communities, social organizations, and law enforcement organizations to serve as mentors or to otherwise assist with such programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H949C03AAB94E4B9EA98881D98554A953"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that youth in the local community participate in designing the after-school activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36E925C4870A48E380BD9F0E6CFE4B17"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop creative methods of conducting outreach to youth in the community served;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0650D6D1240497BA58D8794A50B387C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">request donations of computer equipment and other materials and equipment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9971C18CD414597A7D1C3380572EB88"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with State and local parks and recreation agencies to ensure that activities funded with grant funds awarded under this Act do not duplicate otherwise funded activities in the community served.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6B1EFAD25E814A24A54C0AFCBA9BA10F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<subsection id="HA7EDABE4E3584861915F0204325FEBAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Assistant Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year in which a grant is awarded under this Act, the National Police Athletic/Activities League shall submit to the Assistant Attorney General a report on the use of grant funds awarded under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H73C337ED5B2F46739E12D7C2AC850A6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than May 1 of each fiscal year for which amounts are made available to carry out this Act, the Assistant Attorney General shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and of the House of Representatives a report that details the progress made under this Act in establishing and expanding PAL chapters in public housing projects and other distressed areas, and the effectiveness of PAL programs in reducing drug misuse, school dropout rates, and juvenile crime.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5EDE8FD72B834ACE9EF21A8B5AD206A3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="H65C3E7654C4C4436B9ACC064CB2042C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $16,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2028 through 2032.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H06960DEC4DEE41A583435D00BDD293F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may allocate funding appropriated to, or collected by the Department of Justice as determined appropriate by the Attorney General and the Assistant Attorney General, to the extent that such allocations are not prohibited by law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E7C41BA2B5441B4864BC033351A44E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding for program administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount made available to carry out this Act in each fiscal year—</text> <paragraph id="HB82E6DF979B842BE9F77F99EBE7611EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 2 percent shall be used for research and evaluation of the grant program under this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FB21990A65D49199F7830EE56CEC30A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 1 percent shall be used for technical assistance related to the use of grant funds awarded under this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE13C4DEE3D224C5F82CE417CCE2D4CF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 1 percent shall be used for the management and administration of the grant program under this Act, except that the total amount made available under this paragraph for administration of such grant program may not exceed 6 percent.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0C700FCE47D042769CBEECBFD46A767B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD79F8099E5614A0FA1DBCD815DB73407"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Attorney General</header><text>The term <quote>Assistant Attorney General</quote> means the Attorney General, acting through the Assistant Attorney General for the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H802608ABB9B04CBB89BBAA091F91C72E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distressed area</header><text>The term <quote>distressed area</quote> means an urban, suburban, or rural area in which the percentage of high-risk youth residing in such area equals or exceeds 40 percent.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C2ABCA480C148D9AF7C0EA3653E2F44"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High-risk youth</header><text>The term <quote>high-risk youth</quote> means an individual—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A4E58AC9DCA42DAB885A6FD09BCB19E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who has not attained 21 years of age;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3BD36DAED1E54C9487BE7A6003E52253"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is at high risk of becoming, or has become, a drug abuser or an alcohol abuser; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3EAD89C6DF09405694B8EB157F23DE7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who—</text> <clause id="H9D69F829C9CC4EF185A9B44F6D7076CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is identified as a child of a substance abuser;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBEF9BD90CC694735B5089E8F683484FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a victim of physical, sexual, or psychological abuse;</text></clause> <clause id="H01D1ECF01C6F47B9A4E06C6409E97B45"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has dropped out of school;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8161C02439D541FB801484C7B97052A5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has become pregnant;</text></clause> <clause id="H26C853799F1E46448F66A54BEED02CB2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is economically disadvantaged;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0C11A3D522D44B62A3FBD6DF39065CE9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>has committed a violent or delinquent act;</text></clause> <clause id="H787FECB8773F402FACEA51B9205436A1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>has experienced mental health problems;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBFC1EEB78D7B40048F5E94D9C45DA282"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>has attempted suicide; or</text></clause> <clause id="H959B8E0A314048E195FBA7F5D3C04EBB"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>is disabled by injuries.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8D602337325472E8393FB2900B4B5F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>PAL Chapter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>PAL chapter</quote> means a chapter of a Police or Sheriff’s Athletic/Activities League that is a member of the National Police Athletic/Activities League.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D4C5F76C9F441D38BB9EF7D1DE25FC4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National Police Athletic/Activities League</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>National Police Athletic/Activities League</quote> or <quote>National PAL</quote> means the private, nonprofit representative organization for Police or Sheriff’s Athletic/Activities Leagues throughout the United States, including the United States Virgin Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB64E870EDF5243ADA74DEE90F849D521" commented="no">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
                <header>Public housing; project</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>public housing</quote> and <quote>project</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 3(b)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(1)</external-xref>).</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

