<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06785A9089894A6D9A032FEC8449CD15" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 915 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Ukrainian famine of 1932–1933, known as the Holodomor, is recognized as a genocide and should serve as a reminder of repressive Soviet policies against the people of Ukraine.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 915</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251128">November 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Ukrainian famine of 1932–1933, known as the Holodomor, is recognized as a genocide and should serve as a reminder of repressive Soviet policies against the people of Ukraine.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1932 and 1933, millions of Ukrainians perished from a famine engineered by the former Soviet Union, designed to break the Ukrainian’s resistance to Communist occupation and to provide a cover for a campaign of repression and persecution carried out by the Soviet Union against the citizens and culture of Ukraine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Soviet dictator Joseph Stalin ordered the borders of Ukraine sealed to prevent anyone from escaping the manmade starvation and to prevent the delivery of any international food aid that would provide relief to the starving;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Soviet Union forced the people of Ukraine to relinquish their land, personal property, and housing to collective farms and then confiscated grain harvests, starving the men, women, and children of Ukraine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nearly a quarter of Ukraine’s rural population perished or were forced into exile due to the induced starvation, and the entire nation suffered from the consequences of the prolonged famine;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of Ukraine and the Ukrainian communities in the United States and worldwide continue their efforts to secure awareness and understanding of the 1932–1933 tragedy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Commission on the Ukraine Famine, Investigation of the Ukrainian Famine 1932–1933: Report to Congress, adopted by the Commission, April 19, 1988, and submitted to Congress April 22, 1988, found that in 1932 and 1933, the Government of the Soviet Union had committed genocide against the Ukrainian people; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas victims of the Holodomor genocide of 1932–1933 continue to be remembered: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HDD7A70C242E54B62898735A2908BB31D"><section id="H45E0F6DB26A14F9D947EDED62847D5B5" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HB48E83F93D6E493888FAF8D279BAAEA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the Ukrainian famine of 1932–1933, known as the Holodomor, as a genocide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC3FC1F5601D40D1B1F726C32EDE9868"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solemnly remembers the atrocities of the Holodomor of 1932–1933, and extends its deepest sympathies to the victims, survivors, and families of this tragedy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94A9D1A3E60E4D4C9A41F9E73999234A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>condemns the systematic violations of human rights, including the starvation, repression, and persecution of the Ukrainian people by the Soviet Union;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25D6A94B365246DA801FA0B02172E2BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages dissemination of information regarding the Holodomor of 1932–1933 in order to increase an understanding of the Soviet-engineered genocide denied by the Kremlin for more than half a century;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB927CC612BB24D1F86016B456AA6E85B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns Vladimir Putin’s brutal and unprovoked war in Ukraine and his repeated public rejections of the existence of a Ukrainian people and a sovereign Ukraine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05830DA7988345858C42169FC3A7AA32"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strongly supports efforts to advance the path to a lasting peace in Ukraine and deter future Russian aggression.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

