<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87E2F2047A434C67AAA9A15D4032C095" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6923 IH: Jobs for a Carbon Free Transportation System Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6923</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251223">December 23, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To incentivize innovative transportation corridors to reduce carbon and GHG emissions, to provide a tax structure that allows for certain investments in public transportation systems, and to enable the fossil fuel workforce to transition to sustainable work sectors.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE6333CFE2E21407FA76B8B0067C2A351" style="OLC">
<section id="H7D4428D53FF5435D83187B95D0885557" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jobs for a Carbon Free Transportation System Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <title id="H2DDF729D327B4CCBA7A69330E13CDE1A"><enum>I</enum><header>Low Carbon Corridors</header> <section id="H5D495D3DC2DA41C6AEC17874EB44894A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Low carbon corridor grant program</header> <subsection id="HA659C0FEC0944BDFB45C17ABE64B04F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Low carbon corridor defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>low carbon corridor</quote> means a connected systems-management corridor that connects different methods of transportation, including public transportation systems, rail transportation, roadways, and alternative methods of transportation.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6FD0B16A03E6406BA588E60B926EB135"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible entities to carry out projects to develop low carbon corridors. The purpose of such projects shall be to—</text> <paragraph id="HDA073C03B48D478EA702AC291A624E28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>lower carbon emissions along the corridor;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24C10B4B66694576A33117188FC8B262"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase transportation inter-connectivity; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AA4015D7E8B4ACC93846902F073BD96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase transportation infrastructure reinvestment.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB827B8DCD0B34B52A70D5B74AE449528"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants under the program to a State, local, or tribal government, or a subdivision thereof, or a metropolitan planning organization.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA280430454BA49F5902891564E634D38"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>Funds provided under this section may be used to incorporate low carbon and investment mechanisms into low carbon corridors, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H4B0CF9553D9E4B0E8B25DD5514B44198"><enum>(1)</enum><text>high occupancy vehicle lanes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AAEB9B92EBE4506929A03ED91D48557"><enum>(2)</enum><text>value capture;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBFBABB129F8B426FAD040A642B751BC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>transit-oriented development and high-density development;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA83213FF79C6454CB9A0E1E3D04F9671"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carbon fees;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7921A00670034B1AA2061BDBAD0B6AA2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>automated vehicle or electric vehicle lanes that are timed and connected to a transit system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H093CE79E1F9E42039EC3EB1F778B0DE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Smart Cities connectivity and innovation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD4C887C3D7764FE582C16230201FFC90"><enum>(7)</enum><text>high-speed rail; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC5E5B403E194840B1BBEC8FEDA544FD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>facilities for alternative modes of transportation, including pedestrian and bicycle facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6EC5B332031C40D3B12635996894D601"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Labor requirements</header>
<paragraph id="HB4C17C7A8D5944D7976A64DB16F09E18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A project carried out with a grant under the program shall be subject to the provisions of each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7E2E129ADC38444988D16A6D0CA3D17F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40 (commonly known as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H35546FB8A3F147FBA46B4B71FE74B51A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/65">Chapter 65</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Walsh-Healy Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03870473FAAB4BF6AA889267C3E53C26" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/67">Chapter 67</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>McNamara-O’Hara Service Contract Act of 1965</quote>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAD7A36F942224BB0BF4116E4FD7114BE" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/37">Chapter 37</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Work Hours and Safety Standards Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H180D2A9C7A7D4E7FAA4DAF6B75DBD85E" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1DE6584A4A15424191AE2FD45AD168AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorities of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the labor standards in this subsection, the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6D7E36F9DD34CA99D1E7747CA964B0C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Strategic partnerships</header><text>A recipient of a grant under the program may enter into strategic partnerships with nonprofit organizations or universities to develop plans for low carbon corridors.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HBCEE480A709E40118E65389F9D881215"><enum>(g)</enum><header>DOT and EPA benchmarks</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall jointly monitor how low carbon corridors with respect to which grants were provided under this section reduce carbon emissions and how any mechanisms described in subsection (d) incorporated into such corridor contribute to carbon emission reductions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD2A69ACFC9304BADB9428CD270D01E13"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Use of American products</header> <paragraph id="HD7E1C9A9FC3E439B85EAEA0047E4E561"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A recipient of funds under this section shall ensure that any iron, steel, and manufactured products used in projects carried out with such funds are produced in the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB4CC5F214D344293B31859E4F66DA00F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header>
<subparagraph id="HB4AFAC4A92D6452F93C3E5745FEDC371"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may waive the requirement of paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that—</text> <clause id="H067221E5B1D240B78B946791482C7FF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applying paragraph (1) would be inconsistent with the public interest;</text></clause>
<clause id="H80C609B86416491B99F5246E5498D446"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>iron, steel, and manufactured products produced in the United States are not produced in a sufficient and reasonably available amount or are not of a satisfactory quality; or</text></clause> <clause id="H1809C5B30F6644B3AB68C4A0D7EA9804"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>using iron, steel, and manufactured products produced in the United States will increase the cost of the overall project by more than 25 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H51EF1C1BEB50401684501A6B501EEA41"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Before issuing a waiver under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a detailed written explanation of the waiver determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB98779099DDD41AEA2ED99ECFF2D03D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consistency with international agreements</header><text>This subsection shall be applied in a manner consistent with the obligations of the United States under international agreements.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCDF01862E66B4A17B6973AC7F8932F1F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HDE1495288F4740D7AC2C7E51767D9946"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Produced in the United States</header><text>The term <quote>produced in the United States</quote> means the following:</text>
<clause id="H04C449CCE0AE481B8093C9081DE27CCC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>When used with respect to a manufactured product, the product was manufactured in the United States and the cost of the components of such product that were mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States exceeds 60 percent of the total cost of all components of the product.</text></clause> <clause id="H96D6C8504E1E496FAEAFEB6D45A41D7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>When used with respect to iron or steel products, or an individual component of a manufactured product, all manufacturing processes for such iron or steel products or components, from the initial melting stage through the application of coatings, occurred in the United States, except that the term does not include—</text>
<subclause id="HA3CD7D919A0B4449A55BD3BB117DF711"><enum>(I)</enum><text>steel or iron material or products manufactured abroad from semi-finished steel or iron from the United States; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD0D1EA8674694656A99271158E546298"><enum>(II)</enum><text>steel or iron material or products manufactured in the United States from semi-finished steel or iron of foreign origin.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H779A1046D8D446D485579C8475EC9474"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Manufactured product</header><text>The term <quote>manufactured product</quote> means any construction material or end product (as such terms are defined in part 25.003 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation) that is not an iron or steel product, including—</text> <clause id="H2E87F27BDDBD4FEC9F8E445C9D072948"><enum>(i)</enum><text>electrical components; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H0B8DF0F2B8DB45FF938750929552E774"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>non-ferrous building materials, including, aluminum and polyvinylchloride (PVC), glass, fiber optics, plastic, wood, masonry, rubber, manufactured stone, any other non-ferrous metals, and any unmanufactured construction material.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title> <title id="HF4A5F6913A73401D8F401992A5C8D46B"><enum>II</enum><header>Value Capture</header> <section id="H6A0C502BA1BD4752BBE84CAE469CCFF6" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text>
<paragraph id="HF69132AA244548B9877E3DC22594C2FF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affordable transit-oriented development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>affordable transit-oriented development</quote> means development of commercial and residential areas located near public transportation stations that promotes affordable housing and affordable commercial space.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9F0A5DFDBC44BFAA7C20E4DF9E77E4A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Captured assessed value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>captured assessed value</quote> means the amount, as a percentage or stated sum, of increased assessed value that is utilized from year to year to finance project costs pursuant to the district strategic plan.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9941300669294ED98E53813336C705E8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Current assessed value</header><text>The term <quote>current assessed value</quote> means the assessed value of all taxable real property within a tax increment district as of October first of each year that the tax increment district remains in effect.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H675020B2FAF747959150E7063F495449" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Financial plan</header><text>The term <quote>financial plan</quote> means a statement of the project costs and sources of revenue required to accomplish the district strategic plan.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE8DA3B5CC04745AE887FC284606031F6" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Increased assessed value</header><text>The term <quote>increased assessed value</quote> means the valuation amount by which the current assessed value of a tax increment district exceeds the original assessed value of the tax increment district. If the current assessed value is equal to or less than the original assessed value, there is no increased assessed value.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37D0C7211F804B60B308334B99389E88" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <quote>local government</quote> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2AABDD4F745942F0B24E041A5416EA9C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any county, city, town, township, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E123442A07745F99393705083D29ED3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any combination of political subdivisions or appropriate government entities including special assessment districts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H203F13E1C30048B396D901CE889DD3EA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Nominated area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nominated area</quote> means an area which is nominated by 1 or more local governments and the State or States in which it is located for designation under section 7.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F988B287DBE4C03A422FA593F1308A4" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Original assessed value</header><text>The term <quote>original assessed value</quote> means the assessed value of all taxable real property within a tax increment district as of October first of the tax year preceding the year in which the tax increment district was established by the State or local government.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58980635085F4FABB6BE85A8D4719C5A" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Public Transportation</header><text>The term <quote>public transportation</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E586693C8634536A9F70E79841E803B" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tax increment</header><text>The term <quote>tax increment</quote> means capital gain taxes assessed by the Federal Government upon the increased assessed value of property in the tax increment district.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF0115015A6CB41C8BD81C079B620B636" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Tax increment district</header><text>The term <quote>tax increment district</quote> means that area wholly within the corporate limits of a municipality that has been established and designated in accordance to section 7.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H7CBC5E44B5EE478B8C75877F9822CB04"><enum>4.</enum><header>Value capture policy and planning program</header> <subsection id="H3F73C8AF037F4328AB748F27964D1A5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">Chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H5EA8BF4B29B34C3E95059BF364E76C47" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="HAEF470E4956A4B4DA55E30D55CB2E811"><enum>5341.</enum><header>Technical assistance and value capture policy</header>
<subsection id="H220055689C834B4D8A2DB3F4495EAE7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical assistance and policy development</header>
<paragraph id="H0CDA016A4846422987E54347F442F682"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make grants to States and local governments to—</text> <subparagraph id="H734C665FE71D48BBB0C7B053654FD891"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop State and local value capture mechanisms for long-term funding that promote mobility, public transportation, and affordable transit-oriented development;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H63B44F8CA62644E4B9B3051F674C700B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve public transportation and mobility for individuals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18DF938E929040E08CC633FEF69503A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop strategic partnerships that lead to greater long-term and robust investments in public transportation, mobility, inclusive economic development, and affordable transit-oriented development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFFB17E60D3CA4C8BAE33B9E53879C0AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Value capture policy</header><text>Not later than October 1 of the fiscal year that begins 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary, in collaboration with State departments of transportation, metropolitan planning organizations, and regional governments, shall establish voluntary value capture standards for value capture mechanisms that promote greater investments into public transportation and affordable transit-oriented development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15A717C4382D4CA1B1F305EDFA8D5537"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary, through a competitive bid process, may enter into contracts, cooperative agreements, and other agreements with nonprofit organizations that have a demonstrated capacity to provide value capture-related technical assistance to grant recipients.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H16FCD3CBAC8F4A45A5CC1B20099A44DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall create a report, and make such report available to the public, that contains examples of State and local law and policy that provide for value capture that promotes greater investment in public transportation and affordable transit-oriented development.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0C66F99FCF4C4EC69E380171D41FE496"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on the report required under subsection (b), the Secretary shall identify and disseminate to State departments of transportation, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Environment and Public Works, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives examples of best practices where States and local governments have adopted value capture mechanisms that have successfully provided for greater investment in public transportation and affordable transit-oriented development.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H931868143A964A0AACB3692739B871CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H803CCB4F2B184527B376D3AA8E04F175" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Value capture</header><text>The term <quote>value capture</quote> means collecting from an entity a portion of the economic value created by government investments, activities, and policies that have generated alternative revenue streams, assets, or other financial value and repurposing such economic value to assist in funding government investments and activities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF9F0EAC0A47A48A58A7BFF8D44D68DFB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affordable transit-oriented development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>affordable transit-oriented development</quote> means development of commercial and residential areas located near public transportation stations that promotes affordable housing and affordable commercial space.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DB19D11A4E9489FA7CC9741849A2AE3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local government</header><text>The term <quote>local government</quote> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9DFA5FE6272749BE85B1D3D3BB852814" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any county, city, town, township, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EBE5660F8FA4C21B9AD3D4D04A04A5C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any combination of political subdivisions or appropriate government entities including special assessment districts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDD1A6B783540499C8BDB97666BDC3810" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public Transportation</header><text>The term <quote>public transportation</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 5302 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1CE57C82554347C393ACDADE56980609"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H704ED74AE0A44A8DB15A03571D686AC8" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">5341. Technical assistance and value capture policy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H696FAE6F46B64DA1A9BD2395E44A5E42"><enum>5.</enum><header>Designation of Federal value capture tax increment financing districts</header>
<subsection id="H2557634145644E47A44614D4087756C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From among the eligible areas nominated for designation under this section, the Secretary of Transportation shall designate Federal tax increment financing districts to help State and local government finance the cost for certain improvements and investment in public transportation, affordable housing, and other community development activities in an eligible area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB3C07A6180C844DEBF7078B6CEA8BFEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Number of designations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation may annually designate nominated areas as a Federal value capture tax increment financing district under this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF92AD476299046F7ABA822C654F57A9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period for which designation is in effect</header>
<paragraph id="H4B7AE8E716DD45C9891D0AFBF658BCDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any designation under this section shall remain in effect during the period beginning on the date of the designation and ending on the earliest of—</text> <subparagraph id="H976CA6CE453B4CB4AACF46ABD7947B5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>December 31, 2030;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA1A0E5D6A1214AA2BBB086054A5C5C05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the termination date designated by the State and local governments as provided for in a nomination; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H699E59ED267E46D1AAA861CEEF21EF77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary revokes the designation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6CFE667393A34DD29F1B600B3E72CFCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revocation of designation</header><text>If appropriate, the Secretary may revoke the designation under this section of an area if such Secretary determines that the local government or the State in which it is located—</text> <subparagraph id="H2764D59FE4F841519C72ECD1AC9213B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has modified the boundaries of the area; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7573BE98D1074984BD96E9EC88087410"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not complying substantially with, or fails to make progress in achieving the benchmarks set forth in section 4.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0B74E143EE14401B966DCD7AB1CC1D88"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations on designations</header><text>No area may be designated under this section unless—</text>
<paragraph id="HC529CBA2FDE34F22B659ED429A4D1582"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the area is nominated by 1 or more local governments and the State or States in which it is located for designation under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDB6F3D0F3E5464CACA1C8C994ECC4B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such State or States and the local governments have the authority—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7351AF0120CA4936A681BBAADC717254"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to nominate the area for designation under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B527EF4656C41CCB5573564E0288A4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>meet the Federal requirements described in this title;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H75C7ADC674044ED39CD8E05F8DEABC31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such State or States and the local governments meet the Federal value capture policy standards as described in section 4;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A120E3D17EF4AAAA213F596E414AD9D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that any information furnished is reasonably accurate; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFEAB27EDD669477BBBA9DD227FBC979A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such State or States and local governments certify that no portion of the area nominated is already included in a Federal tax increment financing district, an infrastructure value capture zone, or in an area otherwise nominated to be designated under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H96AD271C4E88410283DA95F5B94542C4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application that at minimum contains—</text>
<paragraph id="H80C81546C55F4BC883117DA9FA4F8AA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a tax increment financing district strategic plan, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H62D8E1C7CB094EBB87B4F5A0C3B6AE55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the boundaries of the tax increment district by legal description;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0B09A6E5F4474305B274AC7F321020CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of the tax identification numbers for all lots or parcels within the tax increment district;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28B55666F84E4C558869CC620A47461F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the present condition and uses of all land and buildings within the tax increment district;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6466A0D05F8249A4A8F1F0BA5315BEB9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the public facilities, improvements or programs within the tax increment district anticipated to be added and financed in whole or in part;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H017350C7E6FE4C5994837FC4B10BD932"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the industrial, commercial, residential, mixed-use or retail improvements, downtown development or transit-oriented development within the tax increment district anticipated to be financed in whole or in part;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCDB55B9AE2604AEF91B1C5DD11080A71"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a financial plan in accordance with subsection (c) of this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EC4183E8F224EC598743AAFCADC9622"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a plan for the proposed maintenance and operation of the tax increment district after the planned capital improvements are completed; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H41833CF414B5451393C7EC5CF6EF2F64"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the maximum duration of the tax increment district, which may not exceed a total of thirty tax years beginning with the tax year in which the tax increment district is established; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87728A46C560473CAE822FA08EEE52F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a financial plan for a tax increment financing strategic plan, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H24DC679D584C4A259DC77B1986FA5B36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cost estimates for the public improvements and developments anticipated in the district strategic plan;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H830549365AEC42B99C92FB65E441B40B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the maximum amount of indebtedness to be incurred to implement the district strategic plan;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0F333D7B2FAA47F9B6AFF213A44BA6C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sources of anticipated revenues;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDEBC075513045A08C37F5D857817FEC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the terms and conditions of any agreements, including any anticipated assessment agreements, contracts or other obligations related to the district strategic plan;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B6C3D1F1CFE4D4D9E006AF40474F9E6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>estimates of increased assessed values of the tax increment district; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7C32B1B97CB47FBAE2E579300FDBAFA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the portion of the increased assessed values to be applied to the district strategic plan as captured assessed values and resulting tax increments in each year of the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HC0629D5603F145B3BE894CD51F2F5468"><enum>6.</enum><header>Eligibility criteria</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A nominated area shall be eligible for designation under section 5 only if the appropriate State or local government or agency—</text> <paragraph id="HD51555F16A9640A2A3DE88622C74995E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates a contiguous area within its jurisdiction as a transit-oriented development or transit-serve corridor; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3C7F3FE42CC44D7A95B57A114BC1D066"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has created a tax increment financing district or other value capture that meet the value capture standards as described in section 4.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD38EA5778CA7462AACC931DF7EEEC57B" commented="no" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Value capture tax increment financing districts; special rule for capital gains</header> <subsection id="H35ACA3DEB6304AF6A9D43841176BACC2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, shall, with respect to designated Federal value capture tax increment financing districts as described in section 5—</text>
<paragraph id="H9F3E485056FF49FF93B0168DA6B7714D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a procedure to certify the original assessed value of the Federal capital gain taxes within the boundaries of a Federal value capture tax increment financing district,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE017483791A649A8A2A65383BC0A3044" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in each year after the establishment of a Federal value capture tax increment financing district, certify with respect to such district the amount of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9AF9014077B449AEBAFAC5ECFC4CF53B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the assessed value of capital gains collected,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB54E3C28315342899BF94511BA7599B8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount by which the current assessed value has increased or decreased from the original assessed value, subject to any assessment agreements, and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8ED5252F5C0F4256ACFF88BA999A87BD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount of the captured assessed value, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2BE3D5DFCC34564B1D18868940ED4CF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct such analysis as is necessary to determine the maximum amount available of Federal guarantees of qualified transit-oriented development bonds, but not to exceed an annual amount to be determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA16F7112D5B942CF84FEA152DC940005"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal value capture tax increment financing district</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>Federal value capture tax increment financing district</quote> means a targeted redevelopment area within a municipality, county, or other government entity, from which all or a portion of projected future property tax revenue increases is temporarily dedicated to finance infrastructure improvements (or other investments) with the objective of stimulating economic development.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBDB51421BB3B4BF6830B75CCCE357849" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking and regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue such rules or regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H674E3C77E8C1452386972F64985FECD4" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least 30 days before issuing a letter of intent for establishment of a Federal value capture tax increment district, the Secretary of the Treasury shall notify in writing the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Environment and Public Works and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives of the designated Federal value capture tax increment districts. The Secretary shall include with the notification a copy of the nomination application and designation as well as the evaluations and ratings for each designation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H51D30CDDD11E40B29FBF99EBD3EA486A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assessment agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>assessment agreement</quote> means an agreement that establishes, with respect to a Federal value capture tax increment financing district—</text>
<paragraph id="HC99A384773C148529579CC5ECBF5C64F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the tax base,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0296E697CC348F0ACC8ADC71714D9FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of increased tax collections to be dedicated to such district,</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0AF780881A8A46E7B36933193558DBD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>procedures for collecting funds, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA75285FD44747E3A91D619D4EBE28AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>approved uses for funds.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H5600E5BA126F446885CD1E04E8BB3E14" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Expansion of long-term local funding for public infrastructure and affordable transit-oriented development</header>
<subsection id="H9B147259682248CEA7E61F5ECE06BB7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part IV of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8D9B5570D6364F29B582B754665CC238" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H25FF5DDDBA914A1FAAB9EB7A7C4C1118" commented="no"><enum>147A.</enum><header>Qualified transit-oriented development bonds</header> <subsection id="HEB3767C23CA04F2D89570F98FB1E2015" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>qualified transit-oriented development bond</quote> means any private activity bond issued as part of an issue for the purposes of the acquisition, construction, reconstruction, or improvement of land or property that is within one half-mile of an existing or planned major public transportation facility including fixed-guideway transit stations (rail and bus rapid transit), designated High Speed Rail or existing intercity rail stations, or an intermodal transportation station.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H60097D8C0D5B4A0E91B66B39A5302BB4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text>A bond shall not be treated as a qualified transit-oriented development bond unless the issue described in subsection (a) is issued pursuant to relevant local government-adopted policies, as determined by the Secretary, that—</text> <paragraph id="HC98FB29D721A49149A04CF8345D106CC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote long-term affordable housing or affordable commercial spaces,</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H80E3AC33C69244439EC7CEC394B34717" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote high-density, mixed-use development near public transportation stations,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD929012F663E44D4B7F9432C26809277" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage value capture and value sharing that promotes greater investment in public transportation and affordable transit-oriented development, including any strategy developed under section 5341,</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H700DDE63A5314767BE1636FEABCD704E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the payment of the principal and interest on such issue is primarily secured by taxes of general applicability imposed by a general purpose governmental unit,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC78ABBC68A754A33B3139D47D3E7B36B" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a 25 to 50 percent increase, as determined by the Secretary, in real property tax revenues (attributable to increases in assessed value) by reason of the carrying out of such purposes in such area is reserved exclusively for debt service on such issue (and similar issues) to the extent such increase does not exceed such debt service, or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H056AFD2AA15A4CAAB62D10E8FE66B7CB" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other value capture mechanisms including user fees, sales tax revenues, or other revenue sources dedicated to the project by property owners and businesses.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD00233425A90442D8E6A7BB183784E5D" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transit-Oriented Development Volume Cap</header> <paragraph id="HD15C72367F77455CB0EBE437B114D3F2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate face amount of Transit-oriented development bonds issued pursuant to an issue, when added to the aggregate face amount of transit-oriented development bonds previously issued by the issuing authority during the calendar year, shall not exceed such issuing authority's Move America volume cap for such year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H83E42AC53AB648F3906E384E7A5B3D09" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation of volume cap</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State may allocate the transit-oriented development volume cap of such State among governmental units (or other authorities) in such State having authority to issue private activity bonds.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF0E94B1D7EA24A67B16DF455FAFFD746" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application of Davis-Bacon Act requirements with respect to Federal value capture tax increment financing districts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter IV of chapter 31 of the title 40, United States Code, shall apply to projects financed with the proceeds of qualified transit-oriented development bonds.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H808F69E33D8F4B778254915E6725F23C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="HFE3E93C1CAC34672ACD56AE313F444CD"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 147A. Qualified transit-oriented development bonds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H3391FAFDE8CB4ADD951FA82A3DB085D4" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the Secretary has determined the procedure described in section 8(a)(1).</text></subsection></section></title>
<title id="HEDC9E8A1CB9F4E1D9338917EB126A3D7"><enum>III</enum><header>Protecting Workers for a Clean Future Act</header>
<section id="HBDD5373FE2DB4492B6BE86B1D1D487B6" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA6EC413B9CC249D0916EA56FFF7FF2A8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The fossil fuel and fossil fuel-dependent industries have been major drivers of employment and economic growth in regions throughout California. Yet, despite the success of these industries, many local residents are unemployed or live in poverty. In addition, nearby communities often suffer from pollution, poor air and water quality, and other health hazards. The goal of community transition grants is to develop a vision for a future economy based on equity, sustainability, and shared prosperity. A regional approach requires bringing together a diverse set of stakeholders that represent the whole community. This coalition must be capable of developing and implementing strategies to support workers and communities that will be affected by the transition away from fossil fuels. To be effective, coalitions should work closely with high road employers and industry leaders to identify in-demand skills and workforce strategies that promote emerging and expanding sectors of the regional economy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E21C516B7EC42139F1868A44BBB1E13" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These strategies should provide pathways for impacted workers to transition to other sustainable jobs and careers. They should also include the frontline communities who have historically been excluded from the economic benefits of the fossil fuel industry, while bearing the greatest costs of pollution and ecological damage.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H265B6BF8FC28427DB013BFF1B3A37C80" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Partnerships should include organizations representing workers and communities impacted by the fossil fuel industry and the transition to a carbon-constrained economy. Workers, residents, and community leaders have inherent knowledge of regional dynamics, issues, and needs, and should function at the center of developing regional solutions.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD3DAEAA2631740FFA9F40AB5B209080C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In addition, coalitions should be diverse and represent a wide range of regional interests and stakeholders, including organizations representing labor, environmental justice, industry, economic development, local tribal and municipal government, and educational institutions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83A9C6B7915A46F292C6F3BBF64B344E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>As the United States and global economies shift from fossil fuels to more sustainable sources of energy, the fossil fuel workforce cannot be left behind. They must be part of the conversation and have a role in shaping the transition.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HC8EA22A6DF4D4253BDA0F89D558F07AF"><enum>10.</enum><header>Renewable energy transition grant program</header>
<subsection id="HE02BFEE44F7D400DAE21420E495FA04C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall establish a grant program for local governments for the purpose of developing a plan to transition workers from employment in fossil fuel industries to employment in sustainable industries.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD3FABFBB0155470A92B1231644E2697B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor may award grants under subsection (a) to a local or Tribal government that—</text>
<paragraph id="HC342CC3934804B4896CB50387F9D5D89"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishes industry or sector partnerships (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>));</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37992F2158AC45E089F341C9A1C3DC9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is in a locality that the Secretary of Energy determines to have a percentage of traditional energy sector jobs that is average or above average relative to the United States; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29DC0BF5D25748DF9A7BE3B3141E1B58"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies that such local or Tribal government will develop the transition plan described in subsection (a) in consultation with relevant State and other experts, including experts in energy labor, green economy policies, and energy policy, and with relevant State officials, if applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDAB8767E927F4B559CE81029BDF29B87"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination of percentage of traditional energy sector jobs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making the determination under subsection (b)(2), the Secretary of Labor shall take into consideration information from the report entitled <quote>U.S. Energy and Employment Report</quote> issued by the Secretary in January, 2017.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H928A1E3A37C648D1907C6481E577BD72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds under subsection (a) may be used for the following purposes:</text> <paragraph id="H495DA975922848F8B8BDE0ACCC79E3ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To develop a transition plan described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBCAF2DB913914C96B3107BCA8C855845"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To support an existing apprenticeship program for apprenticeable occupation or, if in a non-traditional industry, to develop an apprenticeship program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CCDF09B3EB44EBB87C9E5F93FA844F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To train individuals who are new to the workforce for jobs in sustainable industries, including but not limited to, manufacturing, autonomous vehicles, electric vehicles, renewable energy, CERCLA remediation, and may include a partnership or agreements with employers to provide jobs for trainees.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H034808A87D8845B095B41059DF6181C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transition plan requirements</header><text>A transition plan funded under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H26BBB0FA3FC04AFB8F58951602DFEC88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include assistance for accessing all existing applicable Federal and State aid for displaced workers, including unemployment insurance, job transition training, and community services for the affected community as well as trade adjustment assistance and other programs, if applicable; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H116A98E740DA4CE7A0350C8A39AC9931"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may also include assistance to supplement existing Federal and State aid, including funds for bridges to retirement for older workers, wage insurance for workers who find employment in lower wage jobs, and funding for significant career change training for workers who wish to change careers, including case management and career path counseling.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H57BE996478AF4AECA547B1AE11E0384A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6CE9C1926FD04BCE9E0DB9BF3A353ED0"><enum>11.</enum><header>National Employment Corps</header>
<subsection id="HBC75AC45F34A4C8BB2316F8B686A3BDD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Department of Labor a National Employment Corps.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8EDCE4F72ACC445291FBA597CADBED29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Job guarantee grants</header> <paragraph id="H85485B98D83B4D51BBEFBCAFCA713686"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If local government or Tribe described in section 10(b) executes a plan under section 10 in good faith, but all workers described in section 10(a) are not successfully transitioned, the Secretary of Labor, acting through the National Employment Corps, shall establish a program (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>program</quote>) to provide grants to local and Tribal governments to provide direct employment projects for the purpose of guaranteeing a job and job training to any eligible worker not successfully transitioned under such plan.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8DF950D4E1DF488FA816D10415C3F181"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The grants under paragraph (1) shall cover wage, benefits, and material expenses of eligible workers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C8FC2825CD543BC8C5EB9FAFB9DF1B1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>eligible worker</quote> means any individual who loses a job or reasonably anticipates losing a job due to a transition from traditional energy sources to sustainable energy sources.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF794FB6A8FA54D89B04F946CE71104BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination of Federal efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corps shall work with Federal agencies to identify areas of needed investment in the United States economy, including infrastructure, energy efficiency, retrofitting, elder care, child care, job training, education, and health services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB0783EDADE0A492A8A532D1FFB7029EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal component</header> <paragraph id="H65E94A5E6B414EAFBA062E14850D3FB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If projects funded under the program under subsection (b) are inadequate to maintain full employment in the locality or Tribe, the Secretary shall intervene in the locality or Tribe to provide adequate employment opportunities to guarantee employment to workers described in such subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H03CB38A69385442A9FD75FDCA95776CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corps shall also offer the following services to eligible workers:</text> <subparagraph id="HDCDF522E27E14105A9F2DE93C0FFC065"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Supportive services.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDECB8E7371E44AF7BF79252076170509"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Wrap-around services, including:</text> <clause id="H5BA515C9264943D399A0DB3847A5F6FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Transportation.</text></clause>
<clause id="H6128199237DC4263B35684651C7BCCA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Childcare.</text></clause> <clause id="HCAC3BFCC441C4A29A72F50FED270D9AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Job preparation services.</text></clause>
<clause id="HD82180731AA9433DAC8C08A5C1A941B8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Counseling.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD372487241E941E8BAE2BFE27FE40FE9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Adult education and literacy activities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5F95ECE240F64828B3679EA521E1C4F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Activities to assist justice-involved individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95BD206EDA824491A2A546DDE441C257"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Website and database</header><text>To assist with an individual’s move from the job guarantee to other employment opportunities under a National Employment Corps, the Secretary shall establish a website and database listing individuals employed under the program as available for, and seeking, employment. Individuals shall be allowed up to one day (8 hours) per employed month to seek alternative employment and for professional development.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2CFF1F70510E444C994C6EC6F22F5530"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination of local efforts</header><text>Any local or Tribal government that receives a grant shall develop employment proposals in coordination with community leaders, labor organizations, and local residents to ensure the proposals will serve the needs of the constituents and available pool of labor. The employment proposals may not be used to employ individuals who will replace or speed the displacement of existing employees or individuals who would otherwise perform similar work.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8207BAD5389C49E2BB3B36FB6305E8AF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Employment protections</header> <paragraph id="HC33F1B4FAFAE4BA8A6DB7EA1B58EF909"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collective bargaining units</header><text>Participants shall be included in an established bargaining unit and covered by any applicable collective bargaining agreement upon the establishment of such agreement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1226C16561DE41CD8BC0204A849403F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wages under the program</header><text>Wage variation shall be built into the program, as determined by the Secretary of Labor, to account for workers’ previous experience, education, and region of residence, as well as the prospect of promotion within the National Employment Corps.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C2205DD34B34E40A5D3EBE31C80F896"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Website</header><text>To manage projects past, present, and future, the National Employment Corps shall create a website where all projects will be listed.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H48F89D6A73A840F0944D8B783C13CD8B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minimum wage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual employed using funds under this section shall be paid wages at a rate that is not less than $15.00 per hour and that are comparable to wages in the region, plus benefits, and indexed for inflation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0AA61DB44CD94CD9B627C34484BE6035"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Apprenticeship defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>apprenticeship</quote> means an apprenticeship program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>) (50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), including any requirement, standard, or rule promulgated under such Act, as such requirement, standard, or rule was in effect on December 30, 2019.</text></subsection></section></title>
</legis-body>
</bill>


