<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KAT26352-0XC-7C-4V9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4869 IS: Indigenous Students Excel through Parity Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4869</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIA00">Committee on Indian Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve the Indian School Equalization Formula of the Bureau of Indian Education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Indigenous Students Excel through Parity Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id796E0BCA483E470D8DA436EEDCAF3580"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are to study—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ada1dea19694a668f566bc3b982bd11"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the resources that Bureau-funded schools need to provide competitive salaries and benefits to recruit and retain high-quality teachers, administrators, and all school staff;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id239674605a55479eb924761683201dd1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>funding and other resources needed by the Bureau of Indian Education to ensure that students attending Bureau-funded schools receive a high-quality education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc99d6bd957fb4db7a627c94123de39ae"><enum>(3)</enum><text>potential revenue sources to bring Bureau of Indian Education funding, resources, and salaries into parity with other school systems.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id9458798EA470450284949731AC924BB4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idAAA496CBF2E54EF79EE2E7163958DAFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id08FF67E929974AFE8CBBDC04A30FF0AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau-funded school</header><text>The term <term>Bureau-funded school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1141 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2021">25 U.S.C. 2021</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1C44AEEE9A5F467295041EE80BFFE7CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian School Equalization Formula</header><text>The term <term>Indian School Equalization Formula</term> means the Indian School Equalization Formula described in subparts B and C of part 39 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF8C5EE0F6C144543887AF338CE5D0D3A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian School Equalization Program</header><text>The term <term>Indian School Equalization Program</term> means the Indian School Equalization Program described in part 39 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95FF8D68C34F4E739CC4F74D7756D7E6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or other community included on the most recent list published by the Secretary under section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5DFD3D1CA87C4BCA98A4905549B02B10"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id15C20740EA2D4AD0871CAF7C0AA0332A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Tribally controlled school</header><text>The term <term>tribally controlled school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5212 of the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2511">25 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id0611C41591434492ABEB65B3885341A6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Indian School Equalization Formula study</header><subsection id="id1C4B432A5CC947DFB5F8C996C35A0438"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d3f2132c5d24710bac8228f13a894d7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and in accordance with paragraph (3), the Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary and the Director of the Bureau of Indian Education, shall carry out a study relating to updating the Indian School Equalization Formula, including by completing the process of developing alternative methods for the equitable distribution of the Indian School Equalization Formula, with consideration given to the factors described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b1b55fcd5ac4de386a59c88ac820249"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors described</header><text>The factors referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="idD86DC60C342648CF8B5F340E1D0159EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Ensuring that the Indian School Equalization Formula provides sufficient funding to adequately fund Bureau-funded schools, including—</text><clause id="idFCE4A3F6F98B4DE9AAFB89D2B4FB7B27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>schools operated by the Bureau of Indian Education; and</text></clause><clause id="idD1EFAAE77FF74260B28879C767AAF851"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>tribally controlled schools.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9fd6b8e812704851b522b629fcfd8535"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The highest rate of basic compensation, which shall be equal to the higher of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30566BDDEF004B93959464C499BF8EE4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the highest quartile or average State-by-State salaries for school teachers, principals, other leadership positions, and all school staff at public schools that are not Bureau-funded schools; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB947EB2811714D8EA0BF91585C99357A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rate of basic compensation for teacher and teaching positions in the Department of Defense as determined under the Defense Department Overseas Teachers Pay and Personnel Practices Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/901">20 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD8EE96379FD044BCA5B874C9C700DA04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In carrying out the study of the Indian School Equalization Formula under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8EFF435243944ADEA85FECE752D93A4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that an updated Indian School Equalization Formula provides sufficient funding to fully support salaries for school teachers, principals, other leadership positions, and all school staff at a rate commensurate with salaries of non-Bureau of Indian Education teachers, principals, other leadership positions, and all school staff described in clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (2)(B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFE8EC09FAE47408FAC45D5FAA052C276"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider the weights or ratios related to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13AB2325CA544B138F84DDE184E7D546"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tribally controlled schools;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id833C549C2C9E4F779908DBEB762E52C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>schools with fewer than 100 students; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93455256EC8B452CB7042C7C1F568612"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>schools located in rural areas; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA4A7B57DC78A445BB8538C02054C3329"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that, in an updated Indian School Equalization Formula, that Havasupai Elementary School is awarded an additional cost factor of 12.5 Weighted Student Unit (as defined in section 39.2 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7FC0C6D3358641639FCFD7DEB3C63ED4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary and the Director of the Bureau of Indian Education, and in consultation with national organizations representing Indian Tribes and students attending Bureau-funded schools, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available to Indian Tribes a report describing—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id614c629d7acd4c8fb9e9fb40e24f64bd"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the adequacy of the Indian School Equalization Formula and the Indian School Equalization Program in fulfilling the needs of Bureau-funded schools and tribally controlled schools; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebf0dda41d424ddeab56c6424700e389"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for increasing or modifying factors to improve the Indian School Equalization Formula.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id602d2c5d24c848e9b49a5e127872f905"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study of revenue resources</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb46f10615c945f3a4613f29ea7b708f"><enum/><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary and the Director of the Bureau of Indian Education, shall carry out a study to identify potential revenue sources to bring Bureau-funded schools into parity with other schools.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

