<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H21E99B163002457D81E335931FB5ADF2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7635 IH: Countering Harmful Adversarial Rechargeable and Generative Energy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7635</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the importation of certain energy storage systems made by entities within the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H572E682FE1DB4BC29175D44A29F5086E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC680D66A340741348AA22A8374CCB9DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Harmful Adversarial Rechargeable and Generative Energy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CHARGE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HAE544E252FC0475BA45C7439291B1333"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HD6E85D12C5A3432E8418AE166C4AB6C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People’s Republic of China (PRC) presents an incredible risk in infiltrating the energy grid of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H719B7F179A7744BBAA79B4CA5FE9DE9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Energy storage systems manufactured in the PRC, and imported to the United States, are capable of containing remote monitoring capabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA97023F9DEEC4FC7910D886765590EDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such remote monitoring capabilities give the PRC unfiltered access to the electric grid of the United States, and such backdoor affords the PRC the capability to interfere with the reliability of our critical infrastructure systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF993FAECAF3419AAF8DF977B63083D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce, through the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, is responsible for ensuring that import and export control mechanisms are in accordance with strengthening the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CCB05D53CC94988A022F6D2288603C6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Restricting the import of energy storage systems containing remote monitoring capabilities is necessary to protect the energy grid of the United States and safeguard the American people.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5948D559362C46ABADC9A85107C36ACF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition</header> 
<subsection id="HE5E114A1238A48A6A4E35FD10C044112"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person may import, or cause to be imported to the United States, any energy storage system containing remote monitoring capabilities manufactured with technology licensed or owned by—</text> <paragraph id="HAD7A38122A224531BEF9DC4D7F8BA4A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity organized under the laws of the People’s Republic of China (PRC) or any jurisdiction within the PRC; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7C8F208747248A99514F34D3C8E530B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any entity under the jurisdiction, control, authority, or oversight of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA83B1E1765984D6F80040A6D7D156CB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header> <paragraph id="H36CA67C87ED74FD683E0ED72FF309E8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CBP enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall issue regulations to carry out this section, including by establishing mechanisms to allow U.S. Customs and Border Protection to identify products covered under such prohibition and enforce the prohibition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC52F13C5C762496CB05119CE5F1E9AD0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall review and determine whether to impose additional restrictions concerning energy storage systems containing remote monitoring capabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA1E822C25DA0427B86F799160D48685E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever knowingly violates, or causes a violation of, the prohibition under subsection (a) shall be imprisoned for not more than 5 years, fined not more than $250,000, or both, for each shipment of imports that contains one or more such articles.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE1FB9765C07F40D8A1D61D3CC0EC5E66"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report on implementation</header> 
<paragraph id="HFA55FAA6156546A289EE2C9826B51282"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on PRC-developed energy storage systems containing remote monitoring capabilities in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC589AA6E03C945419B19D996FD622D05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FF18F0450B24DCD9E3580476920CFED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The requirement to submit reports under paragraph (1) shall terminate on the date that is 6 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H45A6EE0ADF344076B96EF7F09C877C2F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF9C7E139EADF44FB89D887B8269968D8">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H43365B2B0E82420EAA56ABB518802552">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H206F8B9E4B074996865173473E80E2F7">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, &amp; Transportation, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9BC772A7AC14303858D496AD93B680E">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>energy storage system</quote> means any device, module, or product that is capable of storing an electric current to discharge such current for use at a later time; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25E28635C04B4A7AA3EB1502DC1F9C04">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>remote monitoring capability</quote> means any device that is capable of observing, collecting, analyzing, and disrupting the data of any information technology, communication, or critical infrastructure system.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

