<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HC4B518E7B10744A5B61297E8916A9E48" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1117 IH: Expressing support for the designation of March as “Multiple System Atrophy Awareness Month” to strengthen public awareness of this neurodegenerative disorder.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1117</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of March as <quote>Multiple System Atrophy Awareness Month</quote> to strengthen public awareness of this neurodegenerative disorder.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Multiple System Atrophy is a rare and often fatal neurodegenerative disorder that affects 25,000–75,000 people in the United States each year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas individuals diagnosed with Multiple System Atrophy have trouble walking, eating, and speaking;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Multiple System Atrophy is often fatal and causes difficulty breathing, infections, or blood clots in the lungs;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the cause of Multiple System Atrophy is unknown, including the degree to which genetics or environmental factors influence the disorder;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Multiple System Atrophy is often misdiagnosed as Parkinson’s disease or progressive supranuclear palsy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there is no known cure or treatment for Multiple System Atrophy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a lack of awareness of Multiple System Atrophy hinders research efforts and contributes to misdiagnoses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas groundbreaking scientific research is strengthening understanding of the disease and getting closer to the development of therapeutics and treatments for Multiple System Atrophy, such as at the Multiple System Atrophy Center of Excellence at Stanford School of Medicine; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas public support and greater awareness of Multiple System Atrophy, as well as investments in research, can promote a better understanding of the disease and facilitate progress towards a cure: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H897DEDAEA3CC484484045200C77BBBEF"> <section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC4B518E7B10744A5B61297E8916A9E41"><text>That the House of Representatives supports the designation of <quote>Multiple System Atrophy Awareness Month</quote> to strengthen public awareness of this neurodegenerative disorder and supports funding for research related to Multiple System Atrophy in hopes of developing therapeutics and treatments.</text></section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution> 


