<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF00CAC6B67D442519AFF9D23A5B84A73" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1314 IH: America 250 Commemorative Flag Act.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1314</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Z000018">Mr. Zinke</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">America 250 Commemorative Flag Act.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, during this year of recognition of the Semiquincentennial of the United States of America, it is appropriate that Americans reflect upon the providential vision of our founders, to form a government whose primary role is not to rule over its citizens, but to protect their rights endowed to them by God—a new form of government which derives its limited powers from the consent of the people;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, from the very beginning, our nation has held a firm reliance on the protection of divine providence and many have dedicated their lives, their fortunes, and their sacred honor to preserve and defend our liberties;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, the establishment and preservation of our freedom and independence has required significant sacrifice, and the blood of generations of patriots has stained the soil of battlefields across the world as evidence to their unwavering commitment to defend life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, the most iconic and internationally recognized national symbol is the flag of the United States of America. Wherever the stars and stripes fly around the world, it conveys a commitment to freedom, independence, justice, and liberty;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, throughout our two hundred and fifty years as a free and independent nation, our flag has been a consistent beacon of hope, strength, courage, and fortitude;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, across the world, the flag of the United States flies over battlefields where brave Americans fought in defense of freedom. In honor of their sacrifice, it stands tall above the final resting place of those who have given their last full measure of devotion. It waves proudly over our local, state, and federal institutions of government, and it can be seen hoisted above our embassies across the world. As a testament to American exceptionalism, six American flags have stood proudly on the surface of the moon, an accomplishment unique to the United States of America. It flies over small and large businesses, declaring our freedom to engage in commerce, and is worn on the uniforms of our soldiers, sailors, airmen, guardians, coast guardsmen, law enforcement, and first responders; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in this two hundred fiftieth year of our independence, the America 250 flag, which is a representation of the first flag of our nation with the number 250 emblazoned inside the circle of thirteen stars, has been commissioned to celebrate two hundred and fifty years since the passing of the Declaration of Independence.</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAF6A7ECEF76A4C68A361C9C930CB962C"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC7101626B05D49D8B8AC13232F47A17C"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That in celebration of our Semiquincentennial, the America 250 flag is recognized as an official flag of the United States, and during this year of celebration it is authorized to be flown alongside the Star Spangled Banner and POW/MIA flags worldwide over all government buildings, embassies, and official U.S. locations as a testament to the 250th anniversary of our great nation, the United States of America.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

