<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25L23-NDN-9P-234"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3447 IS: Fortifying United States Markets Against PRC Military Escalation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3447</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to establish an advisory committee on economic impacts of military escalation by the People's Republic of China toward Taiwan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fortifying United States Markets Against PRC Military Escalation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf3c2b0cef7694b2f907c7fd96c40d951"><enum>2.</enum><header>Advisory committee on economic impacts of military escalation by the People's Republic of China toward Taiwan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 111 of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5321">12 U.S.C. 5321</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda59838eaed54d8ba89736a5bc10715f"><subsection id="id3ad37693b79c4a65a1cb309a033a797e"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><paragraph id="id5427eb52db60485b9dbc1466a52cc4f5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established, to advise the Financial Stability Oversight Council, an Advisory Committee on Economic Impacts of Military Escalation by the People's Republic of China toward Taiwan (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>) to—</text><subparagraph id="idef8782aba2dc48a88ec859a6cec38170"><enum>(A)</enum><text>study and report on the market implications and vulnerabilities related to military escalation by the People's Republic of China toward Taiwan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73dee4f0c2b94b03a44db662223a975a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>open lines of communication between policy makers, government agencies, and capital market constituents to prepare for a potential response to, and to mitigate economic strain and market volatility related to, any such escalation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ca27f58244246a0afb31aa4897efc6d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><subparagraph id="id1eccdc8cd61344c9a98749141e3dd01f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall consist of—</text><clause id="id25fd0e0153f4470ebd14490f1f19efd9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a designee of the Securities and Exchange Commission;</text></clause><clause id="idfe0df67f03d146f3980f8ecfa3d39bbf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a designee of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission;</text></clause><clause id="id6226fe4fc95644bd9bf5a4a3fc73ec9d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a designee of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; and</text></clause><clause id="idd43a40dd8da94c7e9e49e02996bdb030"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>10 members to be appointed by the chairperson of the Advisory Committee from among persons who are—</text><subclause id="ida732da3fa415413a8a5d9e31daafc79e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>nongovernmental participants in capital markets, including market makers, banks, asset managers, exchanges, and institutional investors; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id919265e9dcb74c559a9573e920eaf84f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>experts on geopolitical risk related to the People's Republic of China.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3543f7d2305047b2958aedef0c189a64"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall serve as the chairperson of the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2df9654f1d184ea28be61ed8496efb6e"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Private sector lead</header><text>One of the members appointed under subparagraph (A)(iv) shall serve as the private sector lead for the Advisory Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4fd5fe721df49f9986629d5cffbc785"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall meet in person at least 2 times per year, with additional meetings at the call of the chairperson.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf46af79589e04dccb1b473a7c118af28"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Study and recommendations</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and every 3 years thereafter, the Advisory Committee shall—</text><subparagraph id="ide43c4e2f6d73476b9f59850d215e952d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a study of the vulnerabilities of the United States economy, markets, and the financial system related to military escalation of the People’s Republic of China toward Taiwan that includes an assessment of—</text><clause id="idf59de80908e2491485d95eb650e2ba79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the estimated total cost to the United States economy from such escalation;</text></clause><clause id="idea9033c67810473786e7c59b748882e4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the market impacts and potential losses faced by United States and global markets related to such escalation;</text></clause><clause id="idd7b7430276264a6288fae863773efd64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the capacity of United States markets to deal with volatility that could result from such escalation;</text></clause><clause id="idf799620f1cff4005b9e5964c8db32ccc"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the impact of such escalation on securities issued by entities organized under the laws of the People’s Republic of China or Taiwan and listed on a national securities exchange in the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="idf1beecc58d634eb3b61cb208348026a3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the likelihood and potential impact of reductions in holdings by the People's Republic of China of debt securities issued by the Department of the Treasury;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id742471fc939646e4871a38b4cfaf85d9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop and submit to the Council recommendations and supporting analysis based on the results of the study;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b0de309b4f844c6834c4ab196798707"><enum>(C)</enum><text>brief Congress and the Secretary of State on the study conducted under subparagraph (A) and the recommendations developed under subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id90df6217e40749aaa0fe278adecc1c63"><enum>(D)</enum><text>hold a public meeting to present the recommendations and analysis required by subparagraph (B), omitting any portions of such recommendations or analysis that implicate national security concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

