<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H625F95B45E494BEEA033D17D2497941E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6041 IH: Rural Partnership and Prosperity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6041</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to provide rural partnership program grants and rural partnership technical assistance grants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA0D1990153444FF1932EB62CA7C6A876" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7196A1C88FB340FD80236E00C06054F9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Partnership and Prosperity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEF970D873D034A29917ADA7F14167019"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H1586DA32F7A34E6198560559AC3F9021"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE379E816A5EB48B48C58DD0101804B21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rural; rural area</header><text>The terms <term>rural</term> and <term>rural area</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 343(a)(13)(A) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1991">7 U.S.C. 1991(a)(13)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A7CB494749940CBAE6CAC584EA455FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1B9804F0A3241798AB15A9F9F3E4680"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural partnership program grants</header> <subsection id="HFEED67B75B024A9DB003C6D532A217C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations under subsection (j), the Secretary shall establish a program to make multiyear grant awards to coordinate Federal, nonprofit, and for-profit investment in rural areas.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD6A1ED0465E14D338F842B18D9E5FA3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant requirements</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3A9CBCD880C4822BF97C826F6E30320"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a grant awarded under subsection (a) shall be not less than 2 years and not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75F4CFAFBAED48E5BD8D3207C6172C93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Awards</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), the State offices of the rural development mission area shall be responsible for reviewing applications for grant awards under subsection (a) and selecting eligible applicants described in subsection (d) for those grant awards.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8404B85C26AC46BCBC9783E1B09A8F86"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribal awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (4), in the case of grants under subsection (a) allocated to Indian Tribes under subsection (c)(1)(B), the national office of the rural development mission area shall be responsible for reviewing applications for grant awards under subsection (a) and selecting eligible applicants described in subsection (d) for those grant awards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD93A5B79DBE4FB5A76D20BD48B6828C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Competitive process</header><text>If the amount appropriated under subsection (j) for a fiscal year is less than or equal to $300,000,000, the national office of the rural development mission area shall be responsible for reviewing applications for grant awards under subsection (a) and selecting eligible applicants described in subsection (d) for those grant awards—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1AB14403E63F4D93A0D5EBF34E3EE0BD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on a competitive basis; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE471F9054B1042319E3DF8116884FFFD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by giving priority to areas that have higher nonmetropolitan poverty levels and lower population levels, while ensuring that grants under this section are awarded in diverse geographic regions of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2819EA0945FA471EBE86139DB3A18D11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant allocation</header>
<paragraph id="H07DCD41D1F94413AB04AF0C134F4F0F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b)(4), the Secretary shall allocate funding for grants under subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H288265B3F4C34A8DB067E77E0570B555"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each State based on a formula determined by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0A8ADE472DA443DFAB52997EE3FBE233"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for Indian Tribes in such amounts as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, subject to the condition that the total amount allocated to Indian Tribes under this subparagraph shall not be less than 5 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (j), with Indian Tribes located in areas that have higher poverty levels and lower populations receiving higher levels of funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC5A91EB9371479CAED1022434B822B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation requirements</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2E8F95A0F8F4BFAB58AF114A3A40714"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop a graduated scale to allocate funding for States under paragraph (1)(A) based on the nonmetropolitan poverty and population levels in each State.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H23A17F326E074251BF3E94F7922D7BDD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount allocated to any State under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed 5 percent of the amount appropriated under subsection (j).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4085A279476E43F59A3B1C061FDBD3BF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Small State exception to formula</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (1)(A) and (2)(A), the Secretary shall ensure that each State is allocated an amount for grants under this subsection that is sufficient to fulfill the purposes of the program established under this section, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H79D9C6F77D224E23BA2A9346D995E584"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>If a State or Indian Tribe does not use funds allocated to the State or Indian Tribe under this subsection, the Secretary may reallocate the unused funds to 1 or more other States or Indian Tribes, each of which has used all of the funding allocated to the State or Indian Tribe under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4FEC19B435E3491EB587CB6A5DF0ADD7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), an applicant shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H0474E227F4D043DE99F2350DE70DCAC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>propose to serve a rural area;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBBFD47E678149988894317ED7CDFF04" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be composed of a partnership of 2 or more of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H063C6C34F7164F809A2B5D3C4D773B88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an instrumentality or political subdivision of a State, such as a municipality, county, district, or authority;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CEA44167BC34A4AA9F29F49FC5860CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit corporation or association with significant ties to the rural area described in paragraph (1), including through—</text>
<clause id="HFCF4F82FD3DF468D8106DD877FC890DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>association with, or control by, 1 or more public bodies in the rural area;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78E18EC98D06400EBE4F5C4A467467B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">broadly based ownership and control by members of the rural area; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H598EB3424A3B463490E450F0E2CA7314"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a substantial public funding contribution to the rural area through taxes, revenue bonds, other local government sources, or substantial voluntary community funding;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F7EE55DC57948AF98FA6DBD0A2783A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a cooperative with significant ties to the rural area described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H63651A4DE1504E9B951E9F912993C76E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a for-profit entity with a significant presence in the rural area described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43587467661E4B5B870B867B26D1B1F3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an institution of higher education—</text>
<clause id="H8AE71F18A6064FE7A37F76A8E4224850"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a significant contribution to or presence in the rural area described in paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="H020A62CEC0FE4FE286E678E59D94DA81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that includes representatives who are members of the rural area; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H437229032D074EA9BEAC90FB67A31BB3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE48F6875768F4666BFC33AF1DDF42EDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a rural area described in paragraph (1); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9ABF20AF1C474BAE99DB71208871EB13" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with demonstrated support from the Tribal council or duly elected Tribal executive of the appropriate Tribal government; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H339BBD6517D24246B4B9593ACDB3FD77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demonstrate cooperation among the members of the partnership described in paragraph (2) necessary to complete comprehensive, asset-based rural development through eligible activities described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H12E5F4E8418941F19BB2440271184499"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>An eligible applicant described in subsection (d) that receives a grant under subsection (a) may use the grant funds in rural areas—</text> <paragraph id="H41D11C21A19E47B8A6686559283C8D53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to coordinate Federal, State, regional, or Tribal initiatives to reduce duplicative efforts with respect to Federal investments;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA601918B945746A087620381D7C90949"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to leverage non-Federal financial and technical resources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2493FC3EDBF431397149FFCF83E60E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to complete comprehensive predevelopment activities and planning;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0D8841466F474A969952AC24639DB0C3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to create public-private partnerships and attract private investment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05B700491D4A48CBB165D0CF5A9B6CEE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to support eligible operational activities, including staffing, of the eligible applicants, except that a for-profit entity may not use the grant funds for the purpose described in this paragraph;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9C38D7F9E7C441FBBF03CFAB47E06758"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to provide capital to existing or new projects, subject to the condition that not more than 50 percent of the grant funds may be used for that purpose;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FAD4FEBFDD74028B40808650FB8F15C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to support regional projects and initiatives;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB06A0B97C6F24425AA6B824A36AC7552"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to address economic recovery from emergencies and natural or man-made disasters; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5A53DC363D24FCEB6E01D4E5D77E157"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to develop strategic community investment plans described in section 379H(d) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2008v">7 U.S.C. 2008v(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB99AFC0CCA5745929A6AD1CAB84D41E3" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Ineligible activities</header><text>An eligible applicant described in subsection (d) that receives a grant under subsection (a) may not use the grant funds—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5407EBACA504952A758CE854D5D76E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fund operational activities, including staffing, at a for-profit institution;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD4C57EE284E04BD883EC9ED01B9881A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to purchase or lease real property; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48C4E7B17FF34CA2A368555A826FE2DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support a non-rural area.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA90464E6C54A4549A63EC608AD8A604D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (b), the Secretary shall give priority to an eligible applicant described in subsection (d) that proposes to serve—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10D0FFB69E144F489E8A6D26683CD714"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a rural area with a significant change in population;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E1633F288F14E748349F3429FE85A92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a rural area with significant workforce changes or changes in major employers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3C303925A6A4BB0B4119C59704BB61D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an economically distressed rural area, as determined by the Secretary;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA496B63564284EE68335FE4390C6BAD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a rural area that has historically received minimal Federal funding, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCEBD232EF4047FDA0255D41FE835798"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a rural area for the purpose of job retention and economic stabilization, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2069393FACD24CEEBBA488AC19F8EFFE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Matching funds</header>
<paragraph id="HB1CDE4E166D242E88445D14A45FC3379"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), an eligible applicant described in subsection (d) that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall provide non-Federal matching funds in the form of cash or an in-kind contribution in an amount that is not less than 25 percent of the amount of the grant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA5A73672C290428F9B11DD9B9330C2FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA36918977D7243F891065C739D503A61"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the requirement under paragraph (1) based on the demonstrated need of the eligible applicant or the population served by the eligible applicant, as determined by the Secretary, including—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF8459DEDFB04E32838F211875790F36"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an eligible applicant serving an area with a higher nonmetropolitan poverty level;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7DFBC30A0564D14869189D01E377462"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an eligible applicant serving a Tribal population; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5F064244358466791A22E6AEA806C21"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an eligible applicant composed of a partnership that includes an entity described in subsection (d)(2)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H320DA2FD86FD4028B089D2F4EE5D4BBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a justification for each waiver provided under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF7046B8E7ED54D4A87DF4D6692B08680"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Providers</header><text>Non-Federal matching funds under paragraph (1) may be provided by any member of the applicable partnership described in subsection (d)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H608D4C04765042CC83B2397E2EA9CDC9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in coordination with the Rural Partners Network established by section 6306 of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2204b-3">7 U.S.C. 2204b–3</external-xref>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE8360F4192D14A8CA750D2B0838CDDD3"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
<paragraph id="H0CA933EF9640417D96460047158BC73D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15FB3ACA4A1848EFB98E3B2E907A33B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary may retain not more than 2 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section for administration of the program established under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H236C6BA7E14C4BD8A0D51B74B8045289"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rural partnership technical assistance grants</header>
<subsection id="HA3CF40BE58A445BCA6763D3B63A2EE6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations under subsection (g), the Secretary shall establish a program to award grants, on a competitive basis, for up to a 5-year period, to be administered at the national level through the Under Secretary for Rural Development, for the purpose of advising on and assisting rural community organizations with—</text> <paragraph id="H0E8714D411614B568A1953F1792887DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal grant management and the development of financial management systems;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFEC2529326654C7090C746E2EA98F5C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>housing or community economic development projects; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H462A0D668FAD48F3905492F69A9EEA30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the development of placemaking plans and applications for Federal grants.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8CD02462376C4A6BA79CF941088029BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), an applicant shall be a qualified private or nonprofit intermediary organization, including an institution of higher education with an existing community development and planning program, including an extension program, that has demonstrated experience and capacity to provide technical assistance on community development and planning in rural areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H34E02C4DBDFA4B8FACE43DAEEB3B5B80"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>An eligible applicant described in subsection (b) that receives a grant under subsection (a) may use the grant funds to support the capacity building and economic development of identified rural areas and local partners in those rural areas through the following activities:</text>
<paragraph id="H8C716F34469C4C5B81D63713D1AB0854"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training and supporting local staff, including relating to systems development and support.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BEA21F2B0124ACAB24EF4EAE62394DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identifying vetted technical consultants for planning and designing physical infrastructure.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59956E35B469490682707AA0B01DEC9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Facilitating coordination between Federal agencies and local partners.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EAAD0714AFA4B738500A67E87899C6F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing expertise on developing public-private partnerships.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A3E40E98A574575AE5097757B3EFFA8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Development and project predevelopment activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5D41ADB42A4047FE90C8B6E5402D0FE7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Grant writing and grant management activities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H44657A21C92442018E23BF930B7F70A7" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Ineligible activities</header><text>An eligible applicant described in subsection (b) that receives a grant under subsection (a) may not use the grant funds—</text> <paragraph id="HA820D1E83DFC46C5984DD47D1C3E06CB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to fund staffing at a for-profit entity;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAD10C873CE30491BB3B3F15602136AF1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to purchase or lease real property, buildings, or equipment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H202D99B2EE49431C8D67679B18F4CEB1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support a non-rural area; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8D9E20B84EA4C208C0BE8FB1B00423F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for research and development.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5972A3E8DF164B398D443B5C0A5554D2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary may give priority to an eligible applicant described in subsection (b) that serves—</text>
<paragraph id="H45481A7B70EC4A7E87535B0058148049"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a nonmetropolitan area with a high poverty level; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC2C8BA4430244C8901171DD385D3AB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe with demonstrated support from the Tribal council or duly elected Tribal executive of the appropriate Tribal government.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAA75A8BA6D724BC9B7CC856B363B790F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Matching funds</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9047D9C103946DC90AC952D4B48F8C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), an eligible applicant described in subsection (b) that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall provide non-Federal matching funds in an amount that is not less than 30 percent of the amount of the grant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AF43C5E469B426486D719A286B07994"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD03CDDD22E8C40F1AA528C3517E78E64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the requirement under paragraph (1) based on the demonstrated need of the area in which activities using the grant are to be carried out, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11D198F742104067BD1887E4F30E9928"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>The Secretary shall provide to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a justification for each waiver provided under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD45CB38432914DFBA7AFC712CDE8D358"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3542DBAE37E4BA282B0012D8BEC9D69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDC3DB8A32E58430193F32E866A7D9E27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary may retain not more than 2 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section for administration of the program established under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EA82CE5B9D04630B542379B2A2E2DBF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rural Partners Network</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6306 of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2204b-3">7 U.S.C. 2204b–3</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA047065523A7413CA8F15CC1E4DA87F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">Council on rural community innovation and economic development</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="section">Rural Partners Network</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63F310F8AF0E493597869D68D8C862A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>council</quote> and inserting <quote>network</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H745DA89E9B734FF5BB9EE892A90FF5BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB6562D967A64E40AD82480E3FAC7220"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84A125E5A2974D23B589CFFE0E92D3C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03F9197D188F4B849D79EA25F88F1C2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>There is established a Rural Partners Network (referred to in this section as the <term>Network</term>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD0BB35EEEF24DE5BEAA20026103B0AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Successor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Network shall be the successor to the Council on Rural Community Innovation and Economic Development established by this section (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Rural Partnership and Prosperity Act</short-title>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA2FCD97284A41D4A9EB951ADF0955AA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC388530217854EB09AF63ECA9307488D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A1152B65CD446598D5F76B29A13C91D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (C), (D), (N), (Q), (R), (S), (T), (V), (X), (Y), and (Z);</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6E7E3E536654F9DBFE86B767B4F5FCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (E) through (M), (O), (P), (U), (W), and (AA) as subparagraphs (C) through (K), (L), (M), (N), (O), and (X), respectively; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF4B84EBE7AC4B9E942C359F80C81C1D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (O) (as so redesignated) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A2CFC16F73449E0AA4A861C044A71CC">
<subparagraph id="H620F6596BDDA43A6A23029B96B0545D1"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H679BB1AC1DAE4025BD8242517452E39C"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>The Appalachian Regional Commission.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAB13FBF095174B068B4E87C89A4ED9E1"><enum>(R)</enum><text>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DA060E0A9974980B265D627564BBB5B"><enum>(S)</enum><text>The Social Security Administration.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6DFA6AC71FFE4E88ADE609DCF2DDCEFD"><enum>(T)</enum><text>The Delta Regional Authority.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E8E970C29BD4578807A50668C3579D0"><enum>(U)</enum><text>The Denali Commission.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H52B265CB24D54DD481A9077353EC0F3A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The Northern Border Regional Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2C70C8A3C0048178F69A7793E911D90"><enum>(W)</enum><text>The Southeast Crescent Regional Commission.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94623E26BE5D424185C4D6A81A5B05F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraphs (2) through (4), by striking <quote>Council</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Network</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1815856CAEFA484D9E76B6EEFD533525"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>Council</quote> and inserting <quote>Network</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5340235F97084133A13404A0913C31BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF54B1B13B2624C1198B69E6F1E6B5CCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">Council</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">Network</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19EB2058B21C4D2DBBAE425B246410EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Council</quote> and inserting <quote>Network</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5349B3BE15DE4BC2B66F2B7AE4A42185"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H884B59EDA62F4E36ADF95E31D02B61A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7457BAC63724E4E9422FBA5027EE281"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CEDC694B3C3421AA8708DF158216AC9">
<paragraph id="H0A2FBC9D9F724C0390A63E72B655F2F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to improve the efficiency of Federal assistance to rural communities by—</text> <subparagraph id="HB31C6BE74DF64C5C9EFB76148D877120"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing administrative burdens on rural communities to pursue Federal funding;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H52DD9BEDB6084E8D932AD0B86F584DBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving the administrative efficiency of Federal economic development programs serving rural communities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H947988FA4E61498483EC04C7CD62964E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>streamlining and simplifying the application process for Federal funding opportunities for rural communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC846CDE15254924B38C31093077DDDE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (f), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Council</quote> and inserting <quote>Network</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D9EE2A34A804BE7BBA4448F5F8971F2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>Council</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Network</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECFFC61F0ABC4C7CB847FAC1AE05BE5C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>by striking subsection (h) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD66E51D561C44E68E9FAA5D0AC1663B"> <subsection id="H7D20B173AFC043A38476F139FE1A4946"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Innovative cross-Agency coordination</header> <paragraph id="HD7218E4B0662463484CC657C25CE128C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting as Chair of the Network, may carry out innovative strategies for coordinating with other Federal departments and agencies with respect to programs that serve rural areas.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H897D380F2D3D437FBBCCCD2948AB91AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prioritize—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB889FD0AA17427F83330C20E889727F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving ease of access to Federal programs for resource-constrained rural communities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HECD7F04CD63B485EACF00C59E153FE85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilizing early technical assistance to reduce duplicative applications and administrative costs at the Federal level;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5D10941A0434E5082385AD6941E95C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>leveraging partnerships with local, State, philanthropic, and private entities to maximize returns on Federal investments;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H905010CB65554A4E8BB02ED0E2123BE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>integrating stakeholder and program user experience into program design; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE68ADFB4C21643A39A0932A8E9DD3235"><enum>(E)</enum><text>targeting areas experiencing economic distress, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

