<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5DD7B8646E0245B3B5B0D8688E395F9A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6631 IH: Establishing Cyber Security Educational Programs at Academic Institutions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6631</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name>Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to establish a program for the development of cybersecurity education at academic institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0E839D3E2E7B4977BEBD3A14B08841C3" style="OLC"><section id="HD0F94042EF0741CA98A96A6432DB3031" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Establishing Cyber Security Educational Programs at Academic Institutions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBEFEDFDFEE0F44B9970C0C7890388603" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collaborative cybersecurity educational program</header><subsection id="H88F5278798E24127B380EC84A7E729BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish and carry out a program under which the Secretary shall seek to collaborate with academic institutions to develop cybersecurity educational programs at such institutions, including by establishing curriculum standards, developing competencies in cybersecurity at such institutions, promoting community outreach regarding participation in such educational programs, integrating best practices across such educational programs, and advancing solutions to challenges in addressing educational needs with respect to cyber.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5CDD290DE0C34EC899B74E18364A7E6D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation requirements</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall—</text><paragraph id="H17237B085B6B46A3ACED4889438F2A34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Director of the National Security Agency, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of the National Science Foundation, to ensure that the cyber education programs and educational resource development efforts and programs of the Federal Government do not compete or conflict with each other;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F4C9B96C45B43A5863B87E7F325ED41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies and representatives of appropriate private sector entities, academic institutions, and other organizations as determined necessary by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE2957EB2CF84238B06148CB4DD13237"><enum>(3)</enum><text>manage instructional and participatory opportunities available through the efforts, programs, initiatives, and investments accounted for in the report required under section 1649 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; 133 Stat. 1758).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1D9175B592347C6B7356CA91F13619C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designations</header><paragraph id="H01C6238290104A6D8A6557765A0FBE82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall designate academic institutions that meet the standards established under such program in one or more of cyber defense, cyber operations, and cyber research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A0C5C5159564471AE38D0853CA9C59E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall make the designations under paragraph (1) based on the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6C9EDC462CE745C7B7B42CDAEE04374C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Academic requirements and best practices identified by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with Departments and Agencies enabling the development of educational programs reflecting the full range of cyber work roles specified in the Defense Cyber Workforce Framework, the National Initiative on Cyber Education Workforce Framework for Cyber published by the National Institute of Standards and Technology in NIST Special Publication 800–181, Revision 5, or any successor framework.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H714A200915AD4598B378CDD72D04CBB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Criteria and requirements for the academic institution emphasizing the following:</text><clause id="HFDAAF1F0A91C420BA6D81F04D6086C59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Outreach to the surrounding community of the academic institution.</text></clause><clause id="HE75EBD96B21E486AAFD9AF7961175C21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Leadership in contributing to the development of a national cyber workforce, including cultivating educational institution faculty and research leaders.</text></clause><clause id="HFBAA26EEECED4804864808D7E363261A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Leadership in the development of educational and performance expectations for cyber professionals, including through curriculum and degree offerings to prepare future cyber professionals of all knowledge and skill levels.</text></clause><clause id="HE9FE2323AAB041D9995262F536723043"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Demonstrated commitment to implementing cyber best practices within the academic institution across academic disciplines.</text></clause><clause id="H1C90A4DD41BA48E7A86ED9A35772291B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Demonstrated commitment to seeking solutions to challenges in addressing Federal, State, local, territorial, and Tribal-level needs.</text></clause><clause id="H463E50A5D94D4ED9BFAC7143265AC7CA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Regional accreditation from one of the six regional accrediting agencies recognized by the Department of Education providing external review to assure quality and ongoing improvement.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49C2D7DCFE1242BEB1D696EB79E094CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Increasing collaboration within the cyber education community to support development and sharing of educational materials and curriculum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80333610CD054092B4A00D0CDDDF6B93"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Increasing collaboration with private sector entities and government employers at the Federal, State, local, territorial, and Tribal levels to further define workforce requirements and assist in defining academic requirements to prepare students for the field of cyber.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B53E71E3AE64D2090A71188D6B1AF4A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Metrics and report</header><paragraph id="HF6699EE993C84B85BB2D1B745197BF13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Metrics</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD4F73D6C4CEE48CBAF2E8C3CF5187C73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collaborate with the individuals described in subsection (b)(1) to identify metrics and annual data reporting requirements necessary to assess the degree to which the program established under subsection (a) is meeting the objectives of such program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB990EF89AA14F42B0083E87BF5BDFF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure adequate data and best practices are made available to the individuals described in subsection (b)(1) to measure the efficacy of such program and the benefits provided by such program to individuals participating in such program and to the Department of Defense compared to costs of such program paid by academic institutions participating in such program and sponsors of such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CB6832C66614283B19574811FF40494"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on the benefits provided by the program established under subsection (a) to individuals participating in such program and to the Department compared to costs of such program paid by academic institutions participating in such program and sponsors of such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC45BABE8AEE473DA00D3A56BA70BAC6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="HB34584CD620E43D6BE72963A3A2B79F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supersede the statutory responsibilities or authorities of any head of a departments or agencies of the Federal Government; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C5CBAB4DC3349F9A364298B95D104A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>authorize the appropriation of additional amounts for the program established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H154767711045406AB041FC51338DAB6E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Academic institution defined</header><text>The term <term>academic institution</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HF1C8F7CFB7484FA6854793CC5D1B2D63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) in the United States that conducts research sponsored by the Department of Defense; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CC22816DD7A451EB2EB448DF953D119"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a senior military college (as defined in section 2111a(f) of title 10, United States Code).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

