<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0438DBFE66E41C88E543C350791428A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9596 IH: Federal Jobs for STARs Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9596</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260706">July 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To remove educational barriers to Federal employment for workers who are skilled through alternative routes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA2A2294742A74B519CDC611A0B531685" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H50F58DB4153D4A55881DC75530B51DAF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Jobs for STARs Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H2265B08B47904FFBAC68D9A9B858BDBB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HB0EFEE14D4E840E2A3A0FDBC765D79EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>employee</term> means an individual appointed to a position in the civil service (as defined in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code) in an executive agency;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4195FA28E9F54F86A469D5262E1D32AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>executive agency</term> means a department, agency, office, or other establishment in the executive branch of the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE06CE0CD58284268839902E41A5177E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>STAR</term> means an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H740D3EE84AAD4B64AA9E3DE580DC4C0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is active in the labor force;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAB5E8A3623C43D3A4E00C545B66B2B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has not obtained a bachelor’s degree or a higher degree; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F4A157073534B61B9F1B6E6D654B3F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has developed job-related skills through alternative routes, which may include at a community college, in an apprenticeship, through a bootcamp, through military service, through partial college completion, in other training programs, or through on-the-job experience.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H4721774B1A18458580A946E21D0934D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transparency and directives on educational requirements for Federal public sector jobs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To improve transparency and directives related to educational requirements for positions in executive agencies, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0AA93605084E40019A7017ACFD5CD6A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibit the head of an executive agency from requiring a minimum educational attainment as qualification for a position as an employee of the executive agency, unless the Director of the Office of Personnel Management determines that such educational attainment is necessary for the position based on specified skills required for the position that can only be obtained through a certain degree;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AF433B1766A4E0DB5833E07101F8750"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prescribe regulations for hiring of employees by executive agencies regarding alternative qualifications to educational attainment that would meet the knowledge, skills, and abilities requirements for a position;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81CEBA3B3AC140D186DAACD4D78C2E3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review the addition of educational requirements for employees during audits of hiring actions within executive agencies; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FE76E0B886F42B79E2142BFD0098BB9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish a hiring path dedicated to positions for which STAR workers are eligible to apply within usajobs.gov, or any successor website, and direct executive agencies to identify job postings that are within that hiring path, so that STAR workers may search for positions based on this criterion.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDA33D9716528436786A6596A3D61E297"><enum>4.</enum><header>Feasibility study on training programs for stars</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Personnel Management, the Deputy Director for Management of the Office of Management and Budget, and the head of any other appropriate executive agency shall jointly—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB629BD0FBCBA41338895C33A22D28206"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a feasibility study regarding resources required to establish a program to provide STAR employees with pathways for acquiring further training and higher education, including fellowships, scholarships, apprenticeships, and tuition assistance, if the employee chooses to initiate or continue pursuit of further training or higher education while an employee; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0620B674D864BB8BE1FAD86273C25F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit a report on the findings of the feasibility study to—</text> <subparagraph id="H31926472F0E34314B30E514403D284FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAB1379C39AD45939D7AF81DF32C4275"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

