<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3B9D91D2D1B148CD9266B23B3AA754A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8733 IH: Melanie's Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8733</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to establish a grant program to support protective orders that protect individuals who are related by blood or marriage to individuals in intimate relationships, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H98674084A20F42B285BB895D362C9CE2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H71C66BCEA6A748E383039CE9D4D184FE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Melanie's Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3C3885DD4EB2430E87999C3ADF0EB502"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program to support protective orders that protect individuals who are related by blood or marriage to individuals in intimate relationships</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79B84DF2D3D94E8C911F5E20937EE7DB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<part id="H001630B03A1F43118AC91F557CE20D0B"><enum>PP</enum><header>MELANIE’S LAW: GRANT PROGRAM TO SUPPORT PROTECTIVE ORDERS THAT PROTECT INDIVIDUALS RELATED BY BLOOD OR MARRIAGE TO INDIVIDUALS IN INTIMATE RELATIONSHIPS</header> 
<section id="H20CA40F027FB436CA5E18441AE407C3F"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Purpose; definition of Melanie’s Law protective order authorities</header> 
<subsection id="HB37897C932914B12B92C1794D629F58F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this part is to support States to implement the Melanie’s Law protective order authorities and carry out related activities involving protective orders and domestic violence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H38879B55AD954D81A277A16CBE0481CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of Melanie’s Law protective order authorities</header><text>In this part, the term <quote>Melanie’s Law protective order authorities</quote> means laws that ensure that family courts and criminal courts, as applicable, have each of the following authorities:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF2F661CED0294EB1B6E55EC04B6558B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The jurisdiction and authority to issue and enforce a protective order that protects one individual from another, where the two individuals—</text> <subparagraph id="HC1495C19780148378AE9124FF767DABF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are related by consanguinity or affinity;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52DE3787F84549EDA402FBE855764C42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are legally married to each other;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF49157D2954C497CB0F7F85F8A6AC422"><enum>(C)</enum><text>were formerly married to each other, regardless of whether the individuals still reside in the same household;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7BD1149CA9744A609E342A1915B0EDE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>have a child in common, regardless of whether the individuals have been married or have lived together at any time; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF53EAC7E01D34664AD939DEF1604DBC0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>are or have been in an intimate relationship with each other.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FE2ED8FC1EE460F8BC82A73845DD824"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In a situation in which two individuals are or have been in an intimate relationship with each other, the jurisdiction and authority to issue and enforce a protective order that protects a third individual, regardless of age, where that third individual is related by consanguinity or affinity to either of the two individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEE9569069F4C410BB5C2B044CF8FC833"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Grants</header> <subsection id="H2FC06462DE3A4924B2BA1B26E5F74ED0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Attorney General may make grants to eligible States for the following purposes:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC5F876A69EC41E5810C838BC9947DD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To provide education and training to law enforcement officers, prosecutors, and courts on the Melanie’s Law protective order authorities and the implementation of those authorities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H367192B9DA8E45E499DF5F9267009989"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To facilitate the service of process of protective orders, such as by enabling or improving service of process—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB5DEC4B133F34688BB0C289A8C3C687D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in person or by electronic means; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H24476B000E884CF68B374106CE9DE69D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>across State, Tribal, or local jurisdictional lines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3749CDC1E9024E86B70853E977D5A74B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To establish or enhance—</text> <subparagraph id="H1679D82448394F42B719FDA7072DC385"><enum>(A)</enum><text>systems that manage and track information about protective orders and violations of protective orders, such as systems operated by law enforcement agencies or courts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32CD709898EB43D79ABBBB58ED7B2EBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mechanisms for the sharing of such information between and among such systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07B8435665674820B55CC27F291A45F1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To support official units or positions that have specialized responsibilities with respect to protective orders or domestic violence, such as to enforce or promote compliance, to prosecute violations, or to coordinate with others on such matters.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FD79BCB36DD432295596FC56FC7D177"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To enable or improve the provision to victims in matters involving protective orders of—</text> <subparagraph id="H34637B991CD14F4EBE359BFAEA34BC7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">civil legal services, to help such victims obtain, modify, and enforce protective orders or to represent such victims in related matters involving immigration or custody;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BEBE9CDF8A444A9AEE9DEBC26C0D05C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>victim advocacy services, hotline services, and crisis response services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H495BF9F5ABBB4D06B55F2D6146D75396"><enum>(C)</enum><text>emergency shelter services, relocation assistance, transportation assistance, childcare assistance, and short-term housing assistance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80E6527CAC19415385E37C7E346EAEFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>access to counseling, trauma-informed therapy, and case management; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC0C5D9A1DAF4212B5339341EDD4488A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>access to communications equipment and services for personal safety and for participation in hearings or other official proceedings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD35CE2519C8648C89C73C21304AEE3DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for grants under this section, a State must have in effect, and must certify that it has in effect, the Melanie’s Law protective order authorities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA9FC4BD7639543DDBF39B883F3B82164"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grant amounts</header><text>Upon request of an eligible State, the Attorney General may permit the State to use grant amounts under this part to provide the non-Federal share of the cost of programs or projects funded by other grant programs administered by the Attorney General that provide support or services to victims.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6639CF3EA98047A49E110C5BA26A3F81"><enum>3063.</enum><header>Applications</header> 
<subsection id="H681C430F93AA49739817C317D2E0E670"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To request a grant under this part, the chief executive of a State shall submit an application to the Attorney General in such form and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require. Such application shall include assurances that Federal funds received under this part shall be used to supplement, not supplant, non-Federal funds that would otherwise be available for activities funded under this part, except as provided in section 3062(c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7D6F0B62D94741BFB72DB1F76521C9E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such application shall include an implementation plan describing how the funds will be used, what performance measures will be applied, and how the State will coordinate and partner with the relevant elements of the justice system, judicial system, and victims services system.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB324F319C42745E1921AAEE737B174E0"><enum>3064.</enum><header>Allocations</header> 
<subsection id="H3E236F71557D478585CA618AD6FDDBD1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year, of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for that fiscal year, the Attorney General may obligate—</text> <paragraph id="HFA9C0A1A2514410E8698CB97AC126898"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 75 percent for grants to eligible States on a formula basis, with each such State receiving an amount that bears the same ratio to the 75 percent as the population of the State bears to the population of all such States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9F7B0926A864C078435FDA3706001E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 22 percent for grants to eligible States on a competitive basis; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF431AA362B574C0099171156DAF6A5E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not more than 3 percent for the administrative expenses of the Attorney General in carrying out this part for that fiscal year, including technical assistance, training, evaluation, and program administration.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBFEC7AD171EE4CD2886BF13817EDA7A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum allocation under formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a)(1), each eligible State shall receive an amount under subsection (a)(1) of not less than 0.5 percent.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF38EBA671674417F984D789C56A3AF87"><enum>3065.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each grantee receiving funds under this part shall submit a report to the Attorney General evaluating the effectiveness of projects developed with funds provided under this part and containing such additional information as the Attorney General may prescribe.</text></section> 
<section id="H1A98C79D09394CA39B2FF7B1C27D15F2"><enum>3066.</enum><header>Definition of State</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part, the term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States and the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></section> <section id="HBB60F919AC324B8B89E2D36603A2A852"><enum>3067.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2036.</text> </section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

