<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5D27D78247944E72BBAB6683D335A2CE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8496 IH: Marine Mammal Climate Change Protection Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8496</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a climate impact management plan for the conservation of certain marine mammal species, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8236F22F8EF943D4A60D5B58882BBF3F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5A7BFDA791924BCC99692E9CECE517C6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Marine Mammal Climate Change Protection Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H170504537C1948E58A49B10F3092B5EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conservation of marine mammals adversely affected by climate change</header> <subsection id="H1E3B3797698F4D9AA1774F87ABA37733"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 120 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H45BF40D5668F46C09E2EAC01B0BB8A1D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC7CE8399E0D94995BA036CA2DA8F96C2"><enum>121.</enum><header>Conservation of marine mammals adversely affected by climate change</header> 
<subsection id="HB1E4B9ADAB734654A5C2D7F60AC368E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Climate impact management plans</header> 
<paragraph id="H7E19CC465F894706BB3360968F376B30"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 24 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Marine Mammal Commission, shall publish in the Federal Register, after notice and opportunity for public comment, a list of those marine mammal species and population stocks in waters under the jurisdiction of the United States for which climate change, alone or in combination or interaction with other factors, is more likely than not to result in a decline in population abundance, of impeding population recovery, or of reducing carrying capacity. The list shall identify—</text> <subparagraph id="H38D88916004B406D882AC35E902482B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any species or population stock for which such impacts are likely to occur within 20 years; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53B35CCC7E924617BF4F31ADE8D983C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any species or population stock listed as a threatened species or endangered species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) for which such impacts have more than a remote possibility of occurring within 100 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36A4FCCE2F6449649D331261BBAB550B"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H69F36306B1734844A3E6183505AF90CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Marine Mammal Commission, shall review the list adopted pursuant to paragraph (1) at least once every 5 years, or more frequently if significant new information becomes available, and, after notice and opportunity for public comment, shall publish a revised list in the Federal Register.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5994DFBED4934AA9BA638594E3358497" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Within 12 months after receiving the petition of an interested person under section 553(e) of title 5, United States Code, to add a marine mammal species or population stock to the list published under paragraph (1), the Secretary, in consultation with the Marine Mammal Commission and after notice and opportunity for public comment, shall publish in the Federal Register its finding of whether the petitioned action is warranted. If the petitioned action is deemed warranted, the Secretary shall publish at the same time the revision adding such species or population stock.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50C90295475D4B6CBD4E1C78944CFC1D"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1BE9C1985A344173BF83466F146107E4"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H78BBE2C7DB8D4C3382A12B5A5E0B5B94"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a draft climate impact management plan for each marine mammal species or population stock—</text> 
<subclause id="HDF51FFC1B7634168AA01CCBF1846B6D5" indent="up2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">listed under paragraph (1)(A), within 18 months after the listing; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9C56CFF923B44C549EB38C65BCFCE1AE" indent="up2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>listed under paragraph (1)(B), within 30 months after the listing.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HEF1B213AE15A48968FEDEF43287071E1" indent="up2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each draft climate impact management plan shall be developed in consultation with the Marine Mammal Commission and, as appropriate, other Federal agencies, and shall be made available for public review and comment for a period not to exceed 90 days.</text></clause> <clause id="H54D8068B788D450C8CCAB8F7B4985C25" indent="up2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>No later than 120 days after the close of the comment period required under clause (ii), the Secretary shall issue a final climate impact management plan and implementing regulations that are consistent with the other provisions of this section and, to the full extent available under the Secretary’s authorities under this Act and other statutes, implement the conservation and management measures identified in the plan.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H38BD87DBE15046C49514A63B82ADD27A" indent="up2" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum> 
<subclause id="H108A36BE814346969326E537B3CCC895" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>If there is insufficient funding available to develop and implement a climate impact management plan under this subparagraph for each marine mammal species and population stock included on the list published under paragraph (1), the Secretary, after consultation with the Marine Mammal Commission, shall give highest priority to each marine mammal species and population stock for which the impacts described in paragraph (1) are most significant and for which a climate impact management plan will best promote the conservation of the marine mammal species or population stock.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC73B142553874AD485C38AC846BB8988" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Any marine mammal species or population stock included on the list published under paragraph (1) for which a climate impact management plan is not developed or implemented due to insufficient funding shall be deemed to be—</text> 
<item id="H7C15C968CC344F18BE94BB35DF57DC6C" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>depleted for purposes of implementing section 101(a)(3)(B); and</text></item> <item id="H26635233AF444D4CB14BD44E4ABC93BB" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a strategic stock for purposes of implementing this title.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD49FE6451A041F7A15E5B0E647A0326" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each climate impact management plan under subparagraph (A) shall include a comprehensive strategy for conserving and recovering of such marine mammal stocks and species given the anticipated direct and indirect effects of climate change and increasing resiliency in the species or population stock, and shall identify conservation and management measures to—</text> <clause id="HE55548BFC5CE49859D879B4D0C426BA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conserve and recover such species and population stocks given the anticipated adverse effects of climate change on such species and population stocks and their prey;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9720F73EBFBA4B0081EE9930E646ECE0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>monitor, reduce, and prevent interactions with fisheries and other human activities that may occur as a result of changes in marine mammal distribution or other indirect effects of climate change;</text></clause> <clause id="HA42438682F21438389F8D5DDA67B27A5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increase resiliency by materially reducing other human impacts on such species and population stocks, including the reduction of incidental taking of marine mammals and of the degradation of the habitat of such species and population stocks, and by managing prey species to improve the availability of prey to such species and population stocks; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H330C4159441C442CA92B52D2181592BC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>take any other action as may be necessary to implement the strategy set forth in the climate impact management plan.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD491F23C18024B9B960E7DA1A51D3F33" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each climate impact management plan under subparagraph (A) shall include objective, measurable criteria for evaluating the effectiveness and sufficiency of such measures to meet the purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55B8B4648A514044A59798A75DB88E1F" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H96D93615E04D4E529F31D614025F6EA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>All other Federal agencies shall, in consultation with and with the assistance of the Secretary, utilize their authorities in furtherance of the strategy and conservation and management measures set forth in climate impact management plans developed under this subsection and ensure that their actions do not conflict or interfere with the objectives of such climate impact management plans. The Secretary shall consult with the Marine Mammal Commission and, as may be warranted, other agencies in the implementation of such climate impact management plans.</text></clause> <clause id="H342C9394D8DF492BB749D227860674BA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any Federal agency action authorized, funded, or undertaken by such agency that, in the view of the Secretary or of the agency, may conflict or interfere with the objectives of such climate impact management plans, such agency shall, in consultation with the Secretary, ensure that such action is consistent with the climate impact management plans. To the extent that the Secretary determines it is impossible for such action to be consistent with the climate impact management plan, the Secretary shall require measures to minimize any such conflicts, in addition to any other measures required by law, and the agency shall adopt such measures required by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB7D802F64AA49E8AB7F55E752A59D9B" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>When appropriate, the Secretary may, and is encouraged to, integrate climate impact management plans into conservation plans adopted under section 115(b) or recovery plans adopted under section 4(f) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(f)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90A769913F2A4A45A5AD39C51EF367B0" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Secretary shall review climate impact management plans and implementing regulations at least once every 5 years, and shall revise and amend them as necessary to meet the goals and requirements of this section. Any changes shall be subject to the procedures and requirements applicable to the adoption of the initial climate impact management plans and regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F6680B19138425F8703B56CCCC4B588"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall report to Congress 4 years after the date of enactment of this section, and every 2 years thereafter, on—</text> <subparagraph id="H91758D60058C48C2B13F35428C872225"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actions taken to implement this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBAFE52EEBEA54DADA4545528B5EA687B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any backlog in meeting the schedule set forth in this subsection for adopting, reviewing, and implementing climate impact management plans, or additional resources necessary to address any such backlog; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF703F9EDB09142D2995CAD3792826A1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the effectiveness of implementation and sufficiency of the measures adopted in climate impact management plans, and any recommendations for improving the process or the applicable legislation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F5B93A136EF4CC291CC61F56F98A04D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monitoring of climate impacts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to monitor the adverse impacts of climate change on marine mammals. The purposes of the monitoring program shall be to—</text> <paragraph id="H7DFA7B972D044895A8D2D0EB2C65444E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve models of projected future changes in marine mammal distribution and densities resulting from climate change;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEE6063CBFE744FDBE4488ACA6F81527"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and monitor interactions with fisheries and other human activities that may occur as a result of changes in marine mammal distribution or other effects of climate change;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2273695617D40C19CA27EBDEBD23FCB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>monitor the abundance of species and population stocks, to an extent sufficient to detect a 20 percent population decline over 20 years;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H836006CD8B8643FAACA62DBCF5DE457C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve understanding of the impacts of climate change on marine mammal species and population stocks; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96729176767D4888AD6D49669D79BA3F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess the direct and indirect contributions of marine mammals to carbon reduction, including through carbon sequestration and nutrient cycling.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H36F048C4CBD24057A507098388A98FBE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Promulgation of regulations for listing marine mammals adversely impacted by climate change</header><text>The Secretary shall, within 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H56B658B2F0A14B6A8B851EEB18FCDFCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish in the Federal Register for public comment, for a period of not less than 60 days, regulations for listing marine mammal species and population stocks adversely impacted by climate change, alone or in combination or interaction with other factors, as described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), taking into account both quantitative and qualitative indicators of adverse impacts of climate change and human activities on such species and stocks, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD1744DDAE4174C79B7AB2225FC04D630"><enum>(A)</enum><text>direct and indirect mortality and serious injury;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7AE016964264E4CA0B2775D6B0BE20B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>loss or degradation of habitat;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD70AEC70F51C46EF93CA8E4A18C46BC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>changes in the distribution or availability of prey;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C1D28D88F8E4DC68D3FE20AD5804E23"><enum>(D)</enum><text>changes in the distribution of marine mammal species and population stocks;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB507F120999A41338AAB5BD1D2C770A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>decreased genetic diversity or reproductive success;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90D382FEC9F9480D98A83326DA414292"><enum>(F)</enum><text>increased susceptibility to pathogens; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H923029EB5EF94784B8DD453855E762A7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>increased likelihood of interactions with fisheries and other human activities; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54AC5F7F63CA4DC299E5B6BA3F92C6A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no later than 90 days after the close of the period for such public comment, publish in the Federal Register final regulations for listing marine mammals as required by paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), to be reviewed at least once every 3 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8A957835430B4350859A54A4BDDD1D4F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Lack of quantitative information</header><text>The lack of quantitative information shall not be a basis for a determination that a species or population stock is not adversely impacted by climate change, alone or in combination or interaction with other factors, as described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD7A319BFCC9D40A0A8D9357E8C5DE327"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Estimation of potential biological removal</header> <paragraph id="H2B19E59B4E03419EB9BE3CD3E6E6362C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in estimating the potential biological removal level in stock assessments prepared in accordance with section 117, shall consider the adverse impacts of climate change in determining the recovery factor applied to each stock.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H941008F42A5B43EE80080B0BF23B1BAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary, in preparing stock assessments in accordance with section 117, shall reexamine the stock definition and geographic range of marine mammal species and population stocks to identify climate-related changes in spatial distribution and stock definition and to identify how such changes may affect human impacts to the species.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6B137ADE4C7A4589AC182361BC3A5314"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authority To enter into agreements</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H64358089CE76441A862F40FEB0319C9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>periodically review the status of agreements with foreign governments under section 108(a) concerning the management of transboundary marine mammal species and population stocks, and their prey species, that are, or may be affected by climate change; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61531AC855AB493A80DE9B3E957548AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>through the Secretary of State, initiate the amendment of any such agreement, or negotiations for the development of bilateral or multinational agreements, consistent with the goals and policies of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE94AA4DB607E4087A06D4ED4BED19C84"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>This section shall not be construed to limit or restrict any other responsibility of the Secretary or of any other person under this Act or any other statute.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1693F4B54E3C44D09803F2A878C67AF5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="H912566C9FC9441EBA070BB3E8D559560"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator carry out this section, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAA689D5F1224A3392058C66C5919157"><enum>(2)</enum><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior to carry out this section, $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2B47D2457C942ED8E87CEA5B9DA0C10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Marine Mammal Commission to carry out this section, $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA08EE82F63B54D1984771892F4469EA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in the first section of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 120 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1E38BAEC7BAD4A75BE8E78C3B949007D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H45BF40D5668F46C09E2EAC01B0BB8A1D" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="HC7CE8399E0D94995BA036CA2DA8F96C2" level="section">Sec. 121. Conservation of marine mammals adversely affected by climate change.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

