<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26964-FXJ-VW-S4H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4586 IS: Blocking CCP Spy Tech Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a review of the national security risk posed by communications equipment and services produced or provided by certain entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Blocking CCP Spy Tech Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf83a6ac612d44b71b7185176476fc54c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Determination of national security risk posed by certain communications equipment and services</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b62c9af4bf843bf839b81b80d2abf63"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, an appropriate national security agency shall determine if any communications equipment and services described in subsection (b) pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons.</text></subsection><subsection id="id05F5271C739D44D3885962DE12A5C147"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Communications equipment and services described</header><text>The communications equipment or services described in this subsection are any communications equipment or service produced or provided by—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide03de0854c3c4269bec86905f2f8607f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Game Science Interactive Co., Ltd.;</text>
                </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d67125a43e242419c7e11cd0ae5565d">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hangzhou DeepSeek Artificial Intelligence Basic Technology Research Co., Ltd. (commonly known as <quote>DeepSeek</quote>);</text>
                </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e9409d9af83497d9f3a1fa8c7f7a006">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hangzhou Yushu Technology Co., Ltd. (commonly known as <quote>Unitree Robotics</quote>);</text>
                </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id22d442a9067e43b28ab4dd466e9cbaf0">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hangzhou Yunshenchu Technology Co., Ltd. (commonly known as <quote>DEEP Robotics</quote>);</text>
                </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5baa45ad5cbf4de98c070759a84649f3">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">BrainCo, Inc.;</text> </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9a81e43991640cb941381e2b1b2a2e2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Manycore Tech, Inc.; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe940c61af3e4dbab4f879db177705b3">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an entity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (6) (referred to in this paragraph as a <quote>named entity</quote>)—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58aa543d66d343b1b6b63d2160100f2e">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any subsidiary, affiliate, or partner of the named entity;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id163096379f2340989e69cb2178eb5bac">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity in a joint venture with the named entity; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idda5f1ccdc7b5414aa99c0b7cb210e351" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity to which the named entity has issued a license to produce or provide that communications equipment or service.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbe8be50eb38f4f3d882bf0668e01932a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of communications services and equipment on covered list</header><paragraph id="id7fffc5336e7345a6ad543b7cb052a084"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Failure to make determination</header><text>If an appropriate national security agency does not make a determination as required by subsection (a), the Commission shall, not later than 30 days after the date specified in subsection (a), add all communications equipment and services described in subsection (b) to the covered list.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95181749bb404b1d87fd8d36651ed012"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affirmative determinations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after an appropriate national security agency determines that any of the communications equipment or services described in subsection (b) present an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons—</text><subparagraph id="id06311afd0d974cdb91ec2f6401e77515"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Commission shall place such communications equipment or services on the covered list; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4648feaa9c804745b922171f717a7ae6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate national security agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcda3702b3a84e409dce65640404ac2a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Negative determinations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after an appropriate national security agency determines that any of the communications equipment or services described in subsection (b) do not present an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States or the security and safety of United States persons—</text><subparagraph id="id20daf5a217e347c2a06879198e02fb09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the determination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ccfaaab7d454deda515ea3f59cd5171"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 180 days following the determination, all other appropriate national security agencies shall review the determination and shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on their determinations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6cdb844f5dd4d9b9361764804e09173"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each determination required by this subsection shall be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d6d712e171f42ce94b469739917df30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id5b6e95cbafa0474c9c7708a316ef1ec8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id0341b15802aa49959c0709fd143245e2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Select Committee on Intelligence in the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7977672baebe44d18853b875161b7e6d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence in the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4afb26c79e724f4b936ced0452a2051f"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Appropriate national security agency</header> <text>The term <term>appropriate national security agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id18c20a9aa79b41c89307e99b9ecd4b3a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf780916b3fb4a63a81be7ba63f87ad7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered list</header><text>The term <term>covered list</term> means the list of covered communications equipment or services published by the Commission under section 2(a) of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1601">47 U.S.C. 1601(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d14a62a2dbd45fe8676e2df3c23ac4c"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of identification of entities as Chinese military companies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Pursuant to the annual review required under section 1260H(a) of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note), the Secretary of Defense shall determine if any entity described in section 2(b) should be identified under such section 1260H(a) as a Chinese military company operating directly or indirectly in the United States.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

