<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC40E48A6C3AA4C4B9A321FB713E54502" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7879 IH: Saving Us from Pandemic Era Resistance by Building a Unified Global Strategy Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7879</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and other relevant departments and agencies, as appropriate, to formulate a strategy for the Federal Government to secure support from foreign countries, multilateral organizations, and other appropriate entities to facilitate the development and commercialization of qualified pandemic or epidemic products, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD75D73786F034196B863049A1B8BD73E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H48E4726D20C749759056A9F306B7F578" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saving Us from Pandemic Era Resistance by Building a Unified Global Strategy Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SUPER BUGS Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H982C74D1D1C0428883924972E81B5AA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE8A1836DAE6F436789591B7A6EE1155F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Emerging infectious diseases, including antimicrobial-resistant pathogens, pose a significant threat to United States national security by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2878744B2FDA4A01B1255D5D71109412"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing the risk of outbreaks reaching the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC3C81241917943CFABD4597DB1D019F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disrupting critical infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6165880238BC4A2186D868957257D80A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>undermining economic stability and public health; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AD385EDBD40464FA331191E94156FF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>undermining the readiness of the United States Armed Forces abroad.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H586A71FAB0594271A0CC688538593255"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Strengthening international collaboration to develop, commercialize, and deploy qualified pandemic and epidemic products is essential to preventing, detecting, and containing infectious disease threats before they reach the borders of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18FD43C4D0F54C2B9F80176D1C8CFD43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Enhancing partner countries’ public health capabilities and pandemic and epidemic response mechanisms directly contributes to United States homeland security by reducing the likelihood of global outbreaks affecting the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA37F5748C03B4826917CFF75FF75484A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordinated strategies that leverage United States leadership, technology, and medical countermeasures, while ensuring equitable access for international partners, promote global resilience and reduce threats to United States citizens, infrastructure, and national interests.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3E9F2C30B7B843E98753BFBF6BC9ACF0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H778F4BD15FFB41C685DEA1335B364BE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H51ABE11A69944F72BAE5D6DF41BEF76C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5A81B7C961B449B898AF47E540FDB90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAC26D25FA4B4C738679930731FF19FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA407AC3237948829A3DCEB78605AB3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFD80F38B69B44A197C785A851660280"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority pathogens</header><text>The term <term>priority pathogens</term> means pathogens identified in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3B0E8B6D505C47019DEE1732387E2BE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the latest <quote>Antibiotic Resistance Threats Report</quote> of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (or any successor report); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H482AAD80CE7348EBBDFA16DFEED0C1A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the current list of qualifying pathogens maintained by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 505E(f)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355f">21 U.S.C. 355f(f)(2)</external-xref>) (or any successor list).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A4297E09B884623BC09B70A6CD252A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified pandemic or epidemic product</header><text>The term <term>qualified pandemic or epidemic product</term> has the meaning given such term in section 319F–3(i) of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 247d–6d(i)).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF4AF8FC20FB54A1F9B4578BA54E4493B"><enum>4.</enum><header>International strategy for development of qualified pandemic or epidemic products</header> <subsection id="HF25BC6760B8849BCBB3F133DD5F5BE15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header> <paragraph id="HE67DB94F5C86496CA53FAB058C3F2CA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and such other heads of departments and agencies as the Secretary of State considers appropriate, shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H98BF72EC34204E928EFBF52B54EC2E2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>formulate a strategy for the Federal Government to secure support from foreign countries, multilateral organizations, and other appropriate entities to facilitate the development and commercialization of qualified pandemic or epidemic products, including products to address antimicrobial resistant pathogens—</text> <clause id="H943ACC4EFD30416A818090210CE97AC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with pandemic potential; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2BB3E9C26AAE4BC59DD4EAA611A8D780"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that are priority pathogens; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98D0D576D43B46EA94BD2757C88B5DA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit such strategy to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B41A8CB050440BFACB79E4E383F8211"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H836AF5B8F1CA4FDCA44DC2F62CE2425A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for processes the Federal Government is using and would use to enter into arrangements with foreign countries, multilateral organizations, and other appropriate entities in certain circumstances to implement the strategy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C117CC0779F488FA362F3C73A96B69E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strive to ensure that the arrangements described in subparagraph (A) promote equitable contributions based on the budgets and technical expertise of participating countries, organizations, and other entities, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66F4FE4AAAE84D78AF02E337250CB470"><enum>(C)</enum><text>focus the arrangements described in subparagraph (A) on global priorities, while enabling participating countries, organizations, and other entities to emphasize national or regional issues of importance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7E064630B0449E0AE828F2E5E66CF68"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support efforts to strengthen partner country public health capabilities by promoting sustainable improvements in their ability to prevent, detect, and contain infectious disease threats;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA9287B43712489B8AD1DC55B1F52372"><enum>(E)</enum><text>seek to ensure that new and existing arrangements described in subparagraph (A) are harmonized with each other and with other relevant existing or planned efforts to amplify impact, address gaps, prevent duplication of effort, and efficiently distribute funds;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67978EF22A324D90B249A72348F5E17E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide for collaboration to ensure the arrangements described in subparagraph (A) allocate joint or individual responsibility across participating countries, organizations, and other entities for the development and commercialization of particular qualified pandemic or epidemic products, where such collaboration is clearly described in such arrangement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H254E23F838EA45D7ACCEBB4CC5C14DF2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provide for the stewardship of qualified pandemic or epidemic products developed pursuant to the strategy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA62FC6189A9A4D8F898B3FB09EABE014"><enum>(H)</enum><text>identify priority actions in the arrangements described in subparagraph (A) so that scarce domestic and international funds are allocated to develop and commercialize qualified pandemic or epidemic products that can achieve the greatest positive impact on human health, including unprecedented approaches to preventing, treating, and diagnosing infectious diseases;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA632B8D09AB14D1B8442AD18ABA21841"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consider securing contracts with United States companies and the broader private sector, entering into public-private partnerships, implementing alternative payment models, creating coverage and reimbursement pathways, and streamlining regulatory approval processes; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE15366F46CA14DABBFD2543E6AA5E073"><enum>(J)</enum><text>be synchronized with United States pandemic preparedness priorities, such as those articulated in—</text> <clause id="H28165D5A04D14E37910C4C1234A15441"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Strategy for Combating Antibiotic-Resistant Bacteria (dated September 2014); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H804ACEF5F66042838FCAB5E496C6A757" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Biodefense Strategy and Implementation Plan (dated October 2022) and the associated Action Plan (dated October 2022).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0869E0134C634F02945A96055D02B45B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Arrangements with foreign countries and multilateral organizations</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the heads of other relevant departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall seek to enter into arrangements with foreign countries, multilateral organizations, and other appropriate entities to implement the strategy required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

