<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3207F3EC38BB4F35BEA16A16B75A13F4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7115 IH: Jumpstart Savings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7115</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish Jumpstart Programs for saving for apprenticeship and trade occupation training, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE2DC8A9822E74AFDBBBAAF2BD1FEE2F0" style="OLC"><section id="HE05DDC4198B040279598315F04BF6224" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jumpstart Savings Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC95179982177493C9C7BDE2E013FA442"><enum>2.</enum><header>Jumpstart Program</header><subsection id="HCDE7326E47544873A30678C6D3F8C6C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VIII of subchapter F of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 529A the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCE5BDB69D5B34FFD8DE4619B0FE5F7AE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HFD5FE150B071434C92CB3FF2A23A890A"><enum>529B.</enum><header>Jumpstart Program</header><subsection id="HBAF317AFCED64480A331CE55E7B54AEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Jumpstart Program shall be exempt from taxation under this subtitle. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, such program shall be subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable organizations).</text></subsection><subsection id="H21E5DCCF63614E738DF6074CF56A1BA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Jumpstart Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H8F7B7BEFC28546A5957DF5531C8B954A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>Jumpstart Program</quote> means a program established and maintained by a State or agency or instrumentality thereof under which a person may make contributions to an account which is established for the purpose of meeting the qualified occupation, profession, or trade expenses of the designated beneficiary of the account.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H713A688C8A984AA7880EEF92A1A880E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>A program shall not be treated as a Jumpstart Program unless such program meets rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6) of section 529(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5959C34D1ACF4422A51014F437907697"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified occupation, profession, or trade expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified occupation, profession, or trade expenses</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HE9CC49CE79AC45669CB3B93D8A1840AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expenses in connection with completing an apprenticeship program registered and certified with the Department of Labor, as provided in the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>),</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB14B69188E4443FFADBC65B8DF65C3E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>tuition, fees, books, supplies, and equipment required for the enrollment or attendance of a designated beneficiary in an associate degree or certification program at a community and technical college,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D3689A5EE6A47F4A7092BB23945372F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>fees for required certification or licensure for the beneficiary to practice a trade or occupation,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H695210D6F94D4309A4CFA2FAA699BF04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>amounts paid or incurred for the purchase of tools and equipment acquired by the individual in the normal course of the practice of a trade or occupation, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE12C72042D9C43468BE79E3238425163"><enum>(5)</enum><text>costs incurred by the beneficiary that are necessary to establish a business in a State in which the beneficiary will practice an occupation or profession when the costs are exclusively paid or incurred for the purpose of establishing and operating such business.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H39F5D37736A84A229719CB92D45BE92C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of designated beneficiaries and contributors</header><text>For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), and (5) of section 529(c) shall apply to Jumpstart Accounts in the same manner as applied to qualified tuition programs described in section 529(b)(1)(A)(ii).</text></subsection><subsection id="H759AAC383666461DA60568F2170FB5C8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Designated beneficiary</header><text>The term <quote>designated beneficiary</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HEB119975B660442D9610B6E8231B6D54"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual designated at the commencement of participation in the Jumpstart Program as the beneficiary of amounts paid (or to be paid) to the program, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19D715311EDA4463A7C86EE0263BF927"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a change in beneficiaries under rules similar to the rules of section 529(c)(3)(C), the individual who is the new beneficiary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD74B817FB8FE42E2BF128E64EDCBB921"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each officer or employee having control of the Jumpstart Program or their designee shall make such reports regarding such program to the Secretary and to designated beneficiaries with respect to contributions, distributions, and such other matters as the Secretary may require. The reports required by this paragraph shall be filed at such time and in such manner and furnished to such individuals at such time and in such manner as may be required by the Secretary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H247D86DDD34B4308BDAF1DBB297C7018"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rollover from qualified tuition programs</header><text>Section 529(c)(3)(C)(i) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subclause (II), by striking the period at the end of subclause (III) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by inserting after subclause (III) the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB30619DD957E4384AAE1035314CB70BE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="HF1CED5F865D6462FBF769170432FE6BE"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a Jumpstart Program (as defined in section 529B(b)(1)) of the designated beneficiary or a member of the family of the designated beneficiary.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H245329ECC4DF4A5080553051E760B67A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Failure to provided reports</header><text>Section 6693(a)(2) of such Code is amended by redesignating subparagraphs (F) and (G) as subparagraphs (G) and (E), respectively, and by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCEBADAFBDAA2499C9CE937F3A72AF236" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HAC4B5776A3F04566BB350032E88E012B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 529B(f) (relating to Jumpstart Program),</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H38050A3A403E4E0E96AF4876F2057A62"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part VIII of subchapter F of chapter 1 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 529A the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H27D6F224C6FF4CAFAA4773A63D96873D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 529B. Jumpstart Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA42ABECE668B477A878B3D512EF74129"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

