<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP25770-W4W-G1-8LN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3175 IS: Community Involvement in Zone Improvement Plans Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3175</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a pilot program for ZIP Code boundary changes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Involvement in Zone Improvement Plans Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CIPZIP Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc2f78e1f05e84297be543cf049815f9b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot postal service program for ZIP Code boundary changes</header><subsection id="id0a5a4635adb04ae181b1f5e43373f713"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of title 39, United States Code, the United States Postal Service (referred to in this section as the <quote>Postal Service</quote>) shall establish a pilot program through which the Postal Service may consider entering into an agreement with an agency of a State government, local government, or Tribal government to receive money, property, or services to defray part or all of the net costs, if any, in conjunction with a request for a ZIP Code boundary change or realignment.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5dae17f66f4848e1981e02c2b194d72c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Denial of ZIP Code boundary change or realignment requests</header><paragraph id="ide5a81fd0cd5a46299de538c3ad9964bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Postal Service denies a request from a State government, local government, or Tribal government for a ZIP Code boundary change or realignment on the basis of a net cost to the Postal Service, the Postal Service shall—</text><subparagraph id="id37c0ab0d310e41f1884d5a1c54ac9eba"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the requestor in writing of the existence of the program established under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id072ff802eb424097b56c49570e66b8c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide the requestor with an estimate of the net cost to the Postal Service of the implementation of the request;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id628b75b44c784ff9af87f9911801fc86"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow not less than 30 days for the requestor to propose an agreement meeting the requirements of the pilot program established under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0581b39d7874795a1e1afc04f5b1123"><enum>(D)</enum><text>give due consideration to a proposed agreement under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd4e96bbea1b4a368516678d5af4146e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost as only dispositive factor for a denial</header><text>If a net cost to the Postal Service is the only dispositive factor in a denial of a request under paragraph (1), and the requestor is able to defray that cost under an agreement described in subsection (a), the Postal Service shall accept the agreement and grant the request.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id31fec87acd444f2690efbd79bc109f3a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="idf35a5da8ea1b49b0a43c62d7bace45a1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 360 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Postal Regulatory Commission shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives a report on the pilot program under subsection (a), including—</text><subparagraph id="id918a4bfbaf924e678e134d964d268ef5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of requests the United States Postal Service has received for a ZIP Code boundary change or realignment, including the number of requests granted and denied;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id779203cbdb5c4a0fa783cb4ab52e5651"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of agreements entered into under the pilot program established under subsection (a), and with respect to each such agreement, the total value of the costs defrayed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96596fd3815b43c7a21db462ab2a96d8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to each denial of a request for a ZIP Code boundary change or realignment—</text><clause id="id20f834566deb4c14bc0ae8939570e348"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether a notification was provided pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="id56b39b1135864f0ea62fc2b94565376e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the estimated net cost provided pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb6d81a3b263e4cfabf52ae94d76631d8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>By member request</header><text>The Postal Service shall submit to any Member of Congress, upon request, a report of the factors contributing to the denial of a request from a State government, local government, or Tribal government for a ZIP Code boundary change or realignment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id58bd0b95a43e43e985e2e18f46aee465"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The pilot program established under this section shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

