<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31790094B764481FBB7BAF4898E799D6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6930 IH: Protecting Military Readiness from Offshore Wind Industrialization Interference Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6930</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251223">December 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a certification and review of the impact of offshore wind industrialization on military readiness and radar and sonar capabilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9E92AB9778154710ADEB83CBA98044C7" style="OLC"><section id="HAFB87F77A52141EDB2E3C2ED79AF0F40" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Military Readiness from Offshore Wind Industrialization Interference Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7E4C797F786140C181F70E0B04C9BC51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certification</header><subsection id="H456FE33AE13C40B39DFDA52F6FCF0396"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President, or the President’s designee, shall certify in writing that—</text><paragraph id="H2C0B7A2986A040C1BAD6548AB36EBE60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>offshore wind projects in the North Atlantic and Mid-Atlantic Planning Areas will not weaken, degrade, interfere with, or nullify the capability of radar and sonar relied upon by the Armed Forces; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66302E2F1DF64DD8A4BC15B4E770199A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the development of offshore wind projects in the North Atlantic and Mid-Atlantic Planning Areas will not degrade the capabilities of the Armed Forces or limit the ability of the Armed Forces to conduct combat operations, training, or rescue missions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1F68FC7A37A4616890CCF456A811E2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National security action</header><text>Should the President, or the President’s designee, find that certification under subsection (a) is untenable, the President shall ensure that all projects presenting a threat to national security are halted under the authority of the President to protect the national security of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE119ADCA921F40E9807A31CB03C32FFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>DOD Inspector General study and report on offshore wind projects in the North Atlantic and Mid-Atlantic Planning Areas</header><subsection id="HED3978EB25494F168356ACE3AF90CB52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H491199EA4A0740FF932E1A9C813BBD25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inspector General study</header><text>The Inspector General of Department of Defense shall conduct a study on—</text><subparagraph id="H20DE00C146A24472BFEADE3697000F6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effects of offshore wind industrialization on radar and sonar and on military air and maritime traffic; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE17CD3558ACD45A69927DCF9C957C693"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sufficiency of the review and approval process for offshore wind projects in the North Atlantic and Mid-Atlantic Planning Areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60B3B3C19ABA4B7FABBEF3AE28B6EDDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of study</header><text>In conducting the study required under paragraph (1), the Inspector General shall—</text><subparagraph id="H797C1A0851074B05B613A7E06B193757"><enum>(A)</enum><text>investigate—</text><clause id="H2C173C9220C1450B8226996978303278"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether offshore wind projects will weaken, compromise, interfere with, or nullify the usage of radar and sonar used by the Armed Forces, and any effects such projects may have on radar and sonar used by the Federal Aviation Administration, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the United States Maritime Administration; and</text></clause><clause id="HDA050D30AD114730B4D38A70577D4D47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sufficiency of the process for approving offshore wind projects and the effect of such projects on radar and sonar, including the consultation process between the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, the Department of Defense, the Federal Aviation Administration, the United States Maritime Administration, and the Military Aviation and Installation Assurance Siting Clearinghouse;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36FC5C27B2A64A0491588A62E6031336"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct an audit of the approval applications by the Military Aviation and Installation Assurance Siting Clearinghouse regarding concerns voiced over the effect of offshore wind projects on—</text><clause id="HCD6D8DADC5E04B28BBD48F54D8FA8E28" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>radar;</text></clause><clause id="H96D5957AEC2245EC85E665CBDBD4D4F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sonar;</text></clause><clause id="H95355DCE934B4F61B5200152380A310F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the ability to identify airborne threats;</text></clause><clause id="H73D6CA9ABD2A4F588AA73C355E8A0EE6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the freedom to navigate United States airspace or water; and</text></clause><clause id="HFACBA7BE216B48F2A40688C70F57DCBB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the ability to train within United States airspace or waters;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8226C13DE08D4134A2571D46C8EC1312"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine whether any offshore wind projects will affect, alter, or disrupt military aviation flight paths;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3ED00256E46C4842881CC6B65CE61AF3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>determine whether any offshore wind projects will affect, compromise, inhibit, or nullify the use of radar and sonar technologies by the Armed Forces and any agencies carrying out space launch programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE96ACD65A8044EA7850D5B8B5D6C3EDD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>address how offshore wind energy projects affect low-level military airspace and freedom of maritime navigation off the Atlantic Coast;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85CA8444F7334198A4D8B7D36D8C7D7E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>determine whether any offshore wind project in the North Atlantic or Mid-Atlantic Planning Areas will affect, compromise, or inhibit the ability of the United States Coast Guard to conduct maritime safety and lifesaving operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11F28CDB0F414709B8146C0150B088DA"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether approved offshore wind projects, and yet undeveloped offshore wind leasing areas, significantly alter military operations, degrade capability development, or present risks to national security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF308B86D09CC4E3788EE0D599329901E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>determine whether the mitigation strategies laid out in the 2016 Department of Defense report titled <quote>Report on the Impact of Wind Energy Developments on Military Installations</quote> are sufficient, achievable and, realistic.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4722FCCA9D724F3280743C32D91291C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H7901697261B54FC8AA7875C72B7B6643"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ED6A06D6ABC47CE936169D176619D15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

