<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25G71-6WF-Y6-8FG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3280 IS: Measuring Availability of Providers (MAP) for Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3280</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct a study on the feasibility of establishing a full-service hospital of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Alaska, Hawaii, and New Hampshire and to provide continued access to care under the Veterans Community Care Program in States that establish such a hospital.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Measuring Availability of Providers (MAP) for Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d3b7cea6a0a4a0192f305ef184e2fe4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Feasibility study for full-service hospital of Department of Veterans Affairs in certain States</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id731bc7be38194a9b882e7d9530872561"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a study on the feasibility of establishing a full-service hospital of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Alaska, Hawaii, and New Hampshire.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce33d62624654d8daa69ca08147f8dcc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish the results of the study conducted under subsection (a) on a publicly available website of the Department.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H6C12646FD936416F85EEDF7934D1DF14"><enum>3.</enum><header>Continued access to care under Veterans Community Care Program in States that establish full-service medical facility of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1703(d)(1)(B) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>as of the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Measuring Availability of Providers (MAP) for Veterans Act</short-title></quote> before the semicolon at the end.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

