<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HE32A5BA3914A49DBAAC13D2ED8F5FF5E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 96 EH: Expressing support for law enforcement officers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 96</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Expressing support for law enforcement officers.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the brave men and women in law enforcement work tirelessly and relentlessly to safeguard the communities they are sworn to protect, serving as the backbone of public safety across our Nation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers bear the critical responsibility of upholding the rule of law and maintaining the safety, stability, and public order upon which our communities depend;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers routinely and selflessly risk their own lives and safety to combat crime, remove dangerous and lethal drugs from our streets, and stand in defense of the most vulnerable among us;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers strengthen our communities through outreach, mentorship, crisis response, and countless daily acts of service that frequently go unrecognized;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, from resolving neighborhood disputes to checking in on elderly residents and guiding youth programs, officers provide a quiet and steady presence that extends far beyond traditional law enforcement duties;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas rhetoric and policies from leftist activists and progressive politicians seek to defund or dismantle local police departments undermine public safety and place both officers and the communities they serve at greater risk;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas sanctuary city policies that restrict cooperation with Federal immigration authorities can compel local law enforcement agencies to divert already limited resources and actively encourage resentment toward local law enforcement;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Trump administration’s focus on restoring law and order has contributed to a notable decline in homicide rates, with levels reaching among the lowest recorded in over a century;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas drug overdose deaths in the United States have declined significantly, reaching their lowest levels since 2019;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas violent crime rates have declined significantly in major cities across the United States; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers deserve our deepest respect, unwavering support, and profound gratitude: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body style="OLC" id="HF4FB4762347041B3A21EB9A1245DED0F"> <section id="H980797780C69481690E14E4DF55EE08E" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That Congress—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6F81045958504766A35A2DED40F9B9D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appreciates and values the indispensable contributions that law enforcement provides to our communities and our country each and every day;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBADA95DB79B4A4B8FD2E2CFD04D4854"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the extraordinary sacrifice that law enforcement officers make to protect and serve their communities and their country; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D621336EBD24F92BDF2D3B14634A7F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses its profound and wholehearted support for the men and women of law enforcement.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260513" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 13, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </resolution> 

