<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9390 IH: Prices on the Wall Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to require certain facilities to post prices on the walls.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H56A681AF18DA4F4FA0BADA1FA2FDF6CD" style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"> 
<section id="H9D16829515224028B4F192D7A217A0EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prices on the Wall Act of 2026</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HC8808302347C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring certain facilities to post prices on the walls</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2718 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-18">42 U.S.C. 300gg–18</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H83D58A752E744D78931664703FBFED65" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H1DEBC1451EE447B1A63B017B21CF8E27"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Requirement to post prices on the walls</header> 
<paragraph id="HCC613BCBA392403996650CA26A9FB13B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hospitals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each hospital operating in the United States shall, beginning January 1, 2028, post on the wall of such hospital (in such areas as specified by the Secretary) the discounted cash price, as applicable, expressed as a dollar amount, for each Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services-specified shoppable service that is furnished by the hospital when provided in, as applicable, the inpatient setting and outpatient department setting (or, in the case no discounted cash price is available for such service, the median cash price charged by the hospital to self-pay individuals for such service when provided in such settings for the previous 3 years, expressed as a dollar amount).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B3E6D6C8A57416DBC1650C403FA4520"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ambulatory surgical centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each ambulatory surgical center operating in the United States shall, beginning January 1, 2028, post on the wall of such center (in such areas as specified by the Secretary) the discounted cash price, as applicable, expressed as a dollar amount, for each Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services-specified shoppable service that is furnished by the center (or, in the case no discounted cash price is available for such service, the median cash price charged by the center to self-pay individuals for such service for the previous 3 years, expressed as a dollar amount).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE101E6350A494FA8A1E6C2E6BD92E46E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Laboratories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each laboratory operating in the United States shall, beginning January 1, 2028, post on the wall of such laboratory (in such areas as specified by the Secretary) the discounted cash price, as applicable, expressed as a dollar amount, for each specified clinical diagnostic laboratory test that is a Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services-specified shoppable service furnished by the laboratory (or, if no such price exists, the gross charge for such test).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46B12D7071B34B0980C7BEBA01CC8428"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Providers furnishing imaging services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each provider of services and supplier furnishing imaging services operating in the United States shall, beginning January 1, 2028, post on the wall of such provider or supplier (in such areas as specified by the Secretary) the discounted cash price, as applicable, expressed as a dollar amount, for each imaging service that is a Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services-specified shoppable service furnished by the provider or supplier (or, in the case no such price exists, the gross charge for such service).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10E0625541894F1F996E93394E96AFE3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H0758786E106A4DAC8192DFF9272D7CDE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Discounted cash price</header><text>The term <term>discounted cash price</term> means the charge that applies to an individual who pays cash, or cash equivalent, for an item or service.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17B6E30318D54CD8989EE91FEAB7C2E1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Shoppable service</header><text>The term <term>shoppable service</term> means a service that can be scheduled by a health care consumer in advance and includes all ancillary items and services customarily furnished as part of such service.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB59D17B42AA4A4B8A7A9CE8B0F80505"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Specified clinical diagnostic laboratory test</header><text>The term <quote>specified clinical diagnostic laboratory test</quote> means a clinical diagnostic laboratory test other than an advanced diagnostic laboratory test (as defined in section 1834A(d)(5) of the Social Security Act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

