<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2090E541DF7A42F5A4A76ED3A874F1FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7612 IH: End Sanctuary Cities Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7612</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/93">chapter 93</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit obstruction of immigration laws by official interference.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3072A2E17044C53AA7E2B2BE84827EE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7F83B400C37F4BE18F512F7A32525A9A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Sanctuary Cities Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD45BB693CEA349C5AB577956B025E993"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obstruction of immigration laws by official interference</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC213454D0C22476ABDF21611367E96D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/93">Chapter 93</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EFFCC0C2C6E46BC81F39B6490F0603A"> 
<section id="HF5245266E6D249789583448708023E1A"><enum>1925.</enum><header>Obstruction of immigration laws by official interference</header> 
<subsection id="H958A016A7CEF44928CE1AA68186D7CF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F5C8EF615A74653B6ADC89E06A7D2EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal alien</term> means an alien (as defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1001">8 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)) who has been charged with or convicted of a crime under Federal or State law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBC60A18217D42EAA2255FF6FFC1C820"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the terms <term>Federal sex offense</term> and <term>minor</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3559(e)(2);</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H269328FFADE74861A69AE625880F14D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>immigration laws</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59AD3A4B1AB84D6CA06DDF6BAC543CA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>reasonable advance notice</term>, with respect to the release of a criminal alien, means notice regarding the scheduled release date and time of the criminal alien that is provided as early as practicable and, unless impossible, at least 48 hours prior to release;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C917F8FDBB74EAEA97E3F8369D53892"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>the term <term>responsible executive official</term>, with respect to a law, regulation, policy, practice, or action, means the most senior executive official of a State or unit of government charged with overseeing execution of the law, regulation, policy, practice, or action;</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE980BB7A70B4CDDB9E7BDFA1E4D7ADC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>serious violent felony</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3559(c)(2);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E686673E4CC441B90D5C587347B2BE4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the terms <term>State</term> and <term>unit of local government</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 901(a) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251(a)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88F8C1ACAB14467DB38E229A6914107F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>State sex offense</term> means a State or Military sex offense (as defined in section 3559(e)(2)) that is an offense under State law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC89ECE98D0BA4F2D8513E0FFCF707270"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited conduct</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any responsible executive official of a State or unit of local government, acting under color of law, to knowingly prohibit, limit, or restrict compliance with any formal request under the immigration laws by the Department of Homeland Security for reasonable advance notice regarding the release of a criminal alien, including through establishing, directing, implementing, or enforcing any pertinent law, regulation, policy, practice, or action.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF2939739673B4043BB2B62DED3051EE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person who violates subsection (b)—</text> <paragraph id="HC817BFF3ACE34BC281BD9A3851925075"><enum>(1)</enum><text>if the violation results in the release from custody of a criminal alien who has been charged with or convicted of an offense consisting of murder, rape, or a Federal sex offense or State sex offense against a minor, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not less than 10 years and not more than 25 years, or both;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H040F61B930FD4D129B6AB82F6B409A91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the violation results in the release from custody of a criminal alien who has been charged with or convicted of an offense that is a serious violent felony, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not less than 5 years and not more than 10 years, or both; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75FC00237E284AB987118903E208E546"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if the violation results in the release from custody of a criminal alien who has been charged with or convicted of any other Federal or State criminal offense, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not less than 30 days and not more than 6 months, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H64ACBE5044D147558F66256C1A2BE12A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Severability clause</header><text>If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such a provision or amendment to any particular person or circumstance is held invalid, the remaining provisions of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such remaining provisions and amendments to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H617F259F1FA24332AA0EBE288EA65200"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/93">chapter 93</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H3634184B6B224E569AE1F707B95643F9"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HF5245266E6D249789583448708023E1A">1925. Obstruction of immigration laws by official interference.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

