<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEAF9B2CB103444C0B7C035C21862830A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6362 IH: Tax Fairness for Abuse Survivors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6362</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish procedures for relief from joint and several liability on a joint tax return for individuals requesting such relief due to domestic violence or abuse.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8C9B8CD7D11745C4A1B479E98292F073" style="OLC"><section id="H90EE00009CD449F48B56B2FFFB6199BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tax Fairness for Abuse Survivors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H375E998B2F15404E868764C3CFA01256"><enum>2.</enum><header>Procedures for relief from joint and several liability on joint return applicable to individuals requesting relief due to domestic violence or abuse</header><subsection id="H67B8D4030276402FBF08CCF0EAC4B63E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6015">Section 6015</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i) and by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H749729BAE0D24817924443E5630F3A36" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA8336696C7384685B685C6DA8D251D6C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Procedures for relief from liability applicable to individuals requesting relief due to domestic violence or abuse</header><paragraph id="H59EDEA716BF848C6A0D3B73EC3AB6ED2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under procedures prescribed by the Secretary, if—</text><subparagraph id="H67D9A2E139FF42AA90E64BAE0D566A63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a joint return has been made for a taxable year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F21CE22D19040CA8C4D184EDE270EB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on such return there is an understatement of tax attributable to erroneous items of one individual filing the joint return (hereafter referred to as nonrequesting spouse);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD2CCBBBE827482C8ACDDFD3829058B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the other individual (hereafter referred to as requesting spouse), or a member of the requesting spouse’s family was the victim of domestic violence or domestic abuse by the nonrequesting spouse; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H706CCA6CB16F4442AB164E28734D0918"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such requesting spouse establishes that in signing the return, either—</text><clause id="H58AC839B4DE94AD397F856A9B9E45843"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he or she did not know, and had no reason to know, that there was such understatement; or</text></clause><clause id="H64E88F68A4B74ED3BD44858E0583E7A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>he or she did know of such understatement and did not challenge the treatment of items on the return because of fear, pressure, threats of retaliation, or duress by the nonrequesting spouse,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">then such requesting spouse shall be relieved of liability for tax (including interest, penalties, and other amounts) for such taxable year to the extent such liability is attributable to such understatement.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FC4756DE4304781993B3A4FCFA39A7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evidence of domestic violence or abuse</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requesting spouse who elects the application of this subsection shall have the opportunity to provide evidence of domestic violence or abuse against the requesting spouse or a member of the family of the requesting spouse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88D4F66F48EB46E08AE4848ECDDD2941"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Default presumption in the case of a spouse who knew of understatement of tax</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a requesting spouse provides evidence under paragraph (2), for purposes of paragraph (1)(D)(ii), any understatement by the requesting spouse shall be presumed to be due to fear, pressure, threats of retaliation, or duress by the nonrequesting spouse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCF7902200A247C3B4059D63F7DC38E4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice to nonrequesting spouse</header><text>If a requesting spouse elects the application of this subsection, any notice to the nonrequesting spouse—</text><subparagraph id="H37F3217B815E4175BD22518495885181"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not include—</text><clause id="H6D295067347A418DA36ACE7ADE136DC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information indicating that the requesting spouse is seeking relief under this subsection, or</text></clause><clause id="H295E9DCDC64147EC90AD19F2F7ED7DEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any mention of domestic abuse or violence, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A97298EB0D14605872F9A5345396627"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include general information indicating that the Internal Revenue Service is reviewing the return to which such election relates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H12EE262C77064A92B32ED5AAC20D3DF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HB80FCC0C539843F49785E00C690E8855"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6015(a)(2) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or subsection (h)</quote> after <quote>subsection (c)</quote> in each place it appears.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84C577282DE14495A5CA8B4147BC119D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6015 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>subsection (b) or (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b), (c), or (h)</quote> in each place it appears.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE82FC8D0CAA84AD48B2DC751E8DBF0B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Subsection (i) of section 6015 of such Code (as so redesignated by subsection (a)) is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (1), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (2) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD4828BBB74384F738961247E6BA9C928" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H7B9710BBBB2D41378C603BCB36D46226"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulations providing that any notice described in paragraph (2) shall conform with the requirements of subsection (h)(4).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C9B026D9BA848BF8DFE3E9EDFB02512"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to requests for relief after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

