<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H74DB6FA67A19481FB3EC87E547E80E61" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 893 IH: Censuring Representative Cory Mills of Florida and removing him from the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 893</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Censuring Representative Cory Mills of Florida and removing him from the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, prior to serving in the House of Representatives, Representative Cory Mills founded Pacem Solutions International LLC and Pacem Defense LLC, and acquired AMTEC Corporation (now renamed as ALS, Inc.), companies which engage in security and military contracting with the United States Government as well as foreign nations;</text></whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in August 2024, the Office of Congressional Conduct found <quote>from January 2023 to present, Pacem Defense/ALS, has been actively contracting with the federal government, securing close to $1,000,000 in federal contracts for munitions and weapons, distributed to prisons across the country. Specifically, since January 9, 2024, 94 contracts have been awarded to entities owned by Rep. Mills</quote> and went on to conclude <quote>there is substantial reason to believe that Rep. Mills may have entered into, held, or enjoyed contracts with federal agencies while he was a Member of Congress in violation of House rules, standards of conduct, and federal law</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in August 2024, the Office of Congressional Conduct noted <quote>According to its website, Pacem Solutions is currently registered and/or partnered with trusted local firms to work in the following· countries: United States, Iraq, Afghanistan, Pakistan, UAE, Australia, Kenya, Malaysia and Kuwait.</quote> Public reports indicate companies owned by Representative Mills sought, or entered into contracts, to sell munitions to foreign nations while serving as a member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas entities owned by Representative Cory Mills seeking or entering into contracts to sell munitions to the United States Government as well as foreign nations while he serves as a member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services represents a clear and troubling conflict of interest;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in August 2024, the Office of Congressional Conduct further adopted and transmitted to the Committee on Ethics of the House of Representatives a report indicating that there was substantial reason to believe that Representative Cory Mills may have omitted or misrepresented required information in his financial disclosure statements, accepted excessive contributions to his campaign committee in the form of personal loans and contributions that may not have derived from Representative Cory Mills' personal funds, and may have accepted through his campaign committee in-kind contributions or other contributions not lawfully made; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals who served in the military with Representative Cory Mills have called into question the veracity of the account of events which formed the basis of a recommendation that Representative Cory Mills receive an award of a Bronze Star, bestowed in 2021, for his service under enemy fire in Iraq in 2003;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in August 2024, Representative Cory Mills provided the Daytona Beach News with documents purporting to prove that he earned a Bronze Star with heroism, including a Department of the Army Form 638 recommending Representative Cory Mills for a Bronze Star which includes a signature from then-Army Brigade Commander Arnold N. Gordon-Bray;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Retired Brigadier General Arnold N. Gordon-Bray has stated he did not personally write, read, or sign the Department of the Army Form 638 recommending Representative Cory Mills for a Bronze Star;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas five people who served with Representative Cory Mills, including two men who were reported as having been personally saved by Representative Cory Mills at great risk to his own life as a basis for the recommendation for his Bronze Star in the Department of the Army Form 638, disputed that Representative Cory Mills was involved in their rescue or provided life-saving care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas one Private First Class cited as having been involved in one of the listed achievements on Representative Cory Mills's Army Form 638 recommending him for a Bronze Star denied that Representative Cory Mills provided him any aid and also denied that his injuries were life threatening;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas one Sergeant cited as having been involved in one of the listed achievements on Representative Cory Mills's Army Form 638 recommending him for a Bronze Star called the account a <quote>fabrication</quote> and claimed that he <quote>was not involved in any claims that Cory Mills makes about me</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative Cory Mills's employment application to DynCorp Internation stated he served in the United States Army 75th Ranger Regiment and attended United States Army Sniper School, claims which are not corroborated by his military records;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 19, 2025, Washington, DC, Metropolitan Police Department officers were called to resolve a private matter at Representative Cory Mills's residence, where officers were called to the 1300 block of Maryland Avenue, Southwest around 1:15 p.m. for the report of an assault;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas police reports obtained by NBC4 Washington confirmed that the Washington, DC, Metropolitan Police Department was investigating Representative Cory Mills for an alleged assault of a 27-year old woman that took place on February 19, 2025, at the residence of Representative Cory Mills;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the first police report, provided to NBC4 Washington by a source and confirmed by a second source familiar with the investigation, said that the 27-year-old woman accused her significant other for over a year of having grabbed her, shoved her, and pushed her out of the door, and also said that the woman involved showed the officer <quote>bruises on her arm which appeared fresh</quote>; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas NBC4 Washington also reported that the Metropolitan Police Department identified Representative Cory Mills as the significant other of the alleged victim of assault—which alleged victim was a 27-year-old woman who was not the wife of Representative Cory Mills—and that the alleged victim <quote>let officers hear Subject 1 [now identified by MPD as Mills] instruct her to lie about the origin of her bruises . . . Eventually, Subject 1 made contact with police and admitted that the situation escalated from verbal to physical, but it was severe enough to create bruising</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 21, 2025, the Washington post also confirmed two DC police officials said that the alleged victim of assault initially told a 911 operator and police that she had been assaulted and that officers said she also had what seemed to be visible injuries, and that while a supervisor initially classified the offense internally as a family disturbance, police commanders later learned of the incident, reviewed the reports and body camera footage from the responding officers, and reclassified the case as a domestic violence assault;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 21, 2025, NBC4 Washington also reported that the Metropolitan Police Department determined that probable cause to arrest Representative Cory Mills for misdemeanor assault existed and sent an arrest warrant for Representative Cory Mills to the United States Attorney's Office for the District of Columbia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 14, 2025, a different former romantic partner of Representative Cory Mills, who was apparently in a relationship with Representative Mills from November 2021 to February 2025, reported to authorities in Florida that Representative Mills threatened to release nude images and other intimate videos of her, and threatened to harm her future romantic partners in retaliation for her decision to end a relationship with Representative Mills after seeing the public reports described above concerning the alleged February 2025 physical assault;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on October 14, 2025, the Circuit Court of the Third Judicial Circuit in Columbia County, Florida, issued a Final Judgment of Injunction for Protection Against Dating Violence against Representative Cory Mills, based on a finding that his former romantic partner was a victim of dating violence or had reasonable cause to believe she was in imminent danger of becoming a victim of an act of dating violence; and </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas such conduct by Representative Cory Mills affects the dignity and integrity of the proceedings of the House and brings discredit upon the House: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2DC674378A1C47CEA59E0562DD54E982"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC6893B4BD45D491283D100997B6F4ECC"><enum/><text>That—</text><paragraph id="HCFF65AFCDD1849F38932678766BB46D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Representative Cory Mills be censured;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H711BA89DDB42469F8DED59CC55ED82EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Cory Mills forthwith present himself in the well of the House of Representatives for the pronouncement of censure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DD7F40997664DF28A31CDA16DAB10D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Cory Mills be censured with a public reading of this resolution by the Speaker; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H526F94F9B4BF4BCDAD6F6BDB062B6E9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Cory Mills be, and is hereby, removed from the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

