<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF435A96AF3F44ED7892A63B3D78811B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5993 IH: MACV–SOG Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5993</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to the service members of the Military Assistance Command Vietnam-Studies and Observations Group, in recognition of their bravery and outstanding service in South Vietnam, North Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia during the Vietnam War.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCD3B1ECB01CD47B38100E8D98D68C040" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H37538A3741F54D18BECF3178E05BFB85" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>MACV–SOG Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB2C9AFE56FF41CC8B8FF014B550FD45"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H8ADC08075DA54376A86BD9D16FF12CA2">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The Military Assistance Command Vietnam-Studies and Observations Group (referred to in this Act as <quote>MACV–SOG</quote>) was established in January 1964 as a dedicated joint military task force to conduct high risk and special activities in the denied areas of North Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3AC0A5CE9E864A9FA848D78ECA6FF716"><enum>(2)</enum><text>MACV–SOG conducted deep-penetration reconnaissance, sabotage, direct-action mission, rescue missions for downed pilots, prisoner-of-war snatches, bomb-damage assessments, wiretaps, psychological operations, and maritime operations against the North Vietnamese.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E3C14012E394BA1ADEE38E01D501D6F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>MACV–SOG remains one of the most distinguished and elite special operations units in United States military history, setting standards for modern special operations forces. Twelve MACV–SOG operators have been awarded the Congressional Medal of Honor.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H54ADC8EC3FB845E38D3679267DCE9244"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Between 1964 and 1972, approximately 1,579 people of the United States are listed as missing or killed while serving with MACV–SOG. This accounts for more than ½ of all Green Beret fatalities during the Vietnam War and more than 50 MACV–SOG team members are still missing in action.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H458D6632078A4EC9AAE1FC832A1B05D1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The innovative tactics of MACV–SOG, integration with indigenous forces, and mastery of direct action and special warfare created a blueprint for modern special operations. Many of the strategies, technologies, and doctrines they pioneered are now standard across elite military units, reinforcing their legacy as a cornerstone of United States special operations history.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC0B4EAAD4584561915F99802A90AC06"><enum>(6)</enum><text>MACV–SOG created battlefield effects that were vastly disproportionate to the small size of the command. The impact of MACV–SOG on the North Vietnamese logistics, troop deployment, and morale was profound. The North Vietnamese diverted entire divisions, as many as 50,000 troops, and numerous other resources away from offensive operations to defend against incursions by MACV–SOG and to internal security operations in North Vietnam.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E1C0B14D549419881EAE22B53D0097E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>These covert operations remained unacknowledged by military leadership and unknown to the United States public, until their existence began to be declassified decades later. This secret war denied MACV–SOG members their just recognition and deprived the families of deceased and wounded operators from knowing the full extent of the sacrifice of their loved ones to the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H441992A29F8B4F5081F7CEFE6DFD4D66"><enum>(8)</enum><text>MACV–SOG was a joint operations program that included members of the Army Special Forces, Navy SEALs, Force Reconnaissance Marines, the United States Air Force, and the Central Intelligence Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H526B65B6988E49B3968B149243DCD0F7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>MACV–SOG teams also relied heavily on the indigenous population, including Montagnards, Chinese Nung, Cambodian, and Vietnamese personnel, along with the 219th Vietnamese Air Force King Bee helicopter pilots, who were actively engaging in the fight against communist forces.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAE0AFA4DCAF546A2AC1D981D06D89942"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Twelve Medal of Honor recipients have been recognized for their gallantry during actions while operating with MACV–SOG units.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63193904A8F04706976179D1521D4F66"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A Presidential Unit Citation was issued to MACV–SOG by President George W. Bush in 2001.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H590F125433124BF299CBE1B39CFBEE6C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The bravery, sacrifice, and quiet professionalism of MACV–SOG units from 1964 to 1972 reflect favorably upon the highest traditions of the United States military and the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB62BDC267B7A4E719B1CEACA4200CE35"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> <subsection id="H5A5A5F76465348BDBE8B896F3F16FF19"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design to the service members of MACV–SOG, in recognition of their bravery and outstanding service in South Vietnam, North Vietnam, Laos, and Cambodia during the Vietnam War.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H741A8BB3639B4D0193843B2306324566"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4A3DD1472A664AF58469B4BA20D68B1F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian Institution</header> <paragraph id="HF51F5A3038C8474190EDF1CE4EA000A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Following the presentation of the gold medal referred to in subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution, where it will be available for display as appropriate and available for research.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBAEC52C706D409783A58ABA0520DEFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal awarded pursuant to this Act available for display elsewhere, particularly at appropriate locations and events associated with MACV–SOG.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE81F6A1947B84935B743C4FEC883042D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H431D3C9CCDB8412EB712FF860C4AFF4C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header>
<subsection id="HB78A98938BB64AAAB809C1AE175C7F61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medal</header><text>Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB6650C46337F4F05981C87AB6D75DD5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB578047BF89E40A09C56C4E75CB1DB03"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header>
<subsection id="H274114DDE0434BA4A62F1EEBA2FC8379"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0D748E9EE00E43DDA437CC3881DE27D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

