<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEFD8A31C462843F88D67AA11D89A963C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8776 IH: Officer Wellness and Peer Support Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8776</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260513">May 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report by the Attorney General on effective strategies and best practices to reduce stigma related to mental health among law enforcement officers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B141C3BA04643BFAD9CBEAB243B3A02" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H987F116966374AED8D637AD13F7B3271" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Officer Wellness and Peer Support Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3096F1E81BBD4335AD7F0A14B9413757"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report required</header> <subsection id="H2B856A3F22C54624A583EA41E77C8418"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of the National Institute of Justice, shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate a report setting forth—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBCF9821068824D9E9670C93B386D2F19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>effective strategies and best practices to—</text> <subparagraph id="H9695197035A645AEAF52C4E55B0EF937"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce stigma related to mental health among law enforcement officers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF84B5B7028434E86A58DC1353180B726">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>encourage law enforcement officers to access mental health screening, peer-to-peer counseling, and other resources related to mental health; and</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A4F7B5399F84444AEF0A4D9C7A46DD8">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>ensure the confidentiality of mental health services, including peer-to-peer counseling, critical incident stress debriefings, peer crisis lines, and employee assistance programs, for law enforcement officers; and</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D023BEE6D584FC9A44147B42F43F88C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for action to implement such strategies and best practices.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA1401D12D78243ED812B75B64A56CC47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the report under this section, the Attorney General, the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of the National Institute of Justice shall consult with relevant stakeholders including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H778CEA7E29644E7086D2433EA3C7A979"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal, State, Tribal and local law enforcement agencies; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B11CF79787A444D81073305FD932C56"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">professional law enforcement organizations, local law enforcement labor and representative organizations, academic organizations, mental health and suicide prevention organizations, or such other entities as the Attorney General may determine appropriate.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H087C0405CB6B48E5949E76ADD1D27546"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>law enforcement officer</term> means an individual involved in crime and juvenile delinquency control or reduction, or enforcement of the criminal laws (including juvenile delinquency), including, but not limited to, police, corrections, probation, parole, and judicial officers. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

