<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H163B1101419B4B49B99C02799D06303D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8096 IH: Duplication Scoring Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8096</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to analyze certain legislation in order to prevent duplication of and overlap with existing Federal programs, offices, and initiatives.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9A947DC1C3884D669C2C3CB12DFAA873" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HB5AC883EB7B24CB7A60A6B7B8D3F69ED"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Duplication Scoring Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H62355F9C16D14E60A733D9AC50188C41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessments of reported bills by GAO</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 719 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H95849ACF8BD34B19A0062649DE59C872">
<subsection id="H643D728A7B3643A9A52182548A794811"><enum>(i)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC29314CD06534DF79D9D6D90B6880DD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HF97083C2BB6A481BB5EEC672A8340BDE" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>covered bill or joint resolution</term> means a bill or joint resolution of a public character reported by any committee of Congress (including the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on the Budget of either House);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC2ADA5387FD4441FA1BB3F9A7E53C087" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Congressional Budget Office;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64FB9086F0884064939A17E612A49B98" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>existing duplicative or overlapping feature</term> means an element of the Federal Government previously identified as an area of duplication, overlap, or fragmentation in a GAO duplication and overlap report;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7532C9AC43874E18ABE5F86BC163D9F8" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>GAO duplication and overlap report</term> means each annual report prepared by the Comptroller General under section 21 of the Joint Resolution entitled <quote>Joint Resolution increasing the statutory limit on the public debt</quote>, approved February 12, 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/712">31 U.S.C. 712</external-xref> note); and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF530C261C1784950B1873659EF65A8DD" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>new duplicative or overlapping feature</term> means a new Federal program, office, or initiative created under a covered bill or joint resolution that would duplicate or overlap with an existing duplicative or overlapping feature.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H231A0BA568284317BE5449365DE64494" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each covered bill or joint resolution—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D1C949A9402400A9CD5D9E022AAF84B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Comptroller General shall, to the extent practicable—</text>
<clause changed="not-changed" id="H534190A7510B465FB5D862F188CCCF10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine the extent to which the covered bill or joint resolution creates a risk of a new duplicative or overlapping feature and, if the risk so warrants, identify—</text> <subclause id="HEBF222B338044A998D0766C4C181C70E" changed="not-changed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the name of the new Federal program, office, or initiative;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H2F909108DE6141EB95DD9B1728A4151D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the section of the covered bill or joint resolution at which the new duplicative or overlapping feature is established; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H88A7410F53774F7B9F96D0F7CC29F2EB" changed="not-changed"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the GAO duplication and overlap report in which the existing duplicative or overlapping feature is identified; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause changed="not-changed" id="H589D500F1F084A2AAD187E309971588B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit the information described in clause (i) to the Director and the committee that reported the covered bill or joint resolution; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1B1017C194C24223AE43E797CB56B79D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>publish the information prepared under clause (i) on the website of the Government Accountability Office; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB7D42D7166644E64907D7E3173F53745"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (3), the Director may include the information submitted by the Comptroller General under subparagraph (A)(ii) as a supplement to the estimate for the covered bill or joint resolution to which the information pertains submitted by the Director under section 402 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/653">2 U.S.C. 653</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4F65B041E9244D3B7B5D324C095C0D6" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the Comptroller General has not submitted to the Director the information for a covered bill or joint resolution under paragraph (2)(A)(ii) on the date on which the Director submits the estimate for the covered bill or joint resolution to which the information pertains under section 402 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/653">2 U.S.C. 653</external-xref>), the Director may, on the date on which the Comptroller General submits the information to the Director, prepare and submit to each applicable committee the information as a supplement to the estimate for the covered bill or joint resolution.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HA2248CFAFF054B2099280D77F75D70B9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendment made by this Act shall take effect on the earlier of—</text> <paragraph id="H422E508E5B2945C2A6E2B8148FC7D5B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Director of the Office of Management and Budget next, in accordance with section 1122(a) of title 31, United States Code, updates the information made available on the website required under that section; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9821A9027F3149EB8DCAADF395EE4368"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which a new Congress begins after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill> 

