<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H36318E67516C4F9BAE0002D3158F7C11" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8994 IH: Protect Working Musicians Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8994</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To empower independent music creator owners to collectively negotiate with dominant online platforms regarding the terms on which their music may be distributed.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6A4827D31B304CBBBF23DDBE67DDAD46" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8AAAE594EF344B38A88DD22A1A2F5DA8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Working Musicians Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDF0525684F944CFC93A04DAAE79AA60F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0EC201B8D0AE4455B3078A9B02D69330"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Music is a cultural treasure and a unique source of spiritual inspiration, emotional comfort, community connection, and joy. It is also a powerful economic driver that directly and indirectly supports nearly 2 million American jobs and almost $150 billion in annual economic activity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H745C754F5BB14B1CB6A0152F634BC0D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A healthy music ecosystem is a fundamental bedrock for a healthy society.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H668CFC62898B4BFF801F0E5CB52603C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Fair and competitive markets for the use and licensing of recorded music are integral to a healthy music ecosystem.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F3C17CC1CC74C8DA25205B16ED65068"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As music distribution has moved online, the market for use and licensing has become distorted and imbalanced. The largest Dominant Online Music Distribution Platforms use their market power to distort legal requirements and force music creators into licensing agreements that do not reflect market value. Those agreements essentially dictate a price to music creators. If music creators do not agree to licensing terms, the online platforms profit from unlicensed uploads of music anyway.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H416694A70EC94E9ABEC02664246653DB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These platforms game the system created by the Digital Millennium Copyright Act, which allows dominant online platforms to ignore and profit from unlicensed use of music and places the responsibility for finding each and every instance of unlicensed use of music on music creators. This <quote>notice and takedown</quote> scheme has been described as a gigabit-speed game of whack-a-mole.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H969BB00C0AFB42A8BC3E46219C214467"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The trade association for the major record labels spends millions of dollars engaged in this effort which it says has grown to be <quote>largely useless.</quote> The trade association for the independent record labels agrees, calling it a <quote>dysfunctional relic</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1898C2ED81947559AC437504732231F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An effort that is largely useless for major and independent record labels is an exercise in futility for Independent Music Creator Owners—those who own the copyrights and market their work themselves. Independent Music Creator Owners lack the economic, legal, and political resources to stand up to the Dominant Online Music Distribution Platforms and have no way to meaningfully negotiate fair licensing rates for their work.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA323572095F4F03B1BC66FDE30FB7C1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>That power imbalance means that Independent Music Creator Owners are forced to take whatever terms dominant online platforms offer for their work. If they decline, the platforms simply ignore them since in most cases lacking access to any single artists’ work does not present a threat to the platforms’ overall attractiveness to consumers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD78BB7AB120E427F84848D3DFD39EBF3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>This imbalance has decimated careers in music at an untold cost to our society and culture. Multi Grammy-award winning musician Rosanne Cash recently lamented: <quote>I see young musicians give up their missions and dreams all the time because they can’t make a living.</quote></text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FDF90E80A2C4B0BA644546BE9B34A33"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The antitrust laws were intended to and do provide important economic and civic benefits.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8377F712501F414791747919706BE19A"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A central purpose of these laws is to promote, protect, and strengthen fair and open markets, including those for music.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB86F2894BC044101AA70C309F566BC86"><enum>(12)</enum><text>While antitrust exemptions are generally disfavored, should the application of the antitrust laws ever be applied in a manner that conflicts with their purpose—such as protecting the online marketplace for creative works—it is the duty and prerogative of the Congress to resolve the conflict.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC7F5AB8C43FA4556981CE0F48602EE2E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Safe harbor for certain collective negotiations</header> 
<subsection id="HE39DC9B677F945078635016D48AFBA4B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2F607FCEE9D145C7B8191E91366692B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>antitrust laws</quote> has the meaning given such term in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>), and includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H75656CB899C2482083EBB722FE1BC45E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to the extent that such section applies to unfair methods of competition; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE65389A9155A4CBAA63F2D44BCCE7222"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any State law, rule, or regulation that prohibits or penalizes the conduct described in, or is otherwise inconsistent with, subsection (b) of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FA4C3FB1668449E9A4F02E450824F4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>Dominant Online Music Distribution Platform</quote> means any entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="H1CCD2930AE8F402C83333DAF18CAA9D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operates an app, website or other online service that is used by members of the public to listen to sound recordings, whether via a digital audio transmission, an audio-visual presentation, or any other means;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8321763D16B240A0B5261B2A691654A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has annual revenues related to the distribution of music of more than $100 million; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H699EF1B0354A44D09F83E1EB0779E536"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not eligible for a license under section 114(d)(2) of title 17 of the United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6F92A6B6A43478F82BE07CAC72CA33C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>generative artificial intelligence</quote> means an artificial intelligence system that is capable of generating novel text, video, images, audio, and other media based on prompts or other forms of data provided by a person. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEE0FAC5C7A94D379BBA5E59EC03747B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>Individual Music Creator Owner</quote> means any musician or group of musician, producers, mixers, and sound engineers that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H480EEB8EBE9543E6A5BEE03981B4E2C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>owns the copyrights to one or more sound recordings created by the musician or group of musicians, producers, and sound engineers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H212E94367CBE4E40A0CE6A923DBF0498"><enum>(B)</enum><text>either:</text> 
<clause id="H7427DBCC48D240ECB16E28C738282700"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has earned less than $1,000,000 in licensing revenues associated with these copyrights in the prior year; or</text></clause> <clause id="HD2BA7124B14D44228DE91CC705271814"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>qualifies as a small business under the Office of Management and Budget North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) code 512250.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H807FD4FE69CB482EB5582B7770A26A22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Individual Music Creator Owner shall not be held liable under the antitrust laws for agreeing with other Individual Music Creator Owners to collectively negotiate music licensing terms with a Dominant Online Music Distribution Platform or a company engaged in development or deployment of generative artificial intelligence, or agreeing with other Individual Music Creator Owners to collectively refuse to license their music to a Dominant Online Music Distribution Platform or a company engaged in development or deployment of generative artificial intelligence, if—</text> <paragraph id="H1367D600C8D64F73ACDF648255C45EBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the negotiations are not limited to price, are nondiscriminatory as to similarly situated independent creator/owners;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15B9B5CB4B374A21B89C1370713CBDEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the coordination among Independent Music Creator Owners is directly related to and reasonably necessary for negotiations with a Dominant Online Music Distribution Platform that are otherwise consistent with the operation of the Antitrust laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE478BA52F9C34B42A8CDF08A23B91C41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the negotiations do not involve any person that is not an Independent Music Creator Owner or a Dominant Online Music Distribution Platform.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H623D178F577F4D31B1B2E90E781B4B5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Except as provided in this Act, this Act shall not be construed to modify, impair, or supersede the operation of the antitrust laws.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

