<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC26304-H65-00-68V"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4139 IS: Baltic Security Assessment Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4139</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, to submit a report on emerging threats posed to Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDB89AC86507E441AB7A1580EB9CBCB4E"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA674FDFF21F84DA2936A19177A93C466"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Baltic Security Assessment Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H98B143F0FF09490C88B72633B96A9FD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H14AE3FD33FCB4D4B8D24E560DCA84A6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting and strengthening the security of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania (referred to in this section as the <quote>Baltic countries</quote>) is in the national security interests of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H007AF315AE1A4E328166D71C4F6C56AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continuing to strengthen and update the security cooperation roadmap for the United States and the Baltic countries is critical to achieving strategic security priorities as the Baltic countries face ongoing belligerence and threats from the Russian Federation, including amid the Russian Federation’s illegal and unprovoked war in Ukraine that began on February 24, 2022;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H182652DCA2274F6BBA64C477D103D9F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Baltic countries have been valued members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) and continue to contribute to NATO’s collective security and partnership; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39069A3334D94A468D7974DFA4845641"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improved economic ties between the United States and the Baltic countries, including to counter economic pressure by the People’s Republic of China, offer an opportunity to strengthen the United States-Baltic strategic partnership.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H448D1BF137D741B389E37ED8288DC7D6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on emerging threats to the Baltic countries</header><subsection id="idcd5e1a478d7b420390fbbcdc9d6070dc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on—</text><paragraph id="HC50318C5F5A94347A4CABC371DF835A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emerging military, cyber, hybrid, and political threats to the Baltic countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A0AA75E45004167BC4E9920779EB4DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the roles of the Russian Federation, the Republic of Belarus, the People's Republic of China, the Islamic Republic of Iran, and other malign actors in advancing such threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76286A8A3E2A4EADA5DD504AFDFE5BD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the current posture and presence of United States and NATO forces in the Baltic region for the purpose of deterring such threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93ab6c4291b7401ca66ae0267d6de3d9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for strengthening the deterrence posture, cybersecurity infrastructure, and democratic resilience of the Baltic countries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a46a63946eb4a41ba16db9af84dec89"><enum>(5)</enum><text>opportunities to enhance bilateral and multilateral defense cooperation between the United States and the Baltic countries, including through the Baltic Security Initiative established under section 1247 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/60">Public Law 119–60</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FD3621E95C14D9183152FE36508D99A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C129171EF594DCF8DAEFE59BB5C0A3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idfe0dcbdaa71d4edaaa0e7953236d8ea1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5e767efec93426fa6d5972988ed2c3b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

