<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1280239676F84786AD3ECC63E023C162" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8594 IH: Congressional Gold Medal For Inspiring Great Heroism and Tenacity (FIGHT) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8594</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to President Donald John Trump, to the United States Secret Service, and to its local law enforcement partners, in recognition of their dedication to protecting our constitutional republican form of government.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5A143B6C95514B219D4025A7C4AC11B6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAB03E6A79957416D84E1693A40E839AD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Gold Medal For Inspiring Great Heroism and Tenacity (FIGHT) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5D6A720600FA4AF19242970BAC3C4E8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HDCA5F4B317C0420287019A9B930D1183"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recent actions by President Trump, the Secret Service, and local law enforcement partners emphasize bravery, sacrifice, and an unwavering commitment to the safety and stability of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3689949262964CEEBD7BD70974D7D186"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On July 13, 2024, during a peaceful rally in Butler, Pennsylvania, President Trump was shot by a gunman who fired multiple rounds toward the stage which in addition wounded rally attendees and took the life of Corey Comperatore who died shielding his family from gunfire.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC7CFA5D2F9344D7DBF64131DD550A996"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On September 15, 2024, a second assassination attempt was thwarted in West Palm Beach, Florida. The vigilant advance work and rapid response of the United States Secret Service identified a concealed gunman armed with a scoped rifle. Immediate proactive engagement by Secret Service agents prevented the assailant from establishing a line of sight on President Trump, ensuring his safety and leading to the swift apprehension of the suspect by local law enforcement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76D274E2650A4738ACD879D0F3D8B420"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>On April 25, 2026, an act of political violence was prevented during the White House Correspondents’ Association Dinner at the Washington Hilton in Washington, DC. An assailant armed with a shotgun, a handgun, and multiple knives charged the security checkpoint outside the event ballroom. United States Secret Service agents fearlessly intercepted the threat. Simultaneously, protective details swarmed the ballroom stage to shield President Trump, executing a rapid and secure evacuation amid chaos.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89FCB5C7B8774FE3B6F3A0E525CE4F6C">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>These incidents reflect a concerning escalation in violent political rhetoric that seeks to undermine the democratic process by inciting hostility, division, and physical violence against political leaders. This reckless rhetoric created a dangerous environment that directly contributed to the acts of terror witnessed in Pennsylvania, Florida, and Washington, DC.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6CE934211F6B441EAF6FF6E3C69DB183"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Showing steadfast resolve in the wake of these violent incidents, President Trump has demonstrated bravery and fortitude, refusing to waver or neglect his duties. His unwillingness to bend to those who would do him and our nation harm provides vital reassurance to the American people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1A95749F4D549EB93EAC3C5CD02F304"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The agents assigned to the Secret Service Presidential Protective Division put their lives on the line, protecting the President every day. The courage, rapid reflexes, and dedication displayed by these agents exemplify the highest traditions of law enforcement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFF8296ACED4842448B97DB4B4C7B81E1">
        <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>Local law enforcement officers and first responders serve as an essential and integral part of the Presidential protection mission. By securing perimeters, managing massive crowds, providing specialized tactical support, executing rapid emergency medical responses, and aiding in the swift apprehension of violent suspects, State and local police forces act as vital force multipliers without which the safe movement and protection of the President would be impossible.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E35BA1AC5E744C2AF33D81864FB3AFA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The example set by President Trump and the daily resolve shown by the United States Secret Service and its local law enforcement partners serve to reassure the American people that our nation is and will remain strong.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9E277B4F5679401884AC9213A74EAB10"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> <subsection id="H278CF2CBFA484EF098E83002AC655BC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of Congress, of 3 gold medals of appropriate design to each of President Donald John Trump; the United States Secret Service; and its local law enforcement partners, of which—</text>
<paragraph id="H03F6747421EB475296CC5A6A41F14C04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 shall be presented to President Donald John Trump for public display as he sees appropriate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H810FE4545ADF4CE99DECEF8D24C6AD62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>1 shall be presented to the United States Secret Service for display in the United States Secret Service Museum; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H53D46192FCC64417AA23DCDEBFD47E43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>1 shall be presented to local law enforcement partners of the United States Secret Service for display at the National Law Enforcement Museum.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD7DC7BCABD184396A8887021DB2FEF31"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design and striking</header> <subsection id="H42A3C61D43C8427A8D03082BB8E50A82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of the award described in section 3, the Secretary of the Treasury (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5E6CB046E38B4DA8BF99DEA6470A7BEC">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Authority To strike duplicate medals</header>
 <text>The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to subsection (a), at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text>
      </subsection></section>
<section id="HFBF1E8D4D8A44FBF85507A9B1887A26B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header>
<subsection id="HF81AF87C290F438CB6C835AABCAD6320"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF84166B7804542CB89845115D556C702"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HD9BBF7E3E1B24BF1A8A79241E200330C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header>
<subsection id="H5587FE04FAD741A5B9A39F41499E5FF6">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Authority To use fund amounts</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="HC2B1DC7B83B34D2B8DC23C37D09A7FD6">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Proceeds of sale</header>
 <text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund. There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

