<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG26525-8PR-G3-H9W"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4659 IS: Election Security Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4659</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide additional election security funding to States providing voter registration information to the Department of Homeland Security.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idf308a12af2e44bc2bdf2e8dc8d3dd793" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Election Security Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id092e91022f6541f7a0a92314797b3ab1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increased election security grants for States providing voter registration information to the Department of Homeland Security</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38ade8daddd348babbbfbd41b46ff538"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any amounts appropriated under the 2026 election security grant program, there are hereby appropriated to the Election Assistance Commission for necessary expenses to make payments to eligible States in the amount determined under subsection (b) for activities to improve the administration of elections for Federal office, including to enhance election technology and make election security improvements, $20,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2c9808d4b6d424c9d5e95c7706a48ec"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount of payment</header><text>The amount of payment provided under this section to any eligible State shall be not more than 10 percent of the amount provided to such eligible State under the 2026 election security grant program.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62d0dc192acf4c5ca613ae8d18077d0a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd06fa535863c42dfbabb242f7816358e"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible State</header><text>The term <term>eligible State</term> means any State that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id142fba6cbfcc4d8e9daa208e36681838"><enum>(A)</enum><text>received a payment for fiscal year 2026 under the 2026 election security grant program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a49bfe5ec814ffea1c37bdfb7876268"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enters into a written agreement with the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide, not less than quarterly after September 30, 2026, the complete, official list of individuals registered as eligible voters for Federal office in the State to the Secretary for comparison through the Systematic Alien Verification for Entitlements (<quote>SAVE</quote>) system for the purposes of identifying individuals who are not citizens of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20c8b6014acd46a1a578aa0fe17aee7b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>2026 election security grant program</header><text>The term <term>2026 election security grant program</term> means payment made under the heading <quote>Election security grants</quote> under the heading <quote>Election Assistance Commission</quote> in title V of division E of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

