<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26508-SF8-V8-1M9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4540 IS: Reproductive Health Care Accessibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4540</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to improve reproductive health care of individuals with disabilities.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HECDAAA99E93A4C5DAADB3142BAF16B6D"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reproductive Health Care Accessibility Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6DBF4F641A984F6A9982788197A52803"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idabb8d27a1cc14d4a83c0ed5b252b86a2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the United States, approximately 1 in 4 adults have some type of disability, more than 1 in 10 individuals with disabilities can become pregnant, and over 4,100,000 individuals are parents with disabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48c2499f6f9d48cd9dacdd0d9007f7c0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>All people, including individuals with disabilities, have the right to decide if, when, and how to start and raise a family, as well as to have healthy pregnancies and postpartum periods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde6a8f2cb6944d298b1984edd125c650"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Titles II and III of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref> and 12181 et seq.), section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>), and section 1557 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18116">42 U.S.C. 18116</external-xref>) provide individuals with disabilities with the right to equitably access and receive health care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e8479275de04f86861da8223333e778"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Disabled individuals face unique barriers when accessing reproductive health care, including accessibility issues at health care facilities, lack of accessible medical diagnostic equipment, barriers to accessible travel, delay in receiving preventative services, and lack of health care providers with training and knowledge on the needs of individuals with disabilities receiving reproductive health care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id456c31668aa04f15955b908220f57c8f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Reproductive health care is critical to an individual's long-term health. Disabled individuals have higher mortality rates from reproductive related cancers often due to lack of access to reproductive health care, higher rates of maternal mortality and morbidity, and often experience earlier onset menopause.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id37a40bcd034947868a3246d683c296f4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The United States Access Board has established standards for accessible medical diagnostic equipment that were adopted by the Department of Health and Human Services and the Department of Justice in 2024. Awareness about the standards remains low among providers. Greater provider education, implementation, and enforcement of the standards is necessary to ensure equally effective reproductive and sexual health care for individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd62971268ee8434ab5925e1d2840877c"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Disabled individuals have an equal right to reproductive autonomy, but harmful stereotypes about individuals with disabilities create barriers to getting care that respects that autonomy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf91604d84f344c1f8b429a9595434d43"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Laws that restrict access to reproductive health care, including abortion care, disproportionally harm individuals who already face barriers to reproductive health care, which includes disabled individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf52825f4c04541dba157b78bb68eaaac"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Individuals with and without disabilities want children at the same frequency, but individuals with disabilities are less likely to receive contraception counseling and timely prenatal care, experience a higher rate of sterilization, and are at a greater risk for adverse pregnancy outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b94ca07446b414c86247cf9c3aabecb"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Diversity and inclusion in the health care workforce is a critical factor in the delivery of high-quality, culturally competent health care and improves patient outcomes. However, the rate of students and trainees with disabilities in medical and allied health education remains low compared to those without disabilities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id538576E65F6E403AB65E6BE33AE9E4F5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program for training the workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294">42 U.S.C. 294 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idAB8B82F581E04615BE06289D262A59FD"><section id="id8AA291FFA61C4837A2DEADD4806532D3"><enum>760A.</enum><header>Program for training the workforce concerning reproductive health care for individuals with disabilities</header><subsection id="idd15ac3656f0d4bdd83a6e4469bf42b27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and in consultation with the Administrator of the Administration for Community Living, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to carry out training programs for health care professionals and trainees on providing equitable sexual and reproductive health care for individuals with disabilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3A3301136D7A4CFB8B9CB989698C104F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><paragraph id="id6B41AEF00ECD4DA8928E70321E670E05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under this section, an entity shall be a public or private nonprofit entity with demonstrated expertise in serving individuals with disabilities, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id9c2db29125f2478aaa0b527804f798c8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a multidisciplinary health care provider who provides sexual and reproductive health care, such as federally qualified health centers and Title X clinics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9928a62df0a84f0fa467e0f3e712d75d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>institutions of higher education, as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, with expertise in sexual and reproductive health care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id99c34162cdb04c029d0542eec845e78d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity primarily led by individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida30af3a082a5455fb06e4bebb6ecc852"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity with expertise in reproductive rights and justice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc18fd54df32048e68032fbe9c566e3ae"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe, Tribal organization, or urban Indian organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id528a1f54004b41d1b44c6a2d7fb1a6e4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA560A85723614D7AB3D427E8B33F82B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, that includes—</text><subparagraph id="idbf88312b1525476facce00d72690e6fd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the eligible entity’s or consortium of entities’ expertise in providing technical assistance and training, including evidence such as—</text><clause id="idb28363ebd0564f6482c14e0bf6fa9de0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>knowledge of the rights afforded to individuals with a disability under relevant Federal and State law;</text></clause><clause id="id29e5142fb2ab46fb9c406427ab69366c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>knowledge of accessibility standards established by the United States Access Board;</text></clause><clause id="idefc98428bf6e4bd6acd8672b95d08e8d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>expertise in evidence-based or evidence-informed practices in providing trauma-informed sexual and reproductive health care, including preventive health care services and perinatal care, to individuals with disabilities and those facing compounded barriers to accessing care;</text></clause><clause id="ide7149f16fd0a4bf1969eef2fd3178aad"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>experience working with health care providers, public or private nonprofit entities, or Federal, State, or local agencies focusing on sexual and reproductive health care services for individuals with disabilities;</text></clause><clause id="ideb657adbb554417ea32918cd7276ba7e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>experience working with individuals with disabilities and their families;</text></clause><clause id="idf026e90754d441c09e59af699281dd37"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>expertise in providing, collecting, compiling, communicating, and disseminating sexual and reproductive health care information in culturally and linguistically appropriate manner especially in easily accessible formats; and</text></clause><clause id="id1f2dabc7c39046cfb66ae28d79421c8e"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>experience improving coordination of services, such as mental health, substance use disorder prevention, treatment, and recovery support services, social services, other health care services, and transportation services for individuals with disabilities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d92c6a6f9064a0e972e1d358c72ff80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the activities to be funded under the award and the goals of such activities, including a description of—</text><clause id="id8fc6de2a58344d63924e53d8a760c053"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the training or education program to be implemented that meets the requirements of subsection (c);</text></clause><clause id="id6c81d63a6511456d810a9df9944fc54c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the process to be used to identify health care providers that will participate in the training program, including the process to increase diversity in the pool of participating providers;</text></clause><clause id="id48407e4673c64cf6bd71fbf381fb8c17"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the process to be used to engage stakeholders in such training, including individuals with disabilities; and</text></clause><clause id="id596c37c842a84d7f976ddfa4492de6e6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the eligible entity’s evaluation plan to determine the scope and impact of the training program;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaafc4785bf1e404bb3d1da56af9bd703"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assurance that the recipients of the training will receive ongoing and comprehensive training or professional development on the sexual and reproductive health care needs of individuals with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id01689fc80cee4461929be3e58b15a34e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other assurances that the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9525395D13B84A6686C7243EBDF65A1B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subawards</header><text>An eligible entity or eligible consortium receiving an award under this section may, for contracting purposes, make subawards to individuals or entities with expertise in sexual and reproductive health care and serving individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3af0a48e842947c1a3026dd9ae0ded0e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity or entities shall use amounts received under this section to carry out a training program for health care professionals providing sexual and reproductive health care that provides training concerning—</text><paragraph id="idacc8bde8298c4e1ea7855f868c20ede2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>comprehensive disability clinical care curricula to inform health care professionals providing sexual and reproductive health care on how to provide effective, interprofessional team-based health care;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idccf1ee3b11bd48799509affa737b5a7d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>comprehensive clinical care curricula on how disability-based and intersectional discrimination shapes sexual and reproductive health care access and quality for disabled individuals, including historical and ongoing practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id326b8178fa5f4b59b6f3ea460e309f67"><enum>(3)</enum><text>culturally and linguistically competent care for individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd80f2fcd85db41be972b6b8f6b2f8c65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>delivering sexual and reproductive health care for individuals with disabilities in a manner that emphasizes the independence, self-determination, and choices of individuals with disabilities with respect to their sexual and reproductive health through comprehensive disability clinical care curricula;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id29d8f79255994fa1b9fbd7d9b131b5f4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the rights afforded to individuals with disabilities under relevant Federal and State law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3178e28efaa42cabb4e061b51dec7af"><enum>(6)</enum><text>methods and evidence-based or evidence-informed practices for providing sexual and reproductive health care, including preventive health care services, to individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id968344a6b824440f955a93e64b41feca"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header><paragraph id="id161CDE28C02D4C23959970E3A88F065B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity or entities that receives an award under this section shall, at the end of the award period, carry out an evaluation of outcomes achieved through the program in training health care professionals providing sexual and reproductive health care, consistent with the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcdac5cd2e84c41518a51c33e3eccb9e1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of the award period, an entity that receives an award under this section shall submit to the Secretary a report on the results of the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id217b9eb860d442c88f71990c78a1c8f8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall annually compile the reports submitted under paragraph (2) and submit such compilation to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives. Such compilations shall be posted on the internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services in an accessible format.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5233EBDA549341B29D88AA73309B1296"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id94f282a04b454a88b6156e8e84bf0dec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The terms <term>disability</term> and <term>disabilities</term> have the meaning given such terms for purposes of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb746f0193d8d492ba472b5bf76184e3b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06A97D83F7384C0993E65DF436288D0C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Urban Indian organization</header><text>The term <term>Urban Indian organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5302c25a2aaf4d6fb608fa4121a68cf6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. Funds provided to carry out this section shall supplement not supplant funds otherwise made available to carry out this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id650F43AF03134136BE5FE1A3F8C921AA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Program for expanding the reproductive health care provider workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293">42 U.S.C. 293 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDC6DAD6FEAE84253ADA10A95F0B0500B"><section id="id8DA65F703DF84C84B2F7C1BB11BCB240"><enum>742.</enum><header>Program for expanding the reproductive health care provider workforce</header><subsection id="id7F0BA0820485496BA01D78DE92E4ED23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this section—</text><paragraph id="id161444c124ed49138b94204aad446223"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish and sustain a competitive health professions applicant pool of individuals with disabilities by increasing the total number of individuals with disabilities who pursue a career in sexual and reproductive health care, including abortion care and maternal health care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf46d5527a6f0440884a9a22a191cf9db"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to develop a culturally and linguistically competent health care workforce providing sexual and reproductive health care that will serve unserved and underserved populations, including individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide89417cf0c5145c8afceb0c20cd48f8a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards</header><text>To assist individuals with disabilities in undertaking education to enter into the sexual and reproductive health care workforce, the Secretary may award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to public or private nonprofit health or educational entities, including schools of medicine, schools of osteopathic medicine, schools of nursing, and other institutions of higher education, that offer programs, including graduate programs, in obstetrics and gynecology, comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care, or programs for the training of health care providers to enable such entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="id091f3aa48e6b43b7a0fe79c153e79095"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under subsection (b), an entity described in such subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3a2f2264eeac4f35be2851ba2592b4cc"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity shall use amounts received under an award under subsection (b) to—</text><paragraph id="id56d1d936c6354be995a3a0a2fdebe592"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct or support activities to develop a competitive applicant pool, through partnership with public or private nonprofit institutions of higher education, local educational agencies, health care providers, such as sexual and reproductive health care providers and primary care providers, or other community-based entities, and establish an education pipeline for individuals with disabilities entering the sexual and reproductive health care workforce;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id038cc8861ab447bd9fa18386b318f65f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish, strengthen, or expand programs to support the academic performance of individuals with disabilities participating in activities funded under this section, including mentorship programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc64fb8d4d2043d4bfb8d06e074f549e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify, recruit, enroll, and retain individuals with disabilities in education and training related to sexual and reproductive health care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ba52ab4d0dc4c699787e0377207fa4b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve the capacity of the entity involved to train, recruit, and retain faculty with disabilities including the payment of such stipends and fellowships as the Secretary may determine appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id36f15191a0fc48be93e0498aec6043f0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carry out activities to improve the information resources, clinical education, curricula, and competencies of the graduates of the entity involved, as it relates to individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0804cfb4b0f24636a61f0c661c7bcfab"><enum>(6)</enum><text>facilitate faculty and student research on health issues affecting individuals with disabilities, including research on issues relating to the delivery of sexual and reproductive health care to individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id936d3de1f06d433cad7bc94c7c6c3c0c"><enum>(7)</enum><text>carry out programs, or offer experiences, to train students in providing sexual and reproductive health services to individuals with disabilities at community-based health facilities that provide sexual and reproductive health services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d4eacd82d8245adb4acae53fc92ea0b"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provide stipends to individuals with disabilities participating in activities funded under this section as the Secretary determines appropriate, in amounts as the Secretary determines appropriate, with an assurance that such stipends shall not result in loss of an individual’s Federal or State benefits; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef4a94732d204d5791c1926237b5edee"><enum>(9)</enum><text>carry out any other activities that the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6bc829756dcf4a54824e685047aff3fc"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to applications that have been approved for programs that involve a comprehensive approach through multiple entities described in subsection (b) to establish, enhance, and expand educational programs that will result in the development of a competitive applicant pool of individuals with disabilities who desire to pursue careers in sexual and reproductive health care services.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7d8d515d591943fcad69cd04c883972f"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consideration for awards</header><text>In awarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="id0A7D8C74570E4BACA4A0968BDF11A2FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider current enrollment trends and the needs of certain populations, including individuals with disabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc150ed6e673643ed93807a40d3de3a7e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>align and coordinate with other training programs administered by the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA2C202DAFD384935B01E46912F9196E3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Effect on other programs</header><text>Assistance or stipends provided to an individual under this section shall not be considered when applying asset or resource limitation provisions related to the eligibility of such individual for any benefit, assistance, or service provided under any Federal or State program.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide56243a06cf44127ab5b4d15d6cd932e"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of the award period, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report concerning the activities carried out under this section to increase the representation of individuals with disabilities in the sexual and reproductive health profession and related training programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="idD1D3ED2838BD45AAB0C8377DAD02F98B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. Funds provided to carry out this section shall supplement not supplant funds otherwise made available to carry out this title.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" id="id25951C5539644A7697AF65920554FEA7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expanding the reproductive health care nursing workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 821 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/296m">42 U.S.C. 296m</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d5bff4146254f18b435c5e7807e86bf"><subsection commented="no" id="id8ddf58d5c924442198896261641b6679"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expanding the reproductive health care nursing workforce</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idff1006b11ed34b469effb5de8e855331"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Awards</header><text>To assist individuals with disabilities in undertaking education to enter into the reproductive nursing workforce, the Secretary may award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under subsection (a)(1) to eligible entities to enable such entities to carry out the activities described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id673058b46e2f4492a5c84592757cb8a3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under paragraph (1), an entity described in such paragraph shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idca0ea798978e4268ac4f697fd837e2cc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity shall use amounts received under an award under paragraph (1) to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id62a53ca7ffc4429d81f1e63203a34329"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct activities to develop a competitive applicant pool, through partnership with public or private nonprofit institutions of higher education, local educational agencies, nurse-managed health clinics, health care providers, such as sexual and reproductive health care providers and nurses, or other community-based entities, and establish an education pipeline for individuals with disabilities entering the sexual and reproductive health care nursing workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idb6c937b2fab04a91971349d61ef05cee"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish, strengthen, or expand programs to support the academic performance of individuals with disabilities participating in activities funded under this subsection, including mentorship programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id5f54fcb1c7664fbaacee55eb55c14837"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify, recruit, enroll, and retain individuals with disabilities in education and training related to sexual and reproductive health care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idfb33170e1e594a82b48d1c100c75278c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>improve the capacity of the entity involved to train, recruit, and retain faculty with disabilities, including the payment of such stipends and fellowships as the Secretary may determine appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idc472d72f93614d628bfef4b609f2c2eb"><enum>(E)</enum><text>carry out activities to improve the information resources, clinical education, curricula, and competencies of the graduates of the entity involved, as it relates to individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id15ec26596b5c4318a20ffe264da83675"><enum>(F)</enum><text>facilitate faculty and student research to include evidence-based practice and quality improvement projects focused on health issues affecting individuals with disabilities, including research on issues relating to the delivery of sexual and reproductive health care to individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idcd246e9eb93a46a2927229974578a40a"><enum>(G)</enum><text>carry out programs, or offer experiences, to train students in providing sexual and reproductive health services to individuals with disabilities at community-based health care facilities that provide sexual and reproductive health services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1f02f5a527124f0fab8a1a0b7324d5c4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>provide stipends to individuals with disabilities participating in activities funded under this subsection as the Secretary determines appropriate, in amounts as the Secretary determines appropriate, with an assurance that such stipends shall not result in the loss of an individual’s Federal or State benefits; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idabbace643c924f00b20ca6c7e31728e5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>carry out any other activities that the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idfe9884b96c954367bd1ca153b653f3b6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In awarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under this subsection, the Secretary shall give preference to applications that have been approved for programs that involve a comprehensive approach through multiple entities described in paragraph (1) to establish, enhance, and expand educational programs that will result in the development of a competitive applicant pool of individuals with disabilities who desire to pursue careers in sexual and reproductive health care services.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id4078df2ef032479c910c5ee457db88dd"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration for awards</header><text>In awarding grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id69c0190063c740d489c9be49b2cb4bdf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider current enrollment trends and the needs of certain populations, including individuals with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idcb1e9afd59954a7ea32cc36298cabc73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>align and coordinate with other training programs administered by the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id679D9FBBBADB48FEA9C87E3C6B748BB3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Effect on other programs</header><text>Assistance or stipends provided to an individual under this subsection shall not be considered when applying asset or resource limitation provisions related to the eligibility of such individual for any benefit, assistance, or service provided under any Federal or State program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id3b7e64deed62410ebb8fe2bb8a401507"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of the award period, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report concerning the activities carried out under this subsection to increase the representation of individuals with disabilities in the sexual and reproductive health profession and related training programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id5acedab4464a429cb51c6294d28f664b"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection, $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. Funds provided to carry out this subsection shall supplement not supplant funds otherwise made available to carry out this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idEF488F24CA5E4FFD96505468324ACF72"><enum>6.</enum><header>Program for reproductive health education</header><subsection id="id0db242c15bcb4fafa77b70da93fb512b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and in consultation with the Administrator of the Administration for Community Living, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to provide funding for education programs focused on sexual and reproductive health needs for individuals with disabilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="idF492034BF6CB447285722F7B6D36C7CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><paragraph id="id9E293C118FC841E2A8B1CEB025D99963"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under this section an entity shall be a public or private nonprofit entity with a demonstrated expertise in serving individuals with disabilities, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="ided3f34eab83e44be94eb85d979585263"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a multidisciplinary health care provider who provides sexual and reproductive health care services, such as a federally qualified health center or a Title X clinic;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3c35e8fed5f4535a94d4b02718c2620"><enum>(B)</enum><text>institutions of higher education, as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, with expertise in sexual and reproductive health care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40a03b8ab22047f19d28baf1b6fd6869"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity primarily led by individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4cae9acd768e47b2a74cb9d0971e4a34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity with expertise in reproductive rights and justice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccaaaad4ede24d4b97023e0c416228e9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe, Tribal organization, or Urban Indian organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id483074c99d33404992fc2e5d98ca356b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id221494e324c1454d96f18341918b10d8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity or consortium of entities shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, that includes a description of the eligible entity’s or entities’ expertise in providing education programs including evidence that such entity has—</text><subparagraph id="id9e630c2a64304c61a9441836e3665ab5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>knowledge of best practices in providing sexual and reproductive health care, including preventive health care services, to individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23484637ae10402c8e90a9aba2a999b9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experience working with individuals with disabilities and their families; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b7825c6cf9945df9d55bd4222dbb25b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrated expertise of developing materials in culturally and linguistically accessible formats including plain language.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD0CE7B7841A2481AA7F00522DCB05013"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subawards</header><text>An eligible entity or eligible consortium receiving an award under this section may, for contracting purposes, make subawards to individuals or entities with expertise in sexual and reproductive health care and serving individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id35dab6e63f8c467e921422e5be32701f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An entity shall use amounts received under subsection (a) to—</text><paragraph id="ida3794c63ce144f7291fee4a90744fc7b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out evidence-based or evidence-informed sexual and reproductive health education programs for individuals with disabilities, including youth, in culturally and linguistically accessible formats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b2d41204a774683a983441eefb40803"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop sexual and reproductive health education programs in culturally and linguistically accessible formats to be used in carrying out paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ff51655516c43619ce022ea8d8564f8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide education to individuals with disabilities, including youth, concerning abortion care options and their sexual, reproductive, and perinatal health care needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fa36b00a5504d2ea89909046c040838"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide education to individuals with disabilities, including youth, concerning their rights under relevant Federal and State law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb15ad62de7e54a9382ef1e542c09e6b4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide access to disability affirmative and supportive clinical resources that are accessible to individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7bdad782a1c472f96866375f6083558"><enum>(6)</enum><text>build the entity’s capacity and enhance their leadership of the entity within the community to promote community engagement in, and advancement of, evidence-based or evidence-informed sexual and reproductive health care education in easily accessible formats; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id786a36c62a4049e5acc60d5ae1fabfc9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>support dissemination of newly developed sexual and reproductive health care education programs as described in paragraph (2) throughout the State, territorial, and Tribal communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idFAF9505E380F46E9A174CD7EECA8F672"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header><paragraph id="id3E4FC8BFBF6C4C3BA61F4BF9A55E98A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity that receives an award under this section shall, at the end of the award period, carry out an evaluation of success of the entity in achieving the goals of the program for which the award was made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8FE4CBF0F120437FB4F36471962B10D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of the award period, an entity that receives an award under this section shall submit to the Secretary a report on the results of the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEF94FD89526D4403A51B6CF35DA255F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall annually compile the reports submitted under paragraph (2) and submit such compilation to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives. Such compilations shall be posted on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services in an accessible format.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id609E4C147FBD471FA1762FCE15E712F3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id748e3f40a1e343cabdfc25fe37aa47df"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The terms <term>disability</term> and <term>disabilities</term> have the meaning given such terms for purposes of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida51a3707211741168bab015b79f2444d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a102bf065ec43ebb46131333140f931"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Urban indian organization</header><text>The term <term>Urban Indian organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD5CCDF58DD4E4A248C533E285F6A7054"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><section id="id70F0C665BD48446F835AFC17FE16F77D"><enum>7.</enum><header>National Technical Assistance Center</header><subsection id="id7327babd7d964c158257cf6251c747e9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration for Community Living, shall directly, or through a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, establish a National Technical Assistance Center to—</text><paragraph id="idad088fb408334274a09577d6821fdc5c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide recommendations and best practices to States, territories, Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, and Urban Indian organizations concerning improving coordination of services including mental health and substance use disorder services, social services, health care, and transportation to increase access to quality, integrated systems of accessible, comprehensive disability clinical care, and services for individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6818bc295a8040fea843f98f4eb7dd0e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to health care providers on culturally and linguistically accessible and appropriate sexual and reproductive health care, including before, during, and after pregnancy and perinatal care and family planning services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9930142d5c944093bf7afed02f30c7cd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop resources and provide technical assistance to assist covered entities in complying with applicable Federal laws and regulations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2088495e3b1940c7bbdf3909c721df55"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop resources for individuals with disabilities facing barriers to accessible care, including related to accessible medical diagnostic equipment and the Barrier-Free Health Care Initiative.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id05E2FC60EB5748168CF96ED9D4630149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id6821066E8C1A44BDA5D6BC60CEA53718"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The terms <term>disability</term> and <term>disabilities</term> have the meaning given such terms for purposes of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id216EF82667C84DD79AC22CF630DCD32D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9B7001C8CC124B8AAC58675AADC12D18"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Urban indian organization</header><text>The term <term>Urban Indian organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1603">25 U.S.C. 1603</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8E118661C7D446B1ABE7AB1B5A773BC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><section id="id35686A4ED4114C529528965ADB377F17"><enum>8.</enum><header>Research study</header><subsection id="idDD53847D8FBA404A89D32F0781DFDF18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Administrator of the Administration for Community Living, shall carry out a study to—</text><paragraph id="id77f6969baf65407d956efb70ccec3dd3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify the types of programs and services that have demonstrated effectiveness in providing sexual and reproductive health care services for individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7bf16ceed814218b1136a11948d4c6c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyze the effectiveness of Federal, State, Tribal, and local partnerships to coordinate efforts to ensure an integrated system of accessible, comprehensive sexual and reproductive health care for individuals with disabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f35789250044aa9977379c35eb9a2e2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify necessary memoranda of understanding or interagency agreements that are needed to foster data and public health research focusing on sexual and reproductive health care barriers for individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id574ca78e18ec40449f8b17b7ea97d2ba"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id033c651941274307a1986e9c4871a996"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section the terms <term>disability</term> and <term>disabilities</term> have the meanings given such terms for purposes of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="ida202c845a8d642f0adaa953d795a3447"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $15,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

