<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC3744219F1E44E62BC1E6F63B833EC46" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7729 IH: Shared Utility Rewards for Grid Efficiency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260226">February 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Power Act to require the issuance of rules relating to shared savings frameworks for certain transmitting utilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE3F02861EE0144D585233A2BE689FBD5" style="OLC"><section id="H2E638E24645541D48D568893CBA7C42A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HB5FB81086DC9469B81833AD1C083FE84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shared Utility Rewards for Grid Efficiency Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SURGE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5DFD66507ED745388D7BD8635155DC3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H2E638E24645541D48D568893CBA7C42A" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC6DF50A5F2B14308A964BBAE3CCFEB1E" level="section">Sec. 2. Amendments to the Federal Power Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3C2C8CFD3DEC463FB3E0B497A3A1FE28" level="section">Sec. 3. Shared savings framework rule for transmitting utilities subject to Federal Energy Regulatory Commission jurisdiction.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H16A799FA638E4344A20EB73D558E7A5D" level="section">Sec. 4. Guidance for electric utilities not subject to Federal Energy Regulatory Commission jurisdiction.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBF432F78E364491980F1DF93F495C6E4" level="section">Sec. 5. Grant program for State regulatory authorities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3090589AFDC94BE78CACE00D3DAC1EDE" level="section">Sec. 6. Studies on effects of certain rate treatments and alternative frameworks.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCEEC681DA2AC4CB38AA8707B59AD1275" level="section">Sec. 7. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HC6DF50A5F2B14308A964BBAE3CCFEB1E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to the Federal Power Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 219 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824s">16 U.S.C. 824s</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H40DAAE8BBFA547AE9DAA80766606979E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H55D15143CBE44CD7A1CF795F4CEB3215" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission shall establish, by rule,</quote> and inserting <quote>The Commission shall issue such rules as may be necessary to establish</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE520E1D864D746C88E3AF68144A67479" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, improving efficiency,</quote> after <quote>ensuring reliability</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0EC5B6907B496E8BEAC4A3DBDBE097"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H42B56C3F472E433FAC69621E7C6DC819" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>The rule shall</quote> and inserting <quote>The rules issued under this section shall</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10B40F005A234896847C689F1E0E9C16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, and operational improvements for,</quote> after <quote>capital investment in</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4980E2525AF4BDB8BB538FBC2995683"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H347063A609AE45B4A67F123817736BD5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or other incentive mechanism</quote> after <quote>return on equity</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HF4C2F36C45C94E98A2DAD713D1A07DB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or incentivizes improvements that increase the efficiency of the transmission of electric energy and reduce costs for consumers</quote> after <quote>(including related transmission technologies)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB0022D536734549AD5404C1F9997783"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>, including performance-based measures,</quote> after <quote>other measures</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C60391D8236439B87E9344004D856C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><clause id="H4A8E91D25026484692A70B34C00BE52F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="H4294297AB6CB4129887A6B84CED14C93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HB91265220D6A42B9B7E37655E9361584"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H48C2A4A3BBB747619B19B3EAE9F37FF2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H00568DBF1781415D99571976A36CE0FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amounts determined pursuant to shared savings frameworks or other incentive mechanisms prescribed in such rules.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BCB5DBBB54C4D9290038EB6AC574F05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>In the rule</quote> and inserting <quote>In a rule</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3C2C8CFD3DEC463FB3E0B497A3A1FE28"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rulemaking on shared savings framework for transmitting utilities subject to Federal Energy Regulatory Commission jurisdiction</header><subsection id="HA8EF718F56D8454D964FE4A24A714F37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall issue a final rule under section 219(b)(3) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824s">16 U.S.C. 824s(b)(3)</external-xref>), as amended by <internal-xref idref="H2E638E24645541D48D568893CBA7C42A" legis-path="1.">section 2</internal-xref>, that establishes a framework under which a covered transmitting utility may recover a portion of verified cost savings attributable to a qualifying action of such transmitting utility as an incentive (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>shared savings framework</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H347456F4865E481FBE2CDFF5E5BF065A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methodologies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall develop and include in the rule under subsection (a) standardized methodologies, applicable across similarly situated transmission segments, as follows:</text><paragraph id="HB1F22266EA044279BD81575C7929BC06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Baseline performance methodologies</header><text>Methodologies, developed in consultation with the Secretary, for covered transmitting utilities to determine the annual baseline performance of transmission facilities or transmission segments absent qualifying actions—</text><subparagraph id="H07D6272B7CF04E9E94ABC492B387C5E9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by measuring the baseline performance of such a transmission facility or transmission segment—</text><clause id="HED55016543BB420F944A5811FF76B28A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through the actual amount of electrical energy entering and leaving such facility or segment (commonly referred to as <quote>direct metering</quote>); or</text></clause><clause id="H91899DB0F20A4D5DA3ACB0C0852C6324" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the method under clause (i) is not feasible, through an estimation of such amount consistent with modeling methodologies prescribed by the Commission; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB2ADBC1DBE845A09829DDE1BE55D2EF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by normalizing data to ensure such baseline performance accounts for variability in exogenous factors determined by the Commission, such as variability in—</text><clause id="HC78A60DCA57E4B56AC50DDA0EE1FEE49" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>weather;</text></clause><clause id="HE1CB0BF478D04679A731B8CDDDFF80EC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demand over time;</text></clause><clause id="H17D85A4D858445C0BCEA0A13C691B95A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>upgrades, interconnections, or operational changes made by other utilities, Independent System Operators or Regional Transmission Organizations, or other entities determined relevant by the Commission; or</text></clause><clause id="H5F007E1AD089485EAE1F3D56158C95B0" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other conditions affecting demand or generation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED3ABC05629D419C86F4DAEA87E6F1E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Methodologies relating to cost savings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Methodologies for covered transmitting utilities to estimate and calculate, and for independent evaluators to verify, the cost savings attributable to qualifying actions under the shared savings framework, taking into account—</text><subparagraph id="H089AEBF2BC3E42C2BB7795C660646F74" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the baseline performance of any transmission facility or transmission segment with respect to which a qualifying action is conducted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73688AF8A0014363AB088F296AE3156B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">price proxies, determined according to a methodology prescribed by the Commission, for the value of electric energy transmitted (which may include, for a region managed by an Independent System Operator or Regional Transmission Organization, the locational marginal price corresponding to the location on the electric grid where an injection or withdrawal of power is modeled (commonly referred to as a <quote>pricing node</quote>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19ADF00646674E8D934AB1130033D3BD" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Methodologies relating to recoverable percentage and rate recovery timeline</header><subparagraph id="H84B2686350E7479C8DE24FBB28E2E8C2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Methodologies for covered transmitting utilities to determine, taking into account the factors described in subparagraph (B), the following:</text><clause id="H4070670B037F43AEA08F2A8C74A74829" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total percentage of cost savings attributable to a qualifying action that such a utility may recover as an incentive under the shared savings framework, which may not be less than 10 percent or greater than 60 percent of such total attributable cost savings (in this section referred to as the <quote>recoverable percentage</quote> of such savings).</text></clause><clause id="HE4FF1FFBA5064275855BC9D14C0B55E1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period of time during which such a utility may recover amounts as an incentive for such an action, which may not be shorter than a 2-year period or longer than a 5-year period (in this section referred to as the <quote>rate recovery timeline</quote> for such action).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67D10DDBFD0A40FCAAA8375555F45B46" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The factors described in this subparagraph are the following:</text><clause id="H5E5D24AE3C82480DA342CA0DF8BFC137" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent of financial or operational risk to be assumed by a covered transmitting utility in conducting a qualifying action.</text></clause><clause id="H1D81703985CE4D008AD112E713ED791B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The baseline performance for transmission facilities or transmission segments with respect to which such action is to be conducted.</text></clause><clause id="H2BBCE9EF2573497DB8A47D9CD24D32F0" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The replicability or demonstration value of such action.</text></clause><clause id="HA5B19CA4117F4973B3B026D9590E6E43" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duration of cost savings predicted to result from such action and whether such cost savings will remain consistent over such duration.</text></clause><clause id="HD30CDFAB266F4786B84DD1E55A5979A3" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which such action is expected to result in additional benefits, such as improvements to the resilience or the reliable operation of the bulk-power system, reductions to transmission congestion, or reductions to greenhouse gas emissions.</text></clause><clause id="H77A2AA601E204477B0224EA5D2956CCF" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Such other factors as the Commission may determine relevant to ensure the incentive is performance-based, transparent, and cost-effective.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H956130398BE844CD989DFBB5AE510D2F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial filing required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be considered for an incentive under the shared savings framework for the conduct of a qualifying action, a covered transmitting utility shall submit to the Commission an initial filing, the contents of which shall be verified by an independent evaluator determined appropriate by the Commission, that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="HC5DEE65EFEC3400691F9D01E21781534" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the baseline performance of any transmission facility or transmission segment with respect to which such action is to be conducted for the one-year period preceding the date on which such conduct is to be commenced, determined by such utility pursuant to an applicable methodology under <internal-xref idref="HB1F22266EA044279BD81575C7929BC06" legis-path="3.(b)(1)">subsection (b)(1)</internal-xref> (including the data underlying such calculation).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H838F6B63FD5D45DF8BA7152BE9FB4D99"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of such action, including an analysis of improvements expected to result from such action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEE78E25694548FBBBD460912FA191C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rate recovery timeline for such action and the recoverable percentage of cost savings attributable to such action, determined pursuant to an applicable methodology under <internal-xref idref="H19ADF00646674E8D934AB1130033D3BD" legis-path="3.(b)(3)">subsection (b)(3).</internal-xref></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67823DA95A91438BB6519D3E76958B99"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate, developed pursuant to an applicable methodology under <internal-xref idref="H956130398BE844CD989DFBB5AE510D2F" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (b)(2)</internal-xref>, of the cost savings to result from such action for—</text><subparagraph id="HDA183DC209CA451FB1450EC1547019B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the one-year period beginning on the date on which the conduct of such action commences; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69183B0CB4AF4D1BA5F53B187F9E9488" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the duration of the rate recovery timeline for such action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85776451C06C455FB24729F1814B122A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claim for 50 percent of the recoverable percentage of cost savings estimated under paragraph (4)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H534FEA7555184D6BAC2091FDB536E34A" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An agreement by such utility to file with the Commission the annual reports required under <internal-xref idref="H13D607D25CB64B9A8FEAB4B3BB617E72" legis-path="3.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>, the contents of which shall be verified by an independent evaluator determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13D607D25CB64B9A8FEAB4B3BB617E72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reporting required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning one year after the date on which a covered transmitting utility submits an initial filing for a qualifying action under <internal-xref idref="H956130398BE844CD989DFBB5AE510D2F" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, and on an annual basis thereafter until the end of the rate recovery timeline for such action determined under paragraph (3) of such subsection or until such action no longer results in cost savings, whichever occurs first, such utility shall file with the Commission a report containing, with respect to the qualifying action of such utility, the following:</text><paragraph id="H171708C34CE64567AD562531E3EAF5E2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data on the performance during the preceding year of any transmission facility or transmission segment with respect to which such action was conducted, and a comparison of such performance to the baseline performance of that transmission facility or transmission segment determined pursuant to an applicable methodology under <internal-xref idref="HB1F22266EA044279BD81575C7929BC06" legis-path="3.(b)(1)">subsection (b)(1)</internal-xref> for such year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BF1C6C79E4F4355AEDDB06FE671C10F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The actual cost savings attributable to the qualifying action for the preceding year, calculated pursuant to an applicable methodology under <internal-xref idref="H956130398BE844CD989DFBB5AE510D2F" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (b)(2)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96DBCAAB6D5D41E9879DD14D7A9411A5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If such utility expects cost savings to result from the qualifying action during the following year, an estimate, developed pursuant to an applicable methodology under <internal-xref idref="H956130398BE844CD989DFBB5AE510D2F" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (b)(2)</internal-xref>, of the cost savings for such following year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6276ECC20FA4559972716019501C99E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A claim for the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2D53C34FE49A4A30AC1CB36A8BD87200" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An amount that is the recoverable percentage of the actual cost savings for the preceding year calculated under paragraph (2) minus any amount previously recovered based on an estimate of cost savings for such year under <internal-xref idref="H2D210A99844F4747B36DB2CABF45DFA3" legis-path="3.(e)(1)">subsection (e)(1)</internal-xref> or <internal-xref idref="H9EC8BFB0A4E440809D61756D14D85784" legis-path="3.(e)(2)(B)">subsection (e)(2)(B)</internal-xref>, as the case may be.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D5EA80F64F549A286A5CD0DB067961F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the report includes an estimate of cost savings for the following year under paragraph (3), an amount that is 50 percent of the recoverable percentage of such estimated cost savings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0509B95DF2141CFA16D1A5A47401F62"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If such utility finds that the total amount recovered for a year under <internal-xref idref="HCF5E2E47FA2F4CBBAC38333FD551E751" legis-path="3.(e)">subsection (e)</internal-xref> exceeds the amount equal to the total recoverable percentage of the actual cost savings for that year under paragraph (2), an identification of the excess amount.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF5E2E47FA2F4CBBAC38333FD551E751"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recovery mechanism</header><paragraph id="H2D210A99844F4747B36DB2CABF45DFA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rate adjustment based on initial filing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receiving an initial filing of a covered transmitting utility under <internal-xref idref="H956130398BE844CD989DFBB5AE510D2F" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, the Commission shall provide to such utility a rate adjustment under which such utility may recover the amount claimed under <internal-xref idref="H85776451C06C455FB24729F1814B122A" legis-path="3.(c)(5)">subsection (c)(5)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B6452EAC095451AA9B1FEEF22624583"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rate adjustment based on annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receiving an annual report of a covered transmitting utility under <internal-xref idref="H13D607D25CB64B9A8FEAB4B3BB617E72" legis-path="3.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>, the Commission shall provide to such utility a rate adjustment under which—</text><subparagraph id="H9B83C94475F647C9ADB81572C8EE6E43"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to paragraph (3), such utility may recover the amount claimed under <internal-xref idref="H2D53C34FE49A4A30AC1CB36A8BD87200" legis-path="3.(d)(4)(A)">subsection (d)(4)(A)</internal-xref>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EC8BFB0A4E440809D61756D14D85784"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the report included a claim under <internal-xref idref="H9D5EA80F64F549A286A5CD0DB067961F" legis-path="3.(d)(4)(B)">subsection (d)(4)(B)</internal-xref>, such utility may recover the amount so claimed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD913DDB3A837460E88B6AB70BF56B03F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reconciliation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a utility identifies an excess amount under <internal-xref idref="HF0509B95DF2141CFA16D1A5A47401F62" legis-path="3.(d)(5)">subsection (d)(5)</internal-xref>, or the Commission determines the information reported for that year under <internal-xref idref="H13D607D25CB64B9A8FEAB4B3BB617E72" legis-path="3.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref> is insufficient for purposes of this subsection, the Commission shall credit the difference to ratepayers through a rate adjustment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D65F1B6F8B541BCA3EAF6BE23BB3EC5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding additional rulemakings</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HEADDFBF164BC48869CB0617D2FC7F7EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">following the issuance of the rule under subsection (a), the Commission should revise such rule, or issue additional rules under the authority of section 219(b)(3) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824s">16 U.S.C. 824s(b)(3)</external-xref>), as amended by <internal-xref idref="HC6DF50A5F2B14308A964BBAE3CCFEB1E" legis-path="2.">section 2</internal-xref>, to expand the shared savings framework to additional categories of measurable, demonstrable, and verifiable covered transmission actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E306B2E96B434D82E029C173134C02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any such rule should include a version of the methodologies developed under <internal-xref idref="H347456F4865E481FBE2CDFF5E5BF065A" legis-path="3.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref> adapted for such additional categories; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2FB9557D93B40A79F2AF8833DFFB967"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any such rule should take into account the findings of the most recently conducted study under <internal-xref idref="H3090589AFDC94BE78CACE00D3DAC1EDE" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H16A799FA638E4344A20EB73D558E7A5D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guidance for electric utilities not subject to Federal Energy Regulatory Commission jurisdiction</header><subsection id="HCC77A6200CAD4BD39E3E134129001F2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Commission and State regulatory authorities, shall develop and publish on a publicly available website of the Department of Energy guidance to support State regulatory authorities in establishing frameworks under which covered electric utilities may recover a portion of verified cost savings attributable to a covered utility action as an incentive.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7B706151CE84573B47BAAB4CF2D991E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum elements</header><text>The guidance under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HF34CC96FE5A84221AEAD434108C64702"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance, developed in accordance with <internal-xref idref="HAAC55D84268842CB812605EB196B8BF4" legis-path="4.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, for determining the baseline performance of a covered electric utility absent a covered utility action;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C7345F69B3249B8AA0D05A58524581A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance, developed in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H87EBB4F548B646C789E6ECC9E85BF27F" legis-path="4.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>, for determining the cost savings attributable to a covered utility action;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55D58D3E703D4010B564DA359C4D3765"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance for the measurement and verification of a covered utility action, and any cost savings attributable to such action, by an independent evaluator determined appropriate by the State regulatory authority concerned;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88E57B7EC77246D4806F9A1D9A87C79E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance on potential mechanisms by which covered electric utilities may recover a portion of the verified cost savings attributable to a covered utility action, including through the provision of rate adjustments by State regulatory authorities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H898B5357211E458BBB4728ED802205AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other elements as the Secretary determines appropriate to ensure the framework specified in subsection (a) is transparent, performance-based, cost-effective, and consistent with State ratemaking practices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAC55D84268842CB812605EB196B8BF4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Methodology for determining baseline performance</header><paragraph id="HB45DC9F9DED44CA29EA31F0F1081DA2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In developing the guidance under <internal-xref idref="HF34CC96FE5A84221AEAD434108C64702" legis-path="4.(b)(1)">subsection (b)(1)</internal-xref>, the Secretary, in coordination with the Commission, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H75E09ED3C76C46B0816103E0EFF47254"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with State regulatory authorities, Independent System Operators, Regional Transmission Organizations, and independent evaluators determined appropriate by the Secretary regarding such guidance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H907CEB590EC043D38035EAAA4BAD30AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include in such guidance technical guidance for normalizing data to ensure the baseline performance of a covered electric utility accounts for variability in exogenous factors, such as variability in—</text><clause id="H07A2DA31F0F3474A9B6F3035DE2D58A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>weather;</text></clause><clause id="HB0DF1FF3687F407F942E495FD306DBF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demand over time;</text></clause><clause id="H68F586D124BD48079EC91CEEB8025DB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>upgrades, interconnections, or operational changes made by other utilities, Independent System Operators or Regional Transmission Organizations, or other entities determined relevant by the Commission; or</text></clause><clause id="H8CC89907A3F04BDFBC8EC52D0A45DC8B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other conditions affecting demand or generation, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E69019D2E86452A8F990843A6DB3921"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure such guidance supports consistent treatment across covered electric utilities within each category described in <internal-xref idref="H2A54AC6F27FA45C5ABEDD60DC3A62D28" legis-path="4.(e)">subsection (e).</internal-xref></text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D1EE48AB328434C96C97C4F3D979BA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Support from National Laboratories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Laboratories shall provide such technical support as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87EBB4F548B646C789E6ECC9E85BF27F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance on determining cost savings</header><text>In developing the guidance under <internal-xref idref="HF34CC96FE5A84221AEAD434108C64702" legis-path="4.(b)(1)">subsection (b)(2)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HA0894F4DCD4A4A26BFBBE7A455D3E9AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include in such guidance—</text><subparagraph id="H888AD88D555A4EBF8034E51256481F09"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">principles to ensure that cost savings attributable to a covered utility action are calculated in a manner that takes into account price proxies for the value of electric energy and the baseline performance of the covered electric utility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC543A345FD444927A811AD07D30477A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">tools, technical support, and reference data to assist State regulatory authorities in applying the principles specified in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA0C41B17B184C7DB3C71A8DC7201023"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure such guidance supports consistent treatment across covered electric utilities within each category described in <internal-xref idref="H2A54AC6F27FA45C5ABEDD60DC3A62D28" legis-path="4.(e)">subsection (e)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A54AC6F27FA45C5ABEDD60DC3A62D28"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability to utility market structures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out <internal-xref idref="HCC77A6200CAD4BD39E3E134129001F2B" legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall develop separate guidance for each category of covered electric utilities as follows:</text><paragraph id="HE0C238DF5DB649FF9968A530034919B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Vertically integrated utilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A668E64404F4CD28F5F8790127DC068"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered electric utilities that own or operate transmission infrastructure but not distribution or generation infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H844A0158CB094ED2B43FC5EF389AEA34"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered electric utilities that own or operate distribution infrastructure but not transmission or generation infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DA5D30D50B94A2F9F2D5DEDD399A248"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered electric utilities that own or operate distribution and transmission infrastructure but not generation infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0FFD7E66D6C4D168FA275DB9E431D8E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Revisions</header><text>Upon the publication of each report under <internal-xref idref="H3090589AFDC94BE78CACE00D3DAC1EDE" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall determine whether to revise the guidance under <internal-xref idref="HCC77A6200CAD4BD39E3E134129001F2B" legis-path="4.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, taking into account the contents of such report and the recommendations included therein.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBF432F78E364491980F1DF93F495C6E4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grant program for State regulatory authorities</header><subsection id="H713E2DBEA9454BF88833557E2698F12A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary may award grants to State regulatory authorities to support the development, implementation, and oversight by such State regulatory authorities of frameworks under which covered electric utilities may recover a portion of verified cost savings attributable to a covered utility action as an incentive (in this section referred to as the <quote>grant program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA2C66C7F9C5543A9A703DC2C3D1FCB93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized uses of funds</header><text>Amounts awarded under the grant program may only be used to conduct the following activities:</text><paragraph id="HE9F828D7412B4528BCF461D9DC926D2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development of a framework referred to in subsection (a), or revision of an existing such framework, such that the framework is consistent with the guidance developed under <internal-xref idref="HE3F02861EE0144D585233A2BE689FBD5" legis-path="4.">section 4</internal-xref>, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF361A342D1B140E28B354CDC53818C17"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development, including the design or modeling, of methodologies consistent with the methodologies set forth under such guidance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC62A8DCB0BF42F8AEDFFEE7D0FB5167"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development of data systems or other tools necessary for the development of the framework.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H306F7732716D47AAB6EE73CF51A0673E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The issuance or revision of regulations necessary for the development of the framework.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56A61992625541968848054594489D4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The engagement with stakeholders with respect to the development of the framework.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D2F190A9F9E4306BD7D5BD64EB53E90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The implementation or oversight of a framework consistent with such guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1C978A5651D42DBB34DC3D13C167591"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibited use of funds</header><text>No amounts awarded under the grant program may be used to pay a covered electric utility.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F7C338FDF9B432E9BE35E9F39071846" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant recipient reporting requirement</header><paragraph id="H1E6FB0858FBB42099ABCB2798ED57B74" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of receiving amounts under the grant program, a State regulatory authority shall agree to submit to the Secretary, on an annual basis for the duration of the period in which such State regulatory authority expends such amounts, a report describing the activities carried out using such amounts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF72A7135E9FD4B139D4A9F4DA83352BC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a grant recipient fails to submit a report required under paragraph (1), such recipient shall be ineligible for additional awards under this section until the report is submitted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08A8BFAB99D5465C9FA95DD545F07F8C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration of program</header><paragraph id="H72EDC1A696DA4AE5A8A9469A7F1C6AA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technical support; public registry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the grant program, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H330AA7CDEF2046EAA8D1C0CB148A6F61"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to grant recipients technical assistance in support of activities conducted using amounts awarded under the grant program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E685BF88F544BA1A03C2E6251E421CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain a publicly accessible registry of the activities so conducted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04AA8A9EF2DA4ED3870379A3EBDAF142"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting by Secretary</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, and biennially thereafter for the duration of the grant program, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="HC82C632BDF8E4D84B9EF20FBEFEDBE1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the activities conducted using amounts awarded under the grant program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H863716F4C32E4EC2A197DC0720DFCDD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of any framework implemented using such amounts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84AFF3E455824949AD49DF84C6357B42"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of any barrier to the development, implementation, or oversight of a framework consistent with the guidance developed under <internal-xref idref="HE3F02861EE0144D585233A2BE689FBD5" legis-path="4.">section 4</internal-xref> and recommendations for addressing such barrier, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E1D75D81699467BA372CCAA7B5E9344"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text>Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary to carry out the grant program—</text><subparagraph id="H8611DF4A7F7D48C48BAF3DD0B4EE09FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 70 percent may be awarded for the conduct of activities under <internal-xref idref="HA2C66C7F9C5543A9A703DC2C3D1FCB93" legis-path="5.(b)">subsection (b)(1)</internal-xref>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7D9D50566B74C4B886FB5BD01C5649E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 30 percent may be awarded for the conduct of activities under <internal-xref idref="HAC62A8DCB0BF42F8AEDFFEE7D0FB5167" legis-path="5.(b)(1)(B)">subsection (b)(2)</internal-xref>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BCD7A9C240645998F67F9592A277118"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than five percent may be obligated or expended for Federal administrative expenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3090589AFDC94BE78CACE00D3DAC1EDE" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Studies on effects of certain rate treatments and alternative frameworks</header><subsection id="H49B25AF2AEA647588961168C1C565A7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Studies required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every five years thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, shall—</text><paragraph id="HF22B8AEAF60B4225904E9E2E27A95C32"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a study on—</text><subparagraph id="HEBA2ED1AC8594682A1898E6541CC7618"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inefficiencies in the electric power sector incentivized by existing rate treatments for the transmission of electric energy and any economic, environmental, or societal effect of such inefficiencies, including with respect to the customers of electric utilities, the reliable operation of the bulk-power system, and the deployment of cost-effective grid-enhancing technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8F3B59575B1489AB53B5B46B5DE47E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alternative frameworks for incentive-based, including performance-based, rate treatments for such transmission, such as the alternative frameworks described in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC356381F5CB84A35BB9C9C04C6E22811"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish on a publicly available website of the Department of Energy, and submit to the appropriate congressional committees, a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H445AF677FEC641DD839AD10D902B2701"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed description of the findings of such study; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10EDB560108A45D3ADF3C31B210A4141"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations of the Secretary to align rate treatments for the transmission of electric energy with the goals of lowering costs for the customers of electric utilities, enhancing the reliable operation of the bulk-power system, reducing transmission congestion and other inefficiencies in the transmission or delivery of electric energy, and encouraging the deployment of cost-effective grid-enhancing technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FEC6E174953441C8EB41B62987297DE" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Examples of alternative frameworks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The alternative frameworks described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H40C44435007C4D999D814085F4A09144" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Shared savings frameworks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DE59975CF66451C98BF546D9BCC16C4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Revenue decoupling models, under which authorized revenues of utilities are separated from volumetric sales of electricity to reduce disincentives for energy efficiency and programs to reduce the consumption of, or peak demand for, electric energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EDC3BD28ABE4AFDB65AF7128A08006C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Return on equity adjustments, under which authorized utility returns are increased or decreased based on measurable factors such as risk profile, performance outcomes, or efficiency improvements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EA82212B9FF4A229B405DF439948EAD" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Multi-year rate plans, under which revenue requirements and performance expectations for utilities are established for a fixed multi-year period rather than through single-year rate cases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F4FEF9B271A4BDFA0397E65FB6B2FDD" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Earnings sharing mechanisms, under which earnings of utilities falling outside an authorized range as compared to the return on equity are shared between shareholders and ratepayers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6BA08F80D3D4949B3574AC19F3A721E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Total expenditure models, under which capital and operating expenditures of utilities are treated on an equivalent basis to reduce bias toward capital investment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2338F826777143D1951E418DE6E371B1" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Performance scorecards, under which utilities are evaluated against transparent outcome-based metrics such as reliability, affordability, equity, or the reduction of emissions, with results informing regulatory decisions or incentive adjustments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H044A6EC78A8D4C12B72A9EC10D3A567E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that each study under subsection (a) is informed by—</text><paragraph id="HCE2DD0B6D3824510BF73E2A28B18FA93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reports filed with the Commission pursuant to sections 3 and 5 of this Act and section 304 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/825c">16 U.S.C. 825c</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD7E1C02F6547F9BCB55D9FCF9287AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant reports issued by the National Laboratories; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B9DF5065E6401AAEB23C34ECA5C2D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such other studies, reports, and other data sources as the Secretary may determine appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCEEC681DA2AC4CB38AA8707B59AD1275"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD6D00E2642BC49E0B09D08E629D07E3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced conductor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>advanced conductor</quote> means an electric transmission conductor that, relative to a conductor being replaced on a given transmission or distribution line, is designed to substantially improve electrical or mechanical performance through the achievement of at least one of the following criteria, as determined by the Commission:</text><subparagraph id="HA0FA525E51764EA2A5B88B88E26667B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A substantial increase in current-carrying capacity under normal operating conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B29D9377DE436E947FDEEC5B519445"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A substantial reduction in electrical resistance or line losses under normal operating conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87C50EE4DD1D42A188CBCEE2F7E65C74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Operation at materially higher continuous allowable operating temperatures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4E06565FECE4EBFA108EA93657DBECC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A reduction in thermal sag or mechanical constraints that enables increased use of a transmission segment or facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB43164686F204BECA478DDBB19022D9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H026B59A63D884E9BADB7950EF8C09F8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB350198E134F4713A4E318994446FD8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94D21D9B15B24C5F87FC6A0F65D14981"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Bulk-power system; electric utility; Independent System Operator; Regional Transmission Organization; State regulatory authority; transmitting utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>bulk-power system</quote>, <quote>electric utility</quote>, <quote>Independent System Operator</quote>, <quote>Regional Transmission Organization</quote>, <quote>State regulatory authority</quote>, and <quote>transmitting utility</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E7DCC406224666952DBE3691EC1413"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEEA75CF45AE4D149600AC438EDEF28D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered electric utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered electric utility</quote> means an electric utility not subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission for ratemaking purposes under Part II of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824">16 U.S.C. 824 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DAD1E0802AD449C80B9614E3CF1D442"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered action</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H3EEDF82A78874DC1A9D8151D4EC69C64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an action that would generate cost savings for ratepayers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93498510254C457B801BA171E3F8BD55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the construction of a new facility or the complete reconstruction of an existing facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73C26301328A44888F1ED3A1B4D4244C" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Covered transmission action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered transmission action</quote> means a covered action to improve the efficiency, capacity, reliability, or resilience of one or more transmission facilities or transmission segments, including through—</text><subparagraph id="HFA3D58D0A65D45E092497C8DC77B78F1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the replacement of a conductor on a transmission line within such a facility or segment with an advanced conductor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H539BB01195934D5586AA9FFFA6886267" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the deployment of a grid-enhancing technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC395F307C04E4503BF1C76293CC95707"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Covered transmitting utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered transmitting utility</quote> means a transmitting utility subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission for ratemaking purposes under part II of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824">16 U.S.C. 824 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA920D3799CFD4BBAA41202D1DCA51890"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Covered utility action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered utility action</quote> means a covered action taken by an electric utility to—</text><subparagraph id="H0F2C1671F1CB4513B61FF70FE086834C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the efficiency of the generation, transmission, or distribution of electric energy, including by reducing the proportion of electrical energy lost during such generation, transmission, or distribution (including through the deployment of energy storage systems or other technologies); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD74E94A94FF43308EFE3838797A87C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduce the consumption of, or peak demand for, electric energy, including through—</text><clause id="H5A4BEF2A210E4ABFB7D8CCD33C2DB2C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a technological improvement, such as the deployment of high-efficiency appliances, smart thermostats, distributed energy resources, or building retrofits;</text></clause><clause id="H2C614BE5002945658EC0966DEB3BB6CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the establishment of a pricing mechanism to encourage customers of the electric utility to reduce such consumption or shift such demand to non-peak hours; or</text></clause><clause id="HCF3CE05FEE3343E1A1477F03EA455C37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other action or program to incentivize or otherwise produce such a reduction or shift in demand.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04B0D8791BBE440988FC1131BBA730E7" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Grid-enhancing technology</header><text>The term <quote>grid-enhancing technology</quote> means any hardware or software that—</text><subparagraph id="HDC7393BFEA3547F2A1A31BDC953CD6E9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increases the capacity, efficiency, reliability, resilience, or safety of transmission facilities and transmission technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD417F8385B2D45C7B7479816D9B7BC6F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is installed, in addition to transmission facilities and transmission technologies, for the purpose of—</text><clause id="HDD1D9542804C4662909742B39B00AD56" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing operators of such facilities and technologies increased situational awareness and control over the electric grid;</text></clause><clause id="HCDDCE15951DA4B76AB88E9EFA6A7B82D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving the efficiency of such facilities and technologies;</text></clause><clause id="H365C7FEDF8EE48D785D6764CBD6F0F5E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the transfer capacity of such facilities and technologies; or</text></clause><clause id="HAA9F2AAA016544DBACE588E45DF7FCC3" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise enabling the increased use, or more efficient of use, of such facilities and technologies under normal operating conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65AC3D8FB66446FBAEDD12601ED65B8D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Qualifying action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualifying action</quote> means a covered transmission action achieved through the reduction of transmission physical losses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28F92230713243E7A035D007727F9433"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDA82EC7AF1E43EC84D008F1770BCD67"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Similarly situated</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>similarly situated</quote>, with respect to transmission segments, means transmission segments that the Commission determines share comparable characteristics, such as voltage class, geography, load profile, or historical performance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC97F648943C472C92547A387907F02D"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Transmission physical loss</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>transmission physical loss</quote> means the amount of electrical energy that enters a transmission segment but does not exit such transmission segment, as measured over a prescribed period of time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFB6462E9AEC47E5A071A9D57FF5B2B6" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Transmission segment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transmission segment</term> means a functionally distinct portion of an interconnected transmission system (such as a single transmission line or multiple transmission lines within a prescribed zone, such as between prescribed substations), for which the amount of electrical energy transmitted and the amount of electrical energy lost during such transmission may be independently measured, as determined by the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2B7095E1A704F4EBFA0B03DD0D2A219"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Vertically integrated electric utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>vertically integrated electric utility</quote> means a covered electric utility that—</text><subparagraph id="H51614A0885014204813E08481A062047"><enum>(A)</enum><text>owns and operates generation, transmission, and distribution facilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA569EED85C9448B39D48D05B85D1C0D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directly provides retail electric service to end-use customers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

