<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F62379E54B34D1D825A3C5F172CC731" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 897 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives to support the rights of youth in the foster care system.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 897</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives to support the rights of youth in the foster care system.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas a 2020 National Health Statistics Report found that adults aged 22–44 who have ever been in foster care were twice as likely to lack either a high school diploma or a GED compared to their peers who have never been in foster care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a report from the First Star Institute gave 11 States <quote>D</quote> or <quote>F</quote> grades on their legal rights for foster youth;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a study by Casey Family Programs of foster children in Oregon and Washington revealed that one-third of foster youth reported maltreatment by their foster parent or another household adult;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a study from the Department of Health and Human Services found that Black and indigenous children are overrepresented in the foster system and less likely to exit to a permanent home than White children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas experts agree that social workers offer critical support to both foster youth and families, promoting a healthy living environment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a study from the National Institutes of Health found that extensive informed consent requirements for low-risk research activities may contribute to a lack of research on foster children that may in part contribute to this population being at a higher risk for poor physical and mental health outcomes; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a 2020 brief from Casey Family Programs reported that sibling separation slows adjustment to their new home and negatively impacts academic performance: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H31EB58DBFAC646019F7FACE6805026BC"><section id="H7C6F71B99E5F43D9B63BCB4AD81BD777" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that foster youth should have the right—</text><paragraph id="H8E80138F8FB1428A98D6FEF926E22EC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to receive an education and, if they so desire, remain in their original school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C495D1628AB4927BF8C91E96F08286E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to participate in extracurricular, cultural, and social activities appropriate to their age and developmental needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72031357E0764104AFBF3F99528BB498"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to receive needed health services, including medical, dental, vision, and mental health services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9CD6DE637B644EDAACF5FA0E16842B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to freedom from abuse, neglect, or corporal punishment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A16C572F64449DE88B84B7207F0765A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to be represented by, and to be able to speak to, a guardian or attorney ad litem;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H820227B77BDC4BA4BDB4CC2AB5199A2E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to adequate and healthy food, adequate clothing, and a safe and comfortable living environment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31A2AE567DFC4DED90CD7AB9055BCC10"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to freedom from discrimination based on race, gender, religion, or disability;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB434DF62158E49A7BD1CA7D8A526BF7C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to maintain, if they so desire, continued contact with their siblings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96CA22EE85F1478AAC2BCB373C4E6F56"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to regular and reasonable contact with their assigned caseworker or an employee of the agency responsible for their child welfare services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A3E9E210D8049ADA0234621BF6BD88C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to be informed of their rights.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

