<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3CFB28AE28D54DDF8F4EDD15AF348AE4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1326 IH: Denouncing corruption in all its forms.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1326</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Denouncing corruption in all its forms.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas 3 quarters of Americans think United States Government corruption poses a critical threat to the vital interests of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public trust in government is near historic lows;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas only 17 percent of United States adults say they trust the Federal Government to do the right thing just about always or most of the time;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a vast majority of Americans, regardless of their partisan identification, view unlimited political spending as weakening democracy and believe wealthy donors have too much power in elections;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a vast majority of Americans support anticorruption rules that strengthen democracy and constitutional rights by ensuring everyone has equal political representation, regardless of money;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas corruption, self-dealing and dark money in our political system undermine public confidence in the democratic process and democratic institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the revolving door between the private and public sector can create conflicts of interest that prioritize special interests over the public good and reduce the public’s confidence that their representatives are working for them;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas using public office to attack political enemies and for personal enrichment are hallmarks of autocratic and kleptocratic regimes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas using public office for personal enrichment through insider trading, foreign licensing deals, gifts from foreign nations, and the sale of various cryptocurrencies corrupts the basic oath taken by elected officials to serve the American people and further erodes the public’s faith in government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas promising industries favorable policies, tax incentives, and an end to regulatory oversight in exchange for extensive campaign donations further drowns out the voices of the people and increases the risk of systemic corruption; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas providing pardons to individuals who have provided millions of dollars in donations to associated political action committees (PACs), special projects, and inauguration funds creates a system where political donations can cancel out justice and further erodes the public’s trust in our systems of government: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF83467AA5A57438BA739E69BF3C7FA2E"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HFF48AA54AF9346AD9493102647252577"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives denounces corruption in all its forms and opposes the implementation of policies that benefit special interests and corrupt politicians at the expense of the American people.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

