<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H90A9EEFB7DB042BF86BAE41764196006" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 845 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of the week of November 2 through November 8, 2025, as “Drowsy Driving Prevention Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 845</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of the week of November 2 through November 8, 2025, as <quote>Drowsy Driving Prevention Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention defines drowsy driving as <quote>operating a motor vehicle while fatigued or sleepy</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas drowsy driving creates serious risk on the road by making drivers less attentive, slowing reaction times, and affecting his or her ability to make decisions;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Safety Council considers drowsy driving to be a profound impairment that mimics alcohol-impaired driving in many ways, including impaired attention, mental processing, judgment, and decision making;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas studies show that being awake for 18 hours results in impairment equivalent or worse than a blood alcohol content (BAC) of 0.05 percent and being awake for 24 hours results in a BAC of 0.1 percent, higher than the legal limit of 0.08 percent BAC in all States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Sleep Foundation advises that healthy adults need between 7 and 9 hours of sleep per night;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas drivers who work the night shift, work multiple jobs, or have irregular work schedules are at increased risk for motor vehicle crashes caused by drowsy driving;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Sleep Foundation found that 60 percent of adult drivers reported driving while drowsy in the past year and an estimated 1 in 25 adult drivers (aged 18 or older) reported having fallen asleep while driving in the previous 30 days;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 328,000 crashes and 21 percent of all fatal crashes annually, 6,400 deaths per year, involve a drowsy driver;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration conservatively estimates that 100,000 police-reported crashes each year are caused primarily by drowsy driving and that such crashes result in more than 1,550 deaths, 71,000 injuries, and $12,500,000,000 in monetary losses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas numerous States across the Nation promote and participate in Drowsy Driving Prevention Week;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Drowsy Driving Prevention Week informs communities about preventative measures against drowsy driving such as improving overall sleep habits and avoiding medication that causes drowsiness;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the goal of Drowsy Driving Prevention Week is to reduce the number of drivers who drive while sleep deprived; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas drowsy driving deaths are preventable, and lives can be saved through awareness, prevention, and intervention: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8EB1C7057DEF4C0598FFA413E1376966"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1029C9DE554D4FC6AA2353535FAC87DC"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H9FF8C3A432014024BD8F1554251BDE13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>Drowsy Driving Prevention Week</quote> to raise awareness about the dangers of drowsy driving; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AEC051AE3D54F5AA33DC0CFECD09BFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages people across the United States to take preventable steps against drowsy driving.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

