<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2DF788545D040C48D595F432C673869" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9071 IH: Preventing Trafficking of Minors Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9071</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to clarify and expand the prohibition on coercion and enticement to include patronizing or soliciting a minor for a commercial sex act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17B671992EEC48C6A39D9250CB9EBA37" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8786D82FA6C347C8B2664DBC2243651F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Trafficking of Minors Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB4515BAF45874787BCE5862534C5AB58"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to coercion and enticement statute</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2422 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA1C93B9CBAFD4E6CA205643087FA50AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>Whoever, using the mail or any facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce, or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States knowingly persuades, induces, entices, or coerces any individual who has not attained the age of 18 years, to engage in prostitution or any sexual activity for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense, or attempts to do so</quote> and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF1BF15D14CFF4288925A995A27956F85" style="OLC"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Whoever, using the mail or any facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce (including the telephone or internet), or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, knowingly—</text> <paragraph id="H9AD85D4B1E3C42A9B99EE81A6FEBA232"><enum>(1)</enum><text>persuades, induces, entices, or coerces any individual who has not attained the age of 18 years to engage in a commercial sex act or any sexual activity for which any person can be charged with a criminal offense;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58A9FC5D149D470ABCE338F94FC03BEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engages in a commercial sex act with a minor;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B6AC7F1C9CF4C6593FB18D5CBBF9AF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solicits, offers to patronize, or patronizes a minor for a commercial sex act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CFC4E1CA4C64BBBAC8DF386BA93A688"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pays, agrees to pay, or offers to pay any person for the purpose of engaging in a commercial sex act with a minor;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF42A16E7BAD24997A8561BAB5B3C4E62"><enum>(5)</enum><text>enters or remains in a place with the intent to engage in a commercial sex act with a minor; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80895911FA7442C5B250299F9EAE405E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attempts to commit any offense described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of this subsection</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55216418680C44769D8B1C45C456DAC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H23DCB164CAA64F5C86964B375D3A2B00" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HF0FC61661400455D893C48C0542E21FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Knowledge of age</header><text>It is not a defense that the defendant did not know the victim’s age or reasonably believed the victim to be 18 years of age or older. If the defendant had a reasonable opportunity to observe the victim, the Government need not prove that the defendant knew that the victim was under 18 years of age.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H317EBC907D0F436AB4B70926C2C828A7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No requirement of force, fraud, or coercion</header><text>Proof of force, threats of force, fraud, or coercion is not required if the victim is a minor.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB315BAF6A98F47EABDC3389D042C3204"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No defense based on law enforcement involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall not be a defense to prosecution under this section that the purported minor was, in fact, an undercover law enforcement officer or an individual acting at the direction of law enforcement representing themselves as a minor.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H783C0729CA8C40178ACA06E1759B874D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAA9EB84BF1A84B478489A5939264D834"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>commercial sex act</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1591(e)(3);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF99C1C1F0CB649BB91FA6130CACE746D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>minor</quote> means a person under 18 years of age; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H544CB17251BE47D9BD2416B6916E4766"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>sex act</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>sexual act</quote> in section 2246(2), and includes sexual contact as defined in section 2246(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09CBE5D3F57D43FAB593AED1C5D0D7F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b), as amended by paragraph (1), by striking <quote>shall be fined under this title and imprisoned not less than 10 years or for life</quote> and inserting <quote>shall be fined under this title and imprisoned not less than 10 years (or 15 years if the minor is under 14 years of age) or for life</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H43F7CFA6E8A2407DA24261F436012168"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment and shall apply to offenses committed on or after that date.</text></section> <section id="H8E6E3E59F75640BCBBDD8F90DEEBA9AB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provisions of this Act to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

