<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL26222-J67-8H-NL8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4386 IS: Apprenticeship Data Value Improvements to Create Employment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4386</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish an advisory committee regarding data standardization and integration for apprenticeships, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Apprenticeship Data Value Improvements to Create Employment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ADVICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id454cbec621fb494396b77fc4b6641768"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of an advisory committee regarding apprenticeships</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0febc7f22e144b419e1707a675aefb47"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established an apprenticeship advisory committee within the Department of Labor (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2fb1d09ae9340a382a376c1c7e4c0ce"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall appoint to the Committee—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideac54ae6d06344c5921dc2dcfefc91b8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>4 members representing State workforce agencies, of which 2 members shall be from States with a State apprenticeship agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c5ae4bcdc0c4270a31297dc8a02c177"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 members representing statewide longitudinal data systems that specialized in privacy, security, and interoperability;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7027c10ce7934e41a22cd2a079994c27"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 members who are sponsors of a registered apprenticeship program, of which 1 member shall be from a sponsor that is an intermediary;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id405da7f45f654b4eb8122e2b9ba1ad33"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 members that are sponsors of a registered apprenticeship program who represent industries with a historically low proportion of registered apprenticeship programs that experienced a high growth of such programs in the 5 years before the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b18a600b4b445b8bff5ca82b4ec1ef8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 members representing labor organizations and labor-management organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida98096551a9a4c639cbafdc84fd711fb"><enum>(6)</enum><text>2 members representing industry, of which 1 member shall be from an industry with a historically low proportion of registered apprenticeship programs that experienced a high growth of such programs in the 5 years before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9166a2dcf9bc4bb89333750d8be37dd7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>2 members representing institutions of higher education institutions that work with sponsors of registered apprenticeship programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ID49FC1DF7437F4D65827F32F3B59A5C61" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period of appointment; vacancies</header><paragraph id="id074CAA8C186848F69A84BF8EB7E8B53B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Committee shall be appointed for the life of the Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ABA6BEF0A7647CD9CF8FFBE31E586FA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in the Committee—</text><subparagraph id="id76B0CB8404734FF6A1DF2A252ED8694F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Committee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id484DA57A7CD74ED1BC86CBF65528ABB5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id72e37123f95a443f81e07dc7e78f1f2f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Committee shall submit a report with recommendations to the Secretary of Labor and Congress that includes the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf2462a1597cf4f8d9904de6f7266d24c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recommendations to incentivize and permit States to increase the standardization, integration, and interoperability of registered apprenticeship program data with—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4fc8954ab0fa4ac6b840238c11c04f80"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Workforce Integrated Performance System of the Department of Labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id157b0a246c30432f85949e1284f81955"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State wage interchange system of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id261134681c8341919d5b76bce84c5c5d"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data collection for the Consolidated Annual Report of the Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education of the Department of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id437ab43a4d32443aba22d7639220fc21"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unemployment insurance claims data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd49503ef51c40c1b3125b8536aff3f5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local career and technical education management systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1841cd4e3d3f4ffcb147dc268caeb4a9"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">higher education attainment data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id56b4fc6fd8714f1d9bd52ee79b90d8dd"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the data collected for purposes of the temporary assistance for needy families program under section 611 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/411">42 U.S.C. 411</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf0085300b0848aeb6c06fabf23a92a1"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the data collected for the quality control database of the supplemental nutrition assistance program under section 16 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2025">7 U.S.C. 2025</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idecc5d645290a48a2b98296dcca519ee3"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the data collected for the transformed Medicaid Statistical Information System (T–MSIS) (or a successor system);</text>
          </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id5497d29c41e5421189ee1648dc9e626a">
            <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the data collected for the National Housing Preservation Database (or a successor database);</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a598bdb61814e78ae7b49e1dd6d74a3"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">social services data not otherwise described in this paragraph; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9832aa18ba8f4a02bd9644f1987823de"> <enum>(L)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other systems determined by the Secretary of Labor to be appropriate for workforce data standardization.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d6699f9d0e545d4af57bd434003ea01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations to increase such standardization and integration by—</text><subparagraph id="id228096a217144e2cb336060e26204782"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving user interface and user friendliness;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d623812fda444b7b8ffba487c8d932e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lowering the burden on sponsors to meet reporting requirements, including by—</text><clause id="id544b93b6e6fd46fd8aa6a7f5ef53a483" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lowering the amount of software a State is required to use to collect, input, and transfer data to Federal offices; and</text></clause><clause id="idddf0bcf3ec9a4a328dff9caf4ccbb24b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lowering the human hours needed to conduct data collection and aggregation;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51d8e501e4f44bf896936bb34a4ceaa4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving the timeliness and accuracy at which data is collected; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb065c5566ffa4bb6bb0719ecc819c4f7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>preparing States to report data to the Department of Labor in a standardized format that reduces the need for duplicative input.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id641796b6077744f3ac0c0b39297f086b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations to incentivize and establish a mechanism for registered apprenticeship programs to collect outcomes-based data, including for—</text><subparagraph id="id9bb8519258324940bcd670e8211a9803"><enum>(A)</enum><text>statistics on retention when an apprentice completes an apprenticeship and within 5 years of the apprentice completing the apprenticeship; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b627af63a7943ed96144cf98dbae9d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>statistics on pay during and after the apprenticeship program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida83446ff805b46508cc17aef8f9f6cfe"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations to—</text><subparagraph id="id2e163cf7c0654309ae69fd3850cbfa03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>better track the outcomes-based data of paid training programs that are not otherwise a registered apprenticeship program, incorporate related technical instruction into the program, and pay participants in the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6611b1a0f63a4735b4daa346e7f6565d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage incorporation of such outcomes-based data into State longitudinal data systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcde579de320d4a158763e41e95b50e5e"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations to incorporate registered apprenticeship program data into the individual data for students in elementary and secondary education and postsecondary education and individual analysis of such data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d2b370401e64c92923f7d58c4b22bfd"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recommendations to encourage the inclusion and analysis of registered apprenticeship program data within statewide longitudinal systems (as described in section 208(a) of the Educational Technical Assistance Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9607">20 U.S.C. 9607</external-xref>)), to ensure that data is accurately and efficiently managed, analyzed, disaggregated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b06c9e000aa437e9dde4b4558f6ebea"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Recommendations to increase the access of an individual to their own learning and employment records.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a2cb264be134172b123493c55ac6e71"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Personnel matters</header><paragraph id="id315ba540e24d4daf87b402651c3b27d6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>Upon determination of need by the Committee, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, a Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Committee without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19f735a8b690467bb090425a2de39d95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id169931d20d7d4b8aa948b517c6a7eb7c"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="id2c90d5c20ad8490e97b7a82dc878384f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>registered apprenticeship program</term> means an apprenticeship program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4b457bb4ab943db9275b4ecc2bdb3d9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sponsor</header><text>The term <term>sponsor</term> means any person, association, committee, or organization operating an apprenticeship program and in whose name the program is (or is to be) registered or approved as a registered apprenticeship program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf26c660b37854774ac6492f9b3298500"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State apprenticeship agency</header><text>The term <term>State apprenticeship agency</term> means an entity of the government of a State that is recognized, under criteria established by the Secretary of Labor, for purposes of approving program standards that conform with the standards set by the Secretary for registering an apprenticeship program as a registered apprenticeship program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id382c5143cb9347828ee181048099528c"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Committee shall terminate on the day after the date described in subsection (d).</text></subsection></section><section id="id16a5d27820fb47e7b7eb23ee59590265"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recommendations from the Secretary of Labor</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after receipt of the report submitted under section 2(d), the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffc319bb42144417a8bba2639d401c88"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a policy plan based on the recommendations in such report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfaaeaaafbd4c408c914f01eab0f396e2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress a request with targeted appropriations to empower and incentivize States to carry out the recommendations in the policy plan.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id605a83c86a2c4192b54f530783878f20"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation of the data standardization and integration policy plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id0be38b2f7d7b450ba719ba40b284f4e5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 4 as section 5; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1608af11707d4a8792ee4df60cfb238b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 3 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0c200d8d1254edca7966e971bb12eb5"><section id="id08722eec67a54c7f8d717628bc0a11d1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recommendations from the apprenticeship advisory committee data standardization and integration policy plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In administering a system to carry out the activities authorized and directed to be carried out under section 1, the Secretary of Labor, in collaboration with the Secretary of Education, shall consider the recommendations in the policy plan issued under section 3 of the <short-title>ADVICE Act</short-title>.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

