<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H675B6364B7754976B0E8914A7CB9F773" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7886 IH: Failed Bank Executives Accountability and Consequences Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7886</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide Federal financial regulators with clawback authority over executive compensation and additional industry prohibition and civil money penalty authority with respect to executives whose negligence caused financial loss to the applicable financial institution, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H16CD09ED004B414BA3F98142C9FF4549" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H10AF8BF98C474388A5DF6E735E2FFB50" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Failed Bank Executives Accountability and Consequences Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE9E8360A8EE64216ABB80DFFF4F5B5A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0C3F61C5530247F181B68FA7237B6520">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>financial regulators and law enforcement agencies should fully exercise the maximum extent of their authorities to investigate and use available enforcement tools to hold executive officers and board members at Silicon Valley Bank, Signature Bank, First Republic Bank, and any other bank that fails to be fully accountable for any misconduct in which they are found to have engaged; and</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7B89FE83E894A0BB44420CA684BB35F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Directors of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Federal Housing Finance Agency should jointly finalize the regulations or guidelines required under section 956 of the <quote>Investor Protection and Securities Reform Act of 2010</quote>, and those regulations or guidelines should include robust clawback requirements.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H7FA8414F42C9491AA12231CA85B8B169"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clawback authority</header> <subsection id="H9571B7D5C3D948D6B5013A0F160F421E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H8D80F5522D194F7BBF774ACEFD3F680E" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H563F7EBE5E2641BE8CFDB66AEFFB7F74"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Recoupment of compensation from executive officers and directors</header> 
<paragraph id="H395D5065FBC24626B969E1A33E41BBF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During any period in which the Corporation is acting as conservator or receiver for an insured depository institution, the Corporation may recover, from any current or former executive officer or director of such insured depository institution whose negligence caused financial loss to such insured depository institution, any compensation received during the 2-year period preceding the date on which the Corporation was appointed as the conservator or receiver of the insured depository institution, except that, in the case of fraud, no time limit shall apply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F7B29F8A94A4759A2DF643DF877EBC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Corporation shall promulgate regulations to implement the requirements of this subsection, including defining the term <quote>compensation</quote> to mean any financial remuneration, including salary, bonuses, incentives, benefits, severance, deferred compensation, or golden parachute benefits, and any profits realized from the sale of the securities of the insured depository institution (or the securities of an affiliate of the insured depository institution).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8AD64E8AE6FE42348BAB052517544F90"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clawback authority relating to orderly liquidation authority</header><text>Section 210(s)(1) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HD234BAAEA6E24CE987413685DD8B86CC" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE2548AE9375C4DB988EAE14CA3550654"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Corporation, as receiver of a covered financial company, may recover from any current or former executive officer or director whose negligence caused financial loss to the covered financial company any compensation received during the 2-year period preceding the date on which the Corporation was appointed as the receiver of the covered financial company, except that, in the case of fraud, no time limit shall apply.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC7F479BCAC7641BAAF7B715865FA297B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Removal and prohibition authority in the case of institution failure</header> 
<subsection id="H559FCFEF11BF4ACEA4F3F8DD2F157F9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8(e) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1CDE44D686A44A3E80842C4B4BFC7554"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3), (4), (5), (6), and (7) as paragraphs (4), (5), (6), (7), and (8), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C587A74C6EE4470B21F575C80915355"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HFDD942D5BC1D436ABD39E7D92109439E" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H864ED169E4BC4DC68D951EC057C09886"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Suspension, removal, and prohibition from participation orders in the case of institution failure</header><text>Whenever the appropriate Federal banking agency determines that an institution-affiliated party has negligently caused financial loss to any insured depository institution that has failed, the appropriate Federal banking agency for the depository institution may serve upon such party a written notice of the agency’s intention to prohibit any further participation by such party, in any manner, in the conduct of the affairs of any insured depository institution.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5919D906945B4D18B530D72E3AE27789"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4CD5DEF451A945738EC9D91EC9725798"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 8—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8C0A5E5C628C4A6393E714D40C598231"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> <clause id="HA2D17CBEA46B467D8BE72DD6F4CBF7A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>under paragraph (1) or (2)</quote> each place it occurs and inserting <quote>under paragraphs (1), (2), or (3)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0709B4D704FD49A9A7F889EE9E5F2B6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (7)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (8)(A)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF34F204F9E59443D878FE1853057F6B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>subsection (e)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e)(4)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9BA5081CBA44115A617C5BC90537871"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(1)(D)(ii), by striking <quote>paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (e)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1), (2), or (4) of subsection (e)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7453B91FD0E947148CA83DF7E2EDCAEE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (j), by striking <quote>subsection (e)(6)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (e)(7)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB90E2527D42F449FB48DFE92555C0ED8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 10(k)(6)—</text> <subparagraph id="H32C8591073D242838E6293C5A84F4DA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>section 8(e)(4) for written notices or orders under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 8(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 8(e)(5) for written notices or orders under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of section 8(e)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6BF768ECD48048EAADFA033B4AC8A816"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>paragraphs (6) and (7) of section 8(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (7) and (8) of section 8(e)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5489BBB433774426A0409FF28FAEF7AB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Fines for failed bank executives</header> <subsection id="HA48BE081A94348A68FE4E03825D9C928"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8(i)(2) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818(i)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC5AA2D35E2344D8E964C918E6A18A95F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (D), (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), (J), and (K) as paragraphs (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), (J), (K), and (L), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D63F8CDA170445F874A83D50E637768"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C), the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H66A0291B72AD49C29CE76DE1FDAE2888" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H3FED9871E64F42F99C416BC46B1497E0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Fines for contributing to institution failure</header> 
<clause id="H4B2625052D7E47779F7C64D56637E555"><enum>(i)</enum><header>First tier</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), any executive officer or director who has negligently caused financial loss to any insured depository institution that has failed shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each day during which such conduct occurred.</text></clause> <clause id="H6B3B79CA85DB47A89AB24CF07917ACF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Second tier</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), any executive officer or director who knowingly or recklessly caused financial loss to any insured depository institution that has failed shall forfeit and pay a civil penalty in an amount not to exceed the applicable maximum amount determined under subparagraph (E) for each day during which such conduct occurred.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77AFF626028A4999817478A898C4C58D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 8(i)(2) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818(i)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a) is further amended—</text> <paragraph id="H766AD3DDAF7747A2A0B8383E5D0D02DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>to subparagraph (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>to subparagraph (C) or (D)</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H905B72B3DFB143A786C534FABCB3EDB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)—</text> <subparagraph id="H81B58635450042E29E10574ADD375DD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H262085BE0FFD4F6693B601DED2DB1170"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (H)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (I)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49BBD2A1B81A45FB8BEF5C87103425E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77F483FDAAA74AE3B911E16C0F3B1866"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>under subparagraph (A), (B), or (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>under subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5D1BFEF556874CB2905C365CA1FC55C4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act may not be construed to limit the enforcement authorities that financial regulators and law enforcement agencies had, prior to the date of enactment of this Act, to hold executive officers and board members of insured depository institutions and covered financial companies accountable for any misconduct in which they are found to have engaged.</text></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


