<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25D06-77X-KF-75X">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3214 IS: Background Check Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 3214</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To require a background check for every firearm sale.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5080446D69E2481D89BBA73BEFFEAEF9">
<section section-type="section-one" id="idD2A2CA8FB05947F3862F80E69F29A675"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Background Check Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id86C189B434E84F1EA5BEC5F2149A33E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Firearms transfers</header> <subsection id="id38cc6ebea02041a48594ca6a2705ce01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06BD415588A7429AA8AF11C9AD098D46">
<subsection id="ide820698ace5d4097bbf9938454a8c750"><enum>(aa)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3FF550BD49D6481AAE790AD1E6AF6EB3"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id8A1D5D788FFE479EB3626958089185BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>It shall be unlawful for any person who is not a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer to transfer a firearm to any other person who is not so licensed, unless a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer has first taken possession of the firearm for the purpose of complying with subsection (t).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4CDD8603A3E74E29A7881E1E82B98548" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Upon taking possession of a firearm under subparagraph (A), a licensee shall comply with all requirements of this chapter as if the licensee were transferring the firearm from the inventory of the licensee to the unlicensed transferee.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id03C28827B6814AD2A64B987BDE1F1D77" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If a transfer of a firearm described in subparagraph (A) will not be completed for any reason after a licensee takes possession of the firearm (including because the transfer of the firearm to, or receipt of the firearm by, the transferee would violate this chapter), the return of the firearm to the transferor by the licensee shall not constitute the transfer of a firearm for purposes of this chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id72323c03294149e1aab838184c3f7ea0" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text>
<subparagraph id="id6419bdb307db44bdb9df44d7f45257ec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a law enforcement agency or any law enforcement officer, armed private security professional, or member of the Armed Forces, to the extent the officer, professional, or member is acting within the course and scope of employment and official duties;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id3a0ff33f4f0644ccad77b4158246dc2a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a transfer that is a loan or bona fide gift between spouses, between domestic partners, between parents and their children, including step-parents and their step-children, between siblings, between aunts or uncles and their nieces or nephews, or between grandparents and their grandchildren;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id62567f544e094a8a8583a03cb0ba1598"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a transfer to an executor, administrator, trustee, or personal representative of an estate or a trust that occurs by operation of law upon the death of another person;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="iddf5b0f963e994a0880e7c97492f7e1bf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a temporary transfer that is necessary to prevent imminent death or great bodily harm, including harm to self, family, household members, or others, if the possession by the transferee lasts only as long as immediately necessary to prevent the imminent death or great bodily harm, including the harm of domestic violence, dating partner violence, sexual assault, stalking, and domestic abuse;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id73b111baaccf4d8f8dcb3177ab2f69b0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a transfer that is approved by the Attorney General under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/5812">section 5812</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="iddffbec40bc584d66856f592a74fa73fc"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a temporary transfer if the transferor has no reason to believe that the transferee will use or intends to use the firearm in a crime or is prohibited from possessing firearms under State or Federal law, and the transfer takes place and the transferee's possession of the firearm is exclusively—</text>
<clause id="id07255caeb8d442c89920d1b47198ad2b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at a shooting range or in a shooting gallery or other area designated for the purpose of target shooting;</text></clause> <clause id="id884c53541e4f436ea0520d48c5c58c05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>while reasonably necessary for the purposes of hunting, trapping, or fishing, if the transferor—</text>
<subclause id="idA49E53604FF446D3A2E73229439045FF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has no reason to believe that the transferee intends to use the firearm in a place where it is illegal; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="idC038D18E1D084EBC93B553A1F73BA94F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has reason to believe that the transferee will comply with all licensing and permit requirements for such hunting, trapping, or fishing; or</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="id4ead6fccd0a8451f90fc6156ffc46832"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>while in the presence of the transferor.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph indent="up1" id="idCE382A7A916C47B3A9E5F98D0AA77B80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It shall be unlawful for a licensed importer, licensed manufacturer, or licensed dealer to transfer possession of, or title to, a firearm to another person who is not so licensed unless the importer, manufacturer, or dealer has provided such other person with a notice of the prohibition under paragraph (1), and such other person has certified that such other person has been provided with this notice on a form prescribed by the Attorney General.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="id9DEBB2514B184B7B8F45588CB57BF3F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendment To section 924(<enum-in-header>a</enum-in-header>)</header><text>Section 924(a)(5) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>(s) or (t)</quote> and inserting <quote>(s), (t), or (aa)</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="id9A6B41DB4C054A46A89A16B9D673A6E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of interpretation</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, shall be construed to—</text>
<paragraph id="id1f3cebcff6e3495d8d23dbc9fc7d1c0a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorize the establishment, directly or indirectly, of a national firearms registry; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id738861b5bb5748dfb41b3a4187356962"><enum>(2)</enum><text>interfere with the authority of a State, under section 927 of title 18, United States Code, to enact a law on the same subject matter as this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id261b48670830427db1d538f4b9b22f4b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

