<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25E63-41D-L1-WSF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3535 IS: Guaranteed Refugee Admission Ceiling Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3535</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to require the President to set a minimum annual goal for the number of refugees to be admitted, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteed Refugee Admission Ceiling Enhancement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GRACE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6F2F5472F34F41D199E33B79CC8E6575"><enum>2.</enum><header>Admission of refugees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id34BFB6E8CFE04F5DAACFD28A17F40A5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="id944ED90ED90E49A6A558BB122EF169D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraphs (1) and (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a522c3c0c1c4dc5b643bec89b6677b8"><paragraph id="id9b7b653c18e0430da4da7f2346ddc39e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the number of refugees who may be admitted under this section in any fiscal year shall be the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="id9177d25d876a4ef68ba40c273c7acd46"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such number as the President determines is justified by humanitarian concerns or otherwise in the national interest, which shall be not fewer than 125,000; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id886be22121c8451b99e85de770afddb8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such number as the President determines shall be admitted to the United States through community or private sponsorship, by which community groups and private sponsors provide to a refugee and the immediate relatives or beneficiaries of the refugee initial reception and placement services similar to services provided by domestic resettlement agencies and local affiliates, in lieu of services typically provided by domestic resettlement agencies and local affiliates.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c2b07ab7f084fa08a50dae508f3c13e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Absence of determination</header><text>If the President does not issue a determination under paragraph (1) before the beginning of a fiscal year, the number of refugees who may be admitted in that fiscal year under this section shall be 125,000.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82837DF4A0EE45D3942350883A414E03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (7), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idECA90D98ACBB41A883D3824D5589ECCE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5E38789D14784A5F8B6771912CBCDF61"><paragraph id="idD7682A781CF648949BAA4893D94FCCF8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Numerical goals</header><text>Each officer of the Federal Government responsible for refugee admissions or refugee resettlement shall treat as the numerical goals for refugee admissions under this section for the applicable fiscal year—</text><subparagraph id="id07EC2CA134384DDCA5DE868FDF5FC294"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id82FEE2390DF8471782B132CC6C64DB7C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a determination under paragraph (1); or</text></clause><clause id="id4E2FD06122B64755A7316E29FC9E55CA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the absence of a determination under paragraph (1), the number under paragraph (2); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD3236FD922FA4C3ABD0F62B9D3F9DD3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA11B29C705E240D2A82704D1E815BB65"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4), as redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15493D8FB0C04EAD8F6F2F6DC76A6ADA"><paragraph id="id7C3BE5F00008494283694686BBE68532"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration of resettlement needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a determination under paragraph (1), the President shall consider the number of refugees who are in need of resettlement in a third country, as determined by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees in the most recently published projected global resettlement needs report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE2C47E3018C646A7B3A14E6FDA4A6460"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regional allocations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall determine regional allocations for admissions under this subsection, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="idf30e2dcf92b7493f9b8e3515f51dd0b7"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id132f1c872c4643c3b7b741d12acf7ec7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reflect the projected needs identified by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees in the projected global resettlement needs report for the calendar year beginning immediately after the beginning of the applicable fiscal year; or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9cf0f8bd1bba4c42836891017a198320"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include an assessment by the Secretary of State detailing the humanitarian and national interest justifications for prioritizing refugee admissions from 1 or more regions; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF4FD24AD0F354A94A57A76106B4F178F"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>include an unallocated reserve that the Secretary of State, after notifying the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, may use for 1 or more regions in which the need for additional refugee admissions arises.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA86C292911BC416EA14CD053E795778E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id384F0ED38D23457C947ABEB51F0202B9"><subsection id="id6B80FAF5B22D48E7825A00B6045FD106"> <enum>(g)</enum> <header>Quarterly public reports on admissions</header> <text>Not later than 15 days after the last day of each quarter, the President shall submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and publish on a publicly accessible website, a report that includes the following:</text>
                        <paragraph id="idDCD2E0CEBC2A49BBA5568960716127EE" commented="no">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The number of refugees admitted to the United States during the preceding quarter.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id922F0A374DF94EB7AAABA172D5CE75A7" commented="no">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The number of refugees admitted to the United States during the preceding quarter, expressed as a percentage of the number of refugees authorized to be admitted in accordance with the determinations under subsections (a) and (b) for the applicable fiscal year.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="idD84445DAC0D14888B0D84778119AC0AC" commented="no">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The cumulative number of refugees admitted to the United States during the applicable fiscal year, as of the last day of the preceding quarter.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id0E1CFF29B58546DCA4A84EA2BBD84DCC" commented="no">
                            <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The number of refugees to be admitted to the United States during the remainder of the applicable fiscal year so as to achieve the numerical goals set forth in the determinations under subsections (a) and (b) for such fiscal year.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="id95F81ED9BCE24311AE2DC56DB14E6DC1" commented="no">
                            <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The number of refugees from each region admitted to the United States during the preceding quarter, expressed as a percentage of the allocation for each region under subsection (a)(6) for the applicable fiscal year.</text>
                        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id80e91ff99cc74e1dbc55c53974bec5f5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Quarterly reports on processing</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the last day of each quarter, the President shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="ida1024766bc484ceab91b82b04b2564ea"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aliens with enhanced security checks</header><subparagraph id="idc3b01118d1c541dab79107b8e329d8f8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of aliens, by nationality, for whom an enhanced security check has been requested who were security-cleared during the preceding quarter, expressed as a percentage of all cases successfully adjudicated, approved, and security-cleared by the Director of the U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services in the applicable fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id490cfc64da1e4beeb56a1d7c376cf5c8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of aliens, by nationality, for whom an enhanced security check has been requested who were admitted to the United States during the preceding quarter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id52B228F53AB74F5493D0C0F6DC90165C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Circuit rides</header><subparagraph id="idB58C29AEA8AF415DBDBF93B6E79C45BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For the preceding quarter—</text><clause id="id43355AD29F5140EB8EB01F4609244DEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of Refugee Corps officers deployed on circuit rides, expressed as a percentage of the overall number of Refugee Corps officers;</text></clause><clause id="id82371D3D019F450D8154599EDF88C419"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of individuals interviewed—</text><subclause id="id4E66D8253E144CFC879FBFC6EE31A7E5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on each circuit ride; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6C5969655649476B90B12351A1AFE5BB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at each circuit ride location;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4EF807D0CED549E58D7C2B31C8620DFA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of circuit rides;</text></clause><clause id="id7C77FE6BCB6F4592AD6C1BA685DCC443"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for each circuit ride—</text><subclause id="idEC41D3BFFB404DD8B532E9405F3424FE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the duration of the circuit ride;</text></subclause><subclause id="idCAFD2D76248D43F6BFA2321FC46E9030"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the average number of interviews conducted daily on the circuit ride; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id2120A94AB89F460E83E8923B86AB6E8F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the percentages of interviews conducted for—</text><item id="ide72949bf632a472e933224c5753a8d24"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>individuals who require an enhanced security check; and</text></item><item id="id6e757e8891bc43d4b38da609a49c52db"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>individuals who do not require an enhanced security check; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id006f198298174d788e7914c09db889f3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of interviews completed by video teleconferencing.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF831A7E4B21A468F8E711C0973521C5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For the subsequent quarter—</text><clause id="id1817F46C73B442869C05013DB51DD6D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of circuit rides scheduled; and</text></clause><clause id="idD5D3975663FF42E3AA55DEA194601DE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of circuit rides planned.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id22EF66B645B046EE9A75F9CB92C52760"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Processing</header><text>For the preceding quarter—</text><subparagraph id="idE4C2B24B3C7849ACACA45722605BBDFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average number of days between—</text><clause id="id94FF4BBB85234BC3B95261A1538AC56B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which an individual is identified by the United States Government as a refugee; and</text></clause><clause id="id76D1E81809784E8E98DB6A7E3BD8453D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which such individual is interviewed by the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE2FC9E27C8E64851818DA8FA0C066B4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average number of days between—</text><clause id="idCCBFE4D9C8914D658D5BCFF5F36CD9C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which an individual identified by the United States Government as a refugee is interviewed by the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></clause><clause id="id011F10E4E32A4E4784FD0CEF17B9E2C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which such individual is admitted to the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88FD4D51ADD94167B528FD8C251EA1F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to individuals identified by the United States Government as refugees who have been interviewed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, the approval, denial, and hold rates for the applications for admission of such individuals, by nationality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idef541306f17e4807bb0301207e9b8c89"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Plan and additional information</header><text>If the number of refugees admitted during the preceding quarter is less than 25 percent of the number of refugees authorized to be admitted in accordance with the determinations under subsections (a) and (b) for the applicable fiscal year, the President shall submit—</text><subparagraph id="idba176c37cab74e6d96e318660e6e5632"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of country conditions and emergency humanitarian circumstances that contributed to the number of refugees admitted; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAC2710581429438CA880352C2B439D93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a plan that describes the procedural or personnel changes necessary to ensure the admission of the number of refugees authorized to be admitted to the United States in accordance with determinations under subsections (a) and (b), including a projection of the number of refugees to be admitted to the United States each month so as to achieve the numerical goals set forth in such determinations; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87286ecd497a4bbb8b872bf6699c8caf"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional information relating to the pace of refugee admissions, as determined by the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide6d5a521a7034aca90e3a338eaade1f8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Enhanced security check defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>enhanced security check</term> means any evaluation process to investigate national security concerns, including terrorism, espionage, sabotage, or the illegal transfer of goods, technology, or sensitive information, including—</text><subparagraph id="id3a11e846a15d485caf74065fd66a1843"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any process within U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for handling cases with national security concerns;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id212681f7edbb49ea9c00c6ac013d4623"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any interagency check requested by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services during the adjudication process to investigate national security concerns;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c1926a24922403b9022dec4c42bf85f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any additional vetting or review of applicants from a country that is a state sponsor of terrorism or a country with full or partial suspension of entry into the United States under this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba41dcc4cf174e4ea19598adc8e2aeaf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any process to screen applicant data against publicly available social media for national security purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9DE948D1CBED4BA085F3616E5D45663A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed—</text><paragraph id="id309CB1FB94914D9AB213FFD90AB0C011"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to inhibit the expeditious processing of refugee and asylum applications; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3FA8D4B2195640E8A23AC97701017141"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to restrict the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to admit aliens to the United States under any other Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

