<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON26100-W2G-3V-4LP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4010 IS: 21st Century Worker Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4010</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To clarify the classification of service provider payees as employees or independent contractors in Federal law.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Worker Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id4F8A13247BBA4F1693111E13D20A1F63"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id4F8A13247BBA4F1693111E13D20A1F63">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idC7D328C056544708A9D0AE76FFD035A9">TITLE I—Classification of service provider payees</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id5ad2a0cd419e4ff6aa2680d66f9bc759">Sec. 101. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc8a2e13b7cba4ff097ab4809a9ab2a11">Sec. 102. Classification.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idc1a725824b2b4a49a928fa5217f1892b">Sec. 103. Mandatory independent contractor classification.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id34cc5ab357cc4c4fb82293c7e89a8a7f">Sec. 104. Mandatory employee classification.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id9794e58795424aebb359f47bfa9b29fa">Sec. 105. Elective classification service provider payees.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id3f2af9041a1044bba178eda90152320a">Sec. 106. Change in classification; periodic classification review.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="idC2308CAC39164A2884EB444F0C2A92BE">TITLE II—Application to other laws</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id215d0ee5f6d748de82257b6a7c030ee0">Sec. 201. Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id6e095d28e69e4c0a936f637f957bac7b">Sec. 202. National Labor Relations Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7728FA7ED2494C6FA70D9844E3DC9F66">Sec. 203. Tax classification.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id35ec3bef2f204caa895b4feb165cb96b">Sec. 204. GAO study on changes needed to other Federal laws.</toc-entry></toc></section><title id="idC7D328C056544708A9D0AE76FFD035A9" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Classification of service provider payees</header><section id="id5ad2a0cd419e4ff6aa2680d66f9bc759"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="idddc4f94461ab474f8e82778f04ec6d63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bona fide sole proprietor</header><text>The term <term>bona fide sole proprietor</term> means a service provider payee who—</text><subparagraph id="id023591a35b354371b54005a1ca04b728"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has entered into a written contract governing the terms of the goods or services provided to a service recipient payor and the contract is not an employment by agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id992054b2d07b49e2bb183aee77be2948"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not required to provide the goods or services exclusively for the service recipient payor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52227a2e3e5f4bdc810e5ee18e6cb7f0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not had a substantial economic relationship or employment by agreement with the service recipient payor as described in section 104 during the previous calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0621c7ea4a3412293a70048465eeb47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business entity</header><text>The term <term>business entity</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id03D7909A79DB4263A12B37B8C9C4DFB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a corporation, limited liability company, limited partnership, limited liability partnership, limited liability limited partnership, statutory business trust, or a similar entity formed under the laws of the United States, under the law of a State or United States territory (including the District of Columbia), or under the laws of a foreign country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14CEEE48AB0147ADAA5C38E5FFE5DA53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a general partnership not described in subparagraph (A) that has registered to do business under State or local law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2feee2ed8f54d9994c9f158c3ef1958"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation</header><subparagraph id="idB8968987364B465B87EBD844746312B0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>compensation</term>—</text><clause id="idD85E6B0612E541E5AA0B372711C834DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means consideration paid by a service recipient payor to a service provider payee for goods or services provided; and</text></clause><clause id="id2D0F2A0348004DA1BAA5D038701E28DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes payments in money, payments in property, wages, salaries, benefits, and other types of payment.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC8E0C72B685C49BC9C3607E7C26FE7B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fair market value</header><text>For purposes of determining the amount of compensation, the value of payments in a form other than legal tender shall be determined by the fair market value of the payment on the date of payment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id157af896e1a3457ea8fd5e97b4b8e96b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Direct sales service provider payee</header><text>The term <term>direct sales service provider payee</term> means a service provider payee who is a direct seller, as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3508">section 3508(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b469fbd4bfd4a90a8c960161b86e4fe"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Elective classification service provider payee</header><text>The term <term>elective classification service provider payee</term> means a service provider payee who is not classified as either—</text><subparagraph id="id9f90e08fd84f45e5a1437d577a822136"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a mandatory independent contractor under section 103; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide96970da891f45fe80f9612bf9a0179d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a mandatory employee under section 104.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id896bc500e6e04320b552cece061b722f"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd74255728cd04c8d9abe974b5855bcce"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a service provider payee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77dfd9a827ab426db521f52f0b5001fe"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is—</text><clause id="id0AD199B6F6504E84B8F58ADD6BCCB2ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>classified as a mandatory employee under section 104; or</text></clause><clause id="id88228C4E45DE40958A6ABCE782CA4DD7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>classified as an employee under section 105.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id86c6113eefaa4d8880138a2dd2144932"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> means a service recipient payor—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8b0f9d035374388ae8ad7933ba76dc3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is in a substantial economic relationship with a service provider payee who is classified as an employee under section 104 with respect to the service recipient payor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e9e2d21ce094d398854ce935b1b3ba2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that has entered into employment by agreement under section 104 with a service provider payee; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd365d5953c344bb9ffb080163da5163"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for whom a service recipient payee has elected to be classified as an employee under section 105.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89bee0f933094c7aa25b8b992daaaeae"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Employment by agreement</header><text>The term <term>employment by agreement</term> means an agreement, whether written or otherwise, between a service recipient payor and a service provider payee that demonstrably expresses their mutual intent to form an employer-employee relationship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id02469a2d692f410d9e66fbfde41ee2fa"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Formal bona fide contractor</header><text>The term <term>formal bona fide contractor</term>, when used with respect to a service provider payee providing goods or services to a service recipient payor, means a service provider payee who—</text><subparagraph id="idd4922f2717784c77a415a117a5a568ed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is recognized as a contractor under applicable State law; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7aecd7108eb4c3da29f37cf55f19d0b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not required to provide the goods or services exclusively for the service recipient payor and has—</text><clause id="id6a5749d4ede5446a846d73f858a1d339"><enum>(i)</enum><text>entered into a written contract governing the terms of the goods or services provided to the service recipient payor that is not designated as an employment by agreement;</text></clause><clause id="id47fc9408c2b34c5d9a8e4ef176565a9c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>incurred unreimbursed expenses related to providing the goods or services to the service recipient payor annually that exceed 5 percent of the total compensation made to the service provider payee by the service recipient payor; and</text></clause><clause id="idc8709bebee344beda9cb7d397372d5f4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not had a substantial economic relationship or employment by agreement with the service recipient payor as described in section 104 during the previous calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc91b0c9c93de408bb217629e6256ca58"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Independent contractor</header><text>The term <term>independent contractor</term> means a service provider payee who—</text><subparagraph id="idb99c820ef54a41608697157a0ddcecac"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is classified as a mandatory independent contractor under section 103; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id110E7F3CB6FF407EB3B4C0D06A78245A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is classified as an independent contractor under section 105.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e21cbeff31142eb9f97bc090cb23f83"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Licensed profession, trade, or occupation</header><text>The term <term>licensed profession, trade, or occupation</term> means a profession, trade, or occupation that may not be lawfully engaged in unless a license from a Federal, State, or local government is obtained.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id816570cb6beb44d28375cbd3314ed315"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Limited economic relationship</header><text>The term <term>limited economic relationship</term> means an economic relationship between a service recipient payor and a service provider payee under which—</text><subparagraph id="id8093e25c353a43b88ee5c0e1ac59b2ae"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the compensation to the service provider payee by the service recipient payor is based on a period of time worked;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idba1f436d5552431d8957b4cb7bb56f2b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the period of time worked for which the service provider payee is compensated by the service recipient payor is less than 30 days per calendar quarter; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id323b9b946acb4405a000ec22b0afb42a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the service provider payee is not required to provide the goods or services exclusively for the service recipient payor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id74071699947946cb9d2c684fa88f6d01"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Money</header><text>The term <term>money</term> means any legal tender as defined in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfea46fcafad84bc4b53411e65662cb7d"><enum>(14)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Period of time worked</header><text>The term <term>period of time worked</term> includes any specified period of time worked, including hourly, daily, weekly, bi-weekly, bi-monthly, monthly, quarterly, or annually periods of time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34eb4cbc5c514cf599f14039b797d3cd"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Sales commission</header><text>The term <term>sales commission</term> means compensation based on sales made by the service provider payee or by individuals managed, supervised, advised, or recruited by the service provider payee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddaa961d536404f3183754b247f1b0ad9"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida17d031b285d4d0eb46106ed3b9a4ecf"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Service provider payee</header><text>The term <term>service provider payee</term> means an individual providing goods or services to a service recipient payor in return for compensation paid to the individual by the service recipient payor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6acc322798af4232b141dff96d41f918"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Service recipient payor</header><text>The term <term>service recipient payor</term> means a person receiving goods or services from a service provider payee in return for compensation paid by the person to the service provider payee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9049a1d31c054a6a84fc67b66f893219"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Substantial economic relationship</header><text>The term <term>substantial economic relationship</term> means an economic relationship between a service recipient payor and a service provider payee where—</text><subparagraph id="id9760728d5297454fa4f17ed0d67b46b0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the service provider payee is a natural person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1cd87b40f63d48ee8c19b15dce85931b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>more than 75 percent of the compensation to the service provider payee by the service recipient payor is based on a period of time worked;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0ef6b9001a94c968b05b66d6b4ad6d2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the service recipient payor determines the hours of work; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e1ae2c0dfe64b0d80e2fafe69b6aeef"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the service recipient payor requires the service provider payee to work substantially full-time for the service recipient payor for a period of 4 consecutive weeks or more.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fb23a77ad834ca581a2d24d3b5b6b73"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Substantially full-time</header><text>The term <term>substantially full-time</term> means an average of 30 or more hours per week during the relevant period of time worked.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0e54279cacf4b73a869573713a54eff"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Written contract</header><text>The term <term>written contract</term> means writing sufficient to indicate that a contract has been made between the parties that is legally enforceable in the jurisdiction or jurisdictions where the services by the service provider payee are performed or to be performed.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc8a2e13b7cba4ff097ab4809a9ab2a11"><enum>102.</enum><header>Classification</header><subsection id="ida752746766134b86b6a52de2126e7ee8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bifurcated classification</header><text>For purposes of this title, a service provider payee shall be classified as either an employee or an independent contractor in accordance with the following:</text><paragraph id="id7a58d932fc724ea3a95c662cc02221f8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory independent contractors</header><text>A service provider payee meeting the requirements of section 103 shall be classified as an independent contractor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7aafc457d3445a8bc2e7ccf72aecb58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mandatory employee classification</header><text>A service provider payee meeting the requirements of section 104 shall be classified as an employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fa01baa338c424695a5a35f7d932809"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elective classification service provider payees</header><text>A service provider payee that meets neither the requirements of section 103 nor the requirements of section 104 shall be classified as the service provider payee elects in accordance with section 105.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id05664cdee50a417dba0db4d2d6af3c8a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibility for initial determination</header><paragraph id="id7f433320db3e44b2bad26adf56724b21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the service recipient payor is responsible for determining whether a service provider payee is properly classified as a mandatory independent contractor, a mandatory employee, or an elective classification service provider payee, for purposes of subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec88bb73b1ae4612a2f9fb3866c32df1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The service provider payee is responsible for determining whether the service provider payee is properly classified as a mandatory independent contractor if the classification of the service provider payee as an independent contractor is based on meeting the requirements of—</text><subparagraph id="id95555bc93c344eec8ae4a019abef9eb0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 103(2)(A) (relating to licensed professions, trades, or occupations);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5804b88f41824d82a101801cbd7c8c36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 103(2)(B) (relating to business entities);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida71085bf7e7a4a33866f064e441a34b4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 103(2)(E) (relating to bona fide sole proprietors); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf82f19e511d04862ad37aad3c5f45cb8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>section 103(2)(F) (relating to formal bona fide contractors).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id13ba08d8175d4e5db5b0cc85f474ce42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The classification determination of a service provider payee shall be made by the service recipient payor or service provider payee (as required under this subsection) immediately upon entering into an economic relationship between the service recipient payor and the service provider payee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id373239F5E48549389A662291B6703A96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reclassifications and periodic review</header><text>A service provider payee or a service recipient payor, as applicable, shall reclassify or review the classification determination under this section in accordance with section 106.</text></subsection></section><section id="idc1a725824b2b4a49a928fa5217f1892b"><enum>103.</enum><header>Mandatory independent contractor classification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A service provider payee shall be classified as an independent contractor if the service provider payee—</text><paragraph id="idE932CB66A9504A23A4ECA99A847F24C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not classified as an employee pursuant to section 104; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2532b50a82c4d79955496f7e1fc0e3f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>meets one or more of the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="idcaa74e1fa973499f9359ea1066928fa9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Licensed profession, trade, or occupation</header><text>The service provider payee—</text><clause id="id39040838942e4d8181355ac139ad6f56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is engaged in a licensed profession, trade, or occupation; and</text></clause><clause id="id77045b131f7945e3a5a46b2e7c00eb7b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>holds himself or herself out as providing services to the public.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a3a407bd61d4db5bc2b4deb4a57942b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Business entity</header><text>The service provider payee is a business entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idceed5440234f419e9a39f86fa966a1d9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limited economic relationship</header><text>The economic relationship between a service recipient payor and a service provider payee is a limited economic relationship.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60a11b7eaee24923bb31176aaaebdbd1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Direct sales</header><text>The service provider payee is a direct sales service provider payee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6fc67b590d5943fcbd6c536def282ac9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Bona fide sole proprietor</header><text>The service provider payee is a bona fide sole proprietor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6cc608978ba48b3acd4d4a8a22cfc0e"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Formal bona fide contractor</header><text>The service provider payee is a formal bona fide contractor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id34cc5ab357cc4c4fb82293c7e89a8a7f"><enum>104.</enum><header>Mandatory employee classification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A service provider payee shall be classified as an employee if the service provider payee meets one or more of the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="id9ca23b721f4c42cd8d14876a85b7bbd5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Substantial economic relationship</header><text>The economic relationship between a service recipient payor and a service provider payee is a substantial economic relationship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd76a283bd34746a7b3f1875e8b18eb5e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employment by agreement</header><text>There is employment by agreement.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id9794e58795424aebb359f47bfa9b29fa"><enum>105.</enum><header>Elective classification service provider payees</header><subsection id="ide3296b33d26745ae887eda01965f3c5d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elective classification service provider payees; election required</header><text>A service provider payee that does not meet either of the requirements of section 103 or section 104 is an elective classification service provider payee. Each elective classification service provider payee shall elect whether to be classified as an employee or an independent contractor in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida7d87cfa86f34f60996afa50c0bda3ea"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Method of election</header><text>The elective classification service provider payee shall make the election required by this section in writing upon entering into an economic relationship with a service recipient payor. Subject to subsection (c), the election need not be in any particular form as long as the election—</text><paragraph id="id3cb67c371ee3454cb7aab720c52bed64"><enum>(1)</enum><text>clearly indicates the service provider payee’s intent regarding whether to be classified as an independent contractor or an employee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd6df52803f404e7c8db7c440aedb0067"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is dated;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id819f4d7d3905469fa7b8d387db14d0a4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is signed by the elective classification service provider payee; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc57dd026216e4b54b1fea1bfea40d2ee"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is countersigned by the service recipient payor.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide26d7844ae784552b8ad209897fa1118"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Service recipient payor counter signature required</header><text>The elective classification service provider payee shall secure the counter-signature of the service recipient payor acknowledging that the service recipient payor knows the classification election made by the service provider payee. The election required under subsection (a) is not effective until the counter-signature of the service recipient payor is secured, subject to subsection (f).</text></subsection><subsection id="idf9d085fb857a4b72807878c565e89716"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Timing of election</header><text>The election required under subsection (a) shall be made by the elective classification service provider payee upon entering into an economic relationship with a service recipient payor. Failure by the elective classification service provider payee to make the election required by subsection (a) within 14 days of entering into an economic relationship with a service recipient payor shall be subject to a penalty under subsection (g)(1), subject to subsection (f).</text></subsection><subsection id="id7bc9f1671f334bbcb4ae687d806dc995"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Record-keeping retention requirement</header><text>Both the elective classification service provider payee and the service recipient payor are required to maintain a copy of the countersigned election required under subsection (b) for a period of 3 years following its countersignature. Failure by the elective classification service provider payee or the service recipient payor to maintain a copy of the countersigned election required by this section shall be subject to a penalty under subsection (g)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="id73b819d6e5074b63a069021b5f5b77fc"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Absence of countersignature; default rule</header><text>In the event that an elective classification service provider payee makes the election required under subsection (a) except that the elective classification service provider payee requests, but does not receive, the countersignature required by subsection (c) within 14 days of entering into an economic relationship with a service recipient payor, the elective classification service provider payee shall be classified as an independent contractor and shall not be in violation of subsection (g)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="id10c0836a57c94045b725c71c2de51960"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Penalties</header><paragraph id="id5e6bd7f47f634d759b91ca70d93fd85c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Penalty for failure to make election</header><text>The Secretary shall impose a penalty not to exceed $100 on an elective classification service provider payee who fails to make the election required by subsection (a) within 14 days of entering into an economic relationship with a service recipient payor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id84578e051c2d4d519289279ee003cc30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty for failure to keep records relating to election</header><text>The Secretary shall impose a penalty not to exceed $100 on elective classification service provider payees or service recipient payors who fail to maintain the records required by subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f51700e070d452fa892472e89768e5a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Willful or reckless misclassification</header><text>The Secretary shall impose a penalty on a service recipient payor or service provider payee responsible for a classification determination under this section who willfully or recklessly misclassifies a service provider payee as an independent contractor in an amount equal to 15 percent of the compensation paid to the independent contractor.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4c4ae0bc86c5423ea39728a466510df4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No requirement To enter into economic relationship</header><text>Nothing in this title shall be read as a requirement by a service provider payee or a service recipient payor to enter into an economic relationship.</text></subsection></section><section id="id3f2af9041a1044bba178eda90152320a"><enum>106.</enum><header>Change in classification; periodic classification review</header><subsection id="id04f771787b344247874c58362d00b192"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Major change in the nature of the economic relationship</header><paragraph id="id51093904139F4A90BA387ACBB7ED8D72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If there is a major change in the nature of the economic relationship between a service provider payee and a service recipient payor, then a new classification determination shall be made by the service recipient payor or service provider payee responsible for classification determination pursuant to section 102(b) upon the major change in the nature of the economic relationship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD2353ECE64BE4AEFADE70BE85716C294"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Major change described</header><text>For purposes of this section, a major change in the nature of the economic relationship means an increase or decrease of 25 percent or more in the hours worked by, or the compensation paid to, the service provider payee by the service recipient payor in the most recent calendar quarter compared to the previous calendar quarter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8EBA900DAB634C7DBDFC5D2F39044CCD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>If a reclassification determination is made, it shall be effective beginning on the first day of the first month that immediately follows the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb55fafd18c99416498fef99224a7ec85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Change in classification for other reasons</header><paragraph id="idC02706FFBA81456DA82EE86BAC711A95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there is a change in the nature of the economic relationship between a service provider payee and a service recipient payor other than a major change in the nature of the economic relationship described in subsection (a) that a reasonable person should anticipate could change the classification of a service provider payee, then the service recipient payor or service provider payee responsible for classification determination pursuant to section 102(b) shall make a classification determination upon the change in the nature of the economic relationship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id626A6DB21D504AE0989C46D640447992"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Examples</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Changes in the nature of the economic relationship included under paragraph (1) include, without limitation—</text><subparagraph id="id7fa8d02505434c9098d0ef58b3db85e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the loss of a license by a service recipient payee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id442ebc3a5e32464b987e956495ab0ceb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the forfeiture of a business entity charter by a service recipient payee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2d20fbe790b4689993a225be409e14b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a change in the relative importance of sales commissions in compensating a direct sales service provider payee; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a199d88fdb64c91a13ecaae3c06271c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a change in the requirement, or lack thereof, to perform services exclusively for the service recipient payor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id927d8a97be7e4c74a810bd89601f5f66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reclassification timing</header><text>If a reclassification determination is made, then it shall be made effective with respect to the calendar quarter that begins immediately after the date on which the event giving rise to the change in the nature of the economic relationship occurred.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id742fd6e8f16f47d0ab55a168d1971fbf"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Periodic review requirement; frequency</header><paragraph id="id3F54E0A27EE1475F9FAFD24748152CAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The service recipient payor or service provider payee responsible for a classification determination under subsection (a) or (b) shall make annual determinations for any continuing economic relationships with service recipient payors or service provider payees, as the case may be. These periodic reviews shall be completed by January 31 with respect to continuing economic relationships as of December 31 of the previous calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE5C82B614A2B4242873495677AA8CCF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date of determination changes</header><text>If a reclassification determination is made as a result of this review, it shall be made effective beginning on the first day of the first month that immediately follows the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="ide50ad0f2229c4ef7962353e9399fb5a3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>For purposes of this section, if a service provider payee does not have more than 100 hours worked or been compensated more than a total of $10,000 during a calendar quarter in which the reclassification determination is made, then the service provider payor or service provider payee, as the case may be, is exempt from the requirements of this section.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="idC2308CAC39164A2884EB444F0C2A92BE" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Application to other laws</header><section id="id215d0ee5f6d748de82257b6a7c030ee0"><enum>201.</enum><header>Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id36305723E9164A009B4F5414DF8E53A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE6BD2B7925EB488E84197AD4EFD46083"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID1820CBBEFB5F4DAEA72430E6EC37D1CC"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><term>Employer</term>—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16701741A9114E398F7A0BDBC003B6F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided in this subsection, has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the <short-title>21st Century Worker Act</short-title>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA2A1B0F042BA4A74BF49695F4F8F449B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any person (including a public agency) acting directly or indirectly in the interest of an employer in relation to an employee; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA5BB7B245E5E49AB90452E7383ED9345"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include any labor organization (other than when acting as an employer) or anyone acting in the capacity of officer or agent of such labor organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id7AEB904C24CF4504967875757C4D479C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) of subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89ECEACA219B4E5D9082B21955EE7F13"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb5bec4e8a224d918502e93aa4c23424"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), (4), and (5), the term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>employee</quote> in section 101 of the <short-title>21st Century Worker Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idD11612803122482A898EBF86FC4D4B55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (g) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1D4C9ABDC2CB4FF8986744F5D9E542E6"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID19C0AE27976F41D78F437183729B0C8C"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6C954C478E314DC2BA917483F8466B5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><term>Employ</term> includes to suffer or permit to work under a substantial economic relationship (as defined in section 101 of the <short-title>21st Century Worker Act</short-title>) between an employer and employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id588421B38CBB45CB85B931B99C2B6A52" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text><term>Employment</term> means the provision of goods or services by an employee for an employer.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id6e095d28e69e4c0a936f637f957bac7b"><enum>202.</enum><header>National Labor Relations Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id430A2B599B6C45F5A084D0171BB8491A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idBC44A0999F794A27976346208AFE7C9C"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID2B3A71C51407404EADC93E139A44FFA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employer</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4F4E4F6014484A7184803B406B79AFB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the <short-title>21st Century Worker Act</short-title>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE58DF74D6A8245C7B445CC20217650D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any person acting as an agent of an employer, directly or indirectly; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE8B2166F879147B39F7EFE67D86C740E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include the United States or any wholly owned Government corporation, or any Federal Reserve Bank, or any State or political subdivision thereof, or any person subject to the Railway Labor Act, as amended from time to time, or any labor organization (other than when acting as an employer), or anyone acting in the capacity of officer or agent of such labor organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id57377672553F4A5A87464A332F8893ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>shall include any employee, and shall not be limited to the employees of a particular employer, unless the Act explicitly states otherwise, and shall</quote> and inserting <quote>, except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, has the meaning given the term <term>employee</term> in section 101 of the <short-title>21st Century Worker Act</short-title>. The term shall include any employee, and shall not be limited to the employees of a particular employer. The term shall</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC034DCABC789411C8A8C583F9FD778C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF2A7D81DE4F34A029B0693568169C318"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8B4D128483F74C0597924700BD42E12E"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The term <term>employment</term> means the provision of goods or services by an employee for an employer.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id7728FA7ED2494C6FA70D9844E3DC9F66"><enum>203.</enum><header>Tax classification</header><subsection commented="no" id="idf0d7620046364307bbf1a5c5c5ed694f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employee and employer</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">Section 7701(a)(20)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8410491EE7AF43CB8910B792A71A6D5D"><paragraph commented="no" id="id31aa5c011d5c4185bb4f85aa63076808"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Employee and employer</header><text>The terms <term>employee</term> and <term>employer</term> have the same meaning given such terms in section 101 of the <short-title>21st Century Worker Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id017d3371db924c818f7f31e14b1a9dd5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3121">Section 3121(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57B8E8915AE84EE89783A8CA88EE7931"><subsection commented="no" id="id396a6ed36f7543c3b786c52df45bf936"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The term <term>employment</term> means any services performed by an employee for an employer.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id5eddd250c5f5475e971b0e934ce6c854"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="id39EFCF6421454BEA999AE82A9AAFAB75"><enum>(1)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3121">Section 3121</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d967d229e1e43f69eb0ea41720ad6ad"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 3306(a) of such Code is amended by striking paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2C3EEFC2331C4735A17DDA1520A1CD2B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id35ec3bef2f204caa895b4feb165cb96b"><enum>204.</enum><header>GAO study on changes needed to other Federal laws</header><subsection id="id82FC11DB0952474FA41705EDB100EE8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall prepare and submit to Congress a report that identifies—</text><paragraph id="idF7F62389E0FA4B4DA5B8BD585204650D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all covered Federal laws that utilize the terms <term>employee</term>, <term>employer</term>, <term>employ</term>, and <term>employment</term> in ways that do not correspond with the definitions of the terms <term>employee</term> and <term>employer</term> under section 101 of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7CBFAE18FEB8499D8FC7C946FF87F715"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how harmonizing the definitions of <term>employee</term>, <term>employer</term>, <term>employ</term>, and <term>employment</term> across all covered Federal laws would alter each covered Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC68E98C05F364485968DD0001E44D1CB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of covered Federal law</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered Federal law</term> means each of the following:</text><paragraph id="id289d553c0252491c9d6dd48ea93da552"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/621">29 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>), including subsections (b) and (f) of section 11, and section 15(a), of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/630">29 U.S.C. 630(b)</external-xref> and (f); <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/633a">29 U.S.C. 633a(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9021828e68da4bedb8bac5a5e2576da6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), including paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 101, and section 510, of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12111">42 U.S.C. 12111(4)</external-xref> and (5); <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12209">42 U.S.C. 12209</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86d5e4cb968940f5b7018efc2e94fce6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</external-xref>), including subsections (b) and (f) of section 701, and section 717(a), of such title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e(b)</external-xref> and (f); <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e-16">42 U.S.C. 2000e–16(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3B35F41278054081A4FAE03A944D9C1C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 304(a) of the Civil Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16c(a)).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc4434c6c54d4da2b1d8b490c9615867"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1301">2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>), including section 201 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1311">2 U.S.C. 1311</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d8b9c8ace9c4e4f9b8ae105ca8a99e0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Employee Polygraph Protection Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2001">29 U.S.C. 2001 et seq.</external-xref>), including section 2(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2001">29 U.S.C. 2001(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id590F69F1344B42509741867AC5C0926F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), including paragraphs (5) and (6) of section 3 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(5)</external-xref>, (6)) and part 6 of subtitle B of title I of such Act (relating to health insurance continuation by employees) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1161">29 U.S.C. 1161 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id196cf4fde0f34c15ba3294de43bf6155"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2601">29 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>), including paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 101 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2611">29 U.S.C. 2611(3)</external-xref> and (4)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id259a4491366d4cfd915165fe82f48657"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681">15 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), including section 603(h) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a(h)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c255864c4a040f393dd1e549bdfd4fa"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Title II of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ff">42 U.S.C. 2000ff et seq.</external-xref>), including section 201(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ff">42 U.S.C. 2000ff(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1d31ece79854b8aab953d9786bd04f2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Government Employee Rights Act of 1991 (42 U.S.C. 2000e–16a et seq.).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id47c6931df93b48e9800553ca2d5b7a1a"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b7f3cf37dd146cd9d4e5b89f12ac254"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/401">29 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>), including subsections (e) and (f) of section 3 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/402">29 U.S.C. 402(e)</external-xref> and (f)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8c81c70ed2248ac9ef44dbc7d443dc8"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/651">29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>), including paragraphs (5) and (6) of section 3 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/652">29 U.S.C. 652(5)</external-xref> and (6)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id404fd2872e2b4282a7db6747ad4414d3"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Subtitle B of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18001">42 U.S.C. 18001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9fd32f1ea6c45518f6178c8c65b5195"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>), including section 501 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/791">29 U.S.C. 791</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idae4d593f54ae48b193aac72985e72f3c"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.</external-xref>), including section 2(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba8005f4744248d6938ee19cc7c47894"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Section 1977A of the Revised Statutes (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1981a">42 U.S.C. 1981a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e5e80a72b15405598d35abc9d9d929d"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Section 411 of title 3, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5cc7705b10964295843c7e011885715a"><enum>(20)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">Chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Employees’ Compensation Act</quote>), including paragraphs (1) and (12) of section 8101 of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16a7634c50ba4910916a9ab5ceedb89a"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a6afb032ad74a5daec303a7b7b95e86"><enum>(22)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/43">Chapter 43</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act</quote>), including paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 4303 of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide940993daa694cc7a6b60494a1a8d306"><enum>(23)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/37">Chapter 37</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Contract Work Hours and Safety Standards Act</quote>), including section 3701(b)(2) of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51aad439b9bc4b11b62ddc6444f32276"><enum>(24)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/67">Chapter 67</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>McNamara-O’Hara Service Contract Act</quote>), including section 6701(3) of such title.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id310c172939064b2798e2f50ccef074be"><enum>(25)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/81">Chapter 81</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <term>Drug-Free Workplace Act</term>), including section 8101(a)(6) of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

