<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26239-XPJ-HK-38F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 695 ATS: Commemorating April 6, 2026, as the day the Artemis II crew surpassed the record for the farthest distance traveled by astronauts into deep space and celebrating the success of the Artemis II mission.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 695</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating April 6, 2026, as the day the Artemis II crew surpassed the record for the farthest distance traveled by astronauts into deep space and celebrating the success of the Artemis II mission.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 1, 2026, the Artemis II mission launched successfully aboard the Space Launch System rocket from the John F. Kennedy Space Center in Florida, marking a significant milestone in the efforts to return humans to the Moon and advance deep space exploration; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas National Aeronautics and Space Administration astronauts Commander Reid Wiseman, Pilot Victor Glover, and Mission Specialist Christina Koch and Canadian Space Agency Mission Specialist Jeremy Hansen (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Artemis II crew</quote>) demonstrated exceptional skill, courage, and dedication in carrying out the historic Artemis II mission; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Artemis II crew traveled aboard the Orion spacecraft named <italic>Integrity</italic>, which represents the enduring values of exploration, teamwork, and scientific discovery; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on April 6, 2026, the Artemis II crew surpassed the record set by the Apollo 13 mission for the farthest distance traveled by astronauts from Earth, achieving a new milestone in human spaceflight; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas <italic>Integrity</italic> eventually reached a maximum distance of 252,760 miles from Earth, surpassing the previous record of 248,655 miles set in 1970 and setting a new benchmark for crewed spaceflight; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Artemis II mission represents a number of historic firsts in crewed space exploration, including the first woman, first African American, and first non-United States astronaut to travel beyond low Earth orbit; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Artemis II mission was the first human journey to the vicinity of the Moon in more than 50 years; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas this achievement reflects decades of sustained investment and leadership by the United States, in partnership with both the Canadian Space Agency and the European Space Agency, and the contributions of thousands of engineers, scientists, and skilled workers; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Artemis effort is a partnership among government, industry, and international partners that involves more than 2,700 companies across the country whose collective expertise and coordination enabled successful execution of the Artemis II mission, demonstrating the strength of cooperative space exploration;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Artemis II mission was managed from Mission Control and the Mission Evaluation Room at the Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center in Houston, Texas, where flight controllers, engineers, and support teams ensured the safety and success of the mission; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on April 10, 2026, at 5:07 p.m. Pacific time, the Artemis II crew safely returned to Earth, splashing down in the Pacific Ocean off the coast of San Diego, California; </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas following splashdown, the United States Navy, with support from the United States Coast Guard, conducted recovery operations and successfully retrieved the Artemis II crew and spacecraft aboard the USS <italic>John P. Murtha</italic> (LPD–26);</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Artemis II mission showcased the economic and technological strength of the United States, which is supported by a highly skilled workforce and generates innovation across multiple sectors of the economy; and </text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the success of the Artemis II mission has inspired people around the world, rekindling a shared sense of wonder, possibility, and unity and reaffirming the commitment of the United States to peaceful exploration, scientific advancement, and international collaboration in space: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id3a7bd59e2dc0462a94ab20fea4a8a8fd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates April 6, 2026, as the day the Artemis II crew surpassed the record set by Apollo 13 for the farthest distance traveled by astronauts into deep space;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb2eb980a31f4958a371dbd5c5a54865"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the successful completion of the Artemis II mission, including its launch, historic journey, and safe return to Earth;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf51842d92e034f27b6a8d748e3bc7f35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the achievements and service of Reid Wiseman, Victor Glover, Christina Koch, and Jeremy Hansen;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8303a585ef74451b44ea96773a0ff1e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>celebrates technological and manufacturing excellence led by the United States as showcased by the successful Artemis II mission;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4539493d7084c748ac2ceb55e858ab9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the critical contributions of the flight controllers, engineers, contractors, and support personnel, particularly those at the Lyndon B. Johnson Space Center, who ensured mission success;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4eddd0699e342f4a2ac7fc5ef95cf77"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commends the employees of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Canadian Space Agency, and all industry and international partners whose efforts made the Artemis II mission possible; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97389d360dad4f3bad5b67e700df0d4a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to maintaining leadership in space exploration and advancing the peaceful use of space for the benefit of all humanity.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

