<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25L67-4K1-0X-224"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1000 RS: To establish an Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 231</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 1000</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250312">March 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20251030">October 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish an Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id3C7CAECF0F184D39B937564AECFCC13F" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8770E4E64D1F41BA9A8E958D2F6D69EC" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSFR00"><section id="id4486f2ef7fd147ac97209c9d170ba159"><enum>65.</enum><header>United States Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs</header><subsection id="id4fabe46a11404543974cf2f54b82cbe8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized within the Department of State an Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs, appointed under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="idfbf420b1c81a49e0a7b0a69cc954db51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Ambassador shall be appointed by the President, by, and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7fa0eea2d1664ded9301eb568de93a61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Ambassador is authorized to represent the United States in matters and cases relevant to Arctic affairs and shall be responsible to the Secretary of State for all matters, programs, and related activities pertaining to the Arctic region in the conduct of foreign policy by the Department, including, as appropriate, leading the coordination of programs carried out by United States Government agencies abroad, and such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8761af5ebe7848088c8e6fe82ef75b1c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Areas of responsibility</header><text>The Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs is authorized to maintain continuous observation and coordination of all matters indicated by the Secretary of State, including those pertaining to energy, environment, trade, and infrastructure development and maintenance, and, in consultation with the heads of other relevant departments and agencies, those pertaining to law enforcement and political-military affairs in the conduct of foreign policy in the Arctic, including programs carried out by other United States Government agencies when such programs pertain to the following matters, to the extent directed by the Secretary of State:</text><paragraph id="id8cee4c1d496c4208a68b2506d03137d6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>National security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96b891e639ad4bcdb345da12df700970"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Strengthening cooperation among Arctic countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b462810ad6b4f249ab32431a54b0cfc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The promotion of responsible natural resource management and economic development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd13c68d5993c4a8aabd003c52a77cffd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Protecting the Arctic environment and conserving its biological resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64b30057481c45379c044f16f6127abf"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Arctic indigenous peoples, including by involving them in decisions that affect them.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad584ecaf3224be7adca173bf2592e81"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Scientific monitoring and research.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83ab2d6bb52941beb8e1d690a6b18636"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional duties</header><text>In addition to the duties and responsibilities specified in subsections (c) and (d), the Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs shall also carry out such other relevant duties as the Secretary may assign.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc7e0017b8b7d4db48340f9e0c04d7d2f"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id4f7fb906f9314fc897ee5431a330f1ae"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Arctic region</header><text>The term <term>Arctic region</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id0810e98831764285add118e6096da863"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the geographic region north of the 66.56083 parallel latitude north of the equator;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ab3c287473248b3869c946c13060285"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all the United States territory north and west of the boundary formed by the Porcupine, Yukon, and Kuskokwim Rivers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id711aa199b641499094e8bc5e831b6bd9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all contiguous seas, including the Arctic Ocean and the Beaufort, Bering, and Chukchi Seas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa150a50e12b447782f289da244bf948"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Aleutian Chain.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f0f108b7c304c8fb1e51f37244f30f0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Arctic countries</header><text>The term <term>Arctic countries</term> means the permanent members of the Arctic Council, namely the United States, Canada, Denmark, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Russia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section id="id238b2b5b977d4877b4780a513adc6428" section-type="section-one" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="idf2a0bf39-c79e-4278-8db9-dcee42bd9108" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><section id="id6605d94a-4762-423c-ac36-e3601da4bf7f"><enum>66.</enum><header>United States Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs</header><subsection id="id05b19377-a21a-49be-ab0f-e8f7c149ec18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is authorized within the Department of State an Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs, appointed under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id0034bde7-8ac0-4b35-af0e-a093a499fc2a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Ambassador shall be appointed by the President, by, and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa561ca4d1124be1bf7607cb068ae2f0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Ambassador shall carry out the following duties:</text><paragraph id="id5cbffb3e63ed4ef4bd8c5c6a414c04be"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Advance United States interests in the Arctic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idacb713484a344a3a842347701a62704e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Engage with foreign governments, intergovernmental organizations, the Arctic Council, and other international or multilateral organizations of which the United States is a member or has observer status and which advance United States interests in the Arctic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id18432bacd4e64b6c85615bb7a5bb420d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Facilitate the development and coordination of United States foreign policy and programs in the Arctic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id919849614b9641508e82d0281f4f5dd9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Coordinate with relevant offices, bureaus, and interagency partners on efforts to counter the malign influence of the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China in Arctic nations and Arctic multilateral fora and organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id193a2c06e1c34f69803dc08c32a0e607"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Coordinate the diplomatic objectives with respect to the activities described in paragraph (1), and, as appropriate, represent the United States within multilateral fora that address international cooperation and foreign policy matters in the Arctic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide814fca19eac4637abac4bae10ed5488"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Help inform, in coordination with the Bureau of Economic Affairs, transnational commerce and commercial maritime transit in the Arctic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe6c497bd84644ecb12f4feb881a6098"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Ensure, in coordination with the Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, that scientific data, environmental monitoring, and scientific research cooperation is consistent with regional security planning programs and research security best practices in the Department of State and other relevant Departments and agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa65b3e5bf3c4739a6cd100160c4885b"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consult, as appropriate, with Arctic indigenous communities, including by ensuring equal application and full protection of laws relating to investment screening, foreign influence, and other relevant national security regulations and statutes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1cddbd72e0b84eaab28b93e067e5d80e"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSFR00" reported-display-style="italic">(9)</added-phrase></enum><text>Ensure that all actions taken to perform the duties described in this subsection are consistent with the Arctic Region Security Policy in accordance with subsection (f).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb22a38a5bea34e2b8a7f58f78383768d"><enum><added-phrase committee-id="SSFR00" reported-display-style="italic">(10)</added-phrase></enum><text>Use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to encourage other countries and international multilateral organizations to support the principles of the Arctic Region Security Policy implemented pursuant to subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1f03b63e-02a9-47bf-94d7-efdcaede69ca"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Areas of responsibility</header><text>The Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs is authorized to maintain continuous observation and coordination on matters related to the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idddfa578d1b9e45ef8e65cdcbd888c853"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Institutions for cooperation among the Arctic countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9153029e-2de9-471f-9af6-a42870a8ea07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Scientific monitoring and research on local, regional, and global environmental issues.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff6fab474c0f45a4836bd827000bac73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Responsible natural resource management and economic development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb7d5e3862e0043f2b209e3a82dab15c1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional duties</header><text>In addition to the duties and responsibilities specified in subsections (c) and (d), the Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs shall also carry out such other relevant duties as the Secretary of State may assign.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7d476e92-b346-4c84-8aa9-d9a5ded84317"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Arctic region security policy</header><text>The Bureau of European and Eurasian Affairs shall be the lead bureau for developing and implementing the United States’ Arctic Region Security Policy, in coordination with other relevant regional and functional bureaus and offices and relevant Federal departments and agencies to advance United States national security interests. The Arctic Region Security Policy shall advance United States national security interests by assessing, developing, budgeting for, and implementing plans, policies, and actions—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a6283a607b74c858280952b42bcc7c3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to bolster the diplomatic presence of the United States in Arctic countries, including through enhancements to diplomatic missions and facilities, participation in regional and bilateral dialogues that advance United States interests related to Arctic security, and coordination of United States initiatives and assistance programs across agencies to protect the national security of the United States and its allies and partners;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce6c1d2181474ca3be0e8567beb2dd10"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enhance the resilience of Arctic countries to the economic, environmental, and security effects that may result from increased accessibility of the Arctic region;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8d25db3a9344f72b18a9e2600f8b945"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assess specific added risks to the Arctic region and Arctic countries that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd81397662d034f73ae36f1dd42690382"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are vulnerable to the changing Arctic environment; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb45d125e8bc41588b3d75a8f748dff4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are strategically significant to the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde2192ce4451478c98ad651ae76a023c"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to advance principles of good governance by encouraging and cooperating with Arctic countries on collaborative approaches—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbfc3167e9a514ce7bab3dddf745cdeb9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to responsibly manage natural resources in the Arctic region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dcac2902f6744c39d90aec3bdf05098"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to share the burden of ensuring maritime safety in the Arctic region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id277d26d36c514a00adba07d0f87244ea"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to address challenges posed by the militarization of the Arctic region by the Russian Federation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbf388fdce1940ca9f1fa8de8b1907f5"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to address growing security cooperation in the Arctic region by the Russian Federation and People’s Republic of China and the implications for United States national security interests and Arctic security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c115188d87644d4aff859f9956a8270"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop multilateral policies among Arctic countries on the management of maritime transit routes through the Arctic region and work cooperatively on the transit policies for access to and transit in the Arctic Region by non-Arctic countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc279123fc3a44d24a83e815df021ecb7"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to facilitate the development of Arctic Region Security Action Plans to ensure effective implementation of the objectives identified in the Arctic Region Security Policy;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13c557f01e0b4c16bed2f98e4e38054e"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to evaluate the vulnerability, security, survivability, and resiliency of United States interests in the Arctic region;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc10b0e3f30944dd18575aa8e482f45f4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to counter malign influence from the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China in Arctic countries and Arctic multilateral fora, including through the exploitation or manipulation of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb57518e9c5945da9c603464da3f168b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">science and research partnerships or organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf15a845423fa4c2981fae6c61e6bb28e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">economic development projects in strategic sectors including transportation, energy, and telecommunications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49246405a7ee4a0688cb6ea584db16a8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educational, cultural, and religious organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida230f2e546e34fdb95b0d16330c08baa"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engagements with subnational and indigenous governance structures; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dcfcb13daf645708a63df413c3ae3f4"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase coordination among North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Arctic allies on the protection of critical infrastructure, including energy, telecommunications, and scientific infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc06c94915414ab8b21ca4cd2bf69f59"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Restrictions and requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f60d2bf594e4af6be2c8c1868cf8a0a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scope of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs and any other personnel assigned to this office shall not have any authority, or role in decision-making on United States domestic policy issues beyond those directly related to United States foreign policy with international partners and stakeholders in the Arctic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id202b6faacb3642568cc8cfdc9675ebf5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefings requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs shall provide periodic briefings to the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and the House Foreign Affairs Committee on diplomatic engagements in the Arctic.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd26c8e032ac64681889aba8caf9a2460"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance related to attendance and participation at Arctic conferences and multilateral fora</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall disseminate guidance, in coordination with the Bureau of Diplomatic Security and relevant interagency partners, for the attendance and participation of United States Government officials at Arctic conferences and multilateral fora, taking into consideration—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcd78a9260fc4858b2766df49702e2d7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential for United States Government attendance to advance United States national security and foreign policy objectives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70701555efe947b5a1f29a675594cbbb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree to which the organization hosting or funding a conference or other event is funded, controlled, or advances the interests of the Russian Federation or People’s Republic of China. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2935e611a04430db1b21ea1f3c74e5b"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47dabf31975e480dbcf28faf068f2910"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Arctic countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Arctic countries</term> means the permanent members of the Arctic Council, namely the United States, Canada, Denmark, Iceland, Norway, Sweden, Finland, and Russia.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8a028908202457ba002b83e1b94d67c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Arctic region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Arctic region</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id259e09d5c38d4ed3bfd97e4926863252"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the geographic region north of the 66.56083 parallel latitude north of the equator;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85d6349e20e541c3b588db6401fc255e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all the United States territory north and west of the boundary formed by the Porcupine, Yukon, and Kuskokwim Rivers; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fae8c674aa1474fa14e031310efe71f"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all contiguous seas, including the Arctic Ocean and the Beaufort, Bering, and Chukchi Seas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b01b98d41464f739442e8dc8b03d783"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Aleutian Chain.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id545ffbf95d0b484782af5a1efcf54564" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSFR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3c71f08b68a418a81cb66e95306f97c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on Russian and Chinese malign influence in the Arctic region</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55c92fb212b2404a90a6ad7edfb4db18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, the Secretary of Defense, and other relevant Departments and Federal agencies, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on Russian and Chinese malign influence in the Arctic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0c7b432b8bb466dad592524ea2d59e7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68d7e67c3a8347fe8b222e731ee93379"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the Arctic strategies of Russia and China and their impact on United States national security, scientific, and foreign policy interests in the region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ad4959f3ee246ad8cc9f4c082ebe6a1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine Russian and Chinese cooperation in the Arctic region and implications for the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9775ea60447e44a9b0e0e54e2df3f956"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the efforts of Russia and China to advance their strategic interests in the Arctic region through exploiting, manipulating, or co-opting non-governmental and international organizations in the Arctic region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43a4043769064d01a8a517277de79665"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a list of multilateral engagements and conferences attended by the Ambassador-at-Large for Arctic Affairs during the reporting period and an explanation of how such engagements countered Russian and Chinese influence and advanced United States national security and foreign policy interests;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb869fccd01714c84ba70199d4bdd0487"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine Russian and Chinese efforts to gain control and influence over key sectors in the Arctic region, including critical minerals, energy, transportation, and fishing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61f298faee8144b89edbc7f26b778f13"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess Russian and Chinese efforts to exploit scientific and academic research in the Arctic, including through research partnerships with academic institutions in the United States and other Arctic countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddcc10c117dee4b1fb6b111bc3ad9a2e4"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the tools, resources, and funding available to counter Russian and Chinese influence in the Arctic region.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ea80135b9fe4d6398cc0736c6f42d1d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, with a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3a19b2041804be5960371e0cd7deb52" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reporting requirement in this section shall expire on the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20251030">October 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

