<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H534E954766044021BDC4668F58B9BB19" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1401 IH: Honoring John Wathan on his induction into the Kansas City Royals Hall of Fame.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1401</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring John Wathan on his induction into the Kansas City Royals Hall of Fame.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan dedicated 47 years of service to the Kansas City Royals as a player, coach, manager, broadcaster, scout, instructor, and special assistant;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan played 10 Major League seasons with the Kansas City Royals from 1976 through 1985 and was a member of the Kansas City Royals’ 1985 World Series championship team;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan played an integral role in the success of the Kansas City Royals, including contributing to the Kansas City Royals’ first World Series championship in 1985;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan remains the Major League Baseball single season record holder for stolen bases by a catcher, recording 36 stolen bases during the 1982 season;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan managed the Kansas City Royals from 1987 through 1991 and continued to serve the Kansas City Royals in numerous leadership roles following his managerial tenure;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, following his playing career, John Wathan continued to serve the Kansas City Royals as a coach, manager, broadcaster, scout, and mentor to countless players and baseball professionals;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan’s commitment to excellence, leadership, and dedication helped shape generations of Kansas City Royals players and contributed significantly to the success and culture of the Kansas City Royals;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan’s contributions helped establish the Kansas City Royals as one of Major League Baseball’s premier franchises and brought pride to Kansas City, Missouri, and baseball fans throughout the State; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas John Wathan’s lifelong devotion to baseball and the Kansas City Royals has earned him the admiration of fans throughout Missouri and across the Nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H706AC9FDAA474BBEB9E41F922C730BB8"> <section id="H15F1613815DA4E858B0B80451CD82187" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H57B2F008DE8F4F018E86EB2D9AF93206"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates John Wathan on his induction into the Kansas City Royals Hall of Fame;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CC959FBC0744EB39236901B9A923747"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors his distinguished career and decades of service to the Kansas City Royals; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6C36D703DE040CF915EADAE8A104CB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes his contributions to the sport of baseball and to the Kansas City community.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

