<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA2F045563F0E4BBAAE26BB05608BD243" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1167 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the month of April 2026 as “Parkinson’s Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1167</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the month of April 2026 as <quote>Parkinson&#8217;s Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Parkinson’s disease—</text> <paragraph id="id6bb238f8190249a28e555afc573df77d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affects over 1,000,000 individuals in the United States with nearly 90,000 individuals diagnosed each year;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idb60ebac595ba4321aea944c733f70eac"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is the fastest-growing and second most common neurodegenerative disease in the world;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ide002dc96bc2340ec9ac41b61e48c51fd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is believed to be caused by a combination of genetic and environmental factors, but the exact cause in most individuals is still unknown; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idb4f75b9d52fe48119e39fbe700d8e78e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is the 13th leading cause of death in the United States, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, by the year 2045, it is estimated that the number of individuals in the United States with Parkinson’s disease and related conditions will reach 1,700,000, and will cost the United States $112,400,000,000;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the symptoms of Parkinson’s disease can include dementia and cognitive impairment, tremors, slowness of movement and rigidity, gait and balance difficulties, speech and swallowing difficulties, depression, and a variety of other symptoms;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there are millions of family caregivers, friends, and loved ones whose lives are greatly affected by Parkinson’s disease, and recent analysis shows care partners of those facing Parkinson’s shouldered $8,300,000,000 in lost earnings and productivity due to reduced work hours and early retirement in 2024; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas more research, education, and community support services are needed—</text> <paragraph id="idf0398180cbed49cca7070b96d008c271"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to find better treatments and a cure for Parkinson’s disease; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="idbd0de9796c314fad9fa321f90343dad7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to maintain the dignity of individuals living with Parkinson's disease: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0A261E47BD524622993E3B26BCC5B2AB"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8585C0F634FD4FA681C8519E56C1BA34"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4999149ADBD2443C9D35F1AB54C25395"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Parkinson’s Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD70FEAB882A248DF97E88013337F7954"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of Parkinson’s Awareness Month;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58C3E35563D7407591E8B6B79F6BE945"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continues to support research to find better treatments and a cure for Parkinson’s disease;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85E0A3C790124E6EAD093629DC4A3C8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the individuals living with Parkinson’s disease who participate in vital clinical trials to advance the knowledge of the disease; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9433B639F48A499BAD01BADFA22C7318"><enum>(5)</enum><text>commends the dedication of organizations, volunteers, researchers, and millions of individuals across the United States working to improve the quality of life of people living with Parkinson’s disease and their families. </text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

