<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBBE32122F5C14D0D964448B306ACCFE3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6879 IH: Restoring Export and Security Trade Restrictions for Integrated Circuit Technologies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6879</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit sales of the most advanced artificial intelligence chips to countries of concern and facilitate the safe and efficient transfer of chips to approved United States persons abroad.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF068F460AD7F4B3489838299F9748715" style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"> 
<section id="HF4BE0BDA91EA4AD3B5BA75BA5BA76644" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Export and Security Trade Restrictions for Integrated Circuit Technologies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RESTRICT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEA1D701B6758498B810240D2BD93B3A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on exports of advanced integrated circuits to countries of concern</header> <subsection id="HAA72540249C047B9BC5BF472FE2A59DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part I of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4811">50 U.S.C. 4811 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1758 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7F282952B90E4DDD9AF941CE01A5B99D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC6846BF6E1284B4BB10B322BACDDD264"><enum>1758A.</enum><header>Control of exports of advanced integrated circuits</header> 
<subsection id="H5C698E07F8E9497FAEBEA02D9E11841E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H41A4A5523487431EA62C028ECD84C4F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced integrated circuit or product</header> <subparagraph id="H7E99B171F1DF41258B440A031F1DB349"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>advanced integrated circuit</term> means an integrated circuit, computer, or other product containing such a circuit—</text> 
<clause id="H35291921FE8247858A47D9219862733D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">classified under Export Control Classification Number 3A090 or 4A090 or a <quote>.z</quote> Export Control Classification Number on January 1, 2025; or</text></clause> <clause id="H94FE2912FFF846389F475DCFD4C670A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is functionally equivalent or substantially similar to a circuit, computer, or product described in clause (i); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H84ACE585134F4A44882269E0C061DE20"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is designed or marketed for data centers.</text></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60C9D700390E4BE5B2D2AF75C8652B4A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority to update definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 24 months after the date of the enactment of this section, to keep pace with technological advancements in computing, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security may revise the definition of <quote>advanced integrated circuit</quote> through notice in the Federal Register, so long as—</text> 
<clause id="H8F48F734F1D74974947B2FD525B5A24B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the revision poses no adverse impact on the national security of the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="H95DC3167649449DCA88A106ADFB448EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Under Secretary has consulted with the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate on the proposed change to the definition at least 30 days prior to making the change.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6943C66333C7483EB9B148738F54E927"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commerce control list</header><text>The term <term>Commerce Control List</term> means the list set forth in Supplement No. 1 to part 774 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6629FA9405634A78B832BFFFA7BFA0AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D823D4555B24BA2B991B9920972C791"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a country listed in Country Group D:5 in Supplement No. 1 to part 740 of the Export Administration Regulations on January 1, 2025;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H096A2B6EF79547A0860CC6B4477255E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Macau Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCF60AABE5CB64A7ABB9805EC859F4222"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB35559E3E1DC40AABAF58B3AF35AD086"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered country</header><text>The term <quote>covered country</quote> means a country listed in Country Group D in Supplement No. 1 to part 740 of the Export Administration Regulations on January 1, 2025.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87962BC49FCC4A4B8FC9B02E0C5690F8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Approved United States person</header><text>The term <term>approved United States person</term> means any United States person designated as an approved United States person pursuant to the regulations outlined in subsection (d)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2E3F2F4AAF7E43F591F316DED92017AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>License requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall require a license for the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of an advanced integrated circuit or product to a covered country.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB133C71A9BA6462C8738148E4DF0F016"><enum>(c)</enum><header>License policy for countries of concern</header><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall deny a license for the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of an advanced integrated circuit or product to an entity that is primarily located or headquartered in, or the ultimate parent company of which is headquartered in, a country of concern.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3FF95ED23E5F4ECD82AFFBAE21B8664C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption from certain license requirement for approved United States persons</header> <paragraph id="HFE0620DDB6B7441382CEEF6AFA0B412D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The license requirement under subsection (b) shall not apply to the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of an advanced integrated circuit or product if the advanced integrated circuit or product—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC3E9412504864E2388C01A39D686C166"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is destined for a country that is not a country of concern; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6E314CA202C4A909EE27ADCAD1BE45B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>remains under the ownership and control of an approved United States person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8739E1ED2A6422ABDF195401D6A2EB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security shall prescribe regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="H25E9EC7C24CF4F128C1925C7C9B4B606"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing clear standards and requirements a United States person is mandated to meet to obtain a designation as an approved United States person, which shall include—</text> 
<clause id="HBA9386C11176412788DFFB2F8B80DEA0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a requirement that not more than 10 percent of the ultimate beneficial ownership of the United States person may be held, directly or indirectly, by any entity that primarily resides or is domiciled in a country of concern;</text></clause> <clause id="H78C6D7F862BE44ABB05ED67EAEEFE822"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">physical security, cybersecurity, remote access security, and other measures designed to prevent the misuse, illicit access, illicit transfer, or diversion of advanced integrated circuits and products;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H52CF46FCC3574FAC866A5110D85AF728"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>robust know your customer standards; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4EA2FE7A637647429079469C44CAB518"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>annual audit or attestation requirements to ensure compliance with clauses (i), (ii), and (iii); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5412AE5AE00C4B51AF9AE8B6AE1B0719"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describing the process by which the Under Secretary shall approve such a designation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6DE9012E4E142CB9A8CD26F25C68754"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1691417A727041D984BE2F94876AC689"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA11225D821CF4A01865DEE4E18D07F41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the table of contents in section 2(b), by inserting after the item relating to section 1758 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H27528C9B436F4B8BBA98F4BDE29627CB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1758A. Control of exports of advanced integrated circuits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDF9F4E47E6645A0A80E7657C2DFD3BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the table of contents for title XVII of division A, by inserting after the item relating to section 1758 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCB184BAE3E914AAB8214383AD791E642" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1758A. Control of exports of advanced integrated circuits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

