<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA11E70B6F9C14FB28E07CBA2E15FCDC9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8502 IH: Heirs’ Agricultural Resources, Viability, Education, and Succession Transfer</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8502</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct a study on ways to
      increase opportunities for 1890 Institutions to conduct educational programs and provide
      technical assistance with respect to issues relating to the transfer of agricultural land and
      assets, including heirs property, to the next generation of farmers and ranchers, and for
      other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B1CEA41338A430480B6367A92B394FF" style="OLC">
    <section id="H60F140A4996E4931B3E62B0A2CCA8377" section-type="section-one">
      <enum>1.</enum>
      <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heirs’ Agricultural Resources, Viability, Education, and Succession Transfer</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HARVEST Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
    </section>
    <section id="H9AB7BDBB46664B808116C4C6C62CCA6E">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Study on technical assistance with respect to transfer of agricultural land and
        assets</header>
      <subsection id="HAC7645047CF3420B9EC523763CBF4D7B">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2026, the Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study on, and submit to Congress a report on, ways to increase opportunities for 1890 Institutions (as defined in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</external-xref>)) to conduct educational programs and provide technical assistance with respect to issues relating to the transfer of agricultural land and assets, including heirs property, to the next generation of farmers and ranchers.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="H37C725CE274442ADB9B066144C4754A0">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Heirs property defined</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>heirs property</term> means real property held in tenancy in common which, as of the date on which a partition action is filed, satisfies all of the following requirements:</text>
        <paragraph id="H605533AF55B84C7CA2A59E779206BDD9">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>There is no recorded agreement binding all the co-tenants which governs the partition of the property.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H4888C20F3C084FF9BD331C687067337A">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>One or more of the co-tenants acquired title from a relative, whether living or deceased.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HF2085FD78FA04AD59CED16971D3E80A8">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Any of the following applies:</text> <subparagraph id="H78D364F3786546D18CAAA25F81A233E0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>20 percent or more of the interests are held by co-tenants who are relatives.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H824E41F41815499CBA43CA2379E928DA">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>20 percent or more of the interests are held by an individual who acquired title from a relative, whether living or deceased.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HB0539F38DDED495381C784D83DE51B6F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>20 percent or more of the co-tenants are relatives.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

