<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA9BD3D24C85B402697F8B46F545E8BCF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8949 IH: Capitol Police Retirement Reform Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8949</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H000874">Mr. Hoyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to include certain overtime pay received by members of the Capitol Police in the computation of annuities for such members, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE219DEE832FA4436BFDD0BB9FD7F8DCD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA319A8C157794532A15364CC07D513C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Capitol Police Retirement Reform Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6D091775F2FD47AEBBD10EBF59F05131"><enum>2.</enum><header>FLSA overtime compensation included as basic pay of members of capitol police</header> <subsection id="HE73B8E8A9C824A3B8C5278C408C1EDFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8331(3) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1D30E95FEB2D44CE943382DEE3934613"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E4A86AE23854DD084DB12EC82F9824A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F0CA6C428064249B0071ACD03B3BF6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (I) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HEF6FF4883E994A458D3035FC44603DFA" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H8AF09866E76F4356A7CB53225FBA01B9"> <enum>(J)</enum> <text>with respect to a member of the Capitol Police, overtime pay received on or after the date of enactment of this subparagraph for overtime under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) by operation of section 102(a)(1) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1302">2 U.S.C. 1302(a)(1)</external-xref>), for up to an amount equal to 50 percent of any annual statutory maximum in overtime pay for customs officers set pursuant to section 5(c)(1) of the Act of February 13, 1911 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/267">19 U.S.C. 267(c)(1)</external-xref>);</text>
            </subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H489DB0E57B124413A5256C5B315FC177"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the undesignated matter following subparagraph (J) (as added by paragraph (3)), by striking <quote>subparagraphs (B) through (I) of this paragraph</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (B) through (J) of this paragraph,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3F6B409F3AFD4C25AD606605173F369E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header> <paragraph id="H6F8B02FB94C740389878F0878CC918EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8415 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H66A645CD46264B8C92EC687115D3662F" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="HBB17E45F7BEB4BBBB4D80C96475B3EF9"><enum>(o)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H92E2576BED9C46B1B8A467E3603CF49F" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No part of overtime pay (as described in section 8331(3)(J)) paid to a member of the Capitol Police shall be treated as basic pay for purposes of any computation of an annuity under this section, unless, before the date of the separation on which entitlement to annuity is based, the separating individual has completed at least 15 years of service (whether performed before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this subsection).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3605F452E9414E6AA9B7A840C543D145" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the condition under paragraph (1) is met, then any amounts received by the individual in the form of such overtime pay shall (for the purposes referred to in paragraph (1)) be treated as basic pay, but only to the extent that such amounts are attributable to service performed on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85CF5EC596CC4321A699D5D8694D788D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All amounts received as overtime pay (as described in section 8331(3)(J)) shall, to the extent attributable to service performed on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection, be treated as basic pay for purposes of computing—</text> <subparagraph id="HD3585D71C90A4042A7B9CEA0071AE0D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an annuity under section 8452; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78070D6136BC43FEB22AFDC5D47CFA92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a survivor annuity under subchapter IV, if based on the service of an individual who dies before separating from service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1995FE6EFBCF4D248E58241F16247F10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information</header><text>Not less than once every year following the date of enactment of this section, the United States Capitol Police shall provide information to the Office of Personnel Management for the purposes of carrying out this section and the amendments made by this section, including information used to determine the normal-cost percentage (as that term is defined in section 8401 of title 5, United States Code).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

