<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HF99CF3D74ED248368F4B7DA13C550A33"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6278 IH: Charlie Kirk Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6278</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Ms. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Charles <quote>Charlie</quote>
            Kirk, in recognition of his unwavering dedication to the American Spirit, even to the
 point of death at the hand of a terrorist.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3C7F7FC103B1404CB88DFB171A97FE8D"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB4E01B8D62164D329843CD2980E97EE7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Charlie Kirk Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9A5EE86E111C440E8E3EF0C54CF88B61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4041C03FC81141309A035C68046CD314"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Charles <quote>Charlie</quote> James Kirk, born October 14, 1993, was an American hero whose life was tragically cut short by a political assassin on September 10, 2025, at Utah Valley University.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A606D18DB2C43E5954DDD418CE29DEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Charlie Kirk was a devout follower of the Lord Jesus Christ and courageously proclaimed the truth of the Gospel, fighting the good fight and keeping the faith until death.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34053D4A018A434AB34F4F7459666D76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A dedicated husband to his beloved wife, Erika Kirk, and a loving father to his daughter and son, through the example of his well-lived life, Charlie Kirk inspired a generation of people in the United States to embrace the traditional values of family, faith, and freedom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB059FE56640147A7AA707028D189E362"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Charlie Kirk had an undeniable love for his country and inspired an entire generation of young people to boldly protect and defend the principles of the founding of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81253C563B144309B067C0DFC11B767C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2012, at just 18 years of age, he founded Turning Point USA, an organization with the mission to <quote>identify, educate, train, and organize students to promote the principles of fiscal responsibility, free markets, and limited government</quote>, which grew to be the largest conservative youth organization in the United States, with over 800 chapters on college campuses and over 1,000 high school chapters nationwide, and through which Charlie Kirk—</text><subparagraph id="HE3DC39C68B87479CA13654ADE11CA24C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impacted the lives of countless people throughout the United States and the world, especially youth, encouraging them in their beliefs and emboldening them to stand up for truth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3876B2645AE041389DD0D9CD6511FD22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advocated for the <quote>development of knowledge, skills, values, and motivation</quote> in order to <quote>restore traditional American values like patriotism, respect for life, liberty, family, and fiscal responsibility</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91701D5999014105920433BA2E3EBCD1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hosted annual summits such as Turning Point USA’s Student Action Summit, the Young Women’s Leadership Summit, and AmericaFest, which have featured many prominent leaders and political figures, such as United States President Donald J. Trump.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86483552F33946A5800D0984E0B06C9D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Charlie Kirk hosted The Charlie Kirk Show, a top-ranking daily radio and podcast show.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1067197FFA5A4F3597A494419FBF0096"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Charlie Kirk regularly and respectfully—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H152512844FF3471EBD0A423C10D50A5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participated in civil discourse surrounding the political landscape of the United States and reinspired belief in the principles of the country’s founding; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC99F2FCF8ED4B71875AD9C4BC487B6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaged with those who opposed him and his beliefs and did so with earnestness and desire to create awareness for truth and the ability to find unity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E0248F81073476892B5CF8F015F8E85"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Charlie Kirk was the personification of the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, never compromising the truth while also treating those with whom he disagreed with dignity and respect.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H03BEDE5F89FD42CB8E92847E3E51A359"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="HEEACE8D3DDF84EC1BDB93189D61E1B7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of Congress, of 2 gold medals of appropriate design to Charles <quote>Charlie</quote> Kirk, in recognition of his life, service, and dedication to the people of the United States, of which—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H403556E356BB453E87F94873EDB794E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 shall be presented to his family; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BE2075C4E8648699323D676CC9AC4C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution for display and preservation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5F28DC193CC408EA47B52D47E9B04A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public display</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a)(2), the gold medal shall be displayed as appropriate, ensuring that the legacy and contributions of Charles <quote>Charlie</quote> Kirk are preserved for the people of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4FC9A03796BE46B796D0FF085D39B3BA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design and striking</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37D3B6315B7B4BE39FECA68C44B90F6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the award described in section 3, the Secretary of the Treasury (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4553712CF63C4A23A82ACF77B8BC753A"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Authority To strike duplicate medals</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to subsection (a), at a price sufficient to cover the costs thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text>
 </subsection></section><section id="H4DB1776E2B2B41A0991A8321B95ADA13"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="H5A5C2F5694FC4CC4956B0719332FBD2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE684AD00E7CA44B584A96C80416F15B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD64A52DA5406416E988D1F360C4D148D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="HE2CB2D29F9A645B8800490E9DFFFEA97"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Authority To use fund amounts</header> <text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4F4151B64F0345508413589AA3C02D76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

