<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26222-8XM-F4-SNY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 689 ATS: Congratulating the University of South Carolina Aiken women’s polo team on winning the 2026 United States Polo Association Division I Women’s National Intercollegiate Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 689</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the University of South Carolina Aiken women’s polo team on winning the 2026 United States Polo Association Division I Women’s National Intercollegiate Championship.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 22, 2026, the University of South Carolina Aiken (referred to in this preamble as <quote>USCA</quote>) women’s polo team secured a 15 to 6 win against Texas A&amp;M University to win the 2026 United States Polo Association Division I Women’s National Intercollegiate Championship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this win marks the first national title in program history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this win marks the first undefeated season in program history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every member of the USCA women’s polo team contributed to the successful 2026 United States Polo Association Division I intercollegiate championship season and national title victory;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the coaches and staff of the USCA women’s polo team played a vital role in the success of the USCA Pacers during the 2026 season; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the USCA Pacers showed immense strength, resilience, and teamwork to win the national championship: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id7f3f0ebc3f714325a474da21f0db53fd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the University of South Carolina Aiken women’s polo team for an incredible season and for winning the United States Polo Association Division I Women’s National Intercollegiate Championship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85c9cd0e8bf841808858e3bd8df687c0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements of all players, coaches, and staff who contributed to the success of the team; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7af26a6cf8a4ee885aa7f152975937c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="idd3fe7c8315a440eba0e854867da17319"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Brianna Jane Jordan, team member;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4cf90fb3b6f54273a860f11c14b28a10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Madison Ann Jordan, team member; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id732f2a2ad62646a49dc163724f9da509"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Winifred Anne Branscum, team member.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

