<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2FA6D1B39E3F410F8962562CBE125AF9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9723 IH: Fit Future Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9723</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, and Nutrition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H43D51FEFDFBF49988F8DEB8AD39B8C4C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD4C6CB5E3D0647ACB25608ED3EBE9823" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fit Future Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFEC79D5273334439A005D4C891A3DE21"><enum>2.</enum><header>President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, and Nutrition</header> <subsection id="HCFE86EF766C84363BCC35EAA1438F719"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the President’s Council on Sports, Fitness, and Nutrition (referred to in this section as the <quote>Council</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29429E9AFC4A4C1F9CA1BAA773A7E7D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<paragraph id="H9A3FDB50D3444A8A9C17F102BC5CCF90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointments</header><text>The Council shall consist of not more than 30 members appointed by the President.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA98B57337D014107A282D333A5FB43CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the Council may include representatives of relevant stakeholders.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB073A3546BA84573BCE69698199B12A5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>A member of the Council—</text> <subparagraph id="H5442B3575CCC4C01930D978159A1A053"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall serve for a term of 2 years;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D9AB73A61D04426B112034103D3910A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be eligible for reappointment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC04D77F44F5C4A2EBD257BBBFCEA6A9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may continue to serve after the expiration of the term described in subparagraph (A) until the appointment of a successor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E19BB635CE944C5A96025BFA41C4E78"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chair; Vice Chair</header><text>The President may designate one or more of the members of the Council to serve as the Chair or Vice Chair of the Council.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C20C412B16741A08D2B9F9FCDA4263A" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions of Council</header> <paragraph id="HC70DABB35B4442CF8B11C3D3F68FF67F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA990B3F4E05F43ADB1AD059FDD7D5B8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the President and Secretary of Health and Human Services concerning progress made in carrying out the provisions of this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H234BB8028ADF40EBA5B3E7E07ED14F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend to the President and Secretary of Health and Human Services actions to accelerate such progress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A6FF280634E477493754474CE6BE60D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Council shall recommend—</text> <subparagraph id="H191BAE268AC944D682020A76398EB71C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies for reestablishing and implementing the Presidential Fitness Test, with any appropriate improvements, as the main assessment tool for a Presidential Fitness Award;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25FE025D825144EAB85E67FB62954FD1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strategies for the promotion of Presidential challenges and school-based programs that reward excellence in physical education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49345333637C47F193D8A08AB44A7199"><enum>(C)</enum><text>bold and innovative fitness goals for American youth with the aim of fostering a new generation of healthy, active citizens;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H916FA4AF281A4268906631391C28AAE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>campaigns and events that elevate American sports, military readiness, and health traditions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B7459EA6B3D450FB82590217078706C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>actions and opportunities at the global, national, State, and local levels that expand participation in sports and engagement in physical fitness and that emphasize the importance of an active lifestyle and good nutrition, including partnerships with professional athletes, sports organizations, player’s associations, influential figures, nonprofit organizations, and community groups to inspire all Americans, among other initiatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16E23E5F656D4436A5319E5119104AB7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>strategies to address the growing national security threat posed by the increasing rates of childhood obesity, chronic diseases, and sedentary lifestyles, which threaten the future readiness of the United States workforce and military.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HC14039D8311C42CC92315E8141DC08B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header> <paragraph id="HE108371DFEC942CDBFB7B573511A2CD8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall designate an Executive Director of the Council who shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC07BAEBD3A9946D185B401860C63096F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>manage day-to-day operations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H46CE9C502A0D4473847BDFD47688FED1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as a liaison to the President and the Secretary of Health and Human Services on matters and activities pertaining to the Council; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H585E59B621994B70968A35BD66E7B8E3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>oversee engagement with executive departments and agencies, athletic institutions, and community partners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7735BCA6B65E4F518377540CF4523A71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information to be furnished by departments and agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each executive department and agency shall, to the extent permitted by law and subject to the availability of funds, furnish such information and assistance to the Council as the Council may request.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B56EE20B28543029C97B734543BEF19"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Council shall serve without compensation but may receive travel reimbursement, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, subject to the availability of funds.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E72E5C80D1444AB8BD70FA9D2730B82"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding; administrative and technical support</header> <subparagraph id="H32FC6F1F07A244FC83AB2FAA2423C133"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide such funding and administrative and technical support as the Council may require, subject to appropriations Acts.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD52C20BBA4FF443EB422B4E80E4CF6C6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council may receive funds from the National Foundation on Fitness, Sports, and Nutrition in accordance with the National Foundation on Fitness, Sports, and Nutrition Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/332">Public Law 111–332</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72644F6E598F4C2686EF074C4CC82DFA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council may, with the approval of the President, establish subcommittees as appropriate to aid in the work of the Council.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88C65E5E8D4A461E8626872D5A70F0B8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Seal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall modify the seal of the <quote>President’s Council on Physical Fitness and Sports</quote> to reflect the name of the Council as established by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE759F2CBE7C044AEB1699E2913569A30"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (known as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), may apply to the administration of this section, any functions of the President under such chapter, except that of reporting to the Congress, shall be performed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in accordance with the guidelines and procedures issued by the Administrator of General Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3EEA30131CB47ADA4A17694096E983D" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Council shall terminate on a date designated by the President.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

