<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25B81-8KY-FD-ST1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 517 IS: Expressing opposition to congressional spending on earmarks. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 517</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing opposition to congressional spending on earmarks. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas fiscal year 2022 marked the return of <quote>congressionally directed spending</quote> and <quote>community project funding</quote>, also known as <quote>earmarks</quote>, after a 12-year hiatus;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the return of earmarks marked the return of lawmakers using their powers to circumvent the rules of the Senate in order to direct taxpayer dollars to wasteful projects;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, while Congress has the power of the purse, it must be prescriptive and effective in funding programs, projects, and activities of the Federal Government, which is now more than $38,000,000,000,000 in debt, rather than focus on funding earmarks that are wasteful in nature;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has dramatically increased deficit spending, overseeing more than $12,500,000,000,000 in deficit spending since 2020;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas interest payments on the United States national debt have exceeded $1,000,000,000,000 annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Congressional Budget Office projects that between 2025 and 2055, publicly held debt by the United States will increase by $108,100,000,000,000, from $30,100,000,000,000 to $138,200,000,000,000;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Senate Republicans adopted a 2-year moratorium on earmarks in 2010;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Senate Republicans voted favorably for a permanent ban on earmarks in 2019 and reaffirmed that ban in 2021;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas former Senator Tom Coburn condemned the use of earmarks as a <quote>gateway drug to overspending</quote> and former Senator John McCain called earmarks <quote>the gateway drug to corruption and overspending in Washington</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas several former Members of Congress and lobbyists have been convicted of crimes related to earmarking;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is crucial that Congress spend taxpayer dollars wisely and with the best return on investment; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress must stop this reckless Federal spending and corrupt political dealing, start paying down the debt of the United States, and get the United States back on track: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id69fee03fc59f4eed8899c6141e1b5606"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the use of <quote>congressionally directed spending</quote> and <quote>community project funding</quote>, known as <quote>earmarks</quote>, to direct and appropriate taxpayer dollars in any form;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4d530a109e84ebcaf5def0794dbbfd4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaffirms the previous ban on the use of earmarks and affirms to restore the ban permanently and immediately; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01a05ca41e764faca60e832d0db76f8b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms the need for Congress to reign in overspending to help curb the inflation crisis that is crippling the families of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

