<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25235-6C7-03-HD6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 536 ATS: Designating December 2, 2025, as “World Nuclear Energy Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 536</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251208" legis-day="20251204">December 8 (legislative day, December 4), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating December 2, 2025, as <quote>World Nuclear Energy Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 2, 1942, Enrico Fermi and his team achieved a historic milestone by demonstrating the first self-sustaining, controlled nuclear chain reaction in the world at Chicago Pile–1;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, on December 2, 1957, in the State of Pennsylvania, the Shippingport Atomic Power Station began operations as the first commercial nuclear power plant in the world, dedicated exclusively to peaceful applications;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas nuclear energy produces—</text><paragraph id="id102708bd7e914b158e94207411fd77f8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nearly 18 percent of the electricity generated in the United States; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73d51a0868804241a30d9bd7411ef41b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">43 percent of the carbon-free electricity generated in the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the nuclear sector of the United States—</text><paragraph id="id9f6fa43b4f8c4896901dcb62179bfce1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>directly employs more than 70,000 people in high-quality jobs that last for decades; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f7da4a91da442539c36cf4cb018ab93"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is responsible for more than 180,000 secondary jobs;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for every 100 nuclear power plant jobs, another 250 jobs are created in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nuclear energy plays a key role in the national security of the United States, as the United States has the largest nuclear-powered Navy in the world, which is supported by—</text><paragraph id="id5d492865688949818794efadea583ad2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the commercial nuclear energy industry in the United States; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa3b765359df4eb48e34d9798abaa4c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a shared nuclear supply chain;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas advanced nuclear technologies are vital to powering space exploration;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nuclear energy promotes grid security and reliability by being one of the least expensive sources of baseload power generation worldwide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nuclear power plants are largely resilient to adverse weather events, providing electricity 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days a year to distressed areas when other sources of electricity shut down;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas nuclear energy contributes an estimated $63,800,000,000 per year to the gross domestic product of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a strong civilian nuclear sector is essential to United States leadership in global energy diplomacy, which allows the United States to influence and promote the peaceful use of nuclear technologies; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States collaborates with other countries to develop new and innovative opportunities for nuclear technologies: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id359b7b1cc8a74329a279e795aa0630cc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates December 2, 2025, as <quote>World Nuclear Energy Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5276042440df404e86521e008aeb8c35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the contributions of nuclear energy in advancing clean, reliable, and sustainable power generation worldwide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9389df4b05149bca75dca7f40970fcb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the scientists, engineers, and innovators who have worked toward harnessing the potential of nuclear technology for the betterment of humanity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf053a0f7f7084d3ab46c93891958439f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends the global community for its commitment to the safe and responsible utilization of nuclear energy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2dffe925b9ea49eea7c298b8b42ff066"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages continued cooperation domestically and abroad in research, development, and implementation of nuclear energy technologies. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

