<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" public-private="public" dms-id="H7FCACB14604A434285C11EC4AF819F85" stage-count="1" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4684 : Star-Spangled Summit Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4684</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to issue a special use permit with respect to the maintaining of a flagpole bearing the flag of the United States at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point, Utah, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H4945AE15C0AC41DFAFA94CDA1E8F847A"><section id="H06CB126021DF4468BBF5EB9FE0FEB936" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Star-Spangled Summit Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7094A6AF4623448499AA294C4C307957"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special use permit for installation, operation, maintenance, and removal of covered flagpole at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point</header><subsection id="H4021193CA95840C79229D3837AE136C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H81BB8DEBFE504096A6A621B13189FD93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered flagpole</header><text>The term <quote>covered flagpole</quote> means a flagpole bearing the flag of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27D6C0F6892D44FD8D8F03D1F7D724FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Kyhv peak lookout point</header><text>The term <quote>Kyhv Peak Lookout Point</quote> means the peak within the Uinta National Forest overlooking Utah Valley and located approximately at latitude 40°16′18.14″ N, longitude 111°36′58.57″ W.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF552932790994091AE72DFC4E6E984D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified person</header><text>The term <quote>qualified person</quote> means an individual that resides in, or a nonprofit entity or volunteer organization that carries out operations of the entity or organization in, Utah County, Utah, that has—</text><subparagraph id="H03AF7E611909451F975AD1EA43AE12E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>experience placing, maintaining, or otherwise caring for a covered flagpole; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F9F3A06BB5C498AA9F8FC6571E53BA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other experience determined relevant by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2706309383F475CBF063439295411C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD4ADA06C07048E18430F5ED5D50C142"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special use permit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall issue a special use permit for a period of 10 years for the installation, operation, maintenance, and removal, if necessary, of a covered flagpole at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point to—</text><paragraph id="H18CD07BE580044969E086F11B6C026AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual who has submitted a special use permit application to display the flag of the United States seasonally on Kyhv Peak prior to March 5, 2026; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41273441AFDA4046A9CC27273DAF85EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an individual who has placed or displayed the flag of the United States at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point as part of a longstanding seasonal practice prior to the date of enactment of this Act; or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80A7DA13610A464B9FF72477E06BEDA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if an individual described in paragraphs (1) and (2) declines such permit, to a qualified person in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AEDEBF92FF5425B9F0FFE3E002422A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection and issuance</header><paragraph id="H27D9B3820204413287CD2C28ACE92925"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), to be eligible to be selected for a special use permit under this section, a qualified person shall submit to the Secretary a proposal and application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H520580FBD6B34C399F9D73358563568C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>The Secretary may impose such terms and conditions on a holder of a special use permit under this section as the Secretary determines necessary to ensure the proper care and maintenance of a covered flagpole.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H192E012602BC4376AE9B77F874C46579"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Land use fee exemption</header><text>The Secretary shall not assess any land use fees with respect to a special use permit issued under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99E554F2B9C14E139B09133547A80418"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice of application</header><text>The Secretary shall publish notice of the availability of any special use permit under this section on the website of the Forest Service and in a local Utah County, Utah, newspaper of record.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEFB953AD7D3418EB14C801C4AE90E3F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subsequent special use permits</header><paragraph id="HE956CC3D1C7D4713ACA1F6A9B8B75B9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall renew or issue a new 10-year special use permit not later than 180 days after the date that is the earliest of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H19C53438659E41C28A945A7731CDE0EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The date that is 10 years after the date on which the Secretary issued the preceding permit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7A80EC5AED94DBABE2E1EF46FD1ADB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date on which the holder of the current special use permit requests revocation of such permit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FEF4921FE494E86B3FB19685F84DE6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date on which a special use permit is subject to early termination under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC03EBDFC5145FEB5AAE13AF624D894"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text>If the Secretary determines that the holder of a special use permit under this section is not in compliance with the terms and conditions relating to such permit under subsection (c)(3), the Secretary may revoke the special use permit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00797142362646C68E1A26861EE732C3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemption from cost recovery fees</header><text>A holder of a special use permit under this section shall be exempt from any cost recovery fee under section 251.58 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations. </text></subsection><subsection id="H3CEEE746A17941429A2CFCE3FE36996F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Applicability of NEPA</header><text>The National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) shall not apply to the issuance, renewal, or administration of a special use permit under this section, including any activities associated with the placing, maintenance, or removal of a covered flagpole at Kyhv Peak Lookout Point.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFBE754218EE44289BE6174E8EE1AE2CD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary may authorize reasonable access to Kyhv Peak Lookout Point for the purpose of exercising rights under a special use permit issued under this section, subject to conditions necessary to protect public safety and natural resources.</text></subsection><subsection id="H56F213DE9C8B434BA712BC8725299276"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure the activities and access authorized by this section are limited to the smallest practicable area.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260519" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 19, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

