<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A3ADAC5FDD7499A99ACB38A12244B98" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1349 IH: Expressing support for the designation of the week of May 31 through June 6, 2026, as “Our Roads, Our Safety Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of the week of May 31 through June 6, 2026, as <quote>Our Roads, Our Safety Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the movement of goods and people is the backbone of the United States economy, with commercial motor vehicles transporting billions of tons of freight annually;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas road safety is a shared responsibility involving passenger vehicle drivers, truck drivers, bus drivers, bicyclists, and pedestrians sharing the road;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, every year, thousands of lives are lost in crashes involving large trucks and buses, many of which are preventable through increased awareness and better driving practices;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration developed <quote>Our Roads, Our Safety</quote>, a national safety campaign to encourage road users to share the road safely with large trucks and buses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the <quote>Our Roads, Our Safety</quote> campaign—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEF604850B1964E0D93ABC9690F4083D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration’s mission of reducing crashes, injuries, and fatalities involving large trucks and buses; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58939DC737634C249C2255B41572FD21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>educates all drivers, cyclists, and pedestrians on the importance of sharing the road;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas public awareness of the unique safety challenges faced by commercial vehicles, including large blind spots, long stopping distances, and wide turns, is essential to reducing traffic fatalities; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Our Roads, Our Safety Week</quote> serves as a call to action for Federal, State, and local partners to collaborate on initiatives that protect every individual on our nation’s roadways: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5505DF7CADC24887A2CE24FC9EB2422A"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HB135D7FD72D14973A7BC84E433C7B666"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H2A28A41A4A7D45EF9EF808DAF47E9FF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of an <quote>Our Roads, Our Safety Week</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADCD1E6EA5794BA19A7447C207DB5445"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the vital role that commercial motor vehicle drivers play in our daily lives and the importance of ensuring their safety and the safety of those who share the road with them; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4203A33406CB441DA0BDDD498FEAF0DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the Department of Transportation and the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration to continue their outreach and education efforts; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CF541006F844C2C8D31DF34449CA277"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges all road users to learn the <quote>Rules of the Road</quote> for sharing space with large trucks and buses to ensure that everyone reaches their destination safely.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

