<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26C46-WV1-F8-NJ6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S2 PCS: Secure America Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 417</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 2</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="SSBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name>, reported the following original bill; which was read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of S. Con. Res. 33.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id39630498cc494c49b5df893d36b9e8c4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure America Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><title id="idee19b38248c343d89eeb56268d50bb48" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</header><section id="id48af56aa095f4183b54a0ceff247298c"><enum>101.</enum><header>U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel</header><subsection id="idab14835eefac408994f50e7838f969ad"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $9,550,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2029, to hire, pay, train, and equip Border Patrol agents and Border Patrol support personnel to conduct functions other than immigration enforcement and customs functions.</text></subsection><subsection id="id48b0eb71b4204e5abf72a462d8d234be"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>None of the funds made available by subsection (a) may be used to recruit, hire, or train personnel for the duties of processing coordinators after October 31, 2028.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide75ce20cb4504369ae7a321b965fd36e"><enum>102.</enum><header>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $7,450,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2029, to hire, pay, train, and equip Homeland Security Investigations agents and support personnel and to provide other necessary expenses for Homeland Security Investigations’ mission support and operations and maintenance, of which $108,500,000 shall be used to hire, pay, and equip additional child exploitation investigators and forensics analysts at the Victim Identification Laboratory of the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of Homeland Security Investigations and at the Homeland Security Investigations offices of the Special Agent in Charge to support the identification and rescue of victims of child sexual exploitation and abuse, and to train such personnel and State and local law enforcement regarding identifying victims of child sexual exploitation and abuse within the Homeland Security Investigations Cyber Crimes Center, except that funds provided in this section shall be used for functions other than those related to Homeland Security Investigations’ immigration enforcement and customs enforcement missions.</text></section><section id="id973d4f7b038746a7bd99c87c23e68018"><enum>103.</enum><header>Border security, technology, and screening</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7518ce64a16944cd9880dec89dbdea17"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to remain available until September 30, 2029, $3,450,000,000 for the following:</text><paragraph id="iddab7f049f0854861ad13e69cf02b6a3e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Procurement and integration of new nonintrusive inspection equipment and associated civil works, including artificial intelligence, machine learning, and other innovative technologies, as well as other mission support, to combat the entry or exit of illicit narcotics at ports of entry and along the southwest, northern, and maritime borders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff2fc1cc2a15414faf12c5e4fe8958cf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Air and Marine operations’ upgrading and procurement of new platforms for rapid air and marine response capabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id607f1047837944f482ebe33ec2a7429a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Upgrades and procurement of border surveillance technologies along the southwest, northern, and maritime borders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id92032c2789f54ca581a7e6c051c06509"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Necessary expenses, including the deployment of technology, relating to the biometric entry and exit system under section 7208 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1365b">8 U.S.C. 1365b</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2565f7cb6e6740c1800da7e8cc3b9afd"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Enhancing border security by combating drug trafficking, including fentanyl and its precursor chemicals, at the southwest, northern, and maritime borders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a87dc96ff794a33850295be07cab07a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Necessary expenses for U.S. Customs and Border Protection's mission support and operations and maintenance for functions other than those related to its immigration enforcement and customs missions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbd94e83de77f4399b0b79fa64b5a19d5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>None of the funds made available under subsection (a) may be used for the procurement or deployment of surveillance towers along the southwest border and northern border that have not been tested and accepted by U.S. Customs and Border Protection to deliver autonomous capabilities.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7d2ae7b7c32e494d8993cd344a457eca"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of autonomous</header><text>In this section, with respect to capabilities, the term <term>autonomous</term> means a system designed to apply artificial intelligence, machine learning, computer vision, or other algorithms to accurately detect, identify, classify, and track items of interest in real time such that the system can make operational adjustments without the active engagement of personnel or continuous human command or control.</text></subsection></section><section id="idd8a6b87dadd740bba60f1ce21a19619a"><enum>104.</enum><header>Additional Department of Homeland Security appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are appropriated to the Secretary of Homeland Security for fiscal year 2026, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $2,500,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2029, for the purposes provided in this title.</text></section></title></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

