<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5DADC8346E07461588536BEED6697EBD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 868 IH: Honoring the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, Chi Chapter, on its centennial anniversary.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 868</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, Chi Chapter, on its centennial anniversary.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, Chi Chapter, was chartered on May 15, 1925, at Talladega College in Talladega, Alabama, by 12 visionary women dedicated to sisterhood, scholarship, and service;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the establishment of this historic chapter at Talladega College marked a significant milestone as one of the earliest Greek-letter organizations founded by and for African-American women in the State of Alabama, and the first sorority at Talladega College;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, for 100 years, the Chi Chapter has upheld the ideals of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, fostering academic excellence, leadership development, and lifelong service to all mankind;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the 12 charter members, Elizabeth Fletcher, Irene Fullwood, Sarah M. Harris, Alice M. Holtzclaw, Ruth W. Howard, G. Mae Kinckle, Muriel McCorey, Ruby M. Pendergrass, Celestine L. Smith, Anna Belle Sullivan, Vivian O. Walden, and Eunice O. Whitaker, laid a strong foundation that continues to inspire generations of young women to lead with purpose, learn with distinction, and serve with compassion;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas generations of Chi Chapter women have carried forward the legacy of scholarship, sisterhood, and service that defines Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Chi Chapter has maintained an enduring presence on Talladega’s campus, continuing to promote academic excellence, leadership, and civic engagement among its undergraduate members;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, through a century of unwavering commitment, Chi Chapter members have distinguished themselves as educators, public servants, business leaders, faith leaders, attorneys, physicians, artists, and civic advocates whose influence reaches far beyond the campus of Talladega College; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas it is abundantly fitting and proper that the Chi Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, be appropriately honored for its century of leadership, education, and service that has strengthened communities across Alabama and the Nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H7E9A828165884D9D95E224C8AEB7B044"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2CD164EA19F54E16857F8598A60B8274"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HE464B775D7ED46A6BF3DDB9250F0D68B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors and congratulates the Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, Chi Chapter, on its centennial anniversary at Talladega College, commends the Chapter’s members both past and present for their devotion to sisterhood and scholarship, and extends best wishes for continued impact and excellence in the next century of service;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B7EB9AFEFA34F37A794EC9C280D28BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the Chi Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, as a shining example of the transformative power of historically Black colleges and universities, the enduring strength of Black women’s leadership, and the living legacy of <quote>Service to All Mankind</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBD40032FAF647A9A4AE38EA52F009B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requests that the Clerk of the House of Representatives transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the Chi Chapter of Alpha Kappa Alpha Sorority, Incorporated, at Talladega College in honor of its centennial celebration.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

