<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC828C9DB7D1C4254A1F866AB441B1899" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8132 IH: Bonneville Power Leadership Recruitment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8132</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260327">March 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To adjust the compensation of the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H400533A5A4AC4D9C8808A01DA35C6BBA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA1475F3DD4D146C2AC7B7753562A9268" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bonneville Power Leadership Recruitment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H13F6E142D5C74D8BA988B55CCC403B17"><enum>2.</enum><header>Bonneville Power Administrator compensation</header> <subsection id="H169C896163FB4AB98AE4E4946DEA2237"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rate of pay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in the first pay period beginning on or after the date that is 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the annual rate of basic pay—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB828A46A4FFE472FBF80A0BB22F55365"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration (referred to in this section as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall be set at a level determined by the Secretary of Energy (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) to be comparable to chief executives of consumer-owned utilities in the Western Interconnection; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB6FDEB9E5794DABA3865E11100C3EEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for employees of the Bonneville Power Administration, including members of the Senior Executive Service (as defined in section 2101a of title 5, United States Code), shall be set at a level determined by the Secretary to be comparable to compensation for similar positions at consumer-owned utilities in the Western Interconnection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5969BFF666BD4D1BA40991C3888D4C91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional considerations</header><text>The determination of the Secretary with respect to the annual rate of basic pay under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H7D6FFACB120644E4B7C35F8FA35DEF1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be based on an annual survey of the prevailing compensation for similar positions in consumer-owned utilities in the Western Interconnection;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H34B865F5E32A443BA3450858E69F296C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be consistent with the approved annual general and administrative budget of the Administrator, encourage the widest diversified use of electric power at the lowest possible rates to consumers consistent with sound business principles, and be cognizant of the need for deep experience, strategic vision, intelligence, and accountability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF9EB7B4BEBF4604AA1B45769B951B84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to pay for employees of the Bonneville Power Administration, take into account education, experience, level of responsibility, geographic differences, and retention and recruitment needs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9891CE9DF7F045E0AE61226BE98F86C7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide that the individual total compensation of the Administrator and employees of the Bonneville Power Administration shall be comparable to and competitive with similar positions among consumer-owned utilities in the Western Interconnection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD91A310FE8CC4A77A62E600026ADB764"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5316 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>Administrator, Bonneville Power Administration, Department of the Interior.</quote>.</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

