<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H509B576312494701BC08FB58CF1B28BC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5859 IH: Behavioral Health Crisis Care Centers Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251028">October 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for the purpose of establishing, operating, or expanding one-stop crisis facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4AC70516D0384D3B8B37019C2A728890" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5C9C04DB52E847D3869B8FDD9F84BD1C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Behavioral Health Crisis Care Centers Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7DE2A3AD8167454B8252A00C5E39AFA1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for one-stop crisis facilities</header> <subsection id="HCCBE4C173CC945DA88D3411BF607F421"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of any other relevant Federal agencies, shall award grants to eligible entities in the amounts determined pursuant to subsection (d) for the purpose of establishing, operating, or expanding one-stop crisis facilities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB9AB000C41BD4C95BEC9921C8D409107"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>Activities funded through a grant under this section for establishing, operating, or expanding a one-stop crisis facility may include—</text> <paragraph id="HBB176569BA554DD099F542B84627836B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquiring, constructing, or developing facilities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EBD15BCA0ED488AB69B143A90A701E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acquiring supplies or equipment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92B77B96C2F1480C9D37F2E3C7AE64FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>training, hiring, and retaining staff;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79A8655D00344A5495BEDE716473854D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing, operating, or expanding services provided at a one-stop crisis facility, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HF1117F9EBC9F4821AB8D06386DA1024D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">health care services, including behavioral health and substance use disorder treatment, including medication for opioid use disorder;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C890D0EBB124E34BD1BFFBC3E0CD2CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>counseling;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6722043E55849C3919894C0FA7CFCD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">case management services and recovery oriented supports;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC899349727C49BF9B6DD6568D40BD5D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>housing assistance, including financial assistance for housing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95CCE220CCEB4ACA97C74D1C3A4FC7A5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>legal services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3E94C9A7EB042579CF88AAED8C6786E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other wrap-around services, not limited to services that are clinical in nature, provided as part of a one-stop crisis facility;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA24016AE4FFB45C1948971ED45766A3C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating with governmental and nongovernmental partners (including local crisis response, law enforcement, fire services, emergency medical services, health care entities, workforce development programs, aging, disability, and senior services, community-based organizations, faith-based organizations, civic organizations, housing authorities, continuum of care programs, immigrant and refugee assistance organizations, veteran service organizations, deflection initiatives led by first responders, evidence-based jail diversion programs, such as law enforcement-assisted diversion programs, children and family organizations, and other entities involved in the provision of wrap-around services, not limited to clinical services);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD5E6370EE814AC081FB40E607C31AD7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting outreach services to engage with vulnerable and high-need communities, including individuals living at public or federally assisted housing facilities or receiving Federal housing assistance, youths, and unhoused individuals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22EB67EB254B4BECB9FF98E3892FDC75"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">planning system-wide coordination with other entities involved in crisis response.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC244ACE6CC24DBFA851974982403FA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this section may use such grant to award subgrants to nongovernmental entities for the purpose of providing one-stop crisis facility services, including those described in paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) of subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H353E30A805B84A9DB4F007710C38A24F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determination of amounts</header> <paragraph id="H7EA8B4BFAD1B4A2CBFBB1706B3BD6C92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Metropolitan cities</header><text>Of the total amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(A), the Secretary shall award to each metropolitan city receiving a grant under this section an amount that bears the same proportion to such total amount as the population of such metropolitan city bears to the total population of all metropolitan cities receiving grants under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8C42C69289142809FF77527DCCC9BC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonentitlement units of local government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the total amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(B), the Secretary shall award to each nonentitlement unit of local government receiving a grant under this section an amount that bears the same proportion to such total amount as the population of such nonentitlement unit of local government bears to the total population of all nonentitlement units of local government receiving grants under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H643C00DF3D0F4C3E9A583508C5284A29"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Counties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award to each county receiving a grant under this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBA525A07919A47B79B1E140C9139219E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of half of the amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(C), an amount that is equal for each such county; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF8A8D77EDD7471C97B5788E6647A816"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the remaining half of the amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(C), an amount that bears the same proportion to such remaining half as the population of such county bears to the total population of all counties receiving grants under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F541E4B1DB94EF98F7CA2656E39CEB3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award to each State receiving a grant under this section—</text> <subparagraph id="H99DD896A24A3438C91D3841BC9D3DC11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of half of the amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(D), an amount that is equal for each such State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85D7FD5C15C8463A9F963838EF299258"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the remaining half of the amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(D), an amount that bears the same proportion to such remaining half as the population of such State bears to the total population of all States receiving grants under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB340AA9AFC9D4C3891249F0E288FE372"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian Tribes</header><text>The Secretary shall award to each Indian Tribe receiving a grant under this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A008960C2CA458FAA7D82AF85E1EBC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of 25 percent of the amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(E), an amount that is equal for each such Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7EE98F6A073843EAB5C8D0877EF94658"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of 75 percent of the amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(E), an amount determined by the Secretary of the Interior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92134C3E124D42BABAF3C66B442AF807"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Territories</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the total amount made available for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (g)(2)(F), the Secretary shall award to each territory receiving a grant under this section an amount that bears the same proportion to such total amount as the population of such territory bears to the total population of all territories receiving grants under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5BFD56D5E90344869EC8264C798D51C3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header> <paragraph id="HE8A4071B1E734B51BF972681BFCBAAEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8AE9070416224B388E3A4C6363A5E073"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Such an application shall include a plan for how the grant funds will be used, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HCD719175EFA64C45A99F463511D26D98"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such plan is informed by stakeholders in the community, especially people with lived experiences with a behavioral health crisis, people with disabilities, and community organizations that work with these communities;</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0F02EF22D184B13866AAEDA631E1580"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the recipient will collaborate with community-based organizations to connect individuals with appropriate services in a timely and direct manner;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0188DE209318410DA2660F0E3A2F753F"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the recipient will establish a housing first policy strategy for adults experiencing homelessness and a transitional housing, wrap-around services strategy for youth in crisis;</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46D34A4A73304EC7BAB8E61E8651B089"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the recipient will prioritize equitable access for people facing language, cultural, disability-related, and other barriers, including how staff will be trained in cultural competency and trauma-informed care;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC9D02B5E1DB140FEB9565EF8070D4A3C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the recipient will work in conjunction with crisis response systems, law enforcement, fire services, emergency medical services, homeless outreach, community health workers, and emergency departments to divert individuals experiencing a behavioral health or substance use crisis to the one-stop crisis facility;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76562823502E49F89F4C94A00848CA25"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the recipient will consult with people with lived experience with a behavioral health crisis to design centers that have a <quote>home-like</quote> environment that is accessible;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8487D43B0494555BF14CA9DC54D7229"><enum>(G)</enum><text>how the recipient will work in conjunction with continuum of care programs and housing providers to connect individuals at assisted housing facilities with the one-stop crisis facility to receive supportive services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9E718C5B2E0470484431EBCC37DA4D3"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the recipient intends to create programming and services specific to the needs of youth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCC19C403E2D14316A0B5F3B2A84844A3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person in the United States shall, on the basis of actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), or disability, be excluded from participation in, be denied the benefits of, or be subjected to discrimination under any program or activity funded, in whole or in part, with funds made available under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6314DE9A91A043C1B364AAB6DB0CECA1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H341D7C7B75654EC89AB097C6AE416A57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <term>county</term>, <term>metropolitan city</term>, and <term>nonentitlement unit of local government</term> have the meanings given to such terms in section 603(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/803">42 U.S.C. 803(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5BD17B62922417FB49104A7075D10DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a metropolitan city, a nonentitlement unit of local government, a county, a State, an Indian Tribe, or a territory.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H581D924CF77F4BC1945E9BFD1A0E0707"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given to the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5130">25 U.S.C. 5130</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72A07B8291AD45D3B4E2DFD6D95CC411"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>one-stop crisis facility</term> means a facility that provides, at a single location—</text> <subparagraph id="H29E1CED568FD44958A86559115BB379B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on-site services for behavioral health and substance use disorder;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H91C243F73E5A4FC8ABB25123422A5ABD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>housing services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE5AE2E84B67A4095B3CB14EA1BBEA954"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordination with health care services, housing services, legal aid, or other case management or wrap-around services available in the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0443A194A1EA46B78C80A5865B8C0E1A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D34E949765A4D128DE246CC9F3ABDE7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>territory</term> means the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE22EA244240449CB97D622188EA615D2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="HE9FC8AD77C7949EB843B34FF2CFF1409"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $11,500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF70E8798F6514103839EB7DB968F6CAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5A3968E382FA404EB626400B9CF51437"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$3,000,000,000 shall be for grants to metropolitan cities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47AF1204E05B462586D704FDD39A47CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$1,000,000,000 shall be for grants to nonentitlement units of local government;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7CE1AE1EFCA742B09EE03455E73F98AA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$3,000,000,000 shall be for grants to counties;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90D0B26F600445A1A7F072E5C7F65D30"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 shall be for grants to States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB34D7199CA50497E9193F5FF3C201780"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,000,000,000 shall be for grants to Indian Tribes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96BDF5751B5C4980B2E256B5BBDEEB13"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$500,000,000 shall be for grants to territories.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

