<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8665 : Allied Defense Sales Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8665</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the implementation of a strategy to encourage foreign partners to participate in the foreign military sales and direct commercial sales processes on a multinational basis, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBC011DDE7B6E46008AB9A5E8BA79732A" style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section id="HC8808302347C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Allied Defense Sales Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF018AEA7A2864BAE8327E6188205BC08"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy and report on multinational procurement from the United States</header><subsection id="H245E8CB141694ABAAED0F812EDF523DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall implement a strategy to encourage foreign partners to participate in the foreign military sales and direct commercial sales processes on a multinational basis. Such strategy shall incorporate existing efforts by the Department of State to—</text><paragraph id="HA30B3490602F4A3A80DA4344CBEE30BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>survey interest in participating in such multinational procurement processes among potentially eligible countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA52E9250C7B045E28CBF0599C6AA2FC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify countries and partners who may be eligible to serve as the lead purchase coordinator for a multinational procurement process, and potential incentives for their participation as lead coordinator;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA117AE4FC9C2483B939C8465D9A76E49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review pathways for participation in foreign military sales or direct commercial sales processes for countries determined to be ineligible for foreign military financing loans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FF66E82EA4448F993E664D57D63965B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify challenges and solutions for the Department in carrying out such processes in accordance with the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), including applicable end-use monitoring, technical assistance agreements, and license filing requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAB86B4176CF41F49292C5FE595C253A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify ways to provide for expedited license authorizations, sales other than for programs of record, and other potential efforts to increase speed and ease enhanced use of multinational procurement processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34545B62FA8F47DE94757CD3409ED1BA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>detailing the benefits of multinational procurement processes to the national security interest, including enhanced military interoperability and strengthening the domestic industrial base; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA661F737E50E4163A33351CB31BC88E2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identify opportunities to develop and promote exportable defense articles and services, including for purposes of supporting the AUKUS partnership.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AA25A2F346847CF9AF0191E2D1AB582"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for 3 years, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the strategy required by subsection (a) and its implementation. Such report shall also include—</text><paragraph id="H70D76BA4415F490BA8782A6F390C1659"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an update on the development and implementation of the initial strategy during the period following the most recent prior submission of such report (if any);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3116D6D636C84BD8A62D671AD4582514"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of challenges faced in the implementation of the strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75419B406B2B454CA7E2186C8FD6DA8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of all efforts the Department has undertaken to overcome such challenges;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE354B81EA1EE4A4385745D79A1D2C9A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a list and description of any potential legislative changes necessary to fully implement a multinational procurement process for foreign military sales and direct commercial sales; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7D15A271FF4D78B3A73C5736A65048"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a description of efforts to promote exportable defense articles and services specifically for use in multinational procurement processes, including those supporting the AUKUS partnership.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEC79894E0B04943AEE64132B8BFFB08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form and may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDDF98A70149746D9ADEC3A3D32348F8D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H8B0F89A2F438452592824BCDA7F4CB91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E3705746273461E80142B41ADE0C47B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>AUKUS partnership</term> means the enhanced trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States announced in September 2021; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89E71ABCDB6D4FE1B66C80A1DDCC3A5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>multinational procurement process</term> refers to a process by which defense articles or services are sold by the United States to a lead foreign nation, with the intent that the articles or services so sold will subsequently be retransferred to a previously identified group of participating countries, or to countries identified by reference to a qualifying multilateral partnership agreement, such as a cross-servicing agreement described in section 2350 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260608" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 8, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

