<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7DCFA166CAEF400EA55C0F39767FA2FB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5914 IH: Historic Preservation Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5914</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251104">November 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 54, United States Code, to increase amounts deposited in the Historic Preservation Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5856C9525AA345729BF4B26E44EABAD6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7ECFEF5070F24E9FB4F7BF835A8F4012" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Historic Preservation Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF8C49A7459BD49C7B7FFC10300124E50"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to Historic Preservation Fund provisions</header> <subsection id="HAC131DD926434F62B8F09EE6C84461EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 303102 of title 54, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF4CF96BDFF434706A61EAD328EBE04F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>For each</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="USC"><enum-in-header>(a)</enum-in-header> In general.—</header-in-text>Except as provided in subsection (b), for each</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD020E34E5EB14FC4B24A7B4E1DD7C23E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of fiscal years 2012 to 2023</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal year</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2CD9E93DD4E434AB0442C3A40FF35FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$150,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$300,000,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9A38960DB5D4DBA85F23C508DEE4489"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H186738ED9A334AA8A194B23D59D590CE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H9B29425F247742AD83983A0D679636A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>Unless otherwise provided by law, if the revenues described in subsection (a) are not sufficient to cover the amount to be deposited into each of the funds such revenues are directed under other Federal laws, the difference between the shortfall in the revenues and the amount to be deposited into the Historic Preservation Fund under subsection (a) shall be deposited from amounts in the general fund of the Treasury.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2647299A099543DB814638A8C41989C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use and availability</header><text>Section 303103 of title 54, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H6228E81E1A9F4D178C68CB5203421491" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H0F39EF61B4FB40319BF5DB9DD6F1F11C"><enum>303103.</enum><header>Use and availability</header> 
<subsection id="H07B1DD304BB645178C4DBD34314D603F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts deposited in the Historic Preservation Fund under section 303102 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter shall be made available for expenditure for fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, to carry out this division (including programs made available from the Historic Preservation Fund).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9E7EA800B31D43E38981E47D4329B739"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation authority</header> <paragraph id="H0382D528F58A45A4A034FB0D01174888"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Minimum allocation for State and Tribal Historic Preservation Offices</header> <subparagraph id="H661F831D31E6414CB4CF1CEF72F364F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subparagraph (B), of the amounts made available from the Fund for each fiscal year under subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="H3A10063567AF43A796F0B337B17D40AE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 40 percent shall be allocated to State Historic Preservation Offices; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF1FEA8807A344DE598C697EB15184813"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 20 percent shall be allocated to Tribal Historic Preservation Offices.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75C72F18C6254556951598AE1A3B843F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><text>The annual allocation to Tribal Historic Preservation Offices under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be increased as necessary to reflect any annual increase in the number of Tribal Historic Preservation Offices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H689123363C2348DB9D74E325AF5D00AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of cost estimates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall submit to Congress proposed allocations to State Historic Preservation Offices (expressed as the total amount proposed to be allocated to all such Offices), Tribal Historic Preservation Offices (expressed as the total amount proposed to be allocated to all such Offices), grant programs described in the item relating to the Historic Preservation Fund in title I of division G of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>), and any other relevant programs (as determined by the President or a designee of the President), of the full amount made available under subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4FAA5759835644438579F6E93EEB1945"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for fiscal year 2027, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Historic Preservation Enhancement Act</short-title>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14769C5768CF41A5A8C0143FAE7CDCDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each fiscal year thereafter, as part of the annual budget submission of the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3CE84B8935F464090C039D21C289785"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alternate allocation</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB2FDAB20D0654E20A46516C8B729D878"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations Acts may provide for alternate allocation of amounts made available under subsection (a), including allocations by program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3294B123210F4863BC591A5B8B8387E0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation by President</header> <clause id="H5C1FB976F19B4D14AA271ADCCC8DF549"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No alternate allocations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If Congress has not enacted legislation establishing alternate allocations by the date on which the Act making full-year appropriations for the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies for the applicable fiscal year is enacted into law, amounts made available under subsection (a) shall be allocated by the President.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5C884177D1F64D1894E14946791E3900"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Insufficient alternate allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If Congress enacts legislation establishing alternate allocations for amounts made available under subsection (a) that are less than the full amount appropriated under such subsection, the difference between the amount appropriated and the alternate allocation shall be allocated by the President.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E7C0E4AFF92489A947961841DF8A411"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Continuing resolution</header><text>If the Department of the Interior or the National Park Service is operating under a continuing resolution during any period in a fiscal year, the President may distribute funds made available under subsection (a) to State Historic Preservation Offices and Tribal Historic Preservation Offices during such period at the rate of operations provided for such Offices under such subsection during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDC43991E9424B738D7557FD5194AB93"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall submit to Congress an annual report that describes the final allocation, by program, of amounts made available under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HC47BFDE3DACC4F2F9479769C3EE39E82"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of Historic Preservation Fund programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, amounts are authorized to be made available from the Historic Preservation Fund to the following programs:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFB9D97793DFA4603B7E2843E1A4A9BBD">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>African American Civil Rights Movement Initiative &amp; Grants.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H785141DAD2054D688C26FC5689903B76"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">History of Equal Rights Grants (formerly known as <quote>Civil Rights Grants for All Americans</quote>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C587F3184324E568661DA235CE46297"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Survey Grants for Underrepresented Communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC4488C54906745A3AD8ED570D73192CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Paul Bruhn Historic Revitalization Grants.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

