<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE72F5A3AF49A414F9DC107E0D0600923" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6124 IH: End Rent Fixing Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6124</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the manipulation of rent prices in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H526E568EFCF64D1985880E636A3E33EF" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0EB60DBC67A04801B4AD3CEF7C028467"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Rent Fixing Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEB5ED145DAD041BDB9102D4E66B6B9AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HDB53C7B219204EF7A71BAEC603171A1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7C39DFE28C6427CA8CEC5102F03FC60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordinating function</header><text>The term <term>coordinating function</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F2264B1E66244D6B3C299AC29BADB76"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collecting historical or contemporaneous prices, supply levels, or lease or rental contract termination and renewal dates of residential dwelling units, either directly or indirectly, from 2 or more rental property owners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5946E421217A4717BE7CC33A9D4D5D41"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyzing or processing the information described in subparagraph (A) using a system, software, or process that uses the same or a similar formula or methodology, including by using that information to train an algorithm to predict rental prices, lease renewal terms, or ideal occupancy levels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA91BF481478B4B49A74F64C59F626B37"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommending rental prices, lease renewal terms, or occupancy levels to 2 or more rental property owners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H151A8959DE0B4CD6A6A7047CD45316CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>coordinator</term> means any person that performs a coordinating function for any rental property owner, including a rental property owner performing a coordinating function for their own benefit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE634C51F59148F7AB6BB94E3D938BBB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC52431707202470A851E65B011BAF409"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Residential dwelling unit</header><text>The term <term>residential dwelling unit</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52C766BA4C54420188409EB7DB02ED1B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any house, apartment, accessory unit, manufactured home, manufactured housing community lot, or other unit used as a residence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9F17BD1B43C48CDB64870F6038567E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include inpatient medical care, licensed long-term care, and detention or correctional facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB411B4ECCC7464FB2FF5B1155C6E724"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rental property owner</header><text>The term <term>rental property owner</term> means any individual, corporation, partnership, association, joint-stock company, trust, or unincorporated organization, including an organization not organized to carry on business for its own profit or that of its members, that owns real property and leases or rents such property or any portion thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEB6243413974A30801E9A1E43188E16"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2BD17B4D600A405497217EFA85369E5C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unlawful conduct</header><subsection id="HF2E904717D0541AAAAC538F87C7E8E14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conspiracy</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a rental property owner, in or affecting commerce, or any agent or subcontractor thereof, to knowingly subscribe to, contract with, or otherwise exchange anything of value in return for the services of a coordinator, and such action shall be deemed to be an unlawful method of competition in violation of section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) and a per se violation of section 1 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7C3B893349CF462CBD5459616693C800"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person, in or affecting commerce, to perform a coordinating function, and such action shall be deemed to be an unlawful method of competition in violation of section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) and a per se violation of section 1 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H8A72DD1C40164E6E9AEA7458CA31557C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="HDADD9A4C05D1408D84B45A8715AA77B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H8D5A403C408F428BA911CB1628FC2DBC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission</header><text>A violation of this Act shall also constitute an unfair method of competition under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), and if the Commission has reason to believe that a person violated this Act, the Commission—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB060CC77D7B648D187EC6D6F946086AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may commence a civil action, in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, to recover a civil penalty and seek other appropriate relief; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC02747695B024E3BB602E2C16959337A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall have jurisdiction to enforce this Act against an organization not organized to carry on business for its own profit or that of its members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CACC3A9016B403EAB7432E4B615497F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney General</header><text>The Attorney General shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers and duties as though all applicable terms of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>), Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>), and Antitrust Civil Process Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1311">15 U.S.C. 1311 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF282C9C4836B423BB4C9B5E44AB55255"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State attorneys general</header><text>Any attorney general of a State shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers and duties as though all applicable terms of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D9DB2620BA74B6B84F50CC96E5210F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil actions by injured persons </header><paragraph id="H93D154F7F5DB467BA036CC67798793A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil action authorized</header><text>Any person who is aggrieved by a violation of this Act may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States, without respect to the amount in controversy, to recover an amount described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA33B6E6E30A448FB9FFD9BE2FB10F30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Award amount</header><subparagraph id="HA1801EBD71684A278119608C43C303FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The court shall award the plaintiff threefold the damages sustained by the plaintiff and the reasonable cost of litigation, including a reasonable attorney fee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3EE15D192F445A39F4E2E4C2A377598"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interest on damages</header><text>Pursuant to a motion by plaintiff promptly made, the court may award simple interest on actual damages sustained by the plaintiff for the period beginning on the date of service of the pleading of the plaintiff setting forth a claim under this Act and ending on the date of judgment, or for any shorter period therein.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA032579E92D0440388DCF637649D43CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Invalidity of pre-dispute arbitration agreements and pre-dispute joint action waivers</header><text>At the election of the plaintiff in an action authorized under paragraph (1), a pre-dispute arbitration agreement or pre-dispute joint action waiver relating to a violation of this Act shall be invalid or unenforceable.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8E67F7E1A91C42A7B41B184D08E60762"><enum>5.</enum><header>Standards of pleading</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In a civil action alleging a violation of sections 1 or 3(a) of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1</external-xref>, 3(a)), including an action brought by the United States, a State attorney general, or the Federal Trade Commission under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), a complaint need not allege facts tending to exclude the possibility of independent action and shall not be dismissed for failure to state a claim unless it appears beyond doubt that the claimant can prove no set of facts in support of their claim which would entitle them to relief.</text></section><section id="HB180FEEBC16A4FBBABA7D654A29CD69C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to other laws</header><subsection id="H09BCA58588B34BA598292EC602D9CE32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Antitrust laws</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, shall be construed to impair or supersede the operation of any of the antitrust laws, and the unlawful conduct set forth in this Act is in addition to and not instead of conduct prohibited by the antitrust laws.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31BA802A4EF24D9FBF38A15D8E7E8AB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to preempt, annul, alter, or affect, or exempt any person subject to the provisions of this Act from complying with the laws of any State, except to the extent that those laws are inconsistent with any provision of this Act, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency. For purposes of this section, a State law is not inconsistent with this Act if the protection such law affords any person greater than the protection provided by this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC12654D12F154825B319F40960829015"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such a provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remaining provisions of this Act, and the application of such provisions to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

