<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB88A94539D7B49DBB80B84D18BA1F871" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7179 IH: Historic Infrastructure Management and Jobs Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7179</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3029">chapter 3029</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, to establish the Historic Preservation Workforce Development Program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H59DBE744BCE04DD5AE7A7F56B6781FCA" style="OLC"><section id="H96DC606C2373426C9447B7136FE8DB24" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Historic Infrastructure Management and Jobs Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0098CBA0381C4EE0A8306FA0BB355A89"><enum>2.</enum><header>Historic preservation workforce development program</header><subsection id="HBC722C29042A4FF5AF5ECBF7FAC83F0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3029">Chapter 3029</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H30AAEDC778B844C1A28CB4483261952B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H05882A56383C4A31A18305B98BE05A2F"><enum>302911.</enum><header>Historic Preservation Workforce Development grants</header><subsection id="HEFB417F11B694CE3A4A5EDCFB6202DEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>) to support workforce training, apprenticeships, and skilled trade development related to the preservation and conservation of historic properties and objects (including records) of historical, cultural, architectural, or archaeological significance related to such historic properties.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED457720A21B49C6823C3267F43E1517"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may award grants to the following entities for eligible projects described in subsection (c):</text><paragraph id="H8A49D4B7B549457987C02ED78F70BC47"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States, territories, local governments, Indian tribes, and Native Hawaiian organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F546549F7754B699ED9B00B03FA71AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Public or nonprofit organizations with demonstrated experience in historic preservation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7816FD5EDE70477C8350B9D812B6CE2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Accredited educational institutions offering programs or training relevant to historic preservation or conservation fields.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5ABF9C09543D4D16A81C89E4DE67E4B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>To be eligible for funding under the Program, a project carried out by an eligible entity under subsection (b) shall—</text><paragraph id="HC1C69BF67ABF43A5B0F9F15602118F2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">focus on historic properties or other cultural resources, including archaeological resources, that require specialized preservation skills due to age, materials, methods of construction, or historical significance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39DF545F61AD4A45B443DE91DD9BB809"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish or expand workforce education, training, or apprenticeship programs that teach specialized skills necessary to preserve, conserve, stabilize, document, or maintain such historic properties or cultural resources, including training related to—</text><subparagraph id="H7647194F0E954E73A862C01850908FEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>historic masonry, timber framing, and structural systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE998A5D142544C4E95E88F6EB70ABF16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>decorative finishes, plaster, tile, ornamental woodwork, and metalwork;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4FC3355260E49BC9692EADC5AE50C99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conservation of archival, paper-based, or photographic materials; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF25D5DB0A3C1411B80ECC85807553678"><enum>(D)</enum><text>archaeological stabilization, documentation, and materials conservation; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B38992B2ECB481889FF5613300BB9C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the project involves a skilled trade (as defined under section 520.300 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations)—</text><subparagraph id="HFA7B74C7107F4E35B8AE41886B5C2951"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with the standards recognized by the Department of Labor, including coordination with or registration under the Office of Apprenticeship; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CB1585139544BA0AC0F47F1B9B19F01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be carried out consistent with applicable collective bargaining agreements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE79B62F48B0446AEB9D9575D9691574D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority considerations</header><text>In awarding grants under the Program, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that—</text><paragraph id="H96218C5A7ABB409D8D20FDBCBEC13794"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve areas with high unemployment rates relative to the national average; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD30E9B896628464C908F27016C4D4D85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>train or place workers in areas with limited existing preservation expertise, including rural or underserved communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H206EE065294845FF98309B74A527FBA3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="HE8808DFDBCA84A999B0D3508B13374C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may adopt rules, guidance, or application procedures necessary to carry out this section, consistent with competitive grant authority under the Historic Preservation Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43F847E165984C3B9DA86C2291DBFA5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Measurable outcomes</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under the Program shall report to the Secretary measurable workforce outcomes, to be tracked by the Secretary, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2F1E049783474B87B63B078CCA7A05F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of individuals participating in workforce training or apprenticeship programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB85C58F5A712418692D396A71294494E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of individuals completing certifications or credentials in preservation-related skilled trades.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H30F96806183D4CB58073EEB021C92602"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3029">chapter 3029</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 302910 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H3DAB36BF27514B369BD25FD4D84E82FC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">302911. Historic Preservation Workforce Development grants</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

