<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8DD7564247C440DDA4D4C1EDE729F558" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6725 IH: Jobs, On-the-Job Earn-While-You-Learn Training, and Apprenticeships for Young African-Americans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6725</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251215">December 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000058">Mr. Ivey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Apprenticeship Act in order to increase and
            expand the national apprenticeship system to include the immediate recruitment,
            employment, and on-the-job earn as you learn training of young African Americans, and to
            promote the development of equitable hiring standards necessary to safeguard the
 diversity of apprentices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H71753E7C6F1643D0ABE2F8BBF527A38E" style="OLC"><section id="H79B7811F0418478EBAB076CFEC4CAEC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jobs, On-the-Job <quote>Earn-While-You-Learn</quote> Training, and Apprenticeships for Young African-Americans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA06BAE907B59413BBE9D3621CCD2B38E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H5687803877994D9D8BF89B24F94B7B00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Young African-American men and women are the hardest hit by economic instability. Declared and affirmed by the Federal Reserve, African Americans face unemployment rates that are two to three times higher than their White counterparts for the last several decades.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE18C70CAEC744DBA87517716D2E9997B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During economic recessions in 1974 through 1975, 1981 through 1982, 1990 through 1991, and 2008, the African-American community faced significantly higher unemployment rates than their White counterparts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H746B48A78DC34FE39A32D84AAC4D9AE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Even during times of economic growth, African-American communities experience prolonged financial vulnerability and delayed recovery. Unemployment rates decline at a slower rate for African-American men, and even a slower rate for African-American women as compared to their White counterparts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5603ECC96F6E492DAE059FA7EEE711D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Affirmed by the Department of Labor, diversity and inclusion within the workforce benefits employees and businesses across all industries, including apprenticeship programs, which provide economic mobility to its participants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3791BEFC00548E881606BD7250DF0B7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Through the combined efforts of building trades unions and community partners at the State and local level, there have been established more than 150 apprenticeship readiness programs across the United States that focus on creating pathways to Registered Programs for people of color, women, and veterans. Overall, from 2009 to 2019, building trades unions and their signatory contractors have invested over $100,000,000 in outreach efforts targeting underrepresented communities to participate in apprenticeship readiness programs. Of the 4,800 individuals who have successfully completed a building trades apprenticeship readiness program since 2016, 70 percent were from communities of color and 22 percent were women.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7E42F4FFFBE4664994168B9C08B0DE7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The disproportionately highunemployment rates, combined with low participation rates from African Americans in registered apprenticeship programs not only constitute a national crisis but a national tragedy for the young African Americans, many of whom are fathers and mothers who, without jobs, are unable to provide for their families or home.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5D0DEE29B9C44B5D9DC928EC7965C0DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Diversity and Inclusion Administrator</header><subsection id="H802DA493600843258638B520E29A3987"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Office of Apprenticeship in the Office of Employment and Training Administration of the Department of Labor a position to be known as the <quote>Diversity and Inclusion Administrator</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E7178A1F0924E6BB3ACFE5F0EA83411"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Diversity and Inclusion Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H39B2665E50624EE3877DEA246E3985A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote greater diversity, including an increase in the participation of individuals who are African American, Hispanic, Asian American or Pacific Islander, or Native American in the national apprenticeship system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H783FA84C6DEE4C2CB99F30FBA4FF4CBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engage with institutions of higher education and other education and training providers with secondary, postsecondary, and adult education systems, including degree and credential requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E1AE634FBE54555A8E40B67E2D09480"><enum>(3)</enum><text>employers from nontraditional apprenticeship industries and occupations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AA4B12BB47B41C99662FB9ED3092C00"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assist State apprenticeship agencies and sponsors in complying with the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE6D354237DF241BF9CEE72E304DD12D5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship application</header><subsection id="HEB640BF5DDEF44FF9AD4E791A8901121"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Office of Apprenticeship, acting through the Diversity and Inclusion Administrator, shall require each entity seeking to register an apprenticeship under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly referred to as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), to submit, as a part of the application to register such apprenticeship, a plan to increase participation of individuals who are African American.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD352A1957C034B33A29B1E9FB926BF76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Renewal of registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A registered apprenticeship program seeking renewal of such registration under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly referred to as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), shall include in the application for such registration a plan described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H118304B71A404C6B93CC3CC20D6B9910"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grant program authorization</header><subsection id="H2D20EE44E3974A6DAD4E9790E0225220"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Diversity and Inclusion Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Education as appropriate, shall award grants on a competitive basis to eligible registered entities to create or expand diversity in registered apprenticeship programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H018268FCB6754266961BD2B4B900C150"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Target programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing grants under subsection (a), the Diversity and Inclusion Administrator shall target registered apprenticeship programs in traditional and nontraditional apprenticeship industries or occupations, such as for programs demonstrating demand in construction, welding, electrical engineering, plumbing, information technology, energy, green jobs, advanced manufacturing, health care, or cybersecurity.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4D55B13946E14F8AB23C033525774392" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grantee under this section may use funds—</text><paragraph id="H4CE4119270014F91A8081BCA96D69EE3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish or expand partnerships with organizations that provide African-American participants and other nontraditional program participants access to financial planning, mentoring, and supportive services that are necessary to enable an individual to participate in and complete a program under the national apprenticeship system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H722FAB11E9AA4BABB6540656A18C1556" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conduct outreach and recruitment activities, including assessments of potential African-American participants and other nontraditional participants for, and enrollment of such participants in, a program under the national apprenticeship system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22D9210BE8E543079E5DB3F059186A9E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct outreach, engagement, recruitment, and coordination of activities, for the purpose of establishing industry or sector partnerships and opportunities under the national apprenticeship system, with—</text><subparagraph id="H9A9EA89A9496490EB90CD212C106CBD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A8216FAB0A1457989294136B46BB115"><enum>(B)</enum><text>industry associations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H531ABA8EB4CA4C299B2AECC699CC30CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>labor and labor-management organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB38C4D6C6DB4479CBC009CE54AB730E0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>qualified intermediaries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B26DFE1C4AD41AFA450372F938054BC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>education and training providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE219644085514C2C9EB3CA0A164DF467"><enum>(F)</enum><text>State or local workforce agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBE58585BDD04BB29743DE5CE3766DB1"><enum>(G)</enum><text>potential sponsors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H976542CA620240B0A1724A01DE11915D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>community-based organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H211BECEB92DB426CA82D3F14DF6DFE50"><enum>(I)</enum><text>communities with high numbers or percentages of individuals who are African American and other individuals from populations that the Secretary determines to be nontraditional apprenticeship populations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1B7FD83752140C7A2BDFEB6CA737480"><enum>(J)</enum><text>small- and medium-sized businesses; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2FC00BEA8114AD6A5656C91E526CB81"><enum>(K)</enum><text>rural communities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07E78C9F17FC4C0EBD1489273F1D9A4B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to carry out grant requirements, including program evaluation and reporting requirements; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57EADD559E1B4067BBFB74B76ACF39CE" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to conduct any activities as described in the application that would advance the purposes of the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDCE3B59E5EF4B4FB1C1DEEFCF57B91E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant recipient report</header><text>Each recipient of a grant under this section shall—</text><paragraph id="H5DE6C768851F415DA3B02734CB10330F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the Diversity and Inclusion Administrator a report at the conclusion of the grant period, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H17144F7497A84BA1ACD6A88EEF1DD321"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of how the funds received through the grant were used to increase the participation of individuals who are African American, Hispanic, Asian American or Pacific Islander, or Native American in the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BC460549C3C49CEBEA3C73ED77E583C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of active program participants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDBD28EDE7BD4363A3E9A86749CEFA0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number that obtained unsubsidized employment in a field related to the apprenticeable occupation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD37A5FAFDFDD48108258BB6653669292"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the total number of program participants that completed the program in which they were enrolled;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5863BDC860F842269B55431A130332F4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the average time to completion for each program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EF055503E98418FB8C7D99F23E21949"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the average cost per participant during the most recent program year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB99B132FAFE4526AF0BC513248E602F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the percentage of participants who received additional support services; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE43C222B774F4B459FF6012E3E906FBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit each report under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H3668D480A6B345A6B24D0233FD80A339"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the registration agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DB7CC6D3A09429280CA891D0ADE1751"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the Diversity and Inclusion Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69305F86800C4477997E780888A942CE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H957E4F44D71E45ACB766FFAB02E10644"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a program sponsor;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45531993BD5F49B1BE4DA6A611698F36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a State workforce development board or State workforce agency, or a local workforce development board or local workforce development agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AA416FC6D634DE481784F282650307A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an education and training provider, or a consortium thereof;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H148EE3340DFE489B98A93392BDF1DBC8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if the applicant is in a State with a State apprenticeship agency, such State apprenticeship agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAE40754232C48BC87BD6555DCB85BEF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF801ED82624422A960424913D7DD7E7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an industry or sector partnership, a group of employers, a trade association, or a professional association that sponsors or participates in a program under the national apprenticeship system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4BD4F7BA4C44505AB67B3C1F1CA681A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a Governor of a State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6DB2D43298245EFBAC3ADE40D4DEBBF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a labor organization or joint-labor management organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H528D4D456A2D4758A0EB6149A51631FA"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a community organization working in partnership with one or more registered apprenticeship programs; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20EEA9D44ABF45CFBDB513DF257ED763"><enum>(10)</enum><text>a qualified intermediary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3CC2B56963F6441C9F2D3D50B671DD56"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following:</text><paragraph id="H8A9134E5B63C4243AC2337A7CD484891"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Education and training provider</header><text>The term <quote>education and training provider</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0720ABC5BE24414986C7B6AEC3B9ABFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an area career and technical education school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77D3E1490AF24BAE89BE05A8D987E1FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an early college high school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AFAD5F4B64D4D33973A9B36828FFC4E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an educational service agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EB86C65ADC54C74997C3F1F4D7B78AE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a high school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC66BB7AEE29946B18D44A3F9F06ABD0D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a local educational agency or State educational agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5537B68C751A4F2B885FC4CC535A26EB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Tribal educational agency, Tribally controlled college or university, or Tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE67C50C591A349BE8FCC9E7F05C6F7BF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a postsecondary educational institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC79837B75C1845618A5B42D4BE48FAC4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a minority-serving institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FE4F450F6054B72B66CCF742B2FA0AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a provider of adult education and literacy activities under the Adult Education and Family Literacy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3271">29 U.S.C. 3271 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF396953EE2E4A39852B5C231F710058"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a local agency administering plans under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/720">29 U.S.C. 720 et seq.</external-xref>), other than section 112 or part C of that title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/732">29 U.S.C. 732</external-xref>, 741);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DF56B053CB549019B74E7AAC0F69682"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a related instruction provider, including a qualified intermediary acting as a related instruction provider as approved by a registration agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49A0B16F440949B59BCE6A5F49604282"><enum>(L)</enum><text>a Job Corps center (as defined in section 142 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3192">29 U.S.C. 3192</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82522A033B5249969908330727981961"><enum>(M)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (L).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4714AC96DC946B5B65453A9F0E6CD45"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB018B2C9C7D04A69B35DA3AD157D68E2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National apprenticeship system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>national apprenticeship system</quote> means the apprenticeship programs, youth apprenticeship programs, and preapprenticeship programs under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly referred to as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2052D3444B04448094713A8A9588929F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nontraditional apprenticeship population</header><text>The term <quote>nontraditional apprenticeship population</quote> means a group of individuals (such as individuals from the same gender, race, or ethnicity), the members of which comprise fewer than 25 percent of the program participants in an apprenticeable occupation under the national apprenticeship system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8BCD48CA9FA4E12AFEB65814B4497AD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nontraditional apprenticeship industry or occupation</header><text>The term <quote>nontraditional apprenticeship industry or occupation</quote> refers to an industry sector or occupation that represents fewer than 10 percent of apprenticeable occupations or the programs under the national apprenticeship system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD8F0F516B34A4C94EF5EF79E8A6B70" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>registered apprenticeship program</quote> means an apprenticeship program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly referred to as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7EC5FEC6A554E74945216A5D8AD2174"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Registration agency</header><text>The term <quote>registration agency</quote> means the State Office of Apprenticeship or State apprenticeship agency in a State that is responsible for—</text><subparagraph id="H29ADA417794E4D198A02AE7EB795A629"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approving or denying applications from sponsors for registration of programs under the national apprenticeship system in the State or area covered by the registration agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F22BCE6842E406985754FC6B02ED67C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carrying out the responsibilities of supporting the youth apprenticeship, preapprenticeship, or apprenticeship programs registered by the registration agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H109E1124BF1A4860A0EDE29FD038E0CD"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>) and includes each of the outlying areas.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H539EE63640834BECBFD6336E4539E166" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect beginning on April 22, 2026.</text></section><section id="HC0DEB99A5A574BCBA6889F309099D59A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Labor to carry out this Act—</text><paragraph id="HC4E9C4BC5BCC4624BEA0F7836DBCC28E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$2,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB46ABCE5AFE74272AB2F88C8464E4397"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8FF700EB35D44EF9BB365A64699ECA9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$4,000,000 for fiscal year 2028; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7023FA840C6A4050834BDAEABB73B520"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$5,000,000 for fiscal year 2029.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

