<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE48CE5EAD613491A874A5CBDEA4FEFE0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6052 IH: Elijah E. Cummings Family Asthma Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6052</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act with regard to research on asthma, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H81DCD25FC6504284B77DAEC2C1085179" style="OLC"><section id="HC8063E1D621A4E10AF9FD8AEBBB7FB27" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Elijah E. Cummings Family Asthma Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB2EE181DFE294F78B8ECCC9AE62B786A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD5214C25421D403294E03460057A388D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in 2023, more than 27,800,000 people in the United States had asthma, including an estimated 4,800,000 children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBDEDE2220FE42E68E0FDD61340BCFED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, asthma is more common among Black Americans, Native individuals (American Indians/Alaska Natives), Puerto Ricans, and people of multiple races compared to non-Hispanic, White individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CE12475A9694059B41942323977C5BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, among children, males have higher rates of asthma than females, and in adults, women have higher rates of asthma than men. Individuals living below the poverty threshold also had significantly higher rates of asthma in 2023 than individuals living above the poverty threshold.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H224B6C97BB4A4D87972AA2D96DEA7455"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in 2023 more than 3,600 people in the United States died from asthma. The rate of mortality from asthma is higher among Black Americans and women.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97E1176FD12F4BA5AF4D789DD3662C77"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Agency for Healthcare and Quality reports that asthma accounted for approximately 131,000 hospitalizations and 1,100,000 visits to hospital emergency departments in 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H252803DE9133483EA002492B5D038DA1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the annual cost of asthma to the United States is approximately $81,900,000,000, including $3,000,000,000 in indirect costs from missed days of school and work.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84CF0BC5F0784CAA88CC6E7DD1B23977"><enum>(7)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, more than 7,900,000 school days and 10,900,000 workdays are missed annually as a result of asthma.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14A0B48663224594A5CEC4CD8BF6F7B4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Asthma episodes can be triggered by both outdoor air pollution and indoor air pollution, including pollutants such as cigarette smoke and combustion by-products. Asthma episodes can also be triggered by indoor allergens, such as animal dander, mold, cockroaches, and rodents, and outdoor allergens such as pollen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9246A513DD54417E85704A19C01F3935"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Public health interventions and medical care in accordance with existing guidelines have been proven effective in the treatment and management of asthma. Better asthma management could reduce the numbers of emergency department visits and hospitalizations due to asthma. Studies published in medical journals, including the Journal of Asthma and The Journal of Pediatrics, have shown that better asthma management results in improved asthma outcomes at a lower cost. However, research published in Preventing Chronic Disease has shown gaps in consistent and comprehensive coverage of guidelines-based asthma care across State Medicaid programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEACE8CBF4464BB7A36AE2C65F342598"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The high health and financial burden caused by asthma underscores the importance of adherence to the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program Guidelines of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute. Increasing adherence to guidelines-based care and resulting patient management practices will enhance the quality of life for patients with asthma and decrease asthma-related morbidity and mortality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABB60728B2484F57ADE4F744FAE698A9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 2016, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reported that less than half of people with asthma reported receiving self-management training for their asthma. More education about triggers, proper treatment, and asthma management methods is needed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D01A9F7F7A04D13B5D089A21BBD2F12"><enum>(12)</enum><text>21 States do not receive funding through the National Asthma Control Program of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Without this funding, State health departments have a limited capacity to improve the reach, quality, effectiveness, and sustainability of asthma control services, conduct comprehensive adult and pediatric surveillance, and reduce asthma morbidity, mortality, and disparities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CCD9D5D4645492FBB0D308182F348C1"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For every $1 spent by the National Asthma Control Program of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, there is a $71 return on investment from reduced healthcare and economic costs related to asthma.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA78C31BBCB7841BCBFEDB909D443C7F4"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The alarming rise in the prevalence of asthma, its adverse effect on school attendance and productivity, and its cost for hospitalizations and emergency room visits highlight the importance of public health interventions, including increasing awareness of asthma as a chronic illness, its symptoms, the role of both indoor and outdoor environmental factors that exacerbate the disease, and other factors that affect its exacerbations and severity. The goals of the Federal Government and its partners in the nonprofit and private sectors should include reducing the number and severity of asthma attacks, asthma’s financial burden, and the health disparities associated with asthma.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4BA77B613042425AA23D2F5DE24BEBF8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Asthma-related activities of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 317I of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-10">42 U.S.C. 247b–10</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H28A3D9BCFEB0492A988BBEF6D488371C" style="OLC"><section id="HC58CF53766274F42840B4BC55B7EA323"><enum>317I.</enum><header>Asthma-related activities of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</header><subsection id="H9D058AEA08424AA3B4A8F92336C639C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program for providing information and education to the public</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Director of the National Center for Environmental Health, shall collaborate with State and local health departments to conduct activities regarding asthma, including the provision of information and education to the public regarding asthma, including—</text><paragraph id="HA1B3D31B86E24BBE910FF45B52500498"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deterring the harmful consequences of uncontrolled asthma; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B95635577AC4A3DB0140F6EEE8BFD83"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminating health education and information regarding prevention of asthma episodes and strategies for managing asthma.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6B57CA0973342A685EEDE9D17196985"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of State strategic plans for asthma control</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Elijah E. Cummings Family Asthma Act</short-title>, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall collaborate with State and local health departments to develop State strategic plans for asthma control incorporating public health responses to reduce the burden of asthma, particularly regarding disproportionately affected populations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1A9F5399ED394E4885B5D20461B08EE1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compilation of data</header><paragraph id="H71E07D9E75D644D4B20F938E8C676A69"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in collaboration with State and local health departments, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5F13E1A8D674465FB9F73EFE28AA04AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct asthma surveillance activities to collect data on the prevalence and severity of asthma, the effectiveness of public health asthma interventions, and the quality of asthma management, including—</text><clause id="H1334C83E4357477CB03CF2523D4E7DFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collection of data on or among people with asthma to monitor the impact on health and quality of life;</text></clause><clause id="HDBDED77C75274359ACF1BDECCDD379B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>surveillance of health care facilities; and</text></clause><clause id="HB43F4AD9EC5842F3AB088E842EA1B7CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>collection of data from electronic health records or other electronic communications;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61BB3F3400F14346867744B883A889C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compile and annually publish data regarding—</text><clause id="H126C19DD5EDE4926A690AC661836FD02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the prevalence of childhood asthma;</text></clause><clause id="HBB72565E7B8F4058AE40ADCC3A186F92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the child mortality rate of asthma;</text></clause><clause id="H81922D68C2A04F88A34B62B597E3360A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of hospital admissions and emergency department visits by children associated with asthma nationally, disaggregated by State, age, sex, race, and ethnicity;</text></clause><clause id="HF0C842F89ECC47B5A9B7F6EEB64FEB34"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the prevalence of adult asthma;</text></clause><clause id="HC629B1AC8E594F95B5D42B4DC1D0B739"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the adult mortality rate of asthma; and</text></clause><clause id="HBE0122375C694FC9AA2528770940E6AD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of hospital admissions and emergency department visits by adults associated with asthma nationally, disaggregated by State, age, sex, race, and ethnicity; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9B52162961347969D7591716866F7AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modernize asthma surveillance systems to—</text><clause id="H37B321D4DE0945C2B8CA23045C742730"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enable real-time exchange of data from healthcare, schools, and public health entities; and</text></clause><clause id="H069F6729CF9D48F498273E64182A308C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>support timely publication of national and State trend reports, disaggregated by age, sex, race, ethnicity, payer, and geography.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H084EA8BCEF0A4C919BF6CCBFC3664B62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data privacy</header><text>None of the data collected, compiled, or published under paragraph (1) may contain individually identifiable information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H426C4D4068114544A3DE702BB71C8573" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ensuring comparability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in collaboration with State and local health departments, shall ensure that the data described in paragraph (1) are collected and compiled using a consistent methodology so as to maximize the comparability of results.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E50C6996B3C4362934283EA508F5207"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collaboration with nonprofits</header><text>The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention may collaborate with national, State, and local nonprofit organizations to provide information and education about asthma.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB921E0E9950A4DEE9F0B2E8104A19859"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><paragraph id="HFEC6D168FC384AD5A7A29FFC7E4BE4B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Elijah E. Cummings Family Asthma Act</short-title>, and 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall, in collaboration with patient groups, nonprofit organizations, medical societies, and other relevant governmental and nongovernmental entities, submit to Congress a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H69C42F05C08B4A4F89C52AF108085926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>catalogs, with respect to asthma prevention, management, and surveillance—</text><clause id="HBD76D7100C75457AB2256D0885BFED49"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the activities of the Federal Government, including an assessment of the progress of the Federal Government and States, with respect to achieving the goals of the Healthy People 2030 initiative; and</text></clause><clause id="H7B4D6760FFDA44958706B54D6A6DEE54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the activities of other entities that participate in the program under this section, including nonprofit organizations, patient advocacy groups, and medical societies; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78D83762F5C74C109710EA3C843E6660"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes recommendations for the future direction of asthma-related activities, in consultation with researchers from the National Institutes of Health, including—</text><clause id="HD8F438DB11FC438889A8279AE18AF73E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of how the Federal Government may improve its response to asthma, including identifying any barriers that may exist;</text></clause><clause id="H4DF73DFB71E34FFE98D4ABB8B8332FA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the Federal Government may continue, expand, and improve its private-public partnerships with respect to asthma, including identifying any barriers that may exist;</text></clause><clause id="H9D90B06FED114DFEB18FB3FF04B7F4F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the identification of steps that may be taken to reduce the—</text><subclause id="HFF35FA7E746A48C892F28FA590296576"><enum>(I)</enum><text>morbidity, mortality, and overall prevalence of asthma;</text></subclause><subclause id="H78194D49FF64424883668ADA89B6927A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>financial burden of asthma on society;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1C3B8F4AF7F04DEDA73948B9B6C616ED"><enum>(III)</enum><text>burden of asthma on disproportionately affected areas, particularly those in medically underserved populations (as defined in section 330(b)(3)); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H51410533A27146D39FB336DE37C5D0CC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>burden of asthma as a chronic disease that can be worsened by environmental exposures;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2A4773435E944FDF951BE8EF37783661"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the identification of programs and policies that have achieved the steps described in clause (iii);</text></clause><clause id="HD8BC465CE38942CCA027840CC401CCE5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the identification of steps that may be taken to expand such programs and policies to benefit larger populations; and</text></clause><clause id="H8453097878D04A7BB50784A93ACD2DA7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>recommendations for future research and interventions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0FEF253756E49F3BA888B07D48A9456"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination for recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making recommendations under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall coordinate with—</text><subparagraph id="H74FF641403DD465191A972A27683CAC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services, including the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC71EA764D8FA4481BFE426C784014870"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7A243BBF2CD4BE49249248CBD215C63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D29553BC625437BBC2CCE178A0BF2FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA46AAC35E25D40F58571A3E16C9EF267"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0228E154C874F6DA19343E48174D944"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H586598F20FEC4DD38C5EF1128A7A5760"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $70,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

