<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KIN26038-M58-WW-Y6X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3667 IS: Life at Conception Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3667</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To implement equal protection under the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the
 United States for the right to life of each born and preborn human person.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Life at Conception Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id5c5b8a790a92447d8b3bc6df75a2422a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Right to life</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To implement equal protection for the right to life of each born and preborn human person, and pursuant to the duty and authority of Congress, including Congress’ power under section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States to make necessary and proper laws, and Congress’ power under section 5 of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution, the Congress hereby declares that the right to life guaranteed by the Constitution is vested in each human being. Nothing in this Act shall be construed to require the prosecution of any woman for the death of her unborn child, a prohibition on in vitro fertilization, or a prohibition on use of birth control or another means of preventing fertilization.</text></section><section id="id5c08427afb024627b915200ba07af6ca"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="ida18d739abdd14707aa24537e9da528a1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Human person; human being</header><text>The terms <term>human person</term> and <term>human being</term> include each member of the species homo sapiens at all stages of life, including the moment of fertilization or cloning, or other moment at which an individual member of the human species comes into being.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c2213e529d6481ea31b977fabfede8f"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>State</header> <text>For purposes of applying the 14th Amendment to the Constitution of the United States and other applicable provisions of the Constitution to carry out section 2, the term <term>State</term> includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each other territory or possession of the United States.</text>
      </paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

