<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H859473304CA744B693133307B62B0939" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9493 IH: Home Internet Accessibility Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9493</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General to submit to Congress a report on the capacity of federally assisted housing to support broadband service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC4011F97E7ED42678193980E6DC51BC9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H613B8450932E4A8399D8C0B679F203AE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Home Internet Accessibility Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H84E329E4F1B14D268747EE5C428E819D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Comptroller General report on the capacity of federally assisted housing to support broadband service</header> <subsection id="H71AF278F45594CC089E8AE1EFC04A00E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the capacity of federally assisted housing to support broadband service.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9D4014903EDE4439A11AF70F20F8A233"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H637B8219048140A4AF10F0824A3DFB7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis that identifies which federally assisted housing has access to broadband service and which such housing does not have access to broadband service, disaggregated by State, congressional district, ZIP Code, and census tract, that includes demographic information and any Federal agency responsible for such housing;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H529136B0B483471CBA8E5C78AEF269AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of which such housing does not currently have the capacity to support broadband service deployment and would require retrofitting to support broadband service deployment, disaggregated by State, congressional district, ZIP Code, and census tract, that includes demographic information and any Federal agency responsible for such housing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77BB281BBD9545BBB92D0E0CA97B0BC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the estimated costs and timeframe necessary for all federally assisted housing to have the capacity to support broadband service;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAD41F7EDA4094A5B85963E95386D20B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the challenges to more widespread deployment of broadband service, including the comparative market dynamics to expansion in rural areas and low-income urban and suburban areas, and the challenges to pursuing retrofits for all federally assisted housing to have the capacity to support broadband service;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5102D21A6BC64DE68E2AFBD3328C68E7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>descriptions of lessons learned from previous retrofitting actions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H18C4B15B26B548F99F272A6AA40F7DB8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an evaluation of the ConnectHome pilot program of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD2A769C73504637BA6823F4BFE444B7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for Congress to allow for all federally assisted housing to have the capacity to support broadband service under a range of specific projected timelines.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HEF0B080623AA4834AE1F12EE9CD7E28A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Plan for broadband connectivity in federally assisted housing</header>
<subsection id="HD601CE615A9E4881A2FE95C199FA181C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in consultation with the Comptroller General and other relevant heads of Federal agencies, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8AC93580AC274FA6A9EDF2A7668AADE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a plan for retrofitting federally assisted housing, as necessary, to support broadband service; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H994C7BCB3F684B73A78C29F686CCFF10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit such plan to the Congress not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H36ECB4E8DEEE4B0484237D8DBEF697D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H2DD5084C7A0A4CF891E6AE1A6FA23D41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Broadband Service</header><text>The term <term>broadband service</term> has the meaning given the term <term>broadband internet access service</term> in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E61B6E810A7438098C436040EC511F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>federally assisted housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>federally assisted housing</term> means any dwelling that constitutes or contains a housing unit that is assisted under a program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDE33AC850E90499294628F382FFDA1F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

