<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9EEDFD4A7D1B43DA88A53E3893E3476A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6159 IH: Artificial Intelligence for Advancing Literacy and Learning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6159</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000620">Ms. Rivas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish in the Office of Science and Technology Policy the Artificial Intelligence Literacy and Education Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H22110DCBEA0F45F98AFF54B757E2A87F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1C2E5E25FCD647EE817B4616709A1361" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence for Advancing Literacy and Learning Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AI for ALL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HC2E68DE730764149B7CF421160E3B69E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the Artificial Intelligence Literacy and Education Commission</header> 
<subsection id="H6EFE8BC83A9846569A6D6EC0888202B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Office of Science and Technology Policy a commission to be known as the <quote>Artificial Intelligence Literacy and Education Commission</quote>.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H5F740B2BD1354B83A8DDAB18AB2F3B67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the Commission shall be composed of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB0523F6BE9564360ABD1599F34BF7BDC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, who shall serve as the Chairperson.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BAEA650237A4FC2820F633F423C5DCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A representative of the Office of Management and Budget with expertise in AI, appointed by the Director of such Office.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64534EC1BE0744CF82E5793D60A878DA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A representative of the National Science Foundation with expertise in AI, appointed by the Director of such Foundation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC38589BED0144328074322885A13A39"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A representative of the Department of Commerce with expertise in AI, appointed by the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15564D9D55A34F7492C8D31B8550B9D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A representative of the Department of Education with expertise in AI, appointed by the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECD87746BD0A49C286064BC90E3E09A3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A representative of the Department of Labor with expertise in AI, appointed by the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91539F6DFE68468C8C082C64DE3A1EDF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A representative of the General Services Administration with expertise in AI, appointed by the Administrator of General Services.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H89B569292F4F4158900E3E9E307A59F8" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with AI expertise appointed by the Chairperson from an institution of higher education that is leading advanced research of AI.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD24482B4FC3A418ABA72C04C5DC52F2E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>An individual with AI expertise appointed by the Chairperson from a private sector entity.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB449CF3C9DB44FB59C1C3862795B966E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>An individual appointed by the Chairperson from an organization that develops AI literacy recommendations.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A511C73761F4E3987BCE2D8D5D05A02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header> 
<paragraph id="H139FECAFC0864B538244A21D15CF5C5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regular meetings</header><text>The Commission shall hold, at the call of the Chairperson, at least one meeting every three months. The Commission may hold, at the call of the Chairperson, such other meetings as the Chairperson determines appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCBA0F5ADC604DBBBA2801D2A80D75D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Commission shall hold the first meeting of the Commission not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F16986DA915493B9B15BFF951331A50"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties of the Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the duties of the Commission under sections 3 and 4, the Commission shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="H153E78481E86428C986151B3A9448FF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Streamline, improve, and augment AI literacy and education as the Chairperson determines necessary for the ability of persons in the United States to effectively and efficiently utilize AI.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2B0DF4D61EB749FDAC55D7CDF7346CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, coordinate and promote AI literacy and education efforts at the State and local level, including by promoting partnerships among Federal, State, and local governments, nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education, research institutions, and private sector entities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9E05BA46DFA34BC8BED70E798891D56F"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Non-Termination; exemption from charter requirement</header> <text>Section 1013 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Commission.</text>
      </subsection> </section> 
<section id="HBBF77CB7D6174C928EFD13ADC9420FF6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Development and dissemination of materials</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="H867BA35575ED4B73AA982A9632B89510"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop multilingual materials and resources promoting AI literacy and education in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F3F3D5590154A8C9291FCABDD2D42A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Disseminate to the general public such materials and resources in any form or manner the Chairperson determines appropriate, which may include any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HEBC7825D312E4F919B73E4076DFE3BBC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Establishing a publicly available website that contains such materials and resources.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H183E81D4E8714588B4CD325F6D9D10B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting a multilingual national public service multimedia campaign.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HCFD8798DD1A844D297DCD0C4AB9CE5A3"><enum>4.</enum><header>National strategy for AI literacy and education</header> <subsection id="H33656F5D85B34634B98C439FECFB64A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall carry out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE9F65620FF2A4E6F84892CB166F2DBB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Develop a national strategy for the Federal Government to carry out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC0CD66A81B5641EDB0F13E706C5B8A13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Identify the opportunities and challenges for the Federal Government with respect to improving the AI literacy and education of persons in the United States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C8371BF8ECA4E9297144A50E236780E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with such identifications, improve such literacy and education, including by ensuring such persons understand the following:</text> <clause id="H95132482005E451180DD462F643457AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>AI.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H857A44C8768B4449A5A1737145A8D50B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>How AI has evolved and is expected to evolve.</text></clause> <clause id="HE37265B649A945879B44EDF9117ABEC2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>How to utilize AI safely and effectively.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93F015D6F67D413AB603E7F548EC2FAE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Ensure such improvements enable for the United States continued global leadership in AI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA678B6B6EC54CDFBCD41E077BE4657A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Submit to Congress such strategy.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H25CF0C1170404868BA083050D4B250F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent strategies</header> 
<paragraph id="HEB37518365C94C2196CE921671DA6371"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than six months after submitting the strategy pursuant to subsection (a) and biennially thereafter, the Chairperson shall determine whether such strategy is outdated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0DE50B5D7D842199FD538F3B5D5A7C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>If the Chairperson, pursuant to paragraph (1) or (3), as the case may be, makes such a determination in the affirmative, the Commission shall submit to Congress an updated strategy that includes any changes the Chairperson determines necessary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8E6DD5AEABF4F6D9808AC2B96BAA65E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Further determinations</header><text>If an updated strategy is submitted under paragraph (2), not later than two years after such submission and biennially thereafter, the Chairperson shall make a determination described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H0C952CD9EE2343B897BD4E4E93D407A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Commission shall, as appropriate, coordinate the efforts of the Federal Government to implement a strategy submitted under this section.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HD0906ED43F434AE2B7E076FD6757365B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB8754E3425D04EE892F4FA3D7CB24069"><enum>(1)</enum><header>AI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>AI</term> has the meaning given the term <term>artificial intelligence</term> in section 238(g) of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4061">10 U.S.C. 4061</external-xref> note prec.).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H690AA0006C8B491EAF9156FF80D55673"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The term <term>Chairperson</term> means the Chairperson of the Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE213522C3E84DA08BFAB967AF1E9C8F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Artificial Intelligence Literacy and Education Commission established under section 2.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6744A0176AA948B5814A7C51B7D36DC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

