<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77BDE6C9BB774986B08D82907534084B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8425 IH: Strengthening the Vaccines for Children Program Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8425</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to ensure access to immunizations under the Medicaid program and the Vaccines for Children program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HED1E9F9E810A45049BD3E53562DD39CA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H67ACE07008B24876BF880203CDAE8833" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening the Vaccines for Children Program Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCFF61C956AC04D089A342803796370A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring access to immunizations under the Medicaid program and the Vaccines for Children program</header> <subsection id="HF4AFBE75160A47248158952BA6BDCC87"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Expansion of definition of federally vaccine-Eligible child</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 1928(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396s">42 U.S.C. 1396s(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
                <paragraph id="H1843491EA1E742A5BE14BC02D3C9BD1A">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE6480DEEA2D745A9B7FD0E1043DEB99B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>A child who</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>A child who is administered a qualified pediatric vaccine and is not insured with respect to such vaccine.</quote>; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H9DF6F0AFE64F429DB4F4B94789A0AE33">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H37F0B7BC1087440683D545720AB18030" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HA7F6379095B24D6CA0F0CB4953265E01"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A child who is enrolled for child health assistance under a State child health plan approved under title XXI.</text>
                            </clause>
                            <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
                        </quoted-block>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H299664CB1B8D470C9D01AB9A8E58A3AE">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (B)(ii)(II), by striking <quote>for purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii)(II)</quote> and inserting <quote>for purposes of subparagraph (A)(iii)</quote>.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0557835C980344DE9A30C9DEEDBBA53F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum payment requirement for vaccine administration and counseling services</header> 
<paragraph id="HFBFF1CD2A5464D67AEF93F90CF455B5F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902(a)(13) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(13)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H585E00DD9517443CAAA768D1470608C0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A8F07849F5548ABA7D61363DC2787E5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39BD9446F26C4CE3A663B796908715AA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H856FD8A00AA24064A6BF97E4F01A2918" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H04FF4391F72743079857FF7B0FB1C830" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for payment for vaccine administration and counseling services furnished by a provider during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, and ending on December 31, 2028 (including, notwithstanding subsection (c)(2)(C)(ii) of section 1928, any such services furnished with respect to a vaccine furnished under the program established by the State pursuant to such section to a medicaid-eligible child (as defined in subsection (b)(2)(B)(i) of such section)), at a rate not less than 100 percent of the payment rate that applies to such services and provider under part B of title XVIII;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB23F4494AD04DD1A9265870670319FD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Managed care plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1932(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-2">42 U.S.C. 1396u–2(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA69F7B0EF2AB4F968FABFEE28CE96EDC" commented="no">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>in the header, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">payment for primary care services</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">payments</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HADAB443486CB4D0F8413BBB560D86B8E" commented="no">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>section 1902(a)(13)(C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (C) of section 1902(a)(13) and vaccine administration and counseling services described in subparagraph (D) of such section</quote>;</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13F5EFA3CE364F97A578F6094D64F024" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such section</quote> and inserting <quote>such subparagraph (C) or (D), respectively</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD3CF2368174345A1ADE88AE50D2D74B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The provisions of the preceding sentence shall apply to contracts entered into with, and payments made by, other specified entities (as defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D)(iii)) in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to contracts entered into with, and payments made by, medicaid managed care organizations.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11DE9E16C9C7406DB59EF9651A5EDB14"><enum>(3)</enum><header>CHIP</header><text>Section 2103(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397cc">42 U.S.C. 1397cc(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAC2AB01B341049B98277A3A8B365573A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HA374B1E5B7094226B7273B99DEA73EE6"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Vaccine administration services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The child health assistance provided to a targeted low-income child shall include payment for vaccine administration and counseling services furnished by a provider during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph, and ending on December 31, 2028 (including, notwithstanding subsection (c)(2)(C)(ii) of section 1928, any such services furnished to such child with respect to a vaccine furnished under the program established by the State pursuant to such section), at a rate not less than 100 percent of the payment rate that applies to such services and provider under part B of title XVIII.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29FD281FE87D45DBAC52AD282183699F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of coverage of pediatric vaccine administration and vaccine counseling and educational services under the Vaccines for Children program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1928(c)(2)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396s">42 U.S.C. 1396s(c)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC04D0B6FE29E4DC095D4AB4EE4059935"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by amending such clause to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H967CF9A044E54EF8A09763C7E42A2F44" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HB6AF375862BA4AED8276536CDEC1C28D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provider may impose—</text> <subclause id="H6C33D8FD9F2E4B918DE786395AC2CA6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a qualified pediatric vaccine not described in subclause (II), a fee for the administration of and counseling for such vaccine (which, in the case of a counseling fee, may be so imposed regardless of whether such vaccine is actually administered) so long as the fee in the case of a federally vaccine-eligible child does not exceed the costs of such administration and counseling (as determined by the Secretary based on actual regional costs for such administration and counseling and updated as determined appropriate by the Secretary to take into account changes in such costs, including changes attributable to the inclusion of new qualified pediatric vaccines in the program established under this section); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8ACEF5B3EF644EE1819CE3F5027D1784"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a qualified pediatric vaccine that is a multiple component vaccine, a separate charge for the administration of and counseling for each component of such vaccine (which, in the case of a counseling fee, may be so imposed regardless of whether such component is actually administered) so long as the charge in the case of a federally vaccine-eligible child does not exceed—</text> <item id="H270EE95392824B1BB0FDC37A1EF8B64E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the first component of such vaccine, the costs of such administration and counseling for such component (as determined by the Secretary based on actual regional costs for such administration and counseling for such first component and updated as determined appropriate by the Secretary to take into account changes in such costs, including changes attributable to the inclusion of new qualified pediatric vaccines in the program established under this section); and</text></item> 
<item id="H4F4D2807BB3B4C79A07732CE988BC764"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a subsequent component of such vaccine, the payment rate that applies to such administration and counseling for such component and provider under part B of title XVIII.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAF3F1B2FAFB45488E219EE4653BBFC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by inserting <quote>or counseling</quote> after <quote>an administration</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2313736BC81E4CE3A2760E7258EB16D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Increase in Federal medical assistance percentage</header> 
<paragraph id="H81F9528D304244C7A5684F04022F5FE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), for each calendar quarter occurring during the period beginning on or after January 1, 2027, the Federal medical assistance percentage determined for each State, including the District of Columbia, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, and the United States Virgin Islands, under section 1905(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(b)</external-xref>) shall be increased by 1 percentage point.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5AAFAF222D446B2AB6E0B2232FA78D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H8DC66FBC66364ECE9AF8E7F4A1952B77"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State described in paragraph (1) may not receive the increase described in such paragraph in the Federal medical assistance percentage for such State, with respect to a quarter, if such State does not ensure culturally competent and effective messages for vaccination outreach to child populations, which may include the dissemination of information highlighting—</text> 
<clause id="H5C6FE6F617004C38B834FF4DF56AFE84"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancements in research and vaccine development that have saved millions of individuals from death and disability from now-preventable diseases;</text></clause> <clause id="H4C5D897EE160446FAFCB32A439844288"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on how individuals across the lifespan benefit from immunizations, including those who cannot be vaccinated and rely on community immunity;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB07C1F5F82894729A5468FE353E193A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the dangers of not being vaccinated, including the potential for infectious disease outbreaks within communities; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA3CB92E0F49C43A381BA77E284BE273F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on vaccine safety and the systems in place to monitor vaccine safety.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CE7DAE95BD94150AC8712B8D093708F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement for certain States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(cc) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(cc)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="HF8EC13CAC1304AABA2EA3526A6649A84"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and section 2(d) of the Strengthening the Vaccines for Children Program Act of 2026</quote> before <quote>, except that in applying</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC9FCD82F7ACB4C7EBDF6940D7304725A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and in applying such treatments to the increases in the Federal medical assistance percentage under section 2(e) of the <short-title>Strengthening the Vaccines for Children Program Act of 2026</short-title>, the reference to <quote>December 31, 2009</quote> shall be deemed to be a reference to <quote>December 31, 2025</quote></quote> before the period at the end.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEA65D8494A3E4AEDB8E7D35F8FB4DBC1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tribal epidemiology center data access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to data access for tribal epidemiology centers established under section 214 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1621m">25 U.S.C. 1621m</external-xref>), the Director of the Centers for Disease control and Prevention may create a data sharing strategy that ensures such centers have access to data, data sets, monitoring systems, delivery systems, and other protected health information with respect to health care and public health surveillance systems of child and adolescent health necessary to accomplish such centers’ public health authority responsibilities described in such section or section 164.501 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF51EADF3176F44DEA55DBEC007AED118"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H3F4598A999014A11A340BCC1B1623C7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in coordination with each State that has established a pediatric vaccine distribution program under section 1928 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396s">42 U.S.C. 1396s</external-xref>), shall publish on the public internet website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in such manner as determined appropriate by the Director, information on vaccination rates under each such program during such year, including such rates disaggregated by region, age, sex, race, ethnicity, and other demographic factors determined appropriate by the Director.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H771BB48985E24FC592C1DE4C488A0D77" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effects on vaccination rates and program participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing an analysis of the effects of the provisions of, and the amendments made by, this Act on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H31C812B2312843D885AF642608DFC628" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>vaccination rates under the pediatric vaccine distribution program under section 1928 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396s">42 U.S.C. 1396s</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA48437A609F46DE92948A06F304B84B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provider participation in such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

