<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H706D21D0842D45CA8EC692D5A16A1F22" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9622 IH: Modernizing Aeronautical Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9622</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require NASA to conduct a study on the modernization of aeronautical standards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8913110836364B42ACDC5D55608FA5F4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8E670EC6FD1846D0805766666DE2646A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modernizing Aeronautical Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD1E65B56E4CE4E7AAF6FC8E88E51D779"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on aeronautical standards</header> 
<subsection id="H82AB9E28B3824D46B05B06F1FD736C1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and representatives of relevant academic, industry, nonprofit, or standards organizations as the Administrator of NASA determines appropriate, shall conduct a study on the modernization of aeronautical standards.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD44AC833352A4F228B2FAD068B730F50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The study conducted under subsection (a) shall be known as the <quote>Modernization of Aeronautical Standards and Aircraft Performance Study</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>study</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE437F2721A0C431B85C97397D207974E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study may include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAF04EE8A11C14A0E92AEE771A45E4698"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD0F8A8A278704428900077E951C16C7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>current atmospheric conditions, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC742AD160679409A8F548D2080448941"><enum>(B)</enum><text>corresponding atmospheric conditions over the immediately preceding 50 years,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">including an assessment of significant variations between the conditions specified in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C170B8FF6264D6BBCCBA60C410FC53E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the state of current predictions for, or mapping of, future trends or variations in atmospheric conditions in the 50 years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0B77A1AC1074B25861C25BCF36784E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the impacts to operation, maintenance, and sustainment costs of covered commercial aircraft as a result of any significant variations related to atmospheric conditions assessed pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A812EDF1C2A458EB6DDD994EC165A98"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimation of the number of weight restriction hours for covered commercial aircraft at covered commercial airports as a consequence of the assessment of atmospheric conditions pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BA071F83DCD409E8D8722C9A8CA83C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of required infrastructure investment at covered commercial airports as a result of the assessments of atmospheric conditions pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FA7D583D8BA48AB8B21F4852ADDE075"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of recommended considerations for design modifications for future aircraft to account for the assessments of atmospheric conditions pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB4402D5CDA64973A03E3C77A6D600C1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An analysis of impacts to operation, maintenance, and sustainment costs and aircraft performance of aircraft as a result of the atmospheric conditions assessed pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92276AC3FA86426BA27CC5F82C2641E1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Design requirements for aircraft owned by the Federal Government, or other equipment, which should be updated to account for atmospheric conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D1A48410C3F4140919E0506E730C529"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessments of United States aeronautical and atmospheric standards, as a result of the assessments of atmospheric conditions pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C5F530853F84DF1A387B2E50C48C21A"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Criteria under which future updates or supplements to atmospheric standards should be made.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE088722178D4E97854A6E73757E0847"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator NASA may transmit the results of the study to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6E50BFDEC5DD49B5A340AEB8505AFDED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBF403FFDA12148BEBEEAA5D3E8700F4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aircraft performance</header><text>The term <quote>aircraft performance</quote> includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9904CBD51BE2483AAF8794DE9D21C877"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Range.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC38AF258E34F46538B3D63B81CCED3B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Payload capacity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76B34207EB7E4C8DAB5AF039D08E6DC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Runway length requirement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E4C7936D3CE40769AC5EC1CCE0343FF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Climb rate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCD030E1C7DF1436B86F0A7B7EE67C54D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Turn rate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD3598A276B746489BA78E27BCD04C61"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Operating altitude.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E4629D2B2AD42989D982D025B379EBD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Acceleration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09039586232341D1B24713FEFE346396"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Atmospheric standards</header><text>The term <quote>atmospheric standards</quote> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2672710FE80C4F07BC883C12388E4455"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The United States Standard Atmosphere of 1976.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4A4706101BF46FFA09674A41373B66B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other standard as determined by the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9AE34AB6E1F9436DA44F564AF7F18C52" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered commercial aircraft</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered commercial aircraft</quote> means the ten aircraft types still in production with the highest number of operations at covered commercial airports in the most recent calendar year ending before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD33E8778154488EB5F30CFCD9402795" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered commercial airports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered commercial airports</quote> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA2C3EF3649F54133900FE9B62A5A86F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The 30 commercial service airports (as such term is defined in section 47102(7) of title 49, United States Code) with the most passenger boardings (as such term is defined in section 47102(15) of title 49, United States Code) in the most recent calendar year ending before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD015E9E62CBA41D9B5DE4D0124BF3452"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The five public airports (as such term is defined in section 47102(21) of title 49, United States Code) not described in subparagraph (A) with the highest all-cargo landed weight in the most recent calendar year ending before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H319BC627F0B54DE38697B7E810C46A13" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Weight restriction hour</header><text>The term <quote>weight restriction hour</quote> means an hour when the maximum temperature for that hour matches or exceeds the weight-restriction temperature threshold for a specific aircraft.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

