<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY26367-CP1-2X-X8T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4131 IS: Veteran Access to Neurosurgery Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide market-based rate adjustments to certain providers for furnishing qualifying specialized surgical services to veterans under the Veterans Community Care Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Access to Neurosurgery Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7d3f5e751d5447f7b4854cbad4935ceb"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for market-based rate adjustments for qualifying specialized surgical services under the Veterans Community Care Program</header><subsection id="idc6ec296e9d2942448d00c0dab0f4cd46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Commencing not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program to permit qualified providers to negotiate market-based rate adjustments for furnishing qualifying specialized surgical services to veterans under the Veterans Community Care Program (in this section referred to as the <quote>pilot program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf571c4b7742f4aad975371f38de1b0df"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may carry out the pilot program for the five-year period beginning on the commencement of the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="id12472f07c80f4ccc8325a4db83ee2b79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program in not less than two Veterans Integrated Service Networks of the Department of Veterans Affairs with a large number of veterans residing in locations that are in rural or highly rural areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9fc5eb33eef542fba0df7b5f776ca3b3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determination of market-Based rate adjustments</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall provide a market-based rate adjustment to a qualified provider in furnishing qualified specialized surgical services to a veteran if—</text><paragraph id="id291bb1a95bf840288bfcb974d1baf653"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the provider demonstrates that the rate adjustment is necessary to furnish such services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcdf94e9392de46e8af95bcab1bd68209" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the rate otherwise applicable to such services under the Veterans Community Care Program is insufficient to cover the cost of furnishing such services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98889d80f8674db0a1b418742278faa2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the veteran lives in a geographical area where there are no other qualifying specialized surgical services furnished by the Department of Veterans Affairs, either direct care or through the Veterans Community Care Program, available within either a 60-day wait-time or distance of 100 miles.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1ab9c73b57ad441189195439d6794814"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe, through notice and comment rulemaking, regulations necessary to implement this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id408de22c390a4ddd8606f901f40fbeb1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Inspector General review</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter for the duration of the pilot program, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80c39819dcd64b0099c0b7967e21b0ea"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a review of the pilot program to ensure compliance by the Secretary with requirements under the pilot program and to ensure the efficiency and effectiveness of the pilot program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdb9bf8fa69a4112ad1c8d53fa033bd6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Secretary and the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing the findings from such review.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id73e71ca326c84ecda6b719a219ff986b"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter for the duration of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the pilot program that includes, for the year covered by the report, the following:</text><paragraph id="id2851f0b5903f4ed09e9bd9c8baad9020"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of patients served under the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id227076cb3df846a4995435cb8a698408"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The different types of qualifying specialized surgical services furnished under the pilot program and the number of veterans furnished each such service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0a7a87fac63424eb15e5aa8a8485970"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The total costs incurred in furnishing services under the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4f3528ec815487082cdeb367549bbe3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of any measurable outcomes in terms of health results for patients under the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida192a654e10d42b49faad19b5b7b314c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any policy recommendations for improvement of the pilot program or recommendations as to whether the pilot program should be extended or made permanent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d913916ab7c4047b1b537a249ca5eca" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such other information as the Secretary determines relevant to include.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c8f24d1944a4339b8bbf968838a2b2a"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide223081793114613a254f69831745fc1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id654f8fac694c4a399dbbee09fef7627d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdfa5535b1e4499a91f90f5321089fec"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id39d525e816024cdf8609ac2b9ae7685c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified provider</header><text>The term <term>qualified provider</term> means a board-certified surgeon.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id81d427bde9724e4bbc34aeea953d07ba"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifying specialized surgical services</header><text>The term <term>qualifying specialized surgical services</term> means services relating to neurosurgery.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81fda1b6d723477db4b92fdf5a1ef30c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Veterans Community Care Program</header><text>The term <term>Veterans Community Care Program</term> means the program under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

