<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A89841939AD47B8AA22AEDFCA67C4F6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7813 IH: NOAA Weather Radio Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7813</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 to require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to expand and modernize the weather radio system of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17D243CED80C4C53A842AEDA90FD28EA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBF6525658B5D4BCF89441EC169C44E41" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NOAA Weather Radio Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H071044A3C60A454587732AFC770FDA51"><enum>2.</enum><header>NOAA Weather Radio</header> <subsection id="HE2C1652E9C024F938FD8391CE66D08FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8501">15 U.S.C. 8501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new title:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H745BCF157A934BACB9A894BFED9C7DF1" style="OLC"> 
<title id="HF4DA3B0029A248B5814EC1636D621A81"><enum>VII</enum><header>NOAA Weather Radio</header> 
<section id="H0ED8D178C9C3452F8A60CA51B3BE45B5"><enum>701.</enum><header>NOAA Weather Radio</header> 
<subsection id="HB6B4AC65D1F74DD194B632BC4FAFA76B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish or maintain a nationwide weather radio network, to be known as <quote>NOAA Weather Radio</quote>, that—</text> <paragraph id="HD4215F2190754ECFB6C46F8519BD0440" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>broadcasts weather information, including emergency weather watches, warnings, geological hazards, and other hazard information;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1D24065ABD14C948737D529A41FA536" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operates 24 hours a day, 7 days a week; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4B1C1B3D252468CB97E535F7105AEAB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is resilient to emergency hazards, such as loss of power and cellular service.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF920DD7B3C1C486D915637DC33E607F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coverage and reliability</header><text>The Under Secretary shall ensure the reliability of NOAA Weather Radio by—</text> <paragraph id="H265C764144EB4B37A88CC94ECD5723DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintaining support for existing systems before new technologies are implemented, especially such systems that serve areas not covered by or having poor quality cellular service; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07821D9F424C4C2FA31C32D2C800ADC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring consistent maintenance and operations monitoring, with timely repairs to broadcast transmitter site equipment and antennas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3200637C3AEE4678B27C793A41609032"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modernization initiative</header> <paragraph id="H4D213A0485554470B0D410A23093CF4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Under Secretary shall expand the coverage of and modernize NOAA Weather Radio to ensure it remains valuable to the public, including by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA4ED0DE41BC54E9D839856C0EC9D3BA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving those methods of communicating the risks posed by hazardous weather events to the public that are most likely to result in informed decision-making regarding the mitigation of such risks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18DEDE49667C4F7EBFEA3EA07BBF00E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving communication of hazardous weather warnings and the urgency of such warnings, including to areas that experience a high frequency of such warnings;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF99741258204E0680963F5B2A920421"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhancing the ability to amplify non-weather emergency messages for the integrated public alert and warning system (IPAWS) under section 1756 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/321o-1">6 U.S.C. 321o–1</external-xref>) through NOAA Weather Radio, as necessary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87CAF9AD6AE441BF8F745AD541AA7E5A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>acquiring additional transmitters, as determined appropriate, to expand coverage to—</text> 
<clause id="H9AEFC704D98140FAA9554F8CA9D3BA6D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>areas at high risk for rapid onset weather disasters that require short-fuse warnings;</text></clause> <clause id="HD317B07860FF4D80A49FCBA7DAE81956" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communities without—</text> 
<subclause id="HEAF61A7261F146498AACCB91B89B0ADD" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>broadband internet access service (as such term is defined in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)), and as depicted by a map created pursuant to section 802(c)(1)(C) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/642">47 U.S.C. 642(c)(1)(C)</external-xref>);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE4CF4AA03B864F838EB57539F85C26F7" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>State or local emergency warning systems; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1BF552F652B4411AB656CB106B640C60" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>satellite coverage; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H812F44F991B74F16A6521562D87B70AA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Federal lands, such as land in the National Park System or the National Forest System and National Recreation Areas;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A8B06A91C1947CDB8E73C6DD1254696"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adding the capability to disseminate NOAA Weather Radio alerts—</text> <clause id="H7C107C275508469C9947BA826E6E11A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by satellite; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBC5D9E4BB81C4F02AFC48DC8B2EB005A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>through—</text> <subclause id="HFF5E81B6FCBE45CEA0154A3804384FA4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>common internet protocols, such as the Cloud; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF2ECF25919BA47A395E87F7556EE2947"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other emerging technologies that satisfy the intent of this section.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE24193097FC482794FEE288B0233368" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting research and development to modernize geographically specific warnings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD44A3E2E897245048B8670CF16F5D3C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H81A822C5DEBD40BDA0F24CAD78C872D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>upgrade telecommunications infrastructure of NOAA Weather Radio to accelerate the transition of broadcasts to internet protocol-based communications over non-copper media;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D8C95476EE849D1A7E19395BB014CC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accelerate software upgrades to the Advanced Weather Interactive Processing System, or any relevant system successors, in order to implement partial county notifications and alerts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6AD716B97504E63A47DB4F6344469DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhance accessibility and usability of data and feeds of NOAA Weather Radio with feedback from relevant stakeholders, including the private sector;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDEC8FD4203FA4A2DB9138037A56779AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>develop options, including satellite backup capability and commercial provider partnerships, for continuity of service of NOAA Weather Radio in the event of an outage at a weather forecast office;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93B25B5B97E648ECA03FC59D68AC856F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>research and develop alternative options, including microwave capabilities, to transmit NOAA Weather Radio signals to transmitters that are remote or do not have internet protocol capability;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB40EC2310DF54910B11D4F567938FB4F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>transition critical applications to the Integrated Dissemination Program, or any relevant program successors; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E36939A9BBA4DA28E9FD3F55B167744"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with the General Services Administration, and other relevant agencies, to develop new, alternative, or updated expedited mechanisms to secure priority space capacity, such as leased land and tower space, for NOAA Weather Radio critical infrastructure, including transmitters and antennas, that are best suited for the national security and public safety missions of NOAA Weather Radio.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5116048E22DD442F89812B7D2BE924DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall prioritize practices, capabilities, and technologies recommended in accordance with the assessment under subsection (d) to maximize the accessibility of NOAA Weather Radio, particularly in areas of the United States described in subparagraph (D)(i) of such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2199CBF758E64D5BB4D48B76BC530872"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Assessment for management and distribution</header> <paragraph id="H999A3DA6630749D5923FAC6E4B8E18F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary shall complete an assessment of access to NOAA Weather Radio.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40F9906B471A4BC786F45F47863027A8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In conducting the assessment required under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall take into consideration and provide to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate recommendations regarding the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFED10F09A4844B368A5FBF3271DE8592" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Input from relevant stakeholders within the weather enterprise, including third-party platforms that provide online services, such as websites and mobile device applications.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0980BC167430411EB329E9F1E539BE05" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The manner by which existing or new National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration management systems may promote consistent, efficient, and compatible access to NOAA Weather Radio.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFAAE39EE5A1E4C1F8727EFCEC6780417" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The ability of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to aggregate real-time broadcast feeds at one or more central locations, as a redundancy to the broadcast feed from the nearest weather forecast office.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6769484F8FC543D5AAA55DB43B2A9BB8" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Effective coordination between agencies with responsibilities relating to emergencies and natural disasters.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD228D64374874FC08D6AFAC3DE3A6454" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The potential effects of an electromagnetic pulse or geomagnetic disturbance on NOAA Weather Radio.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBE0D8962F47C4C848521A29ABDB39CBA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3F31726978994286A53ECA9EA34B14BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Geological hazard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>geological hazard</quote> means a tsunami, forest fire, mudflow, volcanic eruption, volcanic ash, landslide, geomagnetic storm, or other similar such hazard. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1D4649AD8E74E92BADC564DDD56D612"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Short-fuse warning</header><text>The term <quote>short-fuse warning</quote> means a warning relating to a tornado, severe thunderstorm, or flash flood.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE316550450D4D458E5079E39A274647"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Under Secretary—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAC9805DBD9C642138B84C70961DDAF30" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, $20,000,000 to operate NOAA Weather Radio under subsections (a) and (b); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H407FD17733AC4AD1B307458321DD7224" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2026, $100,000,000, which shall remain available until expended, to carry out subsections (c) and (d).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC40C9B1A425B49EA87B0BE6626663D12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Weather ready all hazards award program</header><text>Section 407 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8546">15 U.S.C. 8546</external-xref>) is—</text> <paragraph id="H17B24589704A40C7921E499F6D4C8EDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transferred to title VII of such Act, as added by subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63B0490F513E44B081D08EA203939B36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>inserted after section 701 of such Act, as added by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E54B5F0F5124373AAC106A89474DFAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>redesignated as section 702.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H22F4CAC30DC2443A83BE5587BEBEF0D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents for the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H73C813D943BC4E7FBD1F0ABE8192143A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the item relating to section 407; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA916365B0C2547029380DCF75C124C62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new items:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H92DE496CBAA447D1BF031F948D7F3A76" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="title">Title VII—NOAA Weather Radio</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 701. NOAA Weather Radio.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 702. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Weather Ready All Hazards Award Program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5E3EFFD5B5A144CFB12AC5DE67EE2E70"><enum>3.</enum><header>National standards for weather warning systems in flash flood zones</header> <subsection id="H1AF9741A14F44071AC9C169CA82BE33A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology, in consultation with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, may support the development of standards for flash flood emergency alert systems with respect to a 100-year floodplain (as such term is defined in section 100202(a) of the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4004">42 U.S.C. 4004(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H472E28F108C64C9A9C73F120E2929889" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology supports the development of standards under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall ensure that such standards—</text> <paragraph id="HEDDCAF54CA22459EAEA34D041F46064A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>meet the needs of communities without—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9DF69926CEC643D38A848CB3FB4C0271" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>broadband internet access service (as such term is defined in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation)) and as depicted by a map created pursuant to section 802(c)(1)(C) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/642">47 U.S.C. 642(c)(1)(C)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60B5A107E7724515934A9F4092B501C9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State or local emergency warning systems; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B8B37C6A25B422FB53D552DBA3DBF34" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>satellite coverage; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE6B79CE918C4539A5E9DC8AC87E7187" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>will result in reliable flash flood emergency alert systems with respect to a 100-year floodplain referred to in subsection (a), especially during hazardous events.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H53A8A1F4258D458A8D5DCDA8612975DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology supports the development of standards under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall, not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that includes a summary of such standards.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H593758F4CE834E7DB39BF81692FA31E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Classification of and staffing plan for employees</header> <subsection id="H62CF184009CF4FB2860F014E52A384A7" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title IV of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8541">15 U.S.C. 8541 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 406 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H29A16F912C764C548DA3387DF335F385" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7038A87510D7472B9D67459A4757DA09" commented="no"><enum>407.</enum><header>Classification of and staffing plan for employees</header> 
<subsection id="H8E586752EE3740AFBB1DDF6CECF59672" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Classification of certain employees</header> 
<paragraph id="HF96B8B7B80AC40F291A2B0B9A796DA11" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary shall coordinate with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to categorize each position in the National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Administration specified in paragraph (2) as a protective service occupation under the Standard Occupational Classification System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40BF968AE592401AA0EC53CDD92A94D5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Positions specified</header><text>The positions specified in this paragraph are the following occupational positions in the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, as defined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6015ADDD5446496BB6B420FAD164946A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Meteorology Series (1340).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA542393EB6D94C2A9702FC412EA50045" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Hydrology Series (1315).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C004338CF8C4D458BCA286871E6B116" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>General Physical Science Series (1301).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H642BB28496AD4AEE9DFA37440781D60D" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Electronics Technical Series (0856).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD87E574832C04BEB93CA323C73FC5EA1" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Information Technology Management Series (GS–2210).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCE766E49CDA464B95EE8D7292822416" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements relating to staffing changes</header><text>The Under Secretary may not carry out any staffing change in any of the occupational positions specified in paragraph (2) unless—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H45C36DC8353340A8B263FE1F1D9F46DE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a period of 30 days has passed after the receipt by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate of a report by the Under Secretary containing a description of the staffing change proposed to be taken and the facts and circumstances relied upon in support of such staffing change; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F29078D37824975A7BE993C805DC71E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each such committee before the expiration of such period has transmitted to the Under Secretary written notice to the effect that such committee has no objection to such proposed staffing change.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2476D86472FB4AA2B435C999ACECB6D2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Five-year staffing plan for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary shall submit to Congress a five-year staffing plan for—</text> <paragraph id="H752E5EDC7562454DA4FB4957639A488F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Weather Service; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B01A4AEFE3245B0B9C1D91566D02856" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any positions within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that support forecasts and warnings to protect human life and property, including positions that involve—</text> <subparagraph id="H96F53B9311A34794893AF0B992773C79" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collection of data for incorporation into watches and warnings;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H617E752507954AC7A4AB81E6D2EDE87D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operation and maintenance of equipment for collection of data described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDCFBE9CF6BE400684F2A1E50B49C806" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintenance of information technology systems;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4780BD71806246EF99D1EF6D34840111" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>modeling for forecasts and warnings; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD65802C839A423EB49E439F5935B022" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>research to improve forecasts, warnings, and communication of such warnings to better protect human life and property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA266CC2CBFA64F6A94C1B0CD963379F4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 406 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H3A09C24736274ED392BAECB00D30E64D" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 407. Classification of and staffing plan for employee.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H39D8C439D2E2493C8661CE6FF52908D6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Staffing for positions of public safety at the National Weather Service</header> <subsection id="H3DE71CEBC35840F499F43387C9E001C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header> <paragraph id="H62661C91510D4EA4B08DB190A08F294F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Weather Service shall submit to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate an assessment of the critical staffing needs of the National Weather Service, including the needs of every Weather Forecast Office and every Center Weather Service Unit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CFAC28436C244F2BAC3D942048C6837"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment under paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</text> <subparagraph id="H0A96699481214DB5A3B418C6F0F3D12F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number and corresponding occupational series of employees needed to fully staff each Weather Forecast Office and Center Weather Service Unit of the National Weather Service that maximize efficiency while considering the following:</text> 
<clause id="H6A008C1C9A3643CD9680F5203EC05197" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Safety.</text></clause> <clause id="H64F39F4698804EB896C9FCA199BA40F0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Morale.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDC5BE4B206BF412BB013D852680A8C64" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Changing seasonal needs.</text></clause> <clause id="HE7D4D4DC31D44F74982026FCEF3522CF" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Forecasting complexity of the geographical area at issue.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17A3B96F4853499CB0CE9669FBC0F7CE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Historical staffing needs versus historical vacancies for each such Weather Forecast Office and Center Weather Service Unit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H548B608571D74EE1844ABD804AD95AE7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct hire authority</header> <paragraph id="H0F239E4204F74E998E9670253FA3D781"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Weather Service may appoint, without regard to sections 3308 through 3319, 3327, and 3330 of title 5, United States Code, qualified candidates to any of the following positions to satisfy critical staffing needs and fill vacancies determined in accordance with the assessment under subsection (a):</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE3250B2B7FD47EA8CC4B48CB96A8639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Employees performing public safety mission functions, including the following:</text> <clause id="H730BA190D0B74BD0992951223D855EE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Meteorologists (classification series 1340).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H24E008275F3C4E5E9B7D10740EBE51F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Hydrologists (classification series 1315).</text></clause> <clause id="H3358B597BF674E5A9D9BB400236A1EFD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>General physical scientists (classification series 1301).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4671748CF0A94FF292AD2BFC883349F1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Computer specialists (classification series 2210).</text></clause> <clause id="H63A975151A38460886E5C6A9B4D20499" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Electronic technicians (classification series 0856).</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F7FDDA5304F41A8A71A334DAF002FF9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Other positions for which primary responsibilities include equipment operations, maintenance, analysis, information technology, or engineering.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86B7287DADFC487CBC1CBF6DAA87FCF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under paragraph (1) shall expire on the date on which all positions to satisfy critical staffing needs and vacancies under such paragraph have been filled.</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>


