<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD2C9B9969BC14D9ABC7E103F1743E02B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8617 IH: American Family Cost-of-Living Relief Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8617</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require an agency to prepare a household cost impact analysis before publishing a proposed and final rule, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFC4CA430B3574A43A4F5F20F42A9046C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7BF940F294CD4A9780E0BCB65C202966" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Family Cost-of-Living Relief Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H38754DFFB8A04DFCA4B892AB9115D08F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Evaluation of impacts of proposed rules on household costs</header> <subsection id="H4DEAE11760BA4828A56756A2BB47D485"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule making impact on household costs</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">Chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/553">section 553</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD9121DB7378740E48BDCB9620E8FF7B3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H4945EF42FA2E48AC97BF710224BFC1EB"><enum>553a.</enum><header>Impact of rule making on household costs</header> 
<subsection id="HAF9D6E59C62A4992A0009D8313B6BAFE"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever an agency is required by section 553 of this title, or any other law, to publish general notice of proposed rule making for any proposed rule, the agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="H397A2FDAB1D8472A8349462280DEC63A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare an initial household cost impact analysis for such rule that contains—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE5E541844D2E4DE39CDA9117DBEFB073" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a statement about whether a proposed rule would substantially increase household costs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70CECD3173584A21B9F6C745AAF7479C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how such increase would affect a household based on the income level of such household;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96CB437D389641C4B9AFDDF7152087B8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of any categories of goods or services that may be affected by such increase; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83C0ACCE03864809A3F38D15994F8FFD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for an alternative rule that would not substantially increase household costs; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BE1B5C48E3A432EBA6D89C978A2909A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such analysis available for public comment by publishing such analysis in the Federal Register at the time of the publication of such general notice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBA15407873C74A0892C592F01FE945A0"><enum>(b)</enum><text>After notice and receipt of public comments, or a hearing pursuant to section 553, an agency shall prepare a final household cost impact analysis that contains—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDEBF7EFEB98A421D91B9BBCE63B501B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the information required under subsection (a)(1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDDCCC5C0F3C4F398A5AFBCC79A03FE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of any significant issues raised by public comments or a hearing in response to the initial household cost impact analysis prepared under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H117221C0EAA74D5BB09FDFE089BF5B2A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how any such public comments or hearing impacted the analysis of whether the proposed rule would substantially increase household costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8911C44FEE84D44A90743C09222A9B9"> <enum>(c)</enum> <text>An agency may not promulgate a final rule, if the agency determines, after preparing a final household cost analysis required under subsection (b), that such rule would substantially increase household costs unless—</text>
                            <paragraph id="H49224F2BE29F46148AE9CB0C32EDED94">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the rule is required by law; or</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B0B5908D9DE412B9AB97EF7B01DF0D8"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>such agency—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="HD4CE41A912BC44AC878C13C6B76B1C36">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines the rule is necessary to address—</text>
                                    <clause id="H8FBC1711A37A45BFBB2CF914C443A934">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>an imminent threat to national security;</text> </clause> <clause id="H9440013851C045DF97D132F47A40FEA7"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>); or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="HFC9D20A0270F450894A339614CC393F5">
                                        <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>an emergency declared by the President under section 502 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>); and</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H0751053D8B7B4633B91F0CDA719B4619">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submits a certification to the House of Representatives and the Senate of such imminent threat.</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B88459F994647FB8BA1BC82370A9BF4"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any final household cost impact analysis prepared pursuant to subsection (b) shall be published in the Federal Register when an agency promulgates a final rule under section 553.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB9B1805F8B584B09979044844EC3915E"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any rules finalized pursuant to subsection (c)(2) may remain in effect for not more than 1 year, unless such rule is subsequently authorized by law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D20BFE30B494CA7AE62F29BB7CD2492"><enum>(f)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall review and publish a report in the Federal Register on any major rules in effect including—</text> <paragraph id="HE0D4FD6A1431495FBE6CFDF6F131A77A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying any such major rules that have substantially increased household costs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBD251D31F794E17922CBE9F4A83595E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making any recommendations to amend or repeal such major rules for the purpose of addressing such increase to household costs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27ED43D19F5349E487340E17288D964A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making any recommendations for legislative action for the purpose of addressing such increase to household costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F1A226D5DBC45C490845A3EE5596C71"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H072F3DE6381A452797BB7A08F911109F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83C360194CC74D97A5476000C48EDBF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>household cost</term> means the average annual out-of-pocket expenditures incurred by a household for basic goods and services necessary for living, including direct and indirect costs related to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF62A4DB30AAA45EB830C2847EAE225CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing, including rent, mortgage payments, homeowner’s insurance, renter’s insurance, maintenance, and homebuilding;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2213DF7019694A2BB77C1D032CEC3DC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilities, including electric, natural gas, water, sewer, and trash collection;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2DBBD559412424D96EB877D692F5C50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transportation, including vehicle purchase or lease, fuel, insurance, maintenance, and public transportation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H353F312CB55B47B7ADE16FC54B4EF3A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>food, including raw, cooked, processed, or prepared food, infant formula, or any substance to provide nutrients through human consumption;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71B3335C255A4A70A711AD2E5EBD974A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>health care, including insurance premiums, deductibles, copayments, prescription drugs, medical devices, over-the-counter medicine, and medical services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E330F919DCF4DFF84DC7485B3005740"><enum>(F)</enum><text>child care, elder care, and dependent care required to maintain employment or household activities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6D40F6E7FE94B68B1CB744106DABC94"><enum>(G)</enum><text>expenses related to education and workforce, including tuition, fees, supplies, and required training or credentialing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71A045CE7DD742C99723422BF9186C09"><enum>(H)</enum><text>household products, including furniture, appliances, cleaning supplies, paper goods, hygiene products, kitchen items, and tools from home upkeep;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H774B804E56474AEA96ADC98B767BF931"><enum>(I)</enum><text>taxes, fees, and mandatory charges imposed directly or indirectly on households under Federal law; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H58E5DD1616E64E128697B23D0BC4648C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other essential goods or services that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget determines materially affects the cost of living for households.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40BB191A2D2B4C129D0F0359AE350A0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>household</term> means any individual or group of individuals who are living together as one economic unit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71795C99081945ADA1D877C3AFC7764D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>major rule</term> has the meaning given such term in section 804.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50C1EF27FE1940C4A6B8C2CC0F366EDC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rule</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9C34F14AEB24D499969E0368D8FDB8A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>substantially increase</term> with respect to household costs, means an increase of $50 or more a year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H49873C7141594BBDBED0E9D1E57EF060" commented="no"><enum>553b.</enum><header>Judicial review</header> <subsection id="H6C4DFB803C354D66B4E7BC52FC9692F4" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any rule subject to section 553a, any household that is adversely affected or aggrieved by final agency action is entitled to judicial review of agency compliance with the requirements of such section in accordance with chapter 7.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB00641395B264011AD27B54571CB4280" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each court having jurisdiction to review such rule for compliance with section 553, or under any other provision of law, shall have jurisdiction to review any claims of noncompliance with section 553a in accordance with chapter 7.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H8E550E206B7E4EE0A07959B75FD989A4" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The term <term>household</term> has the meaning given such term in section 553a.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3FFFD6FAE53428BA22C7C556C86C593"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall issue guidance to the head of each agency on complying with the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H296C8C8BDBC64A7EB9B469D3E2591B63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall apply to rules proposed on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

