<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM26146-HX4-R0-7JC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4431 IS: Time for Completion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4431</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for comprehensive student achievement information.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2B5D3082F2984452BC99A9598F2ABA3E"><section section-type="section-one" id="H186FD44210704D88B687F4421A8DB770"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Time for Completion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H86E554BB17764027994219EB3341A92B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer information about completion or graduation times</header><subsection id="H48EF44F35375409EB9143A14353B92E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transparency in college tuition for consumers</header><text>Subparagraph (J) of section 132(i)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015a">20 U.S.C. 1015a(i)(1)(J)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12E77B5600944919B9CFE9CA0622EF1C"><subparagraph id="HDECE226E01444016A147D7DE32134A67"><enum>(J)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9C40478820224074B981456061AE1CC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For programs of study 4 years of length or longer—</text><subclause id="HA9D7B48B3ADF49ACB3CE6D1F9717EAEA" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (iii);</text></subclause><subclause id="H2A0FE51DFF8B4066AB49A8F9A512ACA3" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (iii);</text></subclause><subclause id="H988C95DD355C47C88929A11EFB5FE8F2" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (iii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H86F5073266C84665AB56990403F08D70" indent="up1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (iii).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCE323005E3E3475193051AA3C9B31F8D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For programs of study less than 4 years—</text><subclause id="H2D13CD2AABA8466F93409BE8E6D481D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iii);</text></subclause><subclause id="HD803AC6761AD46C4BE09C401039EECFD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentages of first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iii);</text></subclause><subclause id="H636E1231A474434495A942D77076C49C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first-time, full-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE76F1C999FE94D29B32A3BFEFAE92E46"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the percentages of non-first-time, part-time, degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who obtain a degree or certificate within each of the times for completion or graduation described in subclauses (I) through (IV) of clause (iii).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6A88D9DBD4814F29892531DC6077286F" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the times for completion or graduation are as follows:</text><subclause id="H9B95F38FD64F4E598BD33D4D76EBD6FB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7C223C6B52154F3180D42F2395D88D2D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>150 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5A03DDCECA8E4E40A3D89E99292CF98C"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">200 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program.</text></subclause><subclause id="HB1F9611A7C12479AA59C8F878FFCBD8E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>300 percent of the normal time for completion of, or graduation from, the student’s program.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4B726FC46A394395B0FD7E6D70A8CFE9" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>In making publicly available the percentages described in this subparagraph, the Secretary shall display each percentage in a consistent manner and with equal visibility.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2C3A6175F53C454AABB79BC3AB678D4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Institutional and financial assistance information for students</header><text>Section 485(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H485C402D5F6440EC8362D6E660F9D323"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking subparagraph (L) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3F8ABDA658245B2B17A85B477BE414E"><subparagraph id="H4E1675F3DEC34066A91765EA4F76CD51" indent="up1"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each completion or graduation rate for each type of student and program described in clauses (i) and (ii) of section 132(i)(1)(J);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA03053A44E34A6CA23A595792C47EE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (3), by striking <quote>within 150 percent of the normal time for completion of or graduation from the program</quote> and inserting <quote>within the time for completion or graduation described in section 132(i)(1)(J) applicable to such student and such program</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

