<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD672C027C95841A9B11822460C2BE55F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7160 IH: First Home Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7160</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260120">January 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish the first-time homebuyer refundable tax credit.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCB9CB9C20E9E41179B729CCBF672FBCD" style="OLC"><section id="HBEE4C8E6950544728B2644D11F49958A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Home Affordability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H64C8CF52C94949B1A05E54A9D06B6FC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>First-time homebuyer refundable tax credit</header><subsection id="H1DE642E73E3B430087040CE8E8CC535A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36">Section 36</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F2E4804B0DC44FCBF02AF5EB4732051"><section id="H9C5F3BDE16B74F0C943837114606BE05"><enum>36.</enum><header>First-time homebuyer credit</header><subsection id="H397A6FB61B6F44F0BA69E6538134D2B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle a credit in an amount equal to the applicable credit amount for the taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4F691072E87445FE867AF54941A22C22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the term <quote>eligible individual</quote> means, with respect to any taxable year, an individual who is a first-time homebuyer with respect to the purchase of a principal residence in the United States during such taxable year or any of the 4 preceding taxable years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H95483E76D75C4AA8B8F3B7A36AF6D8DB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable credit amount</header><paragraph id="HE50AAE45E89243539EF6F49B99C8616D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), the term <quote>applicable amount</quote> means, with respect to any taxable year which occurs during the credit period of an eligible individual, an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H71CA11A5C3A249D6827D211D197ABC2A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>10 percent of the purchase price of the primary residence described in subsection (b), divided by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E7CBF01C9FB4AE3A27721E04D51A7E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62A0EBB4369C451CBDE9DC077AB6DBFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dollar limitation</header><subparagraph id="H3183D53C8E2B426AB97493D2073F257B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this paragraph, the aggregate amount of all credits allowed to any taxpayer allowed with respect to a single purchase of a primary residence shall not exceed $25,000.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E983E6602AF43B3BE785D04D507608E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Married individuals filing separately</header><text>In the case of a married individual filing a separate return, subparagraph (A) shall be applied by substituting <quote>$12,500</quote> for <quote>$25,000</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A27EE50F48C46009E9F7F8F9CFE8BBE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Other individuals</header><text>If 2 or more individuals who are not married purchase a principal residence, the amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) shall be allocated among such individuals in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe, except that the aggregate amount of the credits allowed to all such individuals with respect to such purchase during the credit period with respect to such purchase shall not exceed $25,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA31CDCA6E7264CEA9A2ACA8450AF512D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Phaseout based on area median income</header><subparagraph id="H63027EE7099F4FC5A2D035522C4EC9DA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount allowable as a credit under subsection (a) (determined without regard to this paragraph) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount which is so allowable as—</text><clause id="HE6874BA46F6440DDB7CC92CF09FE9F08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><subclause id="HE352C530EBDD44F0A422929C128957F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the modified adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the taxable year in which the taxpayer makes the purchase of the principal residence with respect to which the credit is allowed, over</text></subclause><subclause id="HAA353088343E407A9D118DE0117F485E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>150 percent of the applicable Area Medium Income, bears to</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF2A96D01F1AE494980796820BC036865"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>20 percent of the applicable Area Median Income.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA99358E44264372972574934E85D04F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modified adjusted gross income</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>modified adjusted gross income</quote> means the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for the taxable year increased by any amount excluded from gross income under section 911, 931, or 933.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1C223B40F2D4B6BBFB0B1E5CF2A4F99"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable Area Median Income</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>applicable Area Median Income</quote> means the Area Median Income set by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development with respect to—</text><clause id="H0883AD233B8F4F8F929E9036308EEABA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the area in which the principal residence is located,</text></clause><clause id="HB547E47C2C53493582D65EC83754B1E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the size of the household of the taxpayer, and</text></clause><clause id="H7138C5F6853646D8B858A5A670FF8183"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the calendar year in which the principal residence is purchased.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F0BB148FF9B44EFB6DB9F77EEEF76D9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation based on area median purchase price</header><subparagraph id="H6180AEB5C46041BAAE2DF8C2F56795AD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount allowable as a credit under subsection (a) (determined without regard to this paragraph) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the amount which bears the same ratio to the amount which is so allowable as—</text><clause id="HB98B8236253F470BA1AC0FF20D74656D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the excess (if any) of—</text><subclause id="HF0473B5751014CC8AE207001C324D949"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the purchase price of the principal residence, over</text></subclause><subclause id="H1F476B372C974EE2A99517E30D78C0E8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the amount which is equal to 110 percent of the area median purchase price, bears to</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF717085876B34FDD90AD53FC26BA924B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount which is equal to 15 percent of the area median purchase price.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE64C627EF07747D49708C8E82F9444CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Area median purchase price</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>area median purchase price</quote> means the median purchase price for a home in both the area and the calendar year in which the purchase of the principal residence takes place.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68FD13EF47A647469ACC79DE47DC29B2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, after consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall promulgate such regulations and guidance as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this subparagraph, including for determining the area median purchase price with respect to different localities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA166D67DA59E4C4C9DF04C7E03E8B032"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2025, each of the dollar amounts in paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="H62B3C8BFBBCF4E499D9A8132A9A861F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="HD9AACB3BD19745F2BF5A854D0166C9C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2024</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any increase determined under the preceding sentence shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6F6B1730A3A465185CA956C8B9EC3AD"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Age limitation</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) with respect to the purchase of any residence unless the taxpayer has attained age 18 as of the date of such purchase. In the case of any taxpayer who is married (within the meaning of section 7703), the taxpayer shall be treated as meeting the age requirement of the preceding sentence if the taxpayer or the taxpayer’s spouse meets such age requirement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DDA8D7EFD5946E89954C94A447820BA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall issue such regulations and guidance as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this subparagraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE842DEF706044C53985228FD53A2C5D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credit period</header><paragraph id="H1743584F7EC84106AD3FC07D54A065B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>credit period</quote> means, with respect to any individual, the 5 taxable year period beginning with the taxable year during which such individual makes a purchase described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H263D3A7560A94D378B26F2FADF22B700"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for teachers, childcare workers, and first responders</header><subparagraph id="HC1F0395FD8DE472AAEF7FE05073EE2DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible individual whose primary occupation during the taxable year in which such individual makes a purchase described in subsection (b) is first responder, childcare worker, or teacher—</text><clause id="H5BF62E3887D84A5A945A2FED85CB1833"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit period with respect to such purchase shall be the taxable year in which such purchase is made, and</text></clause><clause id="HD59D7468ABB04D608D28AC3401F13499"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable amount shall be 10 percent of the purchase price of the primary residence described in subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9070F9A6F44C45EDB623111BD63E761B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>First responder</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>first responder</quote> means an individual who is—</text><clause id="HAA84AD7A11B74C7DB3EDBED5175774EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement officer, firefighter, or member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew (as such terms are defined in section 1204 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968), or</text></clause><clause id="H27EC7A9FA04D47F8B4E1207F2ECAEB8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a public safety telecommunicator, including a 9–1–1 operator or dispatcher.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DC74A322C904BB3B05FB86F0074393A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Childcare worker</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>childcare worker</quote> means an individual—</text><clause id="H94BD107B3C704212B17613130F59E2EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who has a credential or a license under State law for early childhood education, and</text></clause><clause id="H00B6B25B693A4D49B071F4C71229FCD8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose primary responsibility is for the learning and development of children in an early childhood education program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A365A8FF1AE4ECABE2D1194D6042B32"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Teacher</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>teacher</quote> means an individual who—</text><clause id="H09C92CEFDEEC412987E7D5F358754061"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an elementary school or secondary school teacher who, as determined by the State or local educational agency, is a teacher of record who provides direct classroom teaching (or classroom-type teaching in a no classroom setting) to students in an elementary or secondary school, and</text></clause><clause id="HD95A4AFCC3004259AC13A10337472C19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets applicable State certification and licensure requirements, including any requirements for certification obtained through alternative routes to certification, in the State in which such school is located and in the subject area in which the individual is the teacher of record.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEAD414334C364DC195D68DCE7DBEAAC1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HAD5F03A934AF4C5D86BA1615F86DEB53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First-time homebuyer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>first-time homebuyer</quote> means any individual if such individual (and if married, such individual’s spouse)—</text><subparagraph id="H68ED4AFAB4E449A588FE7967D93CA953"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has no present ownership interest in any residence during the 3-year period ending on the date of the purchase of the principal residence to which this section applies, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE519338D9AAB453BAD21BEBA72BF43CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has not taken the credit under this section in any other taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4893E0BB29E3451E81D8ABAA931ADA69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>The term <quote>principal residence</quote> has the same meaning as when used in section 121.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BFCE2067CC94CC1833A45AAE6D057CB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Purchase</header><subparagraph id="H803B0F6FA638421D8D2AEED83D66605B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>purchase</quote> means any acquisition, but only if—</text><clause id="H458460840750442C8691FC9227E709A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the property is not acquired from a person related to the person acquiring such property (or, if married, such individual’s spouse),</text></clause><clause id="HCF95EF7B36F0486FBFD61566887D3EDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the acquisition is financed through a federally backed mortgage loan (as defined in section 4022 of the CARES Act), and</text></clause><clause id="H8CD74FBB7B284777BF260521D1CB9A81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the basis of the property in the hands of the person acquiring such property is not determined—</text><subclause id="H5CBBA53F22184E56A072617031DFF992"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in whole or in part by reference to the adjusted basis of such property in the hands of the person from whom acquired, or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA4045FBC6F964F3DABF0FF02C0A3BA2E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>under section 1014(a) (relating to property acquired from a decedent).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2013FB8051664F30B83CED854837AF40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>A residence which is constructed by the taxpayer shall be treated as purchased by the taxpayer on the date the taxpayer first occupies such residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A36B4C1D10849478B02E1C889F01C3D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Purchase price</header><text>The term <quote>purchase price</quote> means the adjusted basis of the principal residence on the date such residence is purchased.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01FA440DFABC4BA6B1ED92041049D634"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Related persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person shall be treated as related to another person if the relationship between such persons would result in the disallowance of losses under section 267 or 707(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H246A02D4195B4B8C989481B080F96119"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>No credit under subsection (a) shall be allowed to any taxpayer for any taxable year with respect to the purchase of a residence if—</text><paragraph id="H869B2BBE269542E3ABF38BB10A91BCD4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the taxpayer disposes of such residence (or such residence ceases to be the principal residence of the taxpayer (and, if married, the taxpayer's spouse)) before the close of such taxable year,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA483062DB3D24B208B61B35A070C51D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a deduction under section 151 with respect to such taxpayer is allowable to another taxpayer for such taxable year, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C5206FA0532405CA09390A76DE38DF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the taxpayer fails to attach to the return of tax for such taxable year a properly executed copy of the settlement statement used to complete such purchase.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H046705685FD348C19E535F85535C93A7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary requires information reporting under section 6045 by a person described in subsection (e)(2) thereof to verify the eligibility of taxpayers for the credit allowable by this section, the exception provided by section 6045(e)(5) shall not apply.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED0D8210BA844DA6AB98F9983192ADF6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Recapture of credit</header><paragraph id="H0BDEE3DD4F0642B5BD73DF63425DF72A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, if, during any taxable year during the credit period, a taxpayer disposes of the principal residence with respect to which a credit was allowed under subsection (a) (or such residence ceases to be the principal residence of the taxpayer), the tax imposed by this chapter for such taxable year shall be increased by the recoverable amount determined in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B322A2655D34257A2A9340885A0D394"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recoverable amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), the recoverable amount is the product of—</text><subparagraph id="H6383EF6DE0B04DEDAA29E0988900C85E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>25 percent of the amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a) in all taxable years with respect to the same purchase, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5924F10726704A5D8A7EC151C8B2467C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of taxable years remaining in the recapture period as of the beginning of the taxable year in which the taxpayer disposes of the principal residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB68A8EB29D864A0EA83DB9C7B245D14B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation based on gain</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the sale of the principal residence to a person who is not related to the taxpayer, the increase in tax determined under paragraph (1) shall not exceed the amount of gain (if any) on such sale. Solely for purposes of the preceding sentence, the adjusted basis of such residence shall be reduced by the amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAADA0DB5249D43D5ABC164D0C51D758D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="HD5B9D70CCDF54F2BACE481DD8081D07C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Death of a taxpayer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any taxable year ending after the date of the taxpayer’s death.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DCA61869FB5488399B2504079EE616B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Involuntary conversion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of a residence which is compulsorily or involuntarily converted (within the meaning of section 1033(a)) if the taxpayer acquires a new principal residence during the 2-year period beginning on the date of the disposition or cessation referred to in paragraph (1). Paragraph (1) shall apply to such new principal residence during the recapture period in the same manner as if such new principal residence were the converted residence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7933AC669286421C878465B66B9EAEE8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Transfers between spouses or incident to divorce</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a transfer of a residence to which section 1041(a) applies—</text><clause id="HBA3DCAEFFE4C402CA72A62AF63FC6629"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (1) shall not apply to such transfer, and</text></clause><clause id="H4D4D613B65004EE294912136FE741397"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of taxable years ending after such transfer, paragraph (1) shall apply to the transferee in the same manner as if such transferee were the transferor (and shall not apply to the transferor).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81A5C4D050DD43839BE724B6189C55D3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rule for members of the Armed Forces, etc</header><clause id="H138DE9D58EC74434B2ED7D46C8CE1AE7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the disposition of a principal residence by an individual (or a cessation referred to in paragraph (1)) after December 31, 2022, in connection with Government orders received by such individual, or such individual’s spouse, for qualified official extended duty service, paragraph (1) and subsection (d)(2) shall not apply to such disposition (or cessation).</text></clause><clause id="H986CF562DA874381A3FBFDB0BFEA596A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified official extended duty service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified official extended duty service</quote> means service on qualified official extended duty as—</text><subclause id="HD1A9A2947AE141B2A2D83D435872988A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a member of the uniformed services,</text></subclause><subclause id="H06E4C0F39D17423A9E9C07551189B48E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a member of the Foreign Service of the United States, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H7333463CAFE9447E9F26A556B056DC21"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an employee of the intelligence community.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H989BD451F4FB43D89F6D9C76D355E99F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any term used in this subparagraph which is also used in paragraph (9) of section 121(d) shall have the same meaning as when used in such paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H768FFD1F35A94739BDBA10B17C3633B8"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Disposition of residence in connection with change of employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the disposition of a principal residence by an individual (or a cessation referred to in paragraph (1)) after December 31, 2022, in connection with a change of employment which meets the conditions described in section 217(c), paragraph (1) shall not apply to such disposition (or cessation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27E9E71E11EA4BA288ACBE17CBFC79D1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Joint returns</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a credit allowed under subsection (a) with respect to a joint return, half of such credit shall be treated as having been allowed to each individual filing such return for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H238DC9823C8640D69EFB11DFD4601ECA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Return requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year is increased under this subsection, the taxpayer shall, notwithstanding section 6012, be required to file a return with respect to the taxes imposed under this subtitle.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEAEC27F1814F49C083C300B6C02DB324"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Transfer of credit</header><paragraph id="H61FE76D710C54F7494A30A7396AF7559"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to such regulations and other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary, a taxpayer may elect that the credit which would (but for this subsection) be allowed to such taxpayer with respect to the purchase of a principal residence in the taxable year in which the taxpayer makes such purchase shall be allowed to the mortgage lender with respect to such purchase and not to such taxpayer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA455CE6BE9DC41A8B4C015A2706405C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means, with respect to the purchase of the principal residence for which the credit is allowed under subsection (a), the mortgage lender which provides the mortgage to the taxpayer and has—</text><subparagraph id="HD08DA2E314F645F9850B8A91097C507E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>registered with the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph, at such time, and in such form and manner, as the Secretary may prescribe,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9016290E75A14379B288B297D4ADB135"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prior to the election described in paragraph (1) and not later than at the time of such purchase, disclosed to the taxpayer making such purchase—</text><clause id="HA2E598F717A1406A9D46FAF509837BC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the value of the credit allowed under subsection (a), and</text></clause><clause id="H5D7C22B2285444C0A5CED65665277D21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount provided by the mortgage lender to such taxpayer as a condition of the election described in paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7BBED52307D4BE4A656BECD543FE64B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than at the time of such purchase, made payment to such taxpayer (whether in cash or in the form of a partial payment or down payment for the purchase of such principal residence) in an amount equal to the credit otherwise allowable to such taxpayer, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2758F1DEE7C48CD9CF455A4C6C6C486"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any incentive otherwise available for taking a mortgage for which a credit is allowed under this section, including any incentive in the form of a rebate or discount provided by the mortgage lender, ensured that—</text><clause id="H5D9B493D9E4C4F749B526B55498746D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability or use of such incentive shall not limit the ability of a taxpayer to make an election described in paragraph (1), and</text></clause><clause id="H1113729BB55341D88AFA68429D4A3F4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such election shall not limit the value or use of such incentive.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD523638B98C64D3AA715032E8112EB61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>An election described in paragraph (1) shall be made by the taxpayer not later than the date on which the purchase of the principal residence with respect to which the credit under subsection (a) is allowed is made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB67C05962FEA4CA19833337C61669C2A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revocation of registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon determination by the Secretary that a mortgage lender has failed to comply with the requirements described in paragraph (2), the Secretary may revoke the registration (as described in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph) of such mortgage lender.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BC7CB2252C34395BAF65B0B9E1396DF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tax treatment of payments</header><text>With respect to any payment described in paragraph (2)(C), such payment—</text><subparagraph id="HE2E2373BD14249278F3F82C338CBB90B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be includible in the gross income of the taxpayer, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B9253C1119443769611DAA3D2561066"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the mortgage lender, shall not be deductible under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACCF93A85E2946F3B285FEE62C84A455"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Advance payment to mortgage lenders</header><subparagraph id="HAE7B2530BBFB4422901DE118559DE1B3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program to make advance payments to any eligible entity in an amount equal to the cumulative amount of the credits allowed under subsection (a) with respect to any mortgages issued by such entity for which an election described in paragraph (1) has been made.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H352C39204A0C4CF7A6E788FFAB4271B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excessive payments</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 6417(d)(6) shall apply for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F2F809FB79C45E98D430D89DC2BBF4B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of advance payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1324 of title 31, United States Code, the payments under subparagraph (A) shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from a credit provision referred to in subsection (b)(2) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AE55F8165B545A38B73CDE3BADF5F91"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Recapture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxpayer who has made an election described in paragraph (1) with respect to the purchase of a principal residence and received a payment described in paragraph (2)(C) from an eligible entity, such principal residence shall be treated as a principal residence with respect to which a credit was allowed under subsection (a) for purposes of subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC48D3D07EE084F1D96019B341EC08354"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain errors with respect to first-Time homebuyer tax credit treated as mathematical or clerical errors</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6213">section 6213(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>, is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (Z), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (AA) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (AA) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H469CDB3191364673AEEF4D752E5F6242"><subparagraph id="HA6A43C7FFDEA47478B086EDE2E4D8B16"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entry on a return claiming the credit under section 36 if—</text><clause id="HB52F93FB32AE4E99BBBDB251D1F339B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary obtains information from the person issuing the TIN of the taxpayer that indicates that the taxpayer does not meet the age requirement of section 36(b)(4),</text></clause><clause id="H3728E66D7489421EB389888DE999CD32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information provided to the Secretary by the taxpayer on an income tax return for at least one of the 2 preceding taxable years is inconsistent with eligibility for such credit, or</text></clause><clause id="H0520C431CFF840378CF63515B3CAFF3F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the taxpayer fails to attach to the return the form described in section 36(f)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7522093B82A449CD84ED432CDB0C15E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to principal residences purchased after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

