<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDEF64296E9F94A08967F2B5DF70EAE49" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7772 IH: Limiting Intense Glare for Highway and Two-lane Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7772</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to revise the Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards to establish a maximum allowable brightness standard for low beam headlamps on motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7A27909576584A50ABCFE995E48405BD" style="OLC"><section id="HA3DEFC638E6D4181BC836BBB889971DA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Limiting Intense Glare for Highway and Two-lane Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LIGHT Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H865BA9EB15874B9BA35F97AD60571095"><enum>2.</enum><header>Lamps, reflective devices, and associated equipment</header><subsection id="H69F8E0F3FCB540239708CC36BCCDC5C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to revise Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard Number 108 (49 C.F.R. 571.108; relating to lamps, reflective devices, and associated equipment) to establish a maximum allowable brightness standard for low beam headlamps on motor vehicles that is expressed in lumens or another appropriate (as determined by the Secretary) photometric measurement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6659E6E32B634DE587CA424C208E301F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

