<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53BE918E61974CAD813F015D08E2FA16" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7390 IH: Safely Ensuring Lives Future Deployment and Research In Vehicle Evolution Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, regarding the authority of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration over vehicles with automated driving systems to provide safety measures for such vehicles, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H365EEB57265043D4BDB421DF871C705F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H01D4360731D6402AA210838F4041F79C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HB48650EB733B424689433FAFC1E80C18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safely Ensuring Lives Future Deployment and Research In Vehicle Evolution Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SELF DRIVE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H27472F5BA28F4989A8A5BC7BA3712DAB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H01D4360731D6402AA210838F4041F79C" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7A02D4FCEB4649BE8B4971992E710E3A" level="section">Sec. 2. Purpose.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF38C0E8EDEA243F982C2D20FD9408939" level="section">Sec. 3. Updated or new motor vehicle safety requirements for vehicles with automated driving systems.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H529E5BE2850C44E58F12CC0F3B2C09B1" level="section">Sec. 4. Motor vehicle testing or evaluation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H477544C9354B43C59D04F7DD82CF04DC" level="section">Sec. 5. Make inoperative.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC06D4C4D82244AFA956A88106C80C1F1" level="section">Sec. 6. Protecting the security of connected vehicles.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7A02D4FCEB4649BE8B4971992E710E3A" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure continued United States leadership in the global automotive and autonomous driving sector, improve road safety, mobility, and accessibility, and create American jobs by creating rules and regulations that relate to the design, construction, and performance of ADS-equipped vehicles and by encouraging the testing and deployment of such vehicles.</text> </section> <section id="HF38C0E8EDEA243F982C2D20FD9408939"><enum>3.</enum><header>Updated or new motor vehicle safety requirements for vehicles with automated driving systems</header> <subsection id="H05A4C3423EDC4C8CB1CACB1EA632097A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of chapter 301 of subtitle VI of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H6361918FE33C46EA82B744E9000E4342" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H4EBDFE0B73B14F828050AABC5AB854CB"><enum>30130. </enum><header>Motor vehicle safety standards for automated driving systems</header> 
<subsection id="H51458E7EFA4C42FBA2E41CF969F35E2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<paragraph id="H5565BCE80BA9495D831A0B5FC592A38C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), in this section and sections 30103, 30112, 30122, and 30131:</text> <subparagraph id="HA7474A64A6EE4D56A9ED342A9C67781E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>ADS-dedicated vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ADS-dedicated vehicle</term> means an ADS-equipped vehicle designed to be operated exclusively by a Level 4 or Level 5 automated driving system in driverless operation under any routine or normal operating condition during any trip within the operational design domain of the vehicle.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46101E473FD54CA98F7BA13FF9306032"><enum>(B)</enum><header>ADS-equipped vehicle</header><text>The term <term>ADS-equipped vehicle</term> means any motor vehicle equipped with an automated driving system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D7C25130C6043EAB400B5F12B9C859A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Automated driving system; ADS</header><text>The terms <term>automated driving system</term> and <term>ADS</term>—</text> 
<clause id="H3BE4FB30D16B41B1904DCA752E32CD05" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mean the hardware and software that are collectively capable of performing the entire dynamic driving task on a sustained basis, regardless of whether such system is limited to a specific operational design domain; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF313D9B68E1F47A19A4F0A930B4EC507" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include only a system that meets the definition of Level 3, Level 4, or Level 5 automation.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC2A8F3309C0843448F0BE04E421A6B6A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>DDT fallback</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>DDT fallback</term> means, after a DDT performance-relevant system failure or upon the exit of an ADS-equipped vehicle from the operational design domain of that vehicle—</text> <clause id="H1E1CF00C60B74F5A874452CDD2CEE16B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the response by the in-vehicle fallback-ready user to perform the dynamic driving task or to achieve an MRC; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H44E4D43F4E954645A9B253C40E54B0BC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the response by an automated driving system to achieve an MRC.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFAE86A47FFDC47E6AFCB4A5ECDDDAE37" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>DDT performance-relevant system failure</header><text>The term <term>DDT performance-relevant system failure</term> means a malfunction in an ADS, another vehicle system, or both that prevents the ADS from reliably performing the DDT on a sustained basis.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0B55EF9A58C4314A995552034953EA7" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Dynamic driving task; DDT</header><text>The terms <term>dynamic driving task</term> and <term>DDT</term>—</text> <clause id="H6BACC450683744F9A346299E8D0B3BC9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mean all of the real-time operational and tactical function required to operate a motor vehicle in on-road traffic;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5FF4A1AFDC29471892222346A5CB887C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exclude any strategic function, such as trip scheduling and selection of a destination or waypoint; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3A3C40CCF8AD4721A9AE2076558E3536" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>include—</text> 
<subclause id="H98FC068416F0461E93C7C5794D640017" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>lateral vehicle motion control through steering;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H58682467F8C74F6CA7CDD2DB1ACA53B0" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>longitudinal motion control through acceleration and deceleration;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H892B0FFEA53347B9A768662B9C60FDB9" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>monitoring of the driving environment through object and event detection, recognition, classification, and response preparation;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1D24D72A9AFD4ADA8DF7B5F38332043D" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>object and event response execution;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCF15E5595DB24173811D3FD5AC7992EC" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text>maneuver planning; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H100EAE2F82754498ABDAE2851F736185" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhancement of conspicuity through lighting, sounding the horn, signaling, gesturing, or another indicator.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF29721937F954EF4BD2F5EB08171576E" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Fallback-ready user</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fallback-ready user</term> means a user of a motor vehicle equipped with an engaged Level 3 ADS feature who—</text> <clause id="HD4EA1678EA8B43F99760AF22A7C2E419" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is properly qualified and able to operate the vehicle; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD08EE3C449FC4FA49F9F033E73940FCD" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is receptive to an ADS-issued request to intervene and to evident DDT performance-relevant system failure in the vehicle.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85C052D18E4445D98D1E10FE116604C4" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><header>In‑vehicle fallback‑ready user</header><text>The term <term>in-vehicle fallback-ready user</term> means a fallback‑ready user who is seated in the driver’s seat.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B912C5078BB490BA46A486556F5BFDF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Level 3; Level 4; Level 5</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Level 3</term>, <quote>Level 4</quote>, and <quote>Level 5</quote> have the meaning given those terms in the April 2021 edition of the J3016 recommended practice of SAE International, <quote>Taxonomy and Definitions for Terms Related to Driving Automation Systems for On-Road Motor Vehicles</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD196A84E0BC406586950B22739384D2"><enum>(J)</enum><header>Minimal risk condition; MRC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>minimal risk condition</term> and <term>MRC</term> mean a stable, stopped condition to which an in-vehicle fallback-ready user or an ADS may bring a motor vehicle after performing the DDT fallback in order to reduce the risk of a crash when a trip cannot or should not be continued.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA43FB578B9264B46940C456BE7756F00" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><header>Operational design domain; ODD</header><text>The terms <term>operational design domain</term> and <term>ODD</term> mean the operating conditions under which an ADS, or feature thereof, is specifically designed to function, including any environmental, geographical, and time-of-day restriction, or the requisite presence or absence of certain traffic or roadway characteristics.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H409B64BEF27E40DE8FC8078DCC61FBF5" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C8C83E7DFD0460D86BCFFC92C002BD0" commented="no"><enum>(M)</enum><header>Vulnerable road user</header><text>The term <term>vulnerable road user</term>—</text> <clause id="H0E214015EEA94783834596C1AA56A691" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an individual who is present on or in close proximity to a road but is not an occupant of a motor vehicle with more than 3 wheels; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="H4EDF7A6DD62643888B777BFA224179F0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a pedestrian, bicyclist, motorcyclist, individual in a wheelchair, and a rider or occupant of any other transport vehicle that is not a motor vehicle, such as an all-terrain vehicle or tractor.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47FEE92FA97E40E2A09A0F59222C8394" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update to definitions</header> <subparagraph id="H9712BB7E82FE45E1ACB5001E6372E474" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Use of SAE International definitions</header><text>The Secretary shall use any definition set forth in April 2021 edition of the J3016 recommended practice of SAE International, <quote>Taxonomy and Definitions for Terms Related to Driving Automation Systems for On-Road Motor Vehicles</quote> for any term defined in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H713ABDD28477405BA371FDB938B5D5CC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header> 
<clause id="HF794C037C09F4E6B9A02FA73E6F86543" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which any definition for an automated driving system described in subparagraph (A) is released by SAE International, the Secretary—</text> <subclause id="H02F3186779D04D48AFBB637A4480D457" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall publish in the Federal Register a review on the clarity and objectivity of such definition; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H99B4D966DD0D41F6A22F17A95230828C" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may provide feedback to SAE International with suggestions for updates to any such definition.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H4DE2C7BCC9AD44E7ADFE83E6A8B4EB8D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use of revised standard</header> <subclause id="H278EAF9045F64E09A72B9E8A8EBBCCB2" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which SAE International revises a definition described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary, after publishing notice of the revision in the Federal Register, shall determine whether to revise any term defined in paragraph (1).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H89F8DB581F5D4687B82B118E9688096F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of decision not to adopt a revised definition</header><text>If the Secretary decides not to adopt a revised definition—</text> <item id="H45A2FCCD2A7B4CE787B5E690807F343A" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Secretary shall notify SAE International of the decision by the Secretary; and</text></item> 
<item id="H5E1D36872BC34B2F88588A229079EBF1" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the definitions described in subparagraph (A) shall remain in effect.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H2496DCCD69C1401BAECAB4333F398F71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Automated driving system requirements</header> <paragraph id="H05847A0D99734635B458B947D254E435" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H97CC234021CB4D9F9C0AF0862C222B7D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Safety case required</header><text>A manufacturer may not manufacture for sale, sell, offer for sale, introduce or deliver for introduction into interstate commerce, or import into the United States any automated driving system or ADS-equipped vehicle unless the manufacturer has developed a safety case for the automated driving system or ADS-equipped vehicle that meets the requirements described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AC67F7ADB9642D29B8159BFB4A39EB4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations and procedures</header><text>Consistent with paragraphs (3), (4), and (5), the Secretary may prescribe regulations to establish—</text> <clause id="H483324207C114D54B39B2CB107FB9C28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>objective content requirements for a safety case; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDC3AFB648C3B4C239BCFD2557CA66A5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>procedures for manufacturers to certify the completion of a safety case and provide the safety case to the Secretary upon request under section 30166.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB354F3349F624893BF8B2763EBDA9858" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Modification of ADS competencies by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe motor vehicle safety standards that define, modify, or interpret the ADS competencies described in paragraph (5).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H464D9A8526B34BBFA8C3AE3365303165" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safety standard to require safety case</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2509FA04D41449AF9342F6A1046937A4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Safety standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2027, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue a final rule that prescribes a motor vehicle safety standard under section 30111 that requires each manufacturer that manufactures for sale, sells, offers for sale, introduces or delivers for introduction in interstate commerce, or imports into the United States an ADS-equipped vehicle or an automated driving system intended for installation in a motor vehicle not originally equipped with such system to—</text> <clause id="HE20DD3F1E2B34684AFBFFDE82D5AE00A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complete a safety case described in paragraph (3) for each ADS version produced by the manufacturer that meets the requirements described in this section; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F63E09972AA42BEB30DB6E4028105D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide the safety case to the Secretary upon request under section 30166.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C49B638F2D24B2591DD09649A38BA10" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary does not meet the deadline described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that describes the reasons why the deadline was not met.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF79E719D9B71456AA464FA5DB3B3FD3D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Any motor vehicle safety standard issued under this paragraph supersedes any conflicting requirement under paragraph (1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99646E32966240A38BEFD0FD9C15E01A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for safety case</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A safety case described in paragraphs (1) and (2) shall provide claims, supported by arguments and evidence, that support the conclusion of the manufacturer that the design, construction, and performance of the automated driving system to be used in an ADS-equipped vehicle will not present an unreasonable risk of accidents, death, or injury, and shall include:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H101345296DE64D5BBF046C7D4D5AB88F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of each hardware and software element of the ADS that includes the following:</text> <clause id="HDF368D9DA28844B5BEA5224FABECA387" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Braking, steering, and computing capability.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H03BF40A37ADD4F248193F9829AB44710" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Redundancies.</text></clause> <clause id="H708201AE09F44510AC6F60B5C6D65EAF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Each capability of the suite of sensors of the ADS.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA880248C1D2A45189D4DACD5C246653D" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The integration of the ADS into the vehicle platform, including its propulsion system.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H625B9D7E3DEF428A93B8625A20C6EE07" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A complete description of the operational design domain of the ADS and how the ADS performs each element of the dynamic driving task within the ODD of the ADS. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1382DB690A7E47BA9CB702427281DBBD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each engineering methodology, including each hazard analysis used to design and assess the performance of the ADS and ensure motor vehicle safety.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E61727AF3AB4A339F165BDFA36EB748" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analysis of the safety performance of the ADS that uses the methodology described in subparagraph (C), including each competency in normal driving and crash avoidance capability and the acceptance criteria used by the manufacturer in assessing such performance.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5439755178DA47529710C1C6F566C4A8" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An explanation of how the ADS anticipates and responds to any potential crash.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H986DD5725A004B9A9EA5081CE2B6B352" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A description of any vehicle-integrated system that provides a visual or digital hazard that alerts a nearby road user when the vehicle executes or enters a minimal risk condition, including any system that automatically activates a high-conspicuity lighting pattern, transmits a digital hazard message, or both, to any connected vehicle and roadway infrastructure.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD68430416E96412D9F68E6196E70AD7C" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An explanation of how the ADS-equipped vehicle meets each competency listed in paragraph (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92FC10F27AE347B5BBC44A2A32CAA51D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>ADS competencies</header><text>The competencies described in this paragraph are the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD217B523F86C41BAA55C8C7EF0617340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An ADS can perform the entire DDT within the ODD of the ADS and is able to recognize the boundaries of its ODD.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96EBC859EE424AED94712B04D24D2BB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An ADS can detect and respond appropriately to any vulnerable road user likely to be present and in proximity to the ADS in the relevant ODD.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB7F2C4D3F23C4DF48C1E29DA5069EE0E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Level 3 ADS, the ADS has the ability to clearly and unambiguously communicate ADS status and whether a user is a fallback ready user and, during any transfer of control to the fallback-ready user, to provide sufficient lead time for the fallback-ready user to safely assume the DDT and safely maintain vehicle control until the fallback-ready user has assumed control and the transfer is completed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E39E14D66124C178C6DCF331A03A258"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a Level 4 and Level 5 ADS, the ADS has the ability to safely achieve an MRC when necessary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47654F42042949AD96C57D86A1EBDDF1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An ADS can detect the limits of the ODD of the ADS and respond appropriately when 1 or more conditions of the ODD are no longer met, whether by achieving an MRC or, in the case of a Level 3 ADS, alerting the fallback-ready user to intervene and assume control of the DDT.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1651DF18D5234E11995AA3045A8E0A62" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An ADS is can detect and respond to any object or event, including emergency vehicles, emergency personnel, and school buses likely to be present and in proximity to the ADS in the relevant ODD and relevant to any driving decision of the ADS.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09CE130B1E6540239CB3EFAB441BA0C9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An ADS can comply with any applicable State or local traffic law and any law relevant to the performance of the DDT.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A723E45E0ED4D0F99B11C1166AD76CD" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A description of a cybersecurity plan that includes the following:</text> 
<clause id="HE309BE6D332F4E709DE7B0ADCC1EDAB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A written cybersecurity policy with respect to the practices of the manufacturer to detect and respond to cyber attacks, unauthorized intrusions, and false vehicle control commands.</text> </clause> <clause id="H73A6AE7FAD7E427899FBF77521A90161" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A process to identify, assess, and mitigate reasonably foreseeable cyber risks related to motor vehicle safety from cyber attacks or unauthorized intrusions, including false and malicious vehicle control commands.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H41FFBE60507940CEA409F4D0BFE005C9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A process to take preventive and corrective action to mitigate against reasonably foreseeable cyber risks related to motor vehicle safety in an automated driving system or ADS-equipped vehicle, including incident response plans, unauthorized intrusion detection and prevention systems that safeguard key controls, systems, and procedures through testing or monitoring, and updates to such process based on changed circumstances.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4D71ABA6DFE4884AD7B90EC48913441"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than four years after enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the House Commerce on Energy and Commerce and Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation that shall include recommendations for potentially needed new standards specific to ADS and ADS-equipped vehicles that the Secretary finds necessary to promulgate under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30111">49 U.S.C. 30111</external-xref>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC511F8FDBA6646129C61759AC0BC96C5" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Manual controls</header> 
<paragraph id="H04F45A32FF5E4599B0FFE289B4D90206" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A manufacturer may not sell, offer for sale, introduce or deliver for introduction into commerce, or import into the United States any ADS-dedicated vehicle that is configured or subsequently altered to carry 1 or more occupants, unless the vehicle is equipped to—</text> <subparagraph id="H69EAACD9603B48F391CF98C65B7B9C2E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide an occupant inside of the vehicle with the means from within the vehicle to command that the ADS safely achieve an MRC; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47A6F0BC0861405D9AF373A1F93D1726" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the vehicle has achieved an MRC, allow the occupant to safely exit the vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F6730B8BD8D4DD4A15BAE85C0A76CA3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption from motor vehicle safety standards</header> <subparagraph id="H81005ED08C924728B18B2AE2B02C8392" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Manually operated controls and equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a vehicle is equipped with the system described in paragraph (1), a motor vehicle safety standard issued under section 30111 may not require the manufacturer to equip the vehicle with manually operated controls and equipment intended only to support a human driver in an ADS-dedicated vehicle. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB9D2F41274CE48F49692B0F6FC388236" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Vehicle configured to carry property</header><text>A motor vehicle safety standard issued under section 30111 may not be applied to require a manufacturer of an ADS-dedicated vehicle configured solely to carry property and not one or more occupants to comply with the standard by equipping the vehicle with manually operated controls and equipment intended only to support a human driver in an ADS-dedicated vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="HAF3EB68A250E4312923935F3D80684E8"><enum>30131.</enum><header>National Automated Vehicle Safety Data Repository</header> <subsection id="H3743CCD9560E410388CAE007C46B0E14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9CD4C7D36AED44A091513D6CFE74DCC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered crash</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered crash</term> means a crash on a publicly accessible road in the United States—</text> <subparagraph id="H58F77B5CCBBF417A9A88CF606C33CEB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that involves—</text> 
<clause id="H34602A8E2227420D88F671F95DE9BCB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a fatality;</text></clause> <clause id="H7EE9A23509434B1AB4D20F64DD0C9A94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an injury that results in a person being transported from the scene of the crash to a hospital for medical treatment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0B07441C3E5449CA92443540A8C9424E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an airbag deployment;</text></clause> <clause id="H56498F02A92F435D8C9F56AEA2D42B25"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a strike of a vulnerable road user;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H993D55ACB5424107B19F9CA0888019E6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the towing of a vehicle; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CD2347196DB4D9492955D3D9550D507"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which the automated driving system was engaged at any time during the period from 30 seconds immediately prior to the commencement of the crash through the conclusion of the crash.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H594F40F979DF4C449C7C976B28E42A13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repository</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>repository</term> means the National Automated Vehicle Safety Data Repository established pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H901ACF11A59F4C98A6C57DBBEE291825" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State transportation regulatory agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State transportation regulatory agency</term> means a department of motor vehicles, department of transportation, or equivalent State or local agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H354D1C3FCF954F76A745A6BB4081FA06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2026, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue a final rule that includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="H237A8DF3D1A045B1BE77D32555EC57F2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment of a National Automated Vehicle Safety Data Repository to receive and store data from a covered crash from manufacturers of automated driving systems and from manufacturers of ADS-equipped vehicles.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07498D391D60458AB0AD4589D0CC2C49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement, stated in objective terms, for such manufacturers to report to the Secretary for inclusion in the repository, not later than 30 days after the date on which a covered crash occurs or 10 days after the date on which a manufacturer receives notice of such crash, whichever is later, specific information known to the manufacturer about the crash that includes the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H9197658AB81143809DDF62B2CE3A2256"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The time and location.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A91F4965EAB4DB78EA515D208A09A2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each vehicle involved.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE828FC76D1BB4192AD791C8A56892ACF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether a vulnerable road user was involved.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1C526F863A74CF18549C065D4D176CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any injuries that resulted from the crash.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1F86A981BE44DA090D413CA1CA063A8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Whether any local authority investigated the crash.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE469257AD0B45DA8A98DA050EDABF4E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A summary of the circumstances surrounding the crash.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8CF6EDBAAA304ACB8C9D110616F89A38" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement for such manufacturers to submit to the Secretary on a quarterly basis, a report on the total miles traveled with the ADS engaged of the ADS-equipped vehicles of the manufacturer during the previous quarter, including the total miles traveled in revenue service during commercial operations. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A1C7A501A984C6ABA002FDF2250BADF" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A process for a relevant State transportation regulatory agency to access information from a covered crash described in paragraph (2) in a timely manner. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H637CE5D976AD470AACEE1112B4F23853"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A requirement that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7F79C3BF30824B1F9413F7575D3BF056"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any information shared with a relevant State or local transportation regulatory agency is protected by the confidential business information protections and procedures established in part 512 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, and is exempt from disclosure under sections 552(b)(3) and section 552a of title 5; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EFC24A415564C3AA4BC63919C40CA3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any such relevant State or local transportation regulatory agency is subject to the same confidential business information protections and procedures established in such part 512.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BB5FC961CB84BE399699D733D848354"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment of a system to publicly share the data collected for the repository, subject to the confidential business information protections and procedures established in part 512 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H704A83DF52814CC6BC106FE0FE9B2A43" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A requirement to minimize the duplication of information about a covered crash described in paragraph (2) and any other publicly reported data in the repository.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67CEC9D711A7429A856AA0E79D3B33B0"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement for a manufacturer to report whether an ADS-equipped vehicle involved in a covered crash was authorized to operate pursuant to section 30112(b)(10).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB534B88C8B5D43548DAEA9AAEC1DBA56" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset for quarterly mileage reports</header> <paragraph id="H30CE36E9DDC54EE690402ECB960411D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Total miles traveled</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the requirement described in subsection (b)(3) does not apply beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date on which a final rule is issued pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F560EECA8E24B73B04F529EB822707D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Standing General Order 2021–01 issued by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration does not apply to an ADS-equipped vehicle beginning on the compliance date of the final rule issued pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBEC58733248B42219A0762F4BF6D7CAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect on September 30, 2026.</text></subsection></section> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5050ABDE1CF7481B8569F1D104B8401D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subchapter II of chapter 301 of subtitle VI of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">30130. Motor vehicle safety standards for automated driving systems.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">30131. National Automated Vehicle Safety Data Repository.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76311F0DD34B4C6A826E68F2FF35C8D6" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30165(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>30130, 30131,</quote> after <quote>30127,</quote>.</text>
<quoted-block id="HB47C9AC8B1914C58A190768497AE4AA7" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="H4B352D47C5EB4B1B862029F947386308"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal preemption for automated driving systems and ads-equipped vehicles</header>
<subparagraph id="HA03D376C7C5C4D1ABCF59EACBE69AF87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a State, or political subdivision of a State, may not maintain, enforce, prescribe, or continue in effect any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law of the State, or political subdivision of the State, that—</text> <clause id="HBFD98EDFC8084405A2878E5392496B3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prohibits in whole or in part a manufacturer from manufacturing for sale, selling, offering for sale, introducing or delivering for introduction into interstate commerce, or importing into the United States any automated driving system or ADS-equipped vehicle if the manufacturer develops a safety case described in section 30130(b)(3) for the automated driving system or ADS-equipped vehicle; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H5544B216A82D44A694424D2BB1CEA59A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requires manufacturers of automated driving systems and manufacturers of ADS-equipped vehicles to report information about a covered crash to a State or a political subdivision of a State.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H012E08C1AB644A2D9A4CF37B7E97F4CD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A)—</text>
<clause id="H4A6B393F84974C60864C63EE80629430"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State may enforce a law or requirement that is identical to a law or requirement under subparagraphs (A) or (B) of section 30130(b)(1) or section 30131; and</text></clause> <clause id="H377DE0B3025F402B98200ED98826909F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>compliance with subparagraphs (A) or (B) of section 30130(b)(1) or section 30131 does not exempt a person from liability at common law.".</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H79FA7CFE64AC424BBFA1503AC3E981B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit or preempt State or local authority over:</text> <clause id="HD4C145898DBD44D2A74B978CCD492E68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>traffic laws;</text></clause>
<clause id="H8CF1D8B8D42B4E61B6BB1C7141C9AB41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>vehicle registration;</text></clause> <clause id="H610C3B1F399149068649340F1058292B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>safety and emissions inspections;</text></clause>
<clause id="HED57B6F98ADE4A5EB2A6F8B9710E0FD8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>congestion management of vehicles operating within a State or political subdivision of a State;</text></clause> <clause id="H9EC0793C550349C08BCE807E3A807AD1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>insurance;</text></clause>
<clause id="H33A021853B24414985383804DADEE0C4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>generally applicable consumer protection laws; or</text></clause> <clause id="HB6B82C83446E4F8AA71A13622E8BB712"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>environmental laws or regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H345FD52F204E4FE7807E8FD6D073F301"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prohibit a State or a political subdivision of a State from maintaining, enforcing, prescribing, or continuing in effect any law or regulation relating to the sale, distribution, repair, or service of ADS-equipped vehicles or automated driving systems, by a dealer, manufacturer, or distributor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> </section> <section id="H529E5BE2850C44E58F12CC0F3B2C09B1" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Motor vehicle testing or evaluation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 30112 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD3FEDD9B5EED46D9B6F92DF8A0397A24" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(10)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D6B88D2EF61404CAB408194D7EB7799" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC592C0C51993496785502ADF6D06454E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (C) as clauses (i) through (iii), respectively, and moving their margins 2 ems to the right;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E4C2F1B3A7446BDBF9A13897549F888" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>evaluation by a manufacturer that agrees not to sell or offer for sale the motor vehicle at the conclusion of the testing or evaluation and that prior to the date of enactment of this paragraph</quote> and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block id="H3B421E1FE915456F9C28EDB84AED949C" style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluation by—</text> <subparagraph id="H7138116AD1934731A7DB08CFF547F19D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a manufacturer that agrees not to sell or lease or offer for sale or lease the motor vehicle used for testing or evaluation at the conclusion of the testing or evaluation that—</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H24B6DC1CB9AD4DE29D8D05527515238E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H10B0722B4E2A4903A87E55745D68AD91" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE4B0957A8EEB47D3A25301C6EA7E08F0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a manufacturer of an automated driving system or ADS-equipped vehicle (as such terms are defined in section 30130(a)) or any component of such automated driving system or ADS-equipped vehicle that agrees not to sell or lease or offer for sale or lease the automated driving system, ADS-equipped vehicle, or component used for testing or evaluation at the conclusion of the testing or evaluation.</text></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9BE4E67302B4EF6878548B246F9B8EB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C2B7EB11341435DBE3E0B850414FC45"> <subsection id="H3EE0C94E975548C3B76866F6E6CF7958" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Commercial operations permitted for testing or evaluation for ads-equipped vehicles</header> <paragraph id="H5C685176427C4F009704F4606BC62A7B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization by Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may authorize a manufacturer that conducts testing or evaluation under subsection (b)(10) to undertake limited commercial operations for an ADS-equipped vehicle, including through the carrying of members of the public as passengers and transporting of freight, as part of the testing or evaluation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22598B2EC6354441B68B10FC9FD39570" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration for evaluation</header><text>Any limited commercial operation authorized by the Secretary pursuant to paragraph (1) shall consider the operational use case of the manufacturer, the objectives of the manufacturer for the testing or evaluation, and be subject to limitations established by the Secretary based on the operational use case to ensure that the testing or evaluation under this subsection does not constitute de facto deployment of non-compliant motor vehicles, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="HE85926BC0CB844C2907068D88E07A057" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable limitations (on a jurisdiction-by-jurisdiction basis) on the number of participating motor vehicles, mileage, revenue generation, or duration of deployment; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCF120539191C430395E8C78AD6CBCBB0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any additional oversight and transparency requirements determined by the Secretary consistent with the authority of the Secretary described elsewhere in this chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H477544C9354B43C59D04F7DD82CF04DC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Make inoperative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 30122(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H29E07F8E92E944FBA768FD54B5FA50CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="USC">(1) In general.</header-in-text></quote> before <quote>A manufacturer</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H525CFE390E8F4A628AABCD27DD70543D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H4069702AC1524D459AAA5C737AA0B9C7" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HCB5C1BF63E554A72806601EEA23F4A16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) does not apply in a case in which a manufacturer intentionally causes a device or element of a design relating to the performance of the dynamic driving task by a human driver to be temporarily disabled or altered in their functionality for safety reasons during the time that an automated driving system is engaged and capable of performing the entire dynamic driving task.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A87FCB343B44AD38F31EFAF95475080" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance with section <enum-in-header>30130</enum-in-header> required for exception</header><text>Any manufacturer that claims the exception described in paragraph (2) shall comply with section 30130(b). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC06D4C4D82244AFA956A88106C80C1F1" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Protecting the security of connected vehicles</header> 
<subsection id="H4A821A9C44FA451F98E0D99D49157F2E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the head of any relevant agency, shall review the implementation of the final rule Securing the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain: Connected Vehicles (90 Fed. Reg. 5360).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2BF74EA4609B4EA8B1311AC30BEB9D74" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the completion of the review described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Commerce shall provide a briefing on implementation of the final rule to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H191E62914FB74718AB69B2F2AF671E28" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code. </text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

