<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" slc-id="S1-HEN26369-95P-2H-1FD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 690 PCS: Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><calendar>Executive Calendar No. 5</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 690</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was ordered to lie over,
under the rule</action-desc></action><legis-type>EXECUTIVE RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the en bloc consideration in Executive Session of certain nominations on the Executive Calendar.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause" id="H6588ACF116D4487BB0EB832A8A483074"><section commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5A8A37B616754C00BF9B72B9E5A6BF5B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it shall be in order to move to proceed to the en bloc consideration of the following nominations on the Executive Calendar:</text><paragraph id="idbd85419217a54cd7b0ddcd88bdbfba6e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Calendar Number 615: Andrew Benson, of Maine, to be United States Attorney for the District of Maine for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb2050df44c94ac482c55ed45f1495ec"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Calendar Number 616: William Boyle, of North Carolina, to be United States Attorney for the Eastern District of North Carolina for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e209314a63c440d80f784759ad29c35"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Calendar Number 617: Kevin Holmes, of Arkansas, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Arkansas for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id448f8af1c3504423a8791a567b7bab30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Calendar Number 618: Brian David Miller, of Pennsylvania, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of Pennsylvania for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd119c01a65b741fe92b5211372383445"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Calendar Number 619: Richard Price, of Missouri, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Missouri for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida985ffad391a4698b7cf6c700b5e1bc5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Calendar Number 620: Darin Smith, of Wyoming, to be United States Attorney for the District of Wyoming for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe084787f11747b8a4f47eb566dee467"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Calendar Number 621: Gregory LoGerfo, of Massachusetts, a Career Member of the Senior Foreign Service, Class of Minister-Counselor, to be Coordinator for Counterterrorism, with the rank and status of Ambassador at Large.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1510eb7060fa4f8880654f7ccb51c5f7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Calendar Number 622: Eric Meyer, of California, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Democratic Socialist Republic of Sri Lanka.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id281f92411508408f93cd5bffc1d61cdd"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Calendar Number 623: Jennifer Wicks McNamara, of Virginia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Socialist Republic of Vietnam.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0bf51e6d71a24299aff301ab5fdef554"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Calendar Number 624: Frank Weiland, of the District of Columbia, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (International Narcotics and Law Enforcement Affairs).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ae7390896d84e00afd2d1a7fd1eaf25"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Calendar Number 648: Daniel Edwards, of North Carolina, to be an Assistant Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ada0b8df9484765a971199ec6d0d95c"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Calendar Number 649: Steven Haines, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5b6146d667743b2a433399119e18613"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Calendar Number 650: Robert Harvey, of Florida, to be a Federal Maritime Commissioner for a term expiring June 30, 2029.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd96e3958a2e34e36bd813e3de7f95eb0"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Calendar Number 652: Thomas Govan, Jr., of Alabama, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of Alabama for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idda1155f631fd4c78aecb4fe18bed64d7"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Calendar Number 653: Zachary Keller, of Louisiana, to be United States Attorney for the Western District of Louisiana for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f041ac11aaa4443b321d8d0a495f9a0"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Calendar Number 654: Ryan Raybould, of Texas, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Texas for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1080d037ebc7408fbda81521751ff2dc"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Calendar Number 664: Gregory Gilmore, of Illinois, to be United States Attorney for the Central District of Illinois for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ee3cba5baef4be684a80bb578018a8a"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Calendar Number 665: Douglas Weaver, of Maryland, to be a Member of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission for the term of 5 years expiring June 30, 2031. (Reappointment)</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6df455e698eb41669066b1e57676edca"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Calendar Number 666: Stevan Pearce, of New Mexico, to be Director of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80fbd73ad44d43a59980cf6487f93d0d"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Calendar Number 667: David LaCerte, of Louisiana, to be a Member of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission for a term expiring June 30, 2031. (Reappointment)</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f47d0c7addf481b812aecfa27dc4fb3"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Calendar Number 668: Kyle Haustveit, of North Dakota, to be Under Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe02dee86c3c4726b949bfee390650ea"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Calendar Number 675: Robert Rotter, of Iowa, to be United States Marshal for the Northern District of Iowa for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida98e8e601b3149d4b2bd2b663b1c9195"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Calendar Number 676: Daniel Satterlee, of South Dakota, to be United States Marshal for the District of South Dakota for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35f44919d9f542c0815d544f81306cf9"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Calendar Number 677: David St. Pierre, of Maine, to be United States Marshal for the District of Maine for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbbe0de80ed2e472ba8f5dca194f5eeeb"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Calendar Number 678: Brian Birdwell, of Texas, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcfde2adf8f2b4a3da9fc8746577c6695"><enum>(26)</enum><text>Calendar Number 679: Mark Ditlevson, of Minnesota, to be an Assistant Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6081cbf64cc54151adeb64b24698909a"><enum>(27)</enum><text>Calendar Number 680: Lee Lipton, of Florida, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of the Philippines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9c6c2896b8ef4042b5efcc9216cdae3f"><enum>(28)</enum><text>Calendar Number 681: William Long, of Missouri, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Iceland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida9af8353f27b487f9dfaabc7c60e6e1f"><enum>(29)</enum><text>Calendar Number 682: Jared Novelly, of Missouri, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to New Zealand, and to serve concurrently and without additional compensation as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Independent State of Samoa, the Cook Islands, and Niue.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc4fd415d2d5f4710a85693b7c9b47be3"><enum>(30)</enum><text>Calendar Number 683: Robert Sweeney, of Texas, to be United States Director of the Asian Development Bank, with the rank of Ambassador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8dacd7be73c3426d92ff9bdbd2b9d407"><enum>(31)</enum><text>Calendar Number 685: Asel Roberts, of Virginia, to be Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the United States of America to the Republic of Slovenia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id215e9e3dcb124046948185b58ac886da"><enum>(32)</enum><text>Calendar Number 686: Wesley Brooks, of Florida, to be Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0101c6cdfe714b66928453c6b03a03db"><enum>(33)</enum><text>Calendar Number 687: Frank Garcia, of Virginia, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (African Affairs).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1efdcf9006674e2a9f9932529a5c938c"><enum>(34)</enum><text>Calendar Number 688: Matthew Anderson, of Colorado, to be Deputy Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e5ce716d35e4f4f8213d3d8de56fc0e"><enum>(35)</enum><text>Calendar Number 689: Michael Graham, of Virginia, to be a Member of the National Transportation Safety Board for a term expiring December 31, 2030. (Reappointment)</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e92d30dd37048ce91a999fefb91d74f"><enum>(36)</enum><text>Calendar Number 690: Richard Kloster, of West Virginia, to be a Member of the Surface Transportation Board for a term expiring December 31, 2028.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f5e8c06422644379364402156b8c140"><enum>(37)</enum><text>Calendar Number 691: Seval Oz, of California, to be an Assistant Secretary of Transportation. (New Position)</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b225bf4ed37490ca1e66108bc743db2"><enum>(38)</enum><text>Calendar Number 692: Arvind Raman, of Indiana, to be Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a4ad3b26dcc444f9fa6a4b5c5d630f1"><enum>(39)</enum><text>Calendar Number 694: Melissa Holyoak, of Utah, to be United States Attorney for the District of Utah for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41cb5e5da1444857a56fe9d462027aef"><enum>(40)</enum><text>Calendar Number 695: Phillip Williams, Jr., of Alabama, to be United States Attorney for the Northern District of Alabama for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf9de1b70d7a4e23b12be94e91a3db4a"><enum>(41)</enum><text>Calendar Number 698: James Bishop, of North Carolina, to be United States Attorney for the Middle District of North Carolina for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id437777b976134e2aac9e47c5e5468ef4"><enum>(42)</enum><text>Calendar Number 699: Brian Barber, of Louisiana, to be United States Marshal for the Western District of Louisiana for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7904070c05840b6ade2eb92ed453e8e"><enum>(43)</enum><text>Calendar Number 700: Steven Lewis, of Missouri, to be United States Marshal for the Eastern District of Missouri for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8470d87b0f4b4c27aefbbb44d8b24ac6"><enum>(44)</enum><text>Calendar Number 701: Priscilla Lopez, of Florida, to be United States Marshal for the Southern District of Florida for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf620529f657e44e6861caeb2179dace1"><enum>(45)</enum><text>Calendar Number 711: Brian Gootkin, of Montana, to be United States Marshal for the District of Montana for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide42cab29b6694003b8547a1e72ec4326"><enum>(46)</enum><text>Calendar Number 712: James Stuart, of Minnesota, to be United States Marshal for the District of Minnesota for the term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d03cab992f74a459cd97c85f995f371"><enum>(47)</enum><text>Calendar Number 714: Yeouk Kim, of Texas, to be Representative of the United States of America to the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, with the rank and status of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id10a4e03edc7845518f6f2dfe5102b855"><enum>(48)</enum><text>Calendar Number 715: Ademola Adewale-Sadik, of New York, to be United States Director of the African Development Bank for a term of 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ed9766cc9684a01b7e53e142ebed467"><enum>(49)</enum><text>Calendar Number 716: Catherine Dillon, of Maryland, to be an Assistant Secretary of State (Educational and Cultural Affairs).</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body><endorsement><action-date>April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc> Ordered to lie over, under the rule</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

