<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H609F86F3E1C743E59BD65DBBA276D638" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7659 IH: To designate the Pride flag as an authorized flag eligible for display at units of the National Park System, to express the sense of Congress that the Pride flag should be on display at the Stonewall National Monument in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7659</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the Pride flag as an authorized flag eligible for display at units of the National Park System, to express the sense of Congress that the Pride flag should be on display at the Stonewall National Monument in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE88F73DBD0A744229A1A3A414C839E1B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H998398F845A644489A517D7017EC09B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authorization of Pride flag for display at units of the National Park System; Sense of Congress on display of Pride flag at Stonewall National Monument</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AD633C107304804853803D84BD731AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings; Purposes</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H088E6432B71842889F13DCBA0226509F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDF203540CFA34229B2D7CD9F61005109"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Stonewall National Monument in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of New York City, New York, commemorates the June 1969 uprising that occurred at the Stonewall Inn in response to a targeted police attack and longstanding discrimination against the LGBTQ community;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2F0830903064736A793E00BFBCF0425"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the uprising described in subparagraph (A) was a critical moment in the modern fight for LGBTQ rights in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBAD8369C14584DAE989592F37449C51D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on June 24, 2016, the Stonewall National Monument was established as the first national monument in the National Park System to be dedicated to the protection of LGBTQ individuals and the ongoing fight for freedom in the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H39590559A465432CB93DF583F0D7B379"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Stonewall National Monument serves as a daily reminder not only to the LGBTQ community but to all residents and visitors of New York City of the Stonewall Inn uprising in June 1969.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B6AD959427F4D53A31C941F4A065F7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H165196882F3046C695D6DE34983E4B8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to designate the Pride flag as an authorized flag eligible for display at units of the National Park System;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5562B78D2D814BCEB024404A78F2E3B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to condemn the removal of the Pride flag at Stonewall National Monument; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB819FA907CC14E5E90DDE95B52901B01"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to express the sense of Congress that the Pride flag should be restored at Stonewall National Monument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80E8F462719944EAB3DFF01961D57B54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Pride flag is designated as an authorized flag eligible for display at units of the National Park System.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB0F8591E2E743AC86C141C1C39DCC94">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Sense of Congress on the display of the Pride flag at the Stonewall National
          Monument</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that a Pride flag should be on display within the boundary of the Stonewall National Monument established in the State of New York by Presidential Proclamation 9465, as issued on June 24, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/320301">54 U.S.C. 320301</external-xref> note).</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

