<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H57591ACE0C344216B8DCD95C859B3C5C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8428 IH: Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8428</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish a mandatory antifraud and improper payment training program for Federal program administrators, to provide for the availability of such training to State and local entities administering Federally funded programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBE13DE0E556A44A78A20FB84B10C7C80" style="OLC"><section id="H928B7FAB4C9E40138393339DCFDCD636" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H35BB9F52C30D4DEF8EE5DF1A37C3E2CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of antifraud and improper payment prevention training program</header><subsection id="HF14E503755FC4969B71823E72D8C4D28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/41">Chapter 41</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H6CA06E6CEA064D93890EB28D683766E1" style="USC"><section id="H54C37F9BFBF34307AC17ADAA5712B31B"><enum>4122.</enum><header>Federal Government-wide antifraud and improper payment prevention training program</header><subsection id="HEA9EAF70C5754118A2D99DCA90E725FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall establish and maintain a Federal Government-wide program for antifraud and improper payment prevention training (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F028F5A3382462EA1F88202CEB02539"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Curriculum requirements</header><text>The Program shall include comprehensive instruction on—</text><paragraph id="H05A8E820F84C43DF9ECA7BE10523A37A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying and assessing fraud and improper payment risks in Federal programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H140903C2B7AD40D1BE6DCE99400DFA36"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementing resources, including the Government Accountability Office’s Framework for Managing Fraud Risks in Federal Programs and the Office of Management and Budget’s Circular A–123 and its applicable appendices, the Department of the Treasury’s Anti-Fraud Playbook, the National Institute of Standards and Technology Digital Identity Guidelines, and data analytics tools in agency program administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDD9666A804F438A97CDE75EEBD271DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using systems and resources maintained by the Department of the Treasury, including the Do Not Pay system established under 3354 of title 31, and any other payment, account, and payee validation programs (including government-wide antifraud data sharing programs) and services to prevent and address fraud and improper payments in Federal programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79DE6E2DB08F476092794EA5E0088FEA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reporting mechanisms for suspected fraud, waste, and abuse; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6417D37074D40A2957DB087273E2B33"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the establishment and use of internal controls designed to prevent improper payments and fraud in Federal programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3083B5EAA7C244E5B7F0E67B1E52F6B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mandatory participation</header><paragraph id="H5B34D9AC166545269FA733AA1B4F9181"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each agency shall ensure that any employee serving as a program administrator, program officer, financial administrator or manager, disbursement certifying official under section 3528 of title 31, auditing official, grants manager, or in a similar oversight capacity of Federal programs or Federal financial assistance completes the Program—</text><subparagraph id="HA8456C596F344C94AD0AE114FDAF30B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after the date of appointment to such position or, for any employee occupying such a position on the effective date of this section pursuant to section 2(c) of the Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act, within 180 days of such effective date; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF669332E9D6B4651AE5C296BC765BE65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E5E9AE47ED24CDC93F58A012C10C84E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>The Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall provide a system for certifying completion of the Program and maintaining records of such certifications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F1CD936DE8246F1BFEB1FAC7D675243"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Availability to State, local, or Tribal-Administered programs</header> <paragraph id="H2B942FD890B24D33BF92CB0473B32980"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall make the Program available to employees of State (including the District of Columbia), local (including territories of the United States), and Tribal governments who are responsible for the administration of Federally funded programs.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H766A31571AA540129F8BBB0D07DD4FBD">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Technical assistance</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide technical assistance to State, local, or Tribal entities to integrate the Program’s standards into the respective administrative frameworks of such entities.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H04D13A0204AF4D599204BFF322643F80">
                                <enum>(3)</enum>
                                <header>Optional requirement</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency may, as a condition of a Federal grant or award, require that State, local, or Tribal administrators of such funds complete the Program.</text>
                            </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDEB10E0BDB6646B1ABD66B8739DDC080"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the Federal Fraud Prevention Workforce Training Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Treasury and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, shall submit, to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, a report on the implementation of the Program, including participation rates and an assessment of the Program’s effectiveness in reducing fraud.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD93C72083BEC433382666397917DC561"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter, there is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for the Bureau of the Fiscal Service to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H442E60E263D44015A5A98B714184EEC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such subchapter is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H1729402A183240D0B7B2531C156E7DA2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">4122. Federal Government-wide antifraud and improper payment prevention training program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H345B3E83CF96478A86680E6EB265A3C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="H176DA47EC81840838A6537CB3F6AA97F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94464294C7584945B7C2F1CE7FCBB02D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the effective date described in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe such regulations as necessary to implement or administer the training program established under section 4122 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

