<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA2396FD6DDF423F89B36B1A6C48944F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7233 IH: Quick Recognition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide require officers and employees of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection engaged in law enforcement or immigration enforcement activities to wear a clearly visible and scannable QR code, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEE60963EAD534B6EB05243981E03D9E0" style="OLC"><section id="HBB7205CFCF9F4B8985D0E0AD8E9F1B23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Quick Recognition Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>QR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEE6A85EF29F24FDCA885D6B7F1004BCA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identification and verification requirements for immigration enforcement officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H120B9465658B4CFD8FA3ADA9B356B7FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HD1E0B5F7CF7B4EFBB66ABC7020E354BF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Identification and verification requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text><paragraph id="H0A3F00A4F72C465F9C364B0B3ED5F523"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall require that each officer or employee of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection who is engaged in law enforcement or immigration enforcement activities wear a scannable quick response code (commonly referred to as a <quote>QR code</quote>) on their uniform, positioned in a manner that remains clearly visible and unobscured by other clothing or equipment, that, when scanned, links to an official publicly available website of the Department of Homeland Security, which website—</text><subparagraph id="H12FBB818A3E34FCCBED4CA3932C637AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall display—</text><clause id="H886CCA452D9947B2A4C3B280BB622541"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the full name of the officer or employee;</text></clause><clause id="H5B7D9F6636634853B900F0AF84F293B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the badge number of the officer or employee;</text></clause><clause id="H2949C3EF24DD45DF9B4BEE935DEB5777"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the agency and operational unit or office of the officer or employee;</text></clause><clause id="HF9CBE95579904154B268EED3ABBC4D24"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the active status of the officer or employee, including a timestamp verification;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B6FF905F9984E16BC84ED15D2C91AA3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may display a photograph of the officer or employee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0F2AA22CBE4461598DC44E3B2B981F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may not display the home address, telephone number, or other personal contact information of the officer or employee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23A0F0BE3C254228A1D216D7C0183B53"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include a secure mechanism through which an individual may submit a complaint regarding the conduct of the officer or employee during an enforcement activity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A835429404249849CB84922FFCCD4BE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>shall make available aggregated, non-personally identifiable data on the number of complaints received regarding each officer or employee with respect to whom a complaint was submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B786F6B8A2446F5A72FB6C5C113CA16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit, replace, or preempt any other Federal, State, or local law, policy, or requirement that provides for additional transparency, accessibility, or accountability in law enforcement.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

