<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H36A1A3D217634A769104CE0450F73E0A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9088 IH: Polar Express Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9088</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to conduct a feasibility study on the establishment of a rail route linking Alaska to the North American continental rail network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H048967E9C253473E9A551BDE4F2EE17F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD24E3358D5D44F6398996AC9ACE4814B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Polar Express Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H75124CFFA34044ABA6DFC98A73BCB9F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Polar express feasibility study</header> <subsection id="H3C64710F0EC64D6DA94AC7B461468DF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall initiate a feasibility study on the establishment of a rail route linking the State of Alaska to the North American rail network in the continental United States, to be known as the <quote>Polar Express</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H84A20CECE9C047528A047F113B7E308C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the scope, contents, and methodology of the feasibility study conducted under this section, and may consult with such Federal agencies, State, Tribal, and local governments, foreign governments, and other stakeholders as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3A5570ADB2C942D79E45AE5E231997B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the feasibility study is initiated under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing the results of the feasibility study and any recommendations of the Secretary.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H01560B2F3DA348F49A7D3C22E51DC9C0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="HEC469FA5D9C648A0A572C2A53B8264A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to authorize the construction of the rail route described in subsection (a); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D6CC4E95E904100987BDF49EF329916"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to commit Federal funds for the construction of such rail route.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

