<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H92949A1979AD4454ADDE933CCD17DCA9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6244 IH: Protecting our Veterans’ Memories Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6244</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide a plot allowance for spouses and children of veterans buried in State cemeteries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5018B9588F1E4C818352E2159CA90879" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6BF97D22C9BA41BFB6C99C07D768A2F4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting our Veterans’ Memories Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE2C5DDA703904A048B8A6233ACBBCDB3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs plot allowance for spouses and children of veterans buried in State cemeteries</header><subsection id="HEDCE68781980402C85F405EBB186D57E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2303 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC36EA483524A492E8F0ED567A15DD998"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (e) as subsections (d) through (f), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFBE182DD30F434E8786B5AD21058FAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection (c):</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF22F6C31C46143E6BC387BC16EE83938"><subsection id="H75799B673CD341258C8F163D821D2C4B"><enum>(c)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4056F22F70D344D8A3B24C91C54B2211"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual described in paragraph (2) who is buried in a cemetery that is owned by a State or by an agency or political subdivision of a State, the Secretary shall pay to such State, agency, or political subdivision the sum of $525 (as increased from time to time under subsection (d)) as a plot or interment allowance for such individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA88CF2340BDC4C40B8F646D746313F76" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual described in this paragraph is a spouse, surviving spouse (which for purposes of this subsection includes a surviving spouse who had a subsequent remarriage), minor child (which for purposes of this subsection includes a child under 21 years of age, or under 23 years of age if pursuing a course of instruction at an approved educational institution), or, in the discretion of the Secretary, unmarried adult child of any of person described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), (4), or (7) of section 2402 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1FA6A11886844B7833CE6146F22E815"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as redesignated by paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subsection (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (b) and (c)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93CDB02394754CDCB6B0A76FE21C7FF0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (d)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECF261B3D5124D869301A61E66B591C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to deaths occurring on or after such date.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

