<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3BF9CB4DA4C64CC49C4F044631A1E48B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8269 IH: Consumer Labeling for Enhanced API Reporting and Legitimate Accountability for Base Entity Listings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8269</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require drug labeling to include original manufacturer and supply chain information.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9C01B30DC4DA41FF9FE5EC3C6028CF11" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC784618DA1D342A28EC5D8A40EAC8555"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Labeling for Enhanced API Reporting and Legitimate Accountability for Base Entity Listings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAR LABELS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H90F06F500FC34E78923AA44DBE2DC1D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Require drug labeling to include original manufacturer and supply chain information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 502(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/352">21 U.S.C. 352(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3E99CB8B9AF94E55B479451035568496" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H0D415681BB4F416CB6670475281FAF94"><enum>(b)</enum> 
<paragraph id="HCF7D2DE13FAF44C3AECE70598CB85E76" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If it is a finished drug product in a package form, unless it bears a label containing—</text> <subparagraph id="H058C842CA5C141C39011C4E6D956E271" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, place of business, and unique facility identifier of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor or a link, barcode, QR code, or other means to access a searchable electronic portal containing such information; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0E82A22A4A64094BA52E056607B2EB4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an accurate statement of the quantity of the contents in terms of weight, measure, or numerical count, provided that under this clause reasonable variations shall be permitted, and exemptions as to small packages shall be established, by regulations prescribed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE79812B00E9F4470B53A1A2A517A222C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If it is an active pharmaceutical ingredient, unless any accompanying label and certificate of analysis contains the name, place of business, and unique facility identifier of the original manufacturer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H10463FE55E374DF1A9E83303E3251BFF"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBD717454161242F8955F17C34A20BA9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If it is a finished drug product, unless its labeling contains the name, place of business, and unique facility identifier of—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HC8B0712B286B417D8328FCAFBE07D56E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the original manufacturer of each active pharmaceutical ingredient;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HD2EBF471313246FF849809D2FF121CBF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the original manufacturer of the finished drug product; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H01A32D23A5754081BC74588F0D15E861"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the packer or distributor, if any,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" indent="subsection">or a link, barcode, QR code, or other means to access a searchable electronic portal containing such information.</continuation-text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H4D6D3BADC10740EC9E6C5778787D5452"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a finished drug product for which there are multiple potential different manufacturers of the active pharmaceutical ingredient, the requirements of this subparagraph shall be satisfied if all such manufacturers of active pharmaceutical ingredients for the drug product are identified in the labeling or the searchable electronic portal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C774DD708B547D096253A8593E3FC9D" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A manufacturer, packer, or distributor required to furnish information under subparagraphs (1), (2), and (3), in addition to making such information available electronically, as applicable, shall make such information available through a package insert, or in paper copy to any individual who requests such a copy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H12E2E61B508541639EFC4C7AE7F1592C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>original manufacturer</term>, means the single last establishment to conduct substantial manufacturing activities prior to introduction of the active pharmaceutical ingredient or finished drug product into interstate commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="HECE672C564134AABB2CA978624A5ABEC"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue regulations to implement subparagraphs (2) and (3) and may provide for reasonable variations in the implementation of, or an alternative placement for, the labeling requirements under such subparagraphs, including by electronic means. Such regulations shall take effect on a date determined by the Secretary and not earlier than 1 year after the date of publication of the final regulations, and shall apply with respect to drugs manufactured on or after the effective date of such regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
<section id="H0490CF21780E40A4805E553D12D86D1E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption from customs country of origin marking requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1304">19 U.S.C. 1304</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49FB8500DB0B4B48AA48F74F79CC91B4"> <subsection id="H5E94C25AE4114BD197235E03A402DF03"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Marking of certain finished drug products</header><text>The marking requirements of subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to articles that are finished drug products and are marked in accordance with the requirements of section 502(b)(3)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

