<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-STR26069-66C-38-RC1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 796 IS: Recognizing the upcoming 250th anniversary of the United States of America and reaffirming the commitment of the Senate to the Nation’s founding ideals of liberty, equality, and opportunity for all immigrant communities in the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 796</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the upcoming 250th anniversary of the United States of America and reaffirming the commitment of the Senate to the Nation’s founding ideals of liberty, equality, and opportunity for all immigrant communities in the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, as the United States approaches the 250th anniversary of its founding, the people of the United States reflect on the Nation’s history, progress, and enduring commitment to the principles of liberty and justice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, despite attacks from the current Administration, the Senate reaffirms that all people are created equal in dignity and worth and are entitled to unalienable rights, including life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, when the Federal Government fails to secure these ideals, it is the responsibility of Members of Congress to challenge and transform systems that deny dignity and justice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these founding ideals have not always been fully realized and each generation bears responsibility for advancing these ideals more fully in law, policy, and practice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in recognition of the barriers and hardships faced by asylum seekers, refugees, and all immigrant communities, including conditions that undermine internationally recognized human rights and constitutional protections, the Senate must continue to advance systemic change;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the absence of consistent Federal leadership in upholding the Nation’s commitments and obligations to asylum seekers, refugees, and immigrant communities, the Senate plays a critical role in advancing inclusion, equity, and opportunity for all residents regardless of immigration status;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas barriers such as limited English proficiency, employment obstacles, and restricted access to essential services prevent many immigrants from fully engaging in the social, economic, and civic life of their communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas existing pathways to the United States, including pathways to citizenship, face increasing restrictions and adverse policy shifts, creating obstacles that undermine stability, opportunity, and full participation in communities represented by Members of the Senate;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ensuring access to health care, legal services, social services, housing, food security, education, and safe and humane migration pathways are essential components of an equitable and inclusive United States, promoting the health, safety, and well-being of communities across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas immigrant communities in the United States make significant social, cultural, economic, and civic contributions to the United States, strengthening the United States and enriching its shared future, and reflecting the enduring promise of the founding ideals of the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States of America serves not only as a celebration, but as a moment for reflection, civic participation, and renewed commitment to building a more inclusive, equitable, and united future for all who call the United States home: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id71ee4fd479b641d4b409c4697f721ccc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports efforts, consistent with this commitment, to expand and strengthen programs that assist individuals in overcoming common barriers to full participation in the social, economic, and civic life of the United States, including language access programs, workforce and employment assistance, legal support, and naturalization services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb647cc98094a48c9aaa71d92154c58e4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages collaboration with local community-based organizations, nonprofit organizations serving immigrants and refugees, faith institutions, educational institutions, advocacy groups, and labor and business partners to provide critical services and ensure that integration programs are culturally responsive, accessible, and effective;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2f07261f3b145299f8922459e7f1f0d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges Federal, State, and local governments to increase investments in initiatives that advance opportunity, strengthen communities, and uphold the Nation’s commitments to equity and inclusion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0807a6222eff4a8a8966ae33a3628393"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls for a commitment to building a more inclusive, equitable, and united future for all who call the United States home;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idefbbfa7cb6504e21af047951fc55561c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>celebrates the contributions of immigrant communities in the United States to the Nation’s social, cultural, and economic life; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9dba981d59f84c878c2b79e944a5fae0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes the significance of global solidarity in upholding the principles of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, and in advancing dignity, justice, and freedom for all people confronting systemic oppression across borders and continents.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

