<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H211DFBF6C6644DA1A9AC40B4F710E6A6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 890 IH: Expressing support for the designation of November 19, 2025, as “National GIS Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 890</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of November 19, 2025, as <quote>National GIS Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the management, use, and exchange of geographic information and geospatial data and analysis are essential for operations and decision making in Federal agencies and private enterprise;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Geographic Information System technology (referred to in this preamble as <quote>GIS</quote>) embraces new and innovative ways to use, discover, and share geospatial data through online portals and web services;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas GIS facilitates the sharing of geographic data, services, and maps within a digital domain;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas GIS helps provide shared and trusted geospatial data, services, and applications for use by—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8ECF2505A64446B6862092795D2F6220"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5047BEEB1DEB48BB909E9318D4CE2C39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>private enterprise; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1DF044041D449A38BECF2E4A85341A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>government agencies and partners of government agencies to meet their mission needs;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas GIS helps foster collaboration and partnerships in the advancement of the National Spatial Data Infrastructure (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NSDI</quote>);</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas GIS provides a common framework for the Federal Government, State, Tribal, and local governments, non-Federal partners, communities, constituents, professional bodies for standards, data catalogs, partnerships, and tools that make up the NSDI;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas GIS is used to investigate and address societal and cultural issues, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3680B37F9C394D85A04372610CDE9550"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local issues;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43BE5E9C3A3B4DE8AA04D03B59DEB2EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>global issues;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H870056F1C35E44F1B11E8848A83BDF79"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issues from the past;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H522C4C301FEB4194BAF23DBA149068C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>issues in the present; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD240F115347482A9057BA8F1EDBA585"><enum>(5)</enum><text>potential future issues identified through modeling;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas GIS professionals review, store, and manage their data in new ways thanks to technological advancements, given that high accuracy global positioning system (GPS) technology has also evolved greatly over decades;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas GIS and related geospatial technologies are used in classrooms to engage students in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) learning;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas GIS is an interdisciplinary tool used by students, teachers, researchers, universities, local institutions, and practitioners in numerous fields and disciplines;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas GIS fosters competition within the sector of geospatial technologies, which is considered a high-growth industry by the Department of Labor; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many Federal agencies, State and local government agencies, nonprofit organizations, schools, libraries, companies in private enterprise, and universities will join with others around the world to showcase their GIS mapping and geospatial applications on November 19, 2025: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H250A714109C24978B7E06D68DD131AC1"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8AB5EE57DEC14641B80CF778188E93C2"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H047BE72740EB4F279B6916D32B3BF0B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National GIS Day</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C5D112C73A54578BDE0BDB124252E0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages users of Geographic Information System technology (referred to in this resolving clause as <quote>GIS</quote>), educators, students, and innovators to continue to employ GIS to—</text> <subparagraph id="H591E4A1D471E479CB9630DC89AF5199F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>learn and explore;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09131CA7A1AE42E5877C9620F697F10F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyze and address societal challenges; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34404E6CA7A6424BB8F876C212AAB15D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>drive economic growth for the betterment of the people of the United States and individuals around the world.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

