<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAA69048296654A168EEDAB6BB6839441" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6129 IH: Bidirectional Electric Vehicle Charging Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6129</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to develop a National Electric Vehicle Bidirectional Charging Roadmap, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBE7BD8F4E0B2437390510383E9557443" style="OLC"><section id="HB9DAF9E2A1D54124A842198165ED2E96" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bidirectional Electric Vehicle Charging Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H64ACC65A84AD4363B387D867A2F06701"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Electric Vehicle Bidirectional Charging Roadmap</header><subsection id="HD27C324F457F4B1DBD881446B2C2569D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall develop a National Electric Vehicle Bidirectional Charging Roadmap that includes—</text><paragraph id="HD61B426D0C514BB3BCEE27BEA3550748"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a timeline and strategy for increasing the development and use of bidirectional charging;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09E340BB824B4021B7404B65A81AF8AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of strategies and obstacles to increasing the development and use of bidirectional charging;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04E81AA149894A419AF87A5E08F56538"><enum>(3)</enum><text>key actions for Congress to consider taking with respect to bidirectional charging matters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC66453192F343C2BBDD11BD44D6223E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>cost estimates for increasing the development and use of bidirectional charging, including a cost estimate for such an increase if such an increase were to be done at a pace that is slow, moderate, or fast.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAAD3022A770414982CE870C162649AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make available to the public, including on the public website of the Department of Energy, the National Electric Vehicle Bidirectional Charging Roadmap developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H4191AF2371FD41EE89B6F2BD8A9B3C70"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical standards and requirement for bidirectional charging</header><subsection id="H5D70C16848C344F4836DB71E5D87840A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall issue regulations—</text><paragraph id="H91063C343D584F7ABA25C2B2C69D097C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing technical standards for manufacturers of electric vehicles to standardize bidirectional charging technology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E8057B1D47E4E9A94E4FAB6E57929C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requiring that all new electric vehicles manufactured beginning in model year 2029 and thereafter be capable of bidirectional charging, including electric vehicles that are light-duty motor vehicles and school buses, except as exempted by the Secretary of Energy, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9DA318CD320347FF8C3D08D06C8C6E64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><paragraph id="H2242995961F24D5AAEF23B1A7A867C3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person that violates a regulation issued under this section is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $21,000 for each violation. A separate violation occurs for each electric vehicle or item of electric vehicle equipment and for each failure or refusal to allow or perform an act required by this section and the regulations thereunder. The maximum penalty under this subsection for a related series of violations is $105,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11FEA52B0B53412BA25320F30F5DC5DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compromise</header><subparagraph id="H35057D0BEC0340D2891EA14FE17EA2A0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Energy may compromise the amount of a civil penalty imposed under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59CA7D43E54D43F18F7F043E50FE3ECF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relevant Factors in Determining Amount of Penalty or Compromise</header><text>In determining the amount of a civil penalty or compromise under this section, the Secretary of Energy shall consider the nature, circumstances, extent, and gravity of the violation. Such determination shall include, as appropriate—</text><clause id="H0CD1D2D5B131435DBA36A7E58C5740B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the nature of the defect or noncompliance;</text></clause><clause id="H4AA19B0E1FCA4760BF2F5C3E1A2CA450"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>knowledge by the person charged of its obligations under this section;</text></clause><clause id="HE990E07542D64B5DB6AFC094CF9E46DE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of electric vehicles or items of electric vehicle equipment distributed with the defect or noncompliance;</text></clause><clause id="H88827F381FEE4F9BA958D585FE84563F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>actions taken by the person charged to identify, investigate, or mitigate the condition;</text></clause><clause id="HC732F28D5D904AC098CE861F3DFCB364"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the appropriateness of such penalty in relation to the size of the business of the person charged, including the potential for undue adverse economic impacts;</text></clause><clause id="H5789E930E9264C26B0349D9F649F5148"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>whether the person has been assessed civil penalties under this section during the most recent 5 years; and</text></clause><clause id="H04E458D638C54E04B3A835471321D56A"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other appropriate factors.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEF482BFDB3D04F7A9A74169CD06204DD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disaster recovery plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue such regulations as are necessary to require that hazard mitigation plans submitted by States or local governments under section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>) incorporate bidirectional charging capabilities.</text></section><section id="HA5640CF787AC4378A03C8E8BF0ED000A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC50BDEB7F3734ED1B8D1CA367278DB5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bidirectional charging</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>bidirectional charging</term> means, with respect to an electric vehicle, that the electric vehicle can receive energy from electric vehicle supply equipment and provide energy to an external load when it is paired with similarly capable electric vehicle supply equipment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H577B283DF86C43AD8A7D2EA3F218CCAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Electric vehicle</header><text>The term <term>electric vehicle</term> means a vehicle designed to operate exclusively on electricity stored in a rechargeable battery, multiple batteries, or battery pack.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

