<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E4764EBDBBB4408A12BDE729AF02307" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9591 IH: Extreme Temperatures Injustice in Prisons Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260706">July 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve response to, and preparation for, extreme temperatures, in Federal correctional facilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD83DCC4D350F4C3FB2132C1D50FA45D7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF4FD1BCE76784077BD3D5643DB04ABB9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Extreme Temperatures Injustice in Prisons Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H75F46F4E860841DF93199BF2AFE02746"><enum>2.</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons (hereinafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>) shall install or update, as appropriate, heating, ventilation, and air conditioning systems in each correctional facility operated by the Director, including by installing temperature reading devices in each space with a human occupant in such a facility, including each prison cell therein, and those commonly used by incarcerated individuals and staff.</text></section> 
<section id="HFE895103B11A4CBA91A036A7E7277800"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interim monitoring</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall regularly test and monitor the temperature in each space referred to in section 2 during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date that in the interim of the installation of temperature reading devices across the facilities.</text></section> <section id="HF16E11254E9A4960A4EB3D1BCC3A1ABC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Temperature standards for incarcerated individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall develop and enforce mandatory written standards for applicable to all institutions administered by the Director regarding heat stress and cold stress, as it pertains to specific institution work operations, recreational activities, and all conditions of confinement related to the prevention and management of heat-related and cold-related illnesses.</text></section> 
<section id="H29CAD9FC0AD448C7BB84CBF14FF15DBF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study and development of guidelines to protect vulnerable populations</header> 
<subsection id="H7D3DC1F764274D9A9449F19E03D61A2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2F16394891DE49369C378BE332D8A5C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>study the effect of extreme temperature conditions in correctional facilities operated by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, including the effect on the health and safety of incarcerated individuals and consideration of physical regional variations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA07D8F6EABB248DC824E1DD7CBA38DAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall develop recommendations for the Bureau of Prisons regarding safer practices.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H764CCFE5757C4804AA19D78A23172E91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development of guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with the Heat and Medication Guidance for Clinicians issued by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Director, in consultation with the Assistant Director for the Health Services Division of the Bureau of Prisons and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, shall finalize rules to establish and enforce mandatory standards to protect the medically vulnerable populations in facilities operated by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons.</text> </subsection> </section> 
<section id="H6735B3838E4A4231A6A898BE0AD272E2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Temperature standards for Bureau of Prisons staff</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall implement the use of the wet-bulb globe temperature-based NIOSH Recommended Exposure Limits and Recommended Alert Limits to account for humidity when protecting staff from the hazards posed by occupational heat exposure.</text></section> <section id="H1366DBDAA0D54229B2229427CA1BA90B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Required availability of mitigation options</header> <subsection id="H88EFF86B7E374CE19A3D319CF0D7C263"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Heat and summer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall ensure that heat mitigation options, including cold-water bottles, cooling fans, and cooling towels, are made available to inmates in all facilities operated by the Director, outside of the commissary, at no cost, upon request, and in sufficient supply when internal temperatures at correctional facilities operated by the Director reach levels determined to be dangerously high by the Director.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF18414436F4A4D48A772ED2A38115CCC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cold and winter</header><text>The Director shall ensure that cold mitigation options, including winter clothing, blankets, and other necessary thermal items are made available to inmates in all facilities operated by the Director, outside of prison commissary, at no cost, upon request, and in sufficient supply when internal temperatures at correctional facilities operated by the Director reach levels determined to be dangerously low by the Director.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H61E2A872E8BC438B90AE850BCC50A5BA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Electronic record keeping for seasonal training requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall establish an electronic record keeping system for purposes of ensuring completion of seasonal training requirements of personnel of the Bureau of Prisons on winter mitigation practices and identifying heat-related illness symptoms.</text></section> 
<section id="HA781F49844AF41CD958F0B0AA6190F9A"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report</header> 
<subsection id="H7FB9DD1E0BEC40399B4F5C561C93A8D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>On costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Director shall submit a report to Congress that sets forth the estimated cost of maintenance of the heating, ventilation, and air conditioning system of each correctional facility operated by the Director and a progress update on the installation or updating of the heating, ventilation, and air conditioning system of each correctional facility operated by the Director.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H610F20531B6D4873AD4F42338DA12C28"><enum>(b)</enum><header>On illnesses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit a report to Congress that sets forth information about temperature-related illnesses, injuries, and fatalities among vulnerable populations in facilities that the Director operates, including elderly people, pregnant people, and those with compromised immune or compromised thermoregulatory systems (including hyperthyroidism, hyperhidrosis).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H28EB90B4D5F1412BA9B67FCB1E59E984"><enum>10.</enum><header>Annual oversight</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall, each year, conduct an oversight inspection of—</text> <paragraph id="HF82E0532BDA9444687DF6AB168EBE0E8"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>each temperature reading device and each heating, ventilation, and air conditioning systems in each correctional facility operated by the Director;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27B767235A9C48F2BA1A8E9294917388">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the number of heat or cold-related illnesses, injuries, and fatalities in each such facility; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1C857E6CFB443A0AAF0948A7C8F2EAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the implementation of mitigating options in each such facility,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">and publish a report thereon.</continuation-text></section> <section id="H0E434B034A8D4B1885A976206D7EBE34"><enum>11.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031 to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to install and update Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning systems in all facilities operated by the Director.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

