<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22AD81FE3667428D8BB1B86B12EAF433" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8898 IH: End Government Pensions for Sexual Abusers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8898</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to deny Federal retirement benefits to Members of Congress convicted of sexual offenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEEFF384535F44E65A72C0704968AF2A7" style="OLC"> 
<section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="HE2E7216ECB1A40689A47C0AD2D6AD9B2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Government Pensions for Sexual Abusers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA0969A0637344F3598B7212089F5EFB4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Denial of retirement benefits for Members of Congress</header> <subsection id="H1C10D853A48B47D8B60661F6576B0575"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8312">section 8312</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B4852BF80294FC7B384011036B22559"> 
<section id="HA9A8D9C46AD34D78BC1C90909EB7D852"><enum>8312a.</enum><header>Conviction of certain offenses</header> 
<subsection id="H0AD0A4F9726043FCA0316C38B506E601"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> 
<paragraph id="HA3B05F3A2E774260ABF0233405D04ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual who is Member of Congress or former Member of Congress, or a survivor or beneficiary of such an individual, may not be paid annuity or retired pay on the basis of the service of the individual which is creditable toward the annuity or retired pay, subject to the exceptions in sections 8311(2) and (3) of this title and subsections (d) and (e) of this section, if the individual is convicted of an offense—</text> <subparagraph id="H479493A437CB48698F2B07648C580E59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within the purview of—</text> 
<clause id="H203F456B8914476FA4E04157DE99CB8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1470, 1591, 2241, 2242, 2243, 2244, 2245, 2251, 2252, 2260 of title 18;</text></clause> <clause id="HD1AE7A2C9DE746D6A6D994271630DD5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (3) or (5) of section 2244(a) of title 18; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDF8EC72C545E41A28554C1D3BCF0FC89"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>chapter 71 or 77 of title 18; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84F1B4FFDA35431DBA7F1825EF1ECD02"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which the conduct constituting the offense is committed on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>End Government Pensions for Sexual Abusers Act of 2026</short-title>, which shall include any offense that includes conduct that continued on or after such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17F061B430A44FC79890035C5F2AD501"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>If an individual entitled to an annuity or retired pay is convicted of an offense described in paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall notify the head of the agency administering the annuity or retired pay of the individual.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H123F6380A777461986B68A9789FB2248"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign offenses</header> <paragraph id="H484A720C017646A6A8C25762ADF86171"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), a conviction of an offense within the meaning of such subsection may be established if the Attorney General certifies to the agency administering the annuity or retired pay concerned—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF48C8AA2494B439CA03581379867A4CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that an individual has been convicted by an impartial court of appropriate jurisdiction within a foreign country in circumstances in which the conduct would constitute an offense described in subsection (a)(1), had such conduct taken place within the United States, and that such conviction is not being appealed or that final action has been taken on such appeal;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0787A33C0A94AEA9262108264CBA461"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that such conviction was obtained in accordance with procedures that provided the defendant due process rights comparable to such rights provided by the United States Constitution, and such conviction was based upon evidence which would have been admissible in the courts of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC460E3BA6A4C4A438ED3C0AAFA66BF22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that such conduct occurred after the date of enactment of this section, which shall include any offense that includes conduct that continued on or after such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50CAD4E49B56489F809C50D2EC3895A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any certification made pursuant to this subsection shall be subject to review by the United States Court of Federal Claims based upon the application of the individual concerned, or his or her attorney, alleging that a condition set forth in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (1), as certified by the Attorney General, has not been satisfied in his or her particular circumstances. Should the court determine that any of these conditions has not been satisfied in such case, the court shall order any annuity or retirement benefit to which the individual concerned is entitled to be restored and shall order that any payments which may have been previously denied or withheld to be paid by the department or agency concerned.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50643064A8D8450FBD8BEF4999724FA1">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Absence from the United States To avoid
                prosecution</header>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="H8FAAF727EDBF428FA688D34B177939E2">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is Member of Congress or former Member of Congress, or a survivor or beneficiary of such an individual, may not be paid annuity or retired pay on the basis of the service of the individual in any position as an officer or employee of the Federal Government which is creditable toward the annuity or retired pay, subject to the exceptions in sections 8311(2) and (3) of this title, if the individual—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H72E1F9B68BA04D84B765D02A16AF6DD2">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is under indictment for an offense described in subsection (a); and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC3505328696946BA8AB2C6E1E3C51057"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>willfully remains outside the United States, or its territories and possessions including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, for more than 1 year with knowledge of the indictment.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                id="H82419950790B49FDA028ECB1EBEB8347">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Period</header>
 <text>The prohibition on payment of annuity or retired pay under paragraph (1) applies during the period—</text>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="H496AAC19A2FD48E3837C21D0E563E4C4">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>beginning on the day after the end of the 1-year period described in paragraph (1); and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                  id="HCA474EBA507C45DFB070B6812E46C102">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>ending on the date on which—</text> <clause id="HCB0D774412564E81A32D2A3DEA0F3A01"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>a nolle prosequi to the entire indictment is entered on the record or the charges are dismissed by competent authority;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="HC677AA81EAB14977829C66CB7EA1E909">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the individual returns and thereafter the indictment or charges is or are dismissed; or</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H2C734F97726F48038F6F799706E705F1">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>after trial by court or court-martial, the accused is found not guilty of the offense or offenses.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADF2D0B29438470380FFE03011780747"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Payments to victims</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F3C06646E05499AA3F7832BA1F237DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 8346(a), section 8470(a), or any other provision of law exempting an annuity or retired pay from execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, if the annuity or retired pay of an individual is subject to forfeiture under this section, the head of the agency administering the annuity or retired pay shall pay, from amounts that would have been used to pay the annuity or retired pay, amounts to a victim of an offense described in subsection (a) committed by the individual if and to the extent payment of such amounts is expressly provided for in—</text> <subparagraph id="H7DB78EF6AC21418DABE5B5EBDA5AAFC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any court order of restitution to or similar compensation of the victim; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22DB36D4D06A4922B74892EB377E5529"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any court order or other similar process in the nature of garnishment for the enforcement of a judgment rendered against such individual relating to the offense or the course of conduct constituting the offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H058607B7B19C42589B1686BE72DFFA4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>The total amount paid to a victim under paragraph (1) shall not exceed the amount that is subject to forfeiture under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E4C5E419D274901967BE585C0B25865"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limit on refunds</header><text>Contributions and deposits by an individual whose annuity or retired pay is subject to forfeiture under this section shall not be refunded under section 8316 to the extent the amount of such contributions or deposits are paid to a victim under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1FC78BCC1ACE46689550A9C6D2466BF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonaccrual of interest on refunds</header><text>Section 8316 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF6641FA224C040CCB54C2ECA7480FDFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>under section 8312a or</quote> before <quote>because an individual</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4FF8E08E6FB4E61AF80EA47A7E77576"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5B6023215BB94200BF085AEDE46022E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA5B76833F6049A295E6207C83A09997"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF65586A50A544B718EBFA11773CFACFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BF3F54EBC7A49618DEBCF5BFBA96C13"> <paragraph id="HD0547DAD7CAC44D59B061ED6ABC8A146"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if the individual is convicted of an offense described in section 8312a(a), for the period after the conviction.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37C100D8AF8343D881D6207BA3C4D123"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8312">section 8312</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H0B771781201D4933851E6B806AE47697"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" idref="HA9A8D9C46AD34D78BC1C90909EB7D852">8312a. Conviction of certain offenses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

