<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG26150-K5J-YC-TKT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4056 IS: Proprietary Education Oversight Task Force Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4056</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260311">March 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Committee and to facilitate the disclosure and reporting of information regarding complaints and investigations related to proprietary institutions of higher education eligible to receive Federal education assistance.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Proprietary Education Oversight Task Force Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id321509fc9d5c46fba38fee8440bd3fdd"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id4851f04f77784f7396d5e77c1b7a1cb8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accrediting agency</header><text>The term <term>accrediting agency</term> means a private educational association that acts as a reliable authority on the quality of education or training provided by an institution of higher education and is recognized by the Secretary under section 496 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4feb6d6b7db4351a34434d84c8066f5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>Unless otherwise expressly provided, the term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60ddf83c80d14bd3923b09b45452a5dc"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive officer</header><text>The term <term>executive officer</term>, with respect to a proprietary institution of higher education that is a publicly traded corporation, means—</text><subparagraph id="id84fbe760d3804ad6b70e0462640a27ec"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the president of the corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaa8691b1d6c243cb8e880a870313e3fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a vice president of the corporation who is in charge of a principal business unit, division, or function of the corporation, such as sales, administration, or finance; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0e23a4b7cb14cb29d798f04fd10622a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other officer or person who performs a policy-making function for the corporation, including an executive officer of a subsidiary of the corporation if the officer performs a policy making function for the corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idda70d14c05154584bee925f7c75cc548"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal education assistance</header><text>The term <term>Federal education assistance</term> when used with respect to a proprietary institution of higher education, means Federal funds that are disbursed or delivered by the Department, the Department of Veterans Affairs, or the Department of Defense to, or on behalf of, a student to be used for tuition, fees, instruction, or any other component of the student’s cost of attendance (as defined in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>)) to attend the institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0e53a5b97acb4488afa8742687c8bec2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institutional debt</header><text>The term <term>institutional debt</term> means any debt owed by a student or the parent of a student to an institution of higher education, including—</text><subparagraph id="id29c1c99f263d4e708e0a30b73f2af846"><enum>(A)</enum><text>debt owed through a private loan program, income-share agreement, or other financing product operated by the institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida48cc1172f06484e9fdc7f396b0dce46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>debt owed from a return of student assistance made, insured, or guaranteed under title IV of the Higher Education Act 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) to the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31084bcf12764b6bb0c33c8224b1829e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>debt owed from the student’s nonpayment of institutional charges or fees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25001ac7a9a64a81980a0786dfe645b8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Private education loan</header><text>The term <term>private education loan</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id269ceeb5c45e4e55b8593da37ae7b4d4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a loan provided by a private educational lender (as defined in section 140(a) of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1650">15 U.S.C. 1650(a)</external-xref>)) that—</text><clause id="id2c16b559e3364572b7d3f7594fb5ef84"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not made, insured, or guaranteed under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="id6b307c99b2fe47f29593c95d90693c44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is issued expressly for postsecondary educational expenses to a borrower, regardless of whether the loan is provided through the educational institution that the subject student attends or directly to the borrower from the private educational lender (as so defined); and</text></clause><clause id="idefa6ab732bac4969b21e5f4387fdf790"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not made, insured, or guaranteed under title VII or title VIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref> and 296 et seq.); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a243d654fd049849a6ff17dca5fb58d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an extension of credit under an open-end consumer credit plan, a reverse mortgage transaction, a residential mortgage transaction, or any other loan that is secured by real property or a dwelling.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id861392f88b08484eb0a8581430d991ea"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Proprietary institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>proprietary institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f30efe306df435fb9051d4f621208b4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Recruiting and marketing activities</header><subparagraph id="idaa58b96fe13f4de0b3ba5fa1ae280f61"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>recruiting and marketing activities</term> means activities that include any of the following:</text><clause id="id394dbf281d254ac986e14a8f51f45727"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Advertising and promotional activities, including paid announcements in newspapers, magazines, radio, television, billboards, electronic media, naming rights, or any other public medium of communication, including paying for displays or promotions at job fairs, military installations, or college recruiting events, that are made directly or indirectly to a student, a prospective student, the public, an accrediting agency, a State agency, or to the Secretary by a proprietary institution of higher education, one of its representatives, or any person with whom the institution has an agreement to provide educational programs, advertising, or admissions services.</text></clause><clause id="id191aa0328aaf4631aa180af49cba8e5b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Misleading statement, misrepresentation, and substantial misrepresentation (as defined in section 668.71(c) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation).</text></clause><clause id="id4c46df65060c4c009f98e54cbdda95be"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Efforts to identify and attract prospective students, either directly or through a contractor or other third party, including contact concerning a prospective student’s potential enrollment or application for a grant, a loan, or work assistance under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>) or participation in preadmission or advising activities, including soliciting an individual to provide contact information to a proprietary institution of higher education, including through websites established for that purpose and funds paid to third parties for that purpose.</text></clause><clause id="id041811e9f0de4b17b8b209d03e9def2a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Other activities as the Secretary may prescribe, including paying for promotion or sponsorship of education or military-related associations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd14e423f64d4749a8fae9ee40b33d0f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Any activity that is required as a condition of the receipt of funds by an institution of higher education under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>), is specifically authorized under that title, or is otherwise specified by the Secretary, is not a recruiting and marketing activity under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14deaff9b94f4a8fa12ad942d1aaa904"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Unless otherwise expressly provided, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ad37ab79f66470d9cd9fa3ff27f7f23"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State approval agency</header><text>The term <term>State approval agency</term> means any State agency that determines whether an institution of higher education is legally authorized within the State to provide a program of education beyond secondary education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideeb38c5e95b04f64b8f3e27cbb595b01"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Veterans service organization</header><text>The term <term>veterans service organization</term> means an organization that is—</text><subparagraph id="id26f60eb422284e02ba82a2e191a33b24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognized by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the representation of veterans under section 5902 of title 38, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f83bb5e0434484a84704ddde3e3be80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>congressionally chartered under title 36, United States Code, and serves or represents veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6233c7d64cfb4737ac1bc700127eda48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recognized by the Secretary of Veteran Affairs under section 14.628 of title 38, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), as a national organization, State organization, tribal organization, or regional or local organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id345723a7a14344e48658ce69ba07c25c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an organization that has a record of demonstrating expertise in, assists in, or serves the interests of veterans in education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id3fd45f8380e6410381c5ab2deafedda0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Committee</header><subsection id="idd828c471936444ffa916f2b0012a8a6e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Committee (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to be composed of the head (or the designee of the head who is designated under subsection (d)) of each of the following:</text><paragraph id="id4b8a5fe9c9cc4cc6b4fc2b54ffe446d1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7f0854084684a608402e940e6c0ff63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ea454e8d9ec4ef7a9ce28b62337b444"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8700398e33644afd8b39e4599d42c8f9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2108e9b71d749dfaf17e04b4c79f844"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6bbcde2ecf184dc1a3da72d5cbc811c5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id493d686f54e1443c8f6e18488d882537"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee095cff5d83456bb2d37ae8ba08e515"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Department of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ided83fffb58134b7690f21768170d99f8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc3d9d102b0f3428986bdfbab37f93fbc"><enum>(10)</enum><text>At the discretion of the President, any other relevant Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc4d1222feb264727a64029d10265ee83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The Committee shall have the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="iddd3ec28c0e694922871346bfa95d493f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To improve enforcement of applicable Federal laws and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4480a8ddf22b4609a84187d5b5a1b0cf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To increase accountability of proprietary institutions of higher education to students and taxpayers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35a2ee4d3a6040e082ab918e6aaa0749"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To ensure the promotion of high-quality education programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5c6ec9148284309bdd87946b5ab4868"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To reduce and prevent fraud and abuse by proprietary institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide2104d45428f4a2184868a1ba39fbf3e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>To meet the purposes described in subsection (b), the Committee shall—</text><paragraph id="id318e83baa26f45dab65516a8e584c70e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate administrative oversight of proprietary institutions of higher education—</text><subparagraph id="ide467b1f2025d4d62ae2d2b27894fb7e6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such that the Federal agencies represented on the Committee may develop a memorandum of understanding to specify responsibilities of each of those agencies in creating the report under section 6;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ab4208e67d74fc3888f43da237e3117"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage information-sharing, to the extent practicable, among those agencies related to Federal investigations, audits, or inquiries of proprietary institutions of higher education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96ca659032454381930e51db6094cd3f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to increase coordination and cooperation between Federal and State agencies, including State Attorneys General and State approval agencies, with respect to improving oversight and accountability of proprietary institutions of higher education; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9f97b28948c432f9bfef27afbeacf15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>synthesize cross-agency industry data on proprietary institutions of higher education to—</text><subparagraph id="id3a46f914ce2b470b8ee941b27be0b26d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop an annual report under section 6;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id386581b1c08741e0af20ddcb13c4994f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish a <quote>For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students</quote>, in accordance with section 7; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8b6014d83a64f2096adf2f811d87ccd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop consistency among Federal and State agencies in the dissemination of consumer information regarding proprietary institutions of higher education to ensure that students, parents, and other stakeholders have easy access to that information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb2a990b028f649fa9102268019c7153e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="idbd32de4fff784245ac43622a1a056daa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designees</header><text>The head of a Federal agency listed in subsection (a) may designate a high-ranking official of the agency to serve as a designee on the Committee. The designee shall be, whenever possible, the head of the portion of the agency that is most relevant to the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6f6e0b0ec210464ba7240d7c573b6ae7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Secretary or the Secretary's designee shall serve as the Chairperson of the Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59bee26f17594e34b5d4bb5da41330b8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committee support</header><text>The Chairperson of the Committee shall ensure that appropriate staff and officials at the Department are available to support Committee-related work.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ideaa185f8b79e4bab9f9bfa6ff4771df9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Committee meetings</header><text>The members of the Committee shall meet regularly, but not less often than once during each quarter of each fiscal year, to carry out the purposes described in subsection (b) and the responsibilities described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8afac1da231643cda089bcbbe8cb23e8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notification to individuals who submit complaints</header><text>The head of each Federal agency listed in subsection (a) shall notify each individual who submits to the Federal agency a complaint with respect to a proprietary institution of higher education that information from the complaint may be used to carry out the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="idfd37d821615c42ac96139fee9cd1bc17"><enum>4.</enum><header>Proprietary Education Oversight Advisory Committee</header><subsection id="idd891cdb37f074147a4b871cb6f5de1dc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Department shall establish a Proprietary Education Oversight Advisory Committee (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>) to advise the Committee. The Advisory Committee shall meet not less often than twice each fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3a948ce18d5d406bbf974893a3f7d508"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FACA applicability</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID5F3434DEAE114A029434486D50F27011"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Membership</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID8FDAC80C796A4078A034E563A7893468"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall have 13 members, of which—</text><subparagraph id="IDFCAF4FCC16744CE69FCC5B2D206DF7A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>4 members shall be representatives from State attorneys general—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c62de607b9742208e220d2c59cf8b3b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 of whom shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, 1 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the majority leader of the House of Representatives, and 1 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the minority leader of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id785a5663593f46cfadccc82910fbd693"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>2 of whom shall be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate, 1 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the majority leader of the Senate, and 1 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the minority leader of the Senate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6af73ba451141a5b24cc3cb5758dcf1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>9 members shall be appointed by the Secretary, of whom—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd14f9a32fc774342ac9864706468b12a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 member shall be a representative from a State approval agency;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4fd63e9836b4b439fead0c44b2ba479"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 member shall be a representative from a veterans service organization;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3961623ac5a4eeba9fc9382a4f6c7b8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 member shall be a representative from an accrediting agency;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4aa86c1e4ac41bca1d8beaaeb82add4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>1 member shall be a representative from a civil rights organization;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida154720dbe934568ac81f88176f243eb"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 member shall be a representative from a proprietary institution of higher education;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34b76a7e43004a43ae7aff0fdec711b6"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 member shall be a current student of a proprietary institution of higher education who is a dependent student;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65c230da1786434da8fd1fb17a7f211f"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>1 member shall be a current student of a proprietary institution of higher education who is an independent student;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb545badcebfb4bc4bca7feefa1a6eb20"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>1 member shall be a representative from a consumer advocate organization; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b2cbb05ff774f65ab8ad8dbc49aec2f"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 member shall be a representative from a legal assistance organization that represents students or borrowers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID1E2AD9303A4940A698E0042A3ACF7CE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Individuals shall be appointed as members of the Advisory Committee—</text><subparagraph id="ID04963129A5A54C12A467668758C5C0F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the basis of the individuals' experience, integrity, impartiality, and good judgment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ID85AD79FF5A98430984D200D1B068A291"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on the basis of the individuals' technical qualifications, professional standing, and demonstrated knowledge in the field of proprietary education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ID800F46A93C4A405CA9CAF3B7E389B412"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms of members</header><text>The term of office of each member of the Advisory Committee shall be for 6 years, except that any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which the member's predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDAD3C63F36B3F4FD98537527C574D81B1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>A vacancy on the Advisory Committee shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made not later than 90 days after the vacancy occurs. If a vacancy occurs in a position to be filled by the Secretary, the Secretary shall publish a Federal Register notice soliciting nominations for the position not later than 30 days after being notified of the vacancy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idff5e2d54087f4da2a4d7e3e0005dc275"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall provide advice and recommendations to the Committee with respect to—</text><paragraph id="idc11e5315482d42799c85054152876bda"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complaints filed against proprietary institutions of higher education with State attorneys general or State approval agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31d28edef31d48e3acf3b895f6f138a4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>State enforcement actions against proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb3b4ce87d9a48d9a752415deb3f709f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>minority enrollment in proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4feb1538d346409da3d8a26b7fb83ebd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>veteran enrollment in proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca6ad90b67474afeaffa0f342345cee8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>outcome measures at proprietary institutions of higher education, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2860c01b2cd94085a91771989e4d1b71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">graduation rates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide021e7584f274f8da510a57ab6fc2b48"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">percent of graduates earning more than a high school graduate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5b7c70459092442a8a60de235513d3ce"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">licensure pass rates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6f78e1cdf404bfbb3614451a6699fab"><enum>(D)</enum><text>percent of graduates working in a field related to their degree;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id045c19973cae4d50b1408528af2f3855"><enum>(6)</enum><text>student loan burden from enrollment at proprietary institutions of higher education, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7810d8a9d62f4db8b36023fdc15c71df"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">median amount owed disaggregated by degree type;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id12f32a560fdc496da4ffd6203bed4526"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cohort default rate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1311b93f1c094a36bbd7b9e6c40758a7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">percent of students in repayment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id00168f9fdbc34784a8bf05505176d468"><enum>(D)</enum><text>annual debt-to-earnings rates, as calculated under section 668.403 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e50a757b67546b7a8487890a862838f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>marketing and recruitment practices at proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfefde435f4824e1696e5a7e26699c649"><enum>(8)</enum><text>per pupil expenditure for instructional purposes at proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id92639796fbd641d0b090b9984f1542dc"><enum>(9)</enum><text>enforcement actions the Federal Government should take against proprietary institutions of higher education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id62fae7ddeecf4569808becf0b4506415"><enum>(10)</enum><text>preparation of the report under section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18a6745d2f0144da8332dbffa1a24d2d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sharing of data from complaints</header><text>To carry out the duties described under subsection (d), the Advisory Committee may share among the members of the Advisory Committee and the Committee information from complaints filed against proprietary institutions of higher education consistent with the protection of the privacy and confidentiality of personally identifiable information.</text></subsection></section><section id="id68da7490e4e0442f861f5db8798c6127"><enum>5.</enum><header>Collection and tracking of complaints</header><subsection id="id6c21784ffbfc46efaa9c739026857e35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d1f8d00c4a74a00bed01e8e46db6d4d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Centralized collection, monitoring, and response</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In consultation with the Committee, the Secretary shall establish a single, toll-free telephone number, a website, and a database (or use an existing database) to facilitate the centralized collection of, monitoring of, and response to student complaints regarding the services or activities of any proprietary institution of higher education that is eligible for Federal education assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e75c94788c046f9be489fe09259bdfd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall coordinate with the Federal agencies represented on the Committee to route complaints to those agencies, where appropriate, and consistent with—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddeabdd8524be4b5fa7eb2e3b7d1667e9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the protection of the privacy and confidentiality of personally identifiable information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a4d46b11e324e9899cf6d3b5efa703a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data security and integrity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideab8f265c8e240f58f48eff805d0a9b7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of complaint information</header><text>Information collected from complaints under subsection (a) shall be used—</text><paragraph id="idc108aa2666b848e290ab694887e57e4e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to facilitate coordination among the Federal agencies represented on the Committee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b1ca8d97638437a89dc5577a7623315"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to facilitate investigations and enforcement actions against proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a66fb0724224396aa444c2fcc293816"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to prepare the report under section 6; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdb7c5c7fa7740ad981019363802e162"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prepare the For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students under section 7.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1ae6ae666e404b40aaeab9cca5adb597"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Routing complaints to States</header><text>To the extent practicable, State approval agencies may receive appropriate complaints from the systems established under subsection (a), if—</text><paragraph id="id261ff29408da4265b658b4a59a4e2240"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State approval agency system has the functional capacity to receive calls or electronic reports routed by the systems of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4d411d5916c4cd48e6d2b238e5b5bfa"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State approval agency has satisfied any conditions of participation in the system that the Department may establish, including treatment of personally identifiable information and sharing of information on complaint resolution or related compliance procedures and resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id314735281ab847f0b3878e0d7fffdae2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>participation by the State approval agency includes measures necessary to provide for protection of personally identifiable information that conform to the Federal laws and standards for protection of the privacy and confidentiality of personally identifiable information and for data integrity and security that apply to the Federal agencies described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id941d0792e76541e1913f95d8a3f60d52"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Data-Sharing required</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48b7ac9ad44842e592781cea938c5c68"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To facilitate preparation of the reports required under section 6, supervision and enforcement activities, and monitoring of the market for educational services provided by any proprietary institution of higher education that is eligible for Federal education assistance, the Committee members shall share student complaint information with accrediting agencies, the Federal Trade Commission, other Federal agencies, and State agencies, subject to the Federal laws and standards applicable to Federal agencies for the protection of the privacy and confidentiality of personally identifiable information and for data security and integrity.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id05bb3792c8824b8c8e13a8d7226f0d11">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Sharing of data with the department</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The accrediting agencies, the Federal Trade Commission, and other Federal agencies shall share data relating to student complaints regarding educational services provided by any proprietary institution of higher education with the Department, subject to the Federal laws and standards applicable to Federal agencies for the protection of the privacy and confidentiality of personally identifiable information and for data security and integrity.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><section id="idd7e7d57039c14ede9781c18ee0794728"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="idabf8b7e6a120454eaf445287b99d2e7c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee shall submit an annual report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, and any other committee of Congress that the Committee determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="id61d17ae760ce46479a5874e489b40879"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Confidentiality and public access</header><text>The report described in subsection (a)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b44cbfb1cdd4bf68b5b5643f2fd506a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not contain any personally identifiable information; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idddd47a2969ab4f62bd24855f76878604"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be made available to the public in a manner that is easily accessible to parents, students, and other stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2de5dc6a59e2429e88646a9d1764ebe2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><paragraph id="idde36b759d6ef482ca7b71eb4a930f528"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="idadb468c9e9534bdbaa80607a73c77515"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the role of each member of the Committee in achieving the purposes described in section 3(b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id870c89bc3cce4207bf7a6b6d61dbfc85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an accounting of any negative or adverse action taken by the Federal Government, any member agency of the Committee, or a State to enforce Federal or State laws and regulations applicable to a proprietary institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1ee54d92e19f48899e2cc0a17a13a25b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a summary of complaints received, resolved, or pending against each proprietary institution of higher education during the applicable year, including—</text><clause id="idd9548601e1fb438cab4b630c6c009fcc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>student complaints collected by the complaint system established under section 5 or received by any member agency of the Committee;</text></clause><clause id="idaf0466b13a8648e08c6a9ef3767c95ba"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any complaint filed by a Federal or State agency in a Federal, State, local, or Tribal court;</text></clause><clause id="idbc5529925b58443a9cd32ed1192cbff4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any administrative proceeding by a Federal or State agency involving noncompliance of any applicable law or regulation;</text></clause><clause id="ideed3d66da1e84d18b215021ebf1a175e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other review, audit, or administrative process by any Federal or State agency that results in a penalty, suspension, or termination from any Federal or State program; and</text></clause><clause id="id7afbd9850b8841b581046278bdb38a47"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any complaint, review, audit, or administrative process by an accrediting agency that results in probation or equivalent action, denial, withdrawal, suspension, or termination of accreditation;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id24c5550636ec48c988a7c0718771e17b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the data described in paragraph (2) and any other data relevant to proprietary institutions of higher education that the Committee determines appropriate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf0c9e5780ba249528eb91cf5f17b62c8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations of the Committee for the legislative and administrative actions as the Committee determines are necessary to—</text><clause id="iddb59dd1fe09c46d999156096e375ed37"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improve enforcement of applicable Federal laws;</text></clause><clause id="id6f46e15fc7974f0397a6dbcfb40cfaed"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increase accountability of proprietary institutions of higher education to students, parents, and taxpayers;</text></clause><clause id="id18b5b0f926704f7dac05bf841da852a6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reduce and prevent fraud and abuse by proprietary institutions of higher education; and</text></clause><clause id="idec6a20a4255e4b85bb74db268097b186"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>ensure the promotion of quality education programs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b14c195009b4e53aff9248610b8ed3a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data</header><subparagraph id="id6da65802b92541e295c91cdb3c3b504e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Industry-wide data</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall include data on all proprietary institutions of higher education that consists of information regarding—</text><clause id="idcd611b1bfe784dc086b189df1c330b09"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total amount of Federal education assistance that proprietary institutions of higher education received for the previous academic year, and the percentage of the total amount of Federal education assistance provided to institutions of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) for the previous academic year that reflects the total amount of Federal education assistance provided to proprietary institutions of higher education for the previous academic year;</text></clause><clause id="id7e4ab8bf7b504fe69c7f66e58bc45963"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total amount of Federal education assistance that proprietary institutions of higher education received for the previous academic year, disaggregated by—</text><subclause id="id9a1640e609024708975060aa7f87c50d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>educational assistance in the form of a loan provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="idafa1212d04594de4911000896038c139"><enum>(II)</enum><text>educational assistance in the form of a grant provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="id538cd3d9c2814c1cbee0e26f41eabde0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>educational assistance provided under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="id9fe5ef3d15474cd2971d619df6ec16f5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>assistance for tuition and expenses under section 2007 of title 10, United States Code;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida8ca5f619f714807bc9a99ba04228cc7"><enum>(V)</enum><text>assistance provided under section 1784a of title 10, United States Code; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ida14c48aec78a4af69fd5f708a98a1312"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Federal education assistance not described in subclauses (I) through (V);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf25e983ea3dd42af9c50ef56dc598344"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the percentage of the total amount of Federal education assistance provided to institutions of higher education (as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)) for the previous academic year for each of the programs described in subclauses (I) through (VI) of clause (ii), that reflects the total amount of Federal education assistance provided to proprietary institutions of higher education for the previous academic year for each of those programs;</text></clause><clause id="id660a5e275b9047ad933e444b36a86ecb"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the average retention and graduation rates for students pursuing a degree at proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></clause><clause id="id8343cce0b3e2420199a81289fa4ce7e9"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>the average cohort default rate (as defined in section 435(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(m)</external-xref>)) and average annual debt-to-earnings rate (as calculated under section 668.403 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation) for proprietary institutions of higher education, and the cohort default rate and annual debt-to-earnings rate for each proprietary institution of higher education;</text>
 </clause><clause id="idad61a8f7eced42e9bc1924f73149b0a9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the average pre-enrollment expenditures on a per-enrolled-student basis, including expenditures on recruiting and marketing activities;</text></clause><clause id="idb4028c9262124060b71a97d0a1ff2965"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the average educational and general expenditures (as defined in section 502 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a</external-xref>)) per student, excluding all pre-enrollment expenditures, disaggregated by educational expenditures and general expenditures;</text></clause><clause id="id5cf58d7519844dbe89599b10c2084010"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>for careers requiring the passage of a licensing examination—</text><subclause id="id174e017b10024284ae098a7bad069ac5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the passing rate of individuals who attended a proprietary institution of higher education taking the examination to pursue such a career; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb2f1cabb27cf450fbf239898f744cfb1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the passing rate of all individuals taking the exam to pursue such a career;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ida6c2d63159344d0d8f0a7031d182492a"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the use of private education loans at proprietary institutions of higher education that includes—</text><subclause id="idaae0f67d2c844edaa1e2728465a6d595"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an estimate of the total number of those loans;</text></subclause><subclause id="ideb715ad440bc48f9b2184e096fbbe05d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information on the average debt, default rate, and interest rate of those loans; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id1d08ed2bdbdf4445b13783b4bfee1c2f"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the names of each lender providing private education loans to borrowers with respect to each proprietary institution of higher education in the prior academic year, including—</text><item id="id8c744e4598a2475d94e26fbeaccae8d0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the number of borrowers receiving loans from each lender; and</text></item><item id="id8f608850a6d34633bdc94d5c3df7cb57"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the volume of dollars provided to borrowers with respect to the proprietary institution of higher education by each lender; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd473f937c68d426fa9f830d82cc23f36"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the percent of graduates of proprietary institutions of higher education working in a field related to their degree.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id03317629a67d42158189d39c04718a06"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data on publicly traded corporations</header><clause id="iddf84b12d2abc466bab2fafaa3fdfe3f1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The report described in subsection (a) shall include data on proprietary institutions of higher education that are publicly traded corporations, consisting of information on—</text><subclause id="id4e78eff099a147ff8a906d1cbc0554e0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any pre-tax profit of those proprietary institutions of higher education—</text><item id="idb436d86d583b46dca9459dd6fabfc88e"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>reported as a total amount and an average percent of revenue for all those proprietary institutions of higher education; and</text></item><item id="idaa922d1a67a34b6fa48d68af488b6280"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>reported for each of those proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id55830064995144cabb5eac847bd60c61"><enum>(II)</enum><text>revenue for those proprietary institutions of higher education spent on recruiting and marketing activities, student instruction, and student support services, reported—</text><item id="idbfdfb7da9dab4b1fa121c5da56f580cc"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>as a total amount and an average percentage of revenue for all those proprietary institutions of higher education; and</text></item><item id="ida947169979b64d16b852c7abc602b8f4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for each of those proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idf6c02d42939f40c4992b92a503bd833c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>total compensation packages, including bonuses, of the executive officers of each of those proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6a671d2238bc4c8685824d990f2533c5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a list of institutional loan programs offered by each of those proprietary institutions of higher education that includes information on the default and interest rates of those programs; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id58ebe6355cfd4e699d8a8d14cb209de4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the data described in clauses (ii) and (iii).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id2bc6da9dab584a4e8cf2761aa32d5985"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disaggregated by ownership</header><text>The report shall include data on proprietary institutions of higher education that are publicly traded corporations, disaggregated by corporate or parent entity, brand name, and campus, consisting of—</text><subclause id="id570192c2d4b04c78984955d6bb378226"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average total cost of attendance at each proprietary institution of higher education, and information comparing the total cost for each program to—</text><item id="id6cc949f9875f4f0792ad83397b255305"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the average total cost of attendance—</text><subitem id="id68f852bb267f4313ad271834c6995107"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>at each public institution of higher education; and</text></subitem><subitem id="id58cdc474976c4502995080873550aaab"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>at each public institution of higher education that offers the same level of education degree or certification as the proprietary institution of higher education; and</text></subitem></item><item id="id59036a45c7ba43e7811bb809918b8f03"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the average total cost of attendance—</text><subitem id="idec0a3bb1f6eb444aaf8df8654611e7a4"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>at all institutions of higher education, including institutions that are public and institutions that are private; and</text></subitem><subitem id="id02f0fd8ff972446cb24b269905e0f0e7"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>at all institutions of higher education that offer the same level of education degree or certification as the proprietary institution of higher education, including institutions that are public and institutions that are private;</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="idc751f0517cf749099b00890d9837298a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>total enrollment, disaggregated by—</text><item id="idb78252c8f00f40e08ccd98315775886c"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>individuals enrolled in programs taken online;</text></item><item id="idc1549693342942e8afd6af4355ebf3f1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>individuals enrolled in programs that are not taken online; and</text></item><item id="idf2ee0a210a154738ab95e45df5dc6fca"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>individuals enrolled in programs taken both online and not online;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idb647742eef734213a035856a306c1a0a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the average retention and graduation rates for students pursuing a degree at proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="id39313c8d0c4448f0ac3f2f761e654d4b"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the percentage of students enrolled in proprietary institutions of higher education who complete a program of an institution within—</text><item id="idb6add02bffbc430082f376e29e5b6b6b"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the standard period of completion for the program; and</text></item><item id="idfae218f4ebc646b9815e24c856d695d5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a period that is 150 percent of the standard period of completion;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="ida8b4165bf98146b59b96437d03436e3b"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the average total cost of attendance for each program at proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="id61fa1cc629a94cb6be23eab3ed38569c"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the average cohort default rate, as defined in section 435(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(m)</external-xref>), for proprietary institutions of higher education, and an annual list of cohort default rates (as so defined) for all proprietary institutions of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="id30bc5091400b44a9bacaa6574cb035b0"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the median Federal educational debt incurred by students who complete a program at a proprietary institution of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="idff2a71c262a8411a813ca927331ce9e2"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the median Federal educational debt incurred by students who start but do not complete a program at a proprietary institution of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="id988d361c3eac47cd8da27664c87f9977"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the job placement rate for students who complete a program at a proprietary institution of higher education and the type of employment obtained by those students;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6ca04d1b57bf4c06be291a7f0dec3362"><enum>(X)</enum><text>for careers requiring the passage of a licensing examination, the passing rate for individuals who attended a proprietary institution of higher education and passed the examination;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd39db83f60b54bf784f553c3c6c96ffc"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the number of complaints from students enrolled in proprietary institutions of higher education who have submitted a complaint to any member agency of the Committee; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id91f0809ff5ba4e7fa6273ad5dfe256c0"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>the volume of institutional debt, number of students who owe institutional debts, average amount of institutional debt owed by each student, and annual debt-to-earnings rate (as calculated under section 668.403 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id8c6d34859af74a2baf31c56cc54bd9ca"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Department of Defense and Veterans Affairs assistance</header><subclause id="id6f5efcdd18ee43a7ac83263f025a2ada"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent practicable, the report described in subsection (a) shall provide information on the data described in clause (ii) for individuals using, to pay for the costs of attending a proprietary institution of higher education, Federal education assistance provided under—</text><item id="idc7562469cc984e6fb1c8cbce8f6efc06"><enum>(aa)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code;</text></item><item id="id2dc87b3a80664e8ea808690a79093ed4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>section 2007 of title 10, United States Code; and</text></item><item id="idd1791c651be9467a8ca301f03b66d76c"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>section 1784a of title 10, United States Code.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="ida7b7807c17c4482f8de49a3869c9ba49"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Revenue</header><text>The report shall provide information on the revenue of proprietary institutions of higher education that are publicly traded corporations that is derived from the Federal education assistance described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0bafbe101ed4cae89c9b78bccf5b53d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Comparison data</header><text>To the extent practicable, the report shall provide information comparing the data described in subparagraph (B) for proprietary institutions of higher education that are publicly traded corporations with data for public institutions of higher education disaggregated by State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7ac7588dd3b4edc89037b8161ca0563"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Accounting of any action</header><text>As used in paragraph (1)(B), the term <term>any negative or adverse action</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="idf9dbeeca738a42678daed0e8f3590a20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a complaint filed by a Federal or State agency in a local, State, Federal, or Tribal court;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2abd80e7d334c708d371b0f1fb25008"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an administrative proceeding by a Federal or State agency involving noncompliance with any applicable law or regulation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb5f2a687d6246108ba859c5a1cc5e07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other review, audit, or administrative process by any Federal or State agency that results in a penalty, suspension, or termination from any Federal or State program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idff4ed98d0da04da699688ee04ae44c53"><enum>7.</enum><header>For-profit college warning list for parents and students</header><subsection id="id5d9df92ee4fb417eadfaad8dc25378dd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each academic year, the Secretary on behalf of the Committee shall publish a list to be known as the <quote>For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students</quote> to be comprised of the names of proprietary institutions of higher education—</text><paragraph id="id8f4b325d482d4fbd8183680bb9d5b6d4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that have been sued for financial relief by a Federal or State authority, or through a qui tam action in which the Federal Government has intervened;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide052cc2644f64814a31a82c487dccf77"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that are required to pay a debt or incur a liability from a settlement, arbitration proceeding, or final judgment in a judicial proceeding with a Federal or State agency and the case addresses misrepresentation, fraud, liability under sections 3729 through 3733 of title 31, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>False Claims Act</quote>), or other borrower-defense-to-repayment claims;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c020f00a777445abb17a38255914445"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that have pending claims for borrower relief discharge under the borrower defense to repayment regulations from students or former students of the institution and the Secretary has formed a group process to consider the claims;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida117369600bb4e95b605f08434807c56"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that have had any eligibility for participation withdrawn or suspended with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="id3d2f8083207041b4942803a5a949ea57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>educational assistance in the form of a loan provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0d58e3f9951c44c5a2b003a7ae535baf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educational assistance in the form of a grant provided under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe29d38f70fc427b95cbe35f4a9837f1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>educational assistance provided under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c215f02dc784ffeabe4652d8922e958"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assistance for tuition and expenses under section 2007 of title 10, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb39bbc6f3b854256abe67e8268b0ba4e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assistance provided under section 1784a of title 10, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7ed9b94a765401d87999cea0555f6c6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Federal education assistance not described in subparagraphs (A) through (E); or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id70932f90f0974e6b8961cd21c6d6703b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>that have been deemed ineligible to receive Federal education assistance for the next year or required to repay Federal education assistance previously received in an applicable report year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id21e7bb5babd94849b563977b20cd7d12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Summary</header><text>The For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students shall include a summary in plain language of the basis of each proprietary institution of higher education’s inclusion on the list.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide8ceb2ac6d9c4efaa74e05dd8d052203"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Committee shall establish and apply review procedures for the For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students, including evaluation and withdrawal proceedings that provide—</text><paragraph id="ida4952c5dd0d74aa8abb17e7b7350df42"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for adequate written specification of—</text><subparagraph id="id7a1730b48cd746a2b9f90faff66fd368"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the procedure for identifying proprietary intuitions of higher education for inclusion on the list; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5baad250c2894eb8b4a259b5658adc98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identified deficiencies at the proprietary institutions of higher education; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8e64c89a7d974d4ab6d95a97a0f9389b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for sufficient opportunity for a written response by a proprietary institution of higher education regarding any deficiencies identified by the Committee—</text><subparagraph id="id435b63ec0e474313923fae27b5c4dbc1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within a timeframe determined by the Committee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e9047fe94144eaab1cc44d076e03ff3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prior to the final publication of the For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idce323f5329104d5098e9707f3dd19946"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3ca85cb8062476ebc17e85f80ffb6f0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than July 1 of each fiscal year, on behalf of the Committee, the Secretary shall publish the For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students prominently and in a manner that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea92d5a506b641a5baeb4827cfbbfc9c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is easily accessible to parents, current students, prospective students, and other stakeholders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa8db61d1f4a46ebb7a315fd6a703eef"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not contain any personally identifiable information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c0545828e124e318285d586c4439646"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of preexisting platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may incorporate the For-Profit College Warning List for Parents and Students into preexisting, widely used platforms.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

