<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB132319EA889428685EC3EA7F0096899" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8818 IH: End Fentanyl Trafficking with Local Task Forces Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8818</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish grants to combat opioid trafficking.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H889F89A099564453AF177F90E9F4AE38" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H14FE5E12948547EDAC5FFC7D403B204F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Fentanyl Trafficking with Local Task Forces Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4F952947BCFC44558EF8B665D5874E1B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant authorization</header> <subsection id="HE7B68FABE30240D9BDC6BB42FC04FF2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new part:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H064B4EF6E67E418284101148A109AF8D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<part id="H03FB2E01844448E8B4353010A3FAFDE0"><enum>PP</enum><header>Grants to combat opioid trafficking</header> 
<section id="H527606DBC2F745B59B06B6B4489DB630"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Authority to make grants to combat opioid trafficking</header> 
<subsection id="H6832789481DA4D37B90B92E133BFEDE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The COPS Director is authorized to make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of locating, investigating, and interdicting illicit activities relating to the distribution of opioids.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H51D30EA59C0845DBB0C549F04F0D5030" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of the grants made under this part, eligible entities are States, State law enforcement agencies, units of local government, Indian Tribes, multi-jurisdictional task forces, and regional consortia.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9985C271CE54C57AEF604729FC35841"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header> 
<paragraph id="H73194CAADD7049EDA43768A874B506B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To receive a grant under this part, an eligible entity shall submit to the COPS Director an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the COPS Director may require. Each application shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HE8E4A0281E31478686A4569A40F324BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed explanation of—</text> 
<clause id="HAE716E41A2854E44808CEA093BE69D41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the intended uses of funds provided under the grant; and</text></clause> <clause id="H397484B22D094DB5875DC6452BDD7355"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how the activities funded under the grant will meet the purpose of this part;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAD08894F847443ACB532EC08BF767EDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assurance that the applicant shall maintain and report such data, records, and information (programmatic and financial) as the COPS Director may reasonably require;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85ED325E00BB468EB4F7B31097EBF79E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a certification, made in a form acceptable to the COPS Director, that—</text> 
<clause id="HA01DFC056EAF46FD9687A2EA00C84934"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the programs to be funded by the grant meet all the requirements of this part;</text></clause> <clause id="HC47B521D37DC48ECA1591E0DC5E214D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all the information contained in the application is correct; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAF6C614EADE34BC39CB96D82EC857ADA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the applicant will comply with all provisions of this part and all other applicable Federal laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EABC749E451495EBA2FE9737F6DAD47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this part, the COPS Director shall promulgate guidelines to implement this part, including the information that must be included and the requirements that eligible entities must meet, in submitting the applications required under this part.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB009C862951F4074B8D5B72679AB1D8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Streamlining applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the greatest extent possible, the COPS Director shall streamline the grant application process to minimize the administrative burden placed on eligible applicants and to prevent the collection of extraneous or duplicative information.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H45FA6863ED43457EB49724734F928091"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant made under this part shall be used—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA3CC041967242A2B2B4D81CA1EF3D43"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hire and train law enforcement officers and other employees;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33C00C39EC0E4993B22A803FA5D1AECE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hire and train law enforcement officers and other employees to establish new, or support and expand existing, multi-jurisdictional task forces, regional consortia, or both;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C88DC1432474B698A9477C87E61C7B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to procure equipment, technology, or support systems, or pay overtime; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H856DE706BBAD4D7DA1A29F8D905E1CC0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for any other activities or items the Attorney General determines appropriate to support the purpose described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FC59858910F417B9F0DF38A0B0D36D4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant made under this part shall be for not less than 1 year and not more than 3 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8CECDC71288041C4B65B656A45D7EF70"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Allocation of grant funding</header> <paragraph id="H866F103F476D426D8E71E00FB7A50ABC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Set aside</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds allocated to carry out the grant program under this part not less than 20 percent shall be reserved for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9B5035590F584BACB58B5950A8052F9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct grants to Indian Tribes or Tribal law enforcement agencies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H437802DD053547D6ACF0BF22A63A930C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>direct grants to multi-jurisdictional task forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7692EF2E716C44748F71AE46A78F6EE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that a Tribal law enforcement officer or a law enforcement partner affiliated with an Indian Tribe is a member of a multi-jurisdictional task force receiving a direct grant, such membership shall not impact the eligibility of, or reduce the percentage otherwise available for, the Tribal law enforcement agency with jurisdiction over such officer or the Indian Tribe with jurisdiction over such officer or law enforcement partner for the funds reserved under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HC8130BBC1E38494A89D9B4B1CB7BC1A1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Contracts and subawards</header> <paragraph id="H9A1790E07AF841349143B594108D1AC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, unit of local government, or Indian Tribe may, in using a grant under this part for purposes authorized under subsection (d), use the grant to contract with or make subawards to a State, local, or Tribal law enforcement agency, a unit of local government, an Indian Tribe, a Tribal organization, a multi-jurisdictional task force, or a regional consortium.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H914A9724C77D44B58E8FA77693A24DC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The receipt of a contract or subaward under paragraph (1) by an Indian Tribe, Tribal law enforcement agency, Tribal organization, or multi-jurisdictional task force shall not impact the eligibility of, or reduce the percentage otherwise available for, such Indian Tribe, the Indian Tribe with jurisdiction over such agency or organization, or the multi-jurisdictional task force for the funds set aside under subsection (f)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H449D5C9ED45D45B088E6F57F4D1A8749"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The COPS Director may reserve not more than 2 percent from amounts appropriated to carry out this part for administrative costs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF17C98958F664043AE0F09692CF34F87"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> 
<paragraph id="H60D3475D073D4851B528DBE8C3AAA369"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The COPS Director shall provide technical assistance to the eligible entities described in subsection (b) in furtherance of the purposes described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2374B0BD0DA34D68BE1FF2C2822A8CAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training centers and facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The technical assistance provided by the COPS Director may include the establishment and operation of training centers or facilities, either directly or by contracting or cooperative arrangements. The functions of the centers or facilities established under this paragraph may include instruction and seminars for police executives, managers, trainers, supervisors, and such others as the COPS Director considers to be appropriate for supporting efforts related to locating, investigating, and interdicting illicit activities relating to the distribution of opioids.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H115859956BC4427FBCDF5AED8F740AF5"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this part, the COPS Director shall give priority to applicants that will use awarded funds to establish new, or support and expand existing, multi-jurisdictional task forces or regional consortia.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF2583A31C22B463BB7308BB032484704"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this part, and annually thereafter, the COPS Director shall submit to Congress a report describing effectiveness of this grant program and make recommendations for how it can be improved.</text></section> 
<section id="H9A8ED2B630034462B05CC98E48BB572D"><enum>3063.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> <paragraph id="H151608B182FD47BBAA885059BAE90349"><enum>(1)</enum><header>COPS Director</header><text>The term <term>COPS Director</term> means the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H708681BC33124DD6B8C0A343A5EAC5E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means the governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation individually identified (including parenthetically) on the list published by the Secretary under section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9222F684D05F4BAE8F5DE31405B77172"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multi-jurisdictional task force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>multi-jurisdictional task force</term> means any local law enforcement entity composed of law enforcement officers from different State, local, or Tribal law enforcement agencies, which may also include other support staff members or law enforcement partners affiliated with an Indian Tribe, the Federal Government, a State government, or a unit of local government.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H135433723DD742B0B722E2C0894A2163"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional consortium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>regional consortium</term> means any law enforcement entity composed of multi-jurisdictional task forces that cross State lines.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H01868D145EA342E7B93F76A1A991A220"><enum>3064.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part $70,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B51A431E5D54288BE3F0F34F98C57B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1701(m) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(m)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

