<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H5BB4F8E03681447D8F0F3057C3B1C2B7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2152 RH: Artificial Intelligence Practices, Logistics, Actions, and Necessities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 615</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2152</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–708]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250314">March 14, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 14, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a strategy to defend against the economic and national security risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, including fraud and the dissemination of misinformation, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H130C5BDBA48F4D308C905989449CC813"><section id="HF0E0A942B9524BBFB0755D16DD698A59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence Practices, Logistics, Actions, and Necessities Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AI PLAN Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H604EF3B4AA2A4F60BC7680D7DA2A5116"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy to defend against risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence by adversarial actors</header><subsection id="H514EBD8D208145A990BD37C11AF9531A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the development and use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes by adversarial actors poses a significant risk to the national and economic security of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H73ECC733E2AA4EF998CE194015EF5717"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy to defend against risks posed by financial crime conducted with artificial intelligence</header><paragraph id="H6E6DCB28409F4CEBB7F53994E897B4BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the officials specified in paragraph (3), shall jointly submit to Congress a report, which shall include a classified annex and may include an unclassified summary, provided that no sensitive information is disclosed publicly, that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF5809D83539F4AE0B9F0CF92DB166885"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of interagency and applicable intergovernmental policies, procedures, and working groups to defend United States financial markets, United States persons, United States businesses, and global supply chains from the national and economic security risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence by adversarial actors in the commission of financial crimes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CD004CE536847C6A702AFA4D61E58C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of public-private partnerships, collaborative arrangements, and other coordinated activities of Federal departments and agencies in cooperation with the private-sector to defend United States financial markets, United States persons, United States businesses, and global supply chains from the national and economic security risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence by adversarial actors in the commission of financial crimes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91A21B26CCEE4A42854347DC210006F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An itemized list of, and accompanying analysis of, readily available resources, including hardware, software, technologies, and people that can be immediately deployed by Federal departments and agencies to combat the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, with an assessment of their capabilities, limitations, and tradeoffs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5536654DCB6A4071ABF946647CCBBD44"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An itemized list of, and accompanying analysis of, resources, including hardware, software, technologies, and people, and budgetary estimates needed to help Federal departments and agencies to combat the use of artificial intelligence in the commission of financial crimes, with an assessment of their capabilities, limitations, and tradeoffs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE8B2E9DD88540C9871B8927BBDEE1EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>Reports required pursuant to paragraph (1) shall take the following risks into consideration:</text><subparagraph id="HDB2774D7EF04436CB97DAD240A52095F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Deepfakes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA55CD05607147D9BC5B8C9D190113D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Voice cloning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E58018BF3C41FABD8B7FC6364CC59C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Foreign election interference.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47A01DA98ECD4FDE9B3087CA6581ABF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Synthetic Identities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H960C64720B4F4F299197C18049224435"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial Intelligence-Driven Market Response. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A29B93EBCFC4577B55A5A5F5759470C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>False flags and false signals that disrupt market operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6AFB1DEEF0F4F2FB332B0B3189D9D85"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Attacks involving AI-supported social engineering.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E37387B1EC94CEF8BDC181FAD8076CF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Cyber breaches.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0B71B0E24884AECA5C86218A5A0AB30"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Number Spoofing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29FBBB61F916465A821A0CD3ACA5F43A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Overall digital fraud and scams.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9850C51BB3243D783E5EF9EEF66309F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Officials specified</header><text>The officials specified in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H663312FCC1C04DD2B8BB1F3E54A9B6EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38230748EDB044B7BD9695D8917078C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCB6913B55494635B4BDD3B36A938CF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Comptroller of the Currency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBA351AFB3BB49B0A3EBABEE1B186C84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Chairperson of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA415C54B2066411093E30327AB99F5ED"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Chairman of the National Credit Union Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07DE1E9B79F149308CCBA39441B5CE45"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H547E80324C524AFEA1EABF51CC32E88C"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H988FE6861A194D29AA971107EA6070A7" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H115071A5883F4E2FAE26F150945177B9" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF531D6BF17DF45EFA820715C0ABF3951"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after each report under subsection (b) is submitted, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Commerce shall jointly submit to Congress a set of recommendations relating to each such respective report that contains the following:</text><paragraph id="H397ED418D60F41528351F824D0CB4A68"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Legislative recommendations to address the risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence by adversarial actors in the commission of financial crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFF9B3C13EB74B18A385AFE49A843E34"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Best practices to assist American businesses and government entities with risk mitigation and incident response to address the risks posed by the use of artificial intelligence by adversarial actors in the commission of financial crimes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

