<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8183B797C98F4B19A44EDF3BBBB9BA8B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6730 IH: Healthcare Equality and Rights for Our Heroes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6730</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, to allow suit against the United States for injuries and deaths of members of the Armed Forces caused by improper medical care.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H910F276F9AA34E05A882CDF9E3C4204D" style="OLC"><section id="H77CCFCB22DE84211BD1CCAAEC8400929" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthcare Equality and Rights for Our Heroes Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HERO Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDC4CB1FE04B74AFFBBFA0E9CF92FD8BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Claims against United States for injury and death of members of the uniform services caused by improper medical care</header><subsection id="H4E3D30511AF5446AA67109B70C909ECA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2733a of title 10, United States Code, is repealed. </text></subsection><subsection id="H71AFDFAD137B4ACEAD13569519F637F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">Chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2BFC5802A5364D3397960A3B5834D2F8"><section id="H801A59CD08B149D9B92124A0D94BE6CC"><enum>2681.</enum><header>Claims against United States for injury and death of members of the uniformed services</header><subsection id="HE40316639B5F4E3D84A659DC3966FE7A"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a claim may be brought against the United States under this chapter for damages for personal injury or death of a member of the uniformed services arising out of a negligent or wrongful act or omission in the performance of medical, dental, or related health care functions (including clinical studies and investigations) that is provided at a covered military medical treatment facility by an employee acting within the scope of their office or employment or by or at the direction of the Government of the United States and shall be exclusive of any other civil action or proceeding by reason of the same subject matter against such employee (or the estate of such employee) whose act or omission gave rise to the action or proceeding.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE74D16EEC8E40A7AE8CDC2757268E38" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text>A claim under this section may not be reduced—</text><paragraph id="H64A2701BCAC34788B5F8467FA3D4652C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the amount of any benefit received pursuant to laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs; or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H446A0069A31C470C904A5DF056E999A7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by the amount of any benefit received under subchapter III (relating to Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/19">chapter 19</external-xref> of title 38.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22FC9F5E5F7B42C687EAAA7667BF2DBE"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2401(b)—</text><paragraph id="H6A501862817F4C3D98601CE273639502"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in paragraph (2), a claim arising under this section may not be commenced later than 10 years after the date on which the claimant discovered, or by reasonable diligence should have discovered, the injury and the cause of the injury; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98B73BDF68704993B26CF77CA8ADF8AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an administrative claim pending pursuant to section 2733a of title 10 as of the enactment of this subsection, the limitations period described in paragraph (1) shall begin on the date of enactment of this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DC9270666854791A6CB5E3912C8A41F" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><text>For purposes of claims brought under this section—</text><paragraph id="HE471868E379F4436B399DDA5F3466773"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsections (j) and (k) of section 2680 shall not apply; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD4D605718D842B79A1B798731C25F61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an act or omission occurring outside the United States, the law of the place where the act or omission occurred shall be deemed to be the law of the State of domicile of the claimant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3E2908F47A54D9E83D12E611B9BBD59" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, and every 2 years thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the number of claims filed under this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="H48ADF1A4FD5A4428BE9481C46188875D"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text><paragraph id="H16E7A5923EFC46D2A795BBDD9882479D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>active service</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 10; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2568CF69F0904C00881C0DE28A06CDB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Armed Forces</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 10; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09C343E0DAE84D139DA0951BEDEEBFD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered military medical treatment facility</term>— </text><subparagraph id="H70AA175EA4BC4322BC9941C6A383DAD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a facility maintained under section 1073d of title 10; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8673347131F4464A3640C340DB7C35F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include battalion aid stations or other military medical treatment facilities in an area of armed conflict or combatant activities. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79EF32A98E684D2FADF039B36D526780" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>member of the uniformed services</quote> includes a member of a reserve component of the Armed Forces if the claim by the member under this section is in connection with personal injury or death that occurred while the member was performing active service; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F5D3F4265DE4566B1EEAB7D9B4BAD21"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <quote>reserve components</quote> means the reserve components specified in section 10101 of title 10; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD17844FC7DD54FF3ABC27EFF5199898F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>uniformed services</quote> shall have the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 10. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF1DECACFDB4D4E81A29F2358B1D0C126"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">chapter 171</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HD309C3DE76894F4E8E90F5D8C4FFBF8D"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">2681. Claims against United States for injury and death of members of the Armed Forces.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

