<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H597A9EEDC0E14720A959C75C6C50C44E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 107 IH: Recognizing the importance of saving lives, reducing gun violence, and strengthening public safety as the United States celebrates its 250th anniversary.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 107</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance of saving lives, reducing gun violence, and strengthening public safety as the United States celebrates its 250th anniversary.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States commemorates its 250th anniversary in 2026, marking a historic milestone in our its democratic journey;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the promise of the United States includes ensuring the safety, security, and well-being of all people and communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas gun violence remains a leading cause of death and injury in the United States, impacting families, communities, and the public health and economic stability of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States continues to lead the world in the number of gun deaths, with an average of 125 people killed by guns each day;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are over 400,000,000 guns in the United States, but only 340,000,000 people in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 1 in 5 people in the United States will personally witness someone shot;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas people of all communities, including veterans and children, are not immune to the pull of the trigger;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas evidence-informed solutions—including community violence intervention, Federal background checks, effective law enforcement partnerships, and responsible public safety policies—have been shown to reduce gun violence and save lives;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas survivors of gun violence, community leaders, public safety professionals, and advocates play a vital role in advancing effective solutions to improve public safety;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas reducing gun violence is essential to protecting communities and ensuring all people of the United States can live free from preventable harm;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas saving lives and safeguarding the well-being of the people of the United States is a fundamental responsibility of government; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the 250th anniversary of the United States presents an opportunity to renew the commitment of the United States to protecting lives and strengthening public safety for future generations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA6B9DDD5669C4664B8AE73C9CD0F6E77"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF2D8E0B7EE3E4B3D8A4796ADCF40B930"><text>That Congress—</text> <paragraph id="HE937220DCB8744D3B163CB218B1BAC3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the 250th anniversary of the United States as a moment to reaffirm a national commitment to saving lives, reducing gun violence, and strengthening public safety;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5682576D61AD491F98605D985C6AE077"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the lives lost to gun violence and provides support for survivors, families, and communities impacted;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E2F952DF8C64F239B96043EA2E5E44D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the efforts of community leaders, law enforcement, public health professionals, community violence intervention practitioners, and advocates working to prevent gun violence and promote safety;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3EE651B71004319A19E543CB1671954"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritizes support for law enforcement efforts to collect and publish data about violent crimes, improve clearance rates for homicides and shootings, and expand training in deescalation tactics;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6FADC085BB7467EAD9170BC5AB1B503"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports expanded investment in proactive, community-based strategies that stop violence before it occurs by identifying individuals at high risk and intervening with credible messengers and customized services that address the root causes of violence;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CCAF19C687C4D5C9C45B5136A713142"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commits to ensuring robust funding for victim services so many can take the first steps towards recovery;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC548453926B34A2B98BA10AA78349A31"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that preventing gun violence and saving lives must be a national priority as the United States enters its next 250 years; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0D20C01C8C24ED984FEB0E9BD54D28E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursues policies that strengthen public safety, uphold constitutional rights, and protect the well-being of all people of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

