<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E449E8736154FA3AC4DAD515C750A0C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7905 IH: Diabetes Foot Health Access and Modernization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7905</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to cover physician services delivered by podiatric physicians to ensure access by Medicaid beneficiaries to appropriate quality foot and ankle care, to amend title XVIII of such Act to modify the requirements for diabetic shoes to be included under Medicare, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD8425E578A1E4DB8A725F456099040B9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7668F60CB59942DB8496DB9502C6348D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Diabetes Foot Health Access and Modernization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H52C702DBD3DF4D6C86742247A04DCB00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recognizing doctors of podiatric medicine as physicians under the Medicaid program</header> <subsection id="HFE948E62CAB44AC1B4DDE1F7F28CCFCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a)(5)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 1861(r)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 1861(r)</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC06903933E0B4522806B13E238886592"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC907D458816D45BBB7AE1E1FC747C801"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to services furnished on or after January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92133AA4B6CA4319A2E60B38E49D9180"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of effective date for State law amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) which the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines requires State legislation in order for the plan to meet the additional requirement imposed by the amendment made by subsection (a), the State plan shall not be regarded as failing to comply with the requirements of such title solely on the basis of its failure to meet these additional requirements before the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning after the close of the first regular session of the State legislature that begins after the date of enactment of this Act. For purposes of the previous sentence, in the case of a State that has a 2-year legislative session, each year of the session is considered to be a separate regular session of the State legislature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB91842A2DF5842E1B1BE7A1A6A05C97E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarifying Medicare documentation requirements for therapeutic shoes for persons with diabetes</header> 
<subsection id="H212B66A52B424F33ABF598A8CAD9EAF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1861(s)(12) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(s)(12)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A109FB46FD1445D9878C06D361BC497" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H62D9365A609047B8A09BC0BB4735C0AF" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">extra-depth shoes with inserts or custom molded shoes with inserts for an individual with diabetes, if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE370C0B2C7F543F78429761658D84F71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a physician as defined in subsection (r) of this section—</text> <clause id="H53A80EEC82D948D180A57F3A84229B0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documents that the individual has peripheral neuropathy that may include altered foot sensation, weakness, or diminished motor control of the lower extremity; a history of pre-ulcerative calluses or other ulceration of the foot; foot deformity, previous lower extremity amputation, or poor lower extremity circulation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0BA961312637474395671A7B9DACC231"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attests that the individual has a diabetes diagnosis and is under a comprehensive plan of care related to the individual’s diabetic condition; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0561983DA6AC4604A59E7D0237B7863A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attests that the individual needs such shoes; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FF49D3F08E44E1B9084F1CB1CF066C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the shoes are fitted and furnished by a physician or other qualified individual (such as a pedorthist or orthotist) as established by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBCB774DFD891400E8C041C61674E4FF1"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Conforming amendment</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1877(h)(6) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. § 1395nn(h)(6)) is amended by inserting after subparagraph (L) the following:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF44D0ED5F75A4CE7939FE97AD4EA9103"
          display-inline="no-display-inline">
          <subparagraph id="H54249EA4232747C7AD4CFA083F60A829">
            <enum>(M)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Extra-depth shoes with inserts or custom molded shoes with inserts.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H567D399178D14EB98B8951D0941F093E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2028.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

