<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="first-star-print" slc-id="S1-MEE26144-0NK-4J-N32" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 801 ATS: Honoring the life and legacy of the Honorable Lindsey Olin Graham, a Senator from the State of South Carolina.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 801</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor>Mr. Thune</sponsor> (for <sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S440">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>)) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and legacy of the Honorable Lindsey Olin Graham, a Senator from the State of South Carolina.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Olin Graham was born on July 9, 1955, in Central, South Carolina;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham graduated from D. W. Daniel High School, received a Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of South Carolina in 1977, and earned a Juris Doctor from the University of South Carolina School of Law in 1981;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham served with distinction in the United States Air Force Judge Advocate General’s Corps, the South Carolina Air National Guard, and the United States Air Force Reserves, attaining the rank of Colonel before retiring after more than 3 decades of military service, and receiving the Bronze Star Medal and the Meritorious Service Medal;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham served as an Assistant County Attorney for Oconee County, South Carolina, before being elected to the South Carolina House of Representatives in 1992;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham was elected to the United States House of Representatives in 1994, where he represented the Third Congressional District of South Carolina for 4 terms;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham was elected to the United States Senate in 2002 and was subsequently reelected by the people of South Carolina several times to continue representing them with distinction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during his service in the Senate, Lindsey Graham served on numerous committees, including the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Budget, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs, and the Committee on Environment and Public Works;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham served as Chairman of the Committee on the Judiciary during the 116th Congress and as Chairman of the Committee on the Budget during the 119th Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, throughout his career, Lindsey Graham was a steadfast advocate for the national defense of the United States, the rule of law, the men and women of the Armed Forces, and the people of South Carolina;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham earned the respect of colleagues on both sides of the aisle through his candor, wit, willingness to engage in difficult debates, and unwavering commitment to public service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham devoted more than 3 decades of his life to serving the people of South Carolina and the United States with honor and distinction;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the voice of Lindsey Graham carried influence far beyond the halls of Congress, and his steadfast advocacy for the leadership of the United States, a strong national defense, and the cause of freedom earned him the respect of leaders around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham was preceded in death by his father, Florence James Graham, and his mother, Millie Walters Graham, whose example of hard work, sacrifice, and perseverance profoundly shaped his life of public service; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham is survived by his sister, Darline Graham Nordone, and a grateful United States that benefitted from his faithful service: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id46c8d1f9ce9a42fea889b7b3822d003e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the death of the Honorable Lindsey Olin Graham, a Senator from the State of South Carolina;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf51f7d9f4cb546b8bfa3bcd67f96f737"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requests that the Secretary of the Senate communicate these resolutions to the House of Representatives and transmit an enrolled copy thereof to the family of Lindsey Olin Graham; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddab092e2caa3483aa5f477218ec7b68e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>stands adjourned as a further mark of respect to the memory of the Honorable Lindsey Olin Graham when the Senate adjourns today.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

