<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HABCFCCED6E3644B198EA2047CFF620C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7779 IH: Harmonizing Environmental Analyses and Launching Therapeutic Hubs to Yield Bolstered Research And Innovation in Neurological Science Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7779</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program for the conduct and support of research, training, and health information dissemination with respect to environmental risk factors of neurodegenerative diseases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9767B0F7CBF946F7B0D245E6276B8044" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0AFE3E6E34DB42C1B718ED52DC713215"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Harmonizing Environmental Analyses and Launching Therapeutic Hubs to Yield Bolstered Research And Innovation in Neurological Science Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HEALTHY BRAINS Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAA76F9B7157548E5BAC976A6817ACB6C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Research into environmental risk factors that may contribute to neurodegenerative disease</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/284">42 U.S.C. 284 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEACBA149534F4A5A929C6E46DB92466C"><section id="H4B97E083B7D54D5880113F076B31E3FF"><enum>409K.</enum><header>Neurodegenerative disease environmental research</header><subsection id="HDD958210B26D4EA3A39C20097C260A71"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program for the conduct and support of research, training, and health information dissemination with respect to environmental risk factors (including environmental toxicant exposures) of neurodegenerative diseases.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3DDCDBC3B87543D3AF1BFBA9BD880B74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research conducted or supported under this section shall—</text><paragraph id="HBCA07339EBCB45B4AE82AE706B34AD80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be focused on—</text><subparagraph id="H547C011DC1934EBB8641C72B6F39CFF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>potential environmental toxicants, including environmental stressors such as volatile organic compounds, particulate matter, per- and polyfluorinated substances, and heavy metals in environmental media such as air, water, food, and soil;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4406D64351042DC969BB0DBE3827768"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the mechanistic interactions of such toxicants with neurodegenerative disease outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H733334262A2F437097321DFABBA5BE49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the presymptomatic markers of neurodegenerative disease; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H232300ADD71E4D789D707FC12F0DD856"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancing development of environmental health strategies to prevent, manage, treat, or slow the progression of neurodegenerative disease; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD2FE083F14E4215BACFD66BEF27B25C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include research—</text><subparagraph id="H52E195E9FC7D4D0C99C47040774D621E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>examining environmental exposures, including occupational risk factors, sociobehavioral factors, and social determinants of health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC353B968E71646F2B9F834E0A8A07B43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>using fundamental approaches to identify historical, existing, and emerging environmental risks and factors that affect disease progression;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AA0E9F61CA04008BE43763212C42A1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>examining multifactorial causation from chemical and nonchemical exposures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4AEFF8CD1724878AF982FD19C9408E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>examining prevalence of the disease in relation to the distribution of exposures across communities and populations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5DDB2EBE71E4895BE3B1136775013EF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>examining the expression of disease traits that result from the interplay of genes and environment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1775290B20424C09B703201B7D9B9120"><enum>(F)</enum><text>exploring physiological mechanisms driving neurodegeneration from toxicant exposures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF68B187382BD419FB6F65E1A445B2E09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination within HHS</header><paragraph id="HDC494E4B78B74AF8B215E9BC34E6857B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HAACEB3C82C69476194C0C5DB7F8BC474"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for coordination across the programs and activities of the Department of Health and Human Services to avoid duplication; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F50EB9EFBB4443881B0099471E0C082"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand the funding of environmental health research by leading an ongoing, coordinated, and focused effort to fund new and existing centers for the study and evaluation of environmental risk factors (including environmental toxicants) of neurodegenerative diseases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA68FCD3145EC4B20BAF4D15371644272"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE45ABEFC59D64AFA9B9BD62AF44B3E9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a biennial report detailing the findings and conclusions of research under this section to—</text><clause id="H7DD89414CE434657B800CCEBC526E52B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate;</text></clause><clause id="HD2044C8E856043F1AA0EBCA89EF2F82C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="H682DFBF828584F55A00BF955262EC190"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF9020D838FE402289C5CCD18E6AE3EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">post each report under subparagraph (A) on the public website of the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FC4E0E466AE4745B425B31AD94A96B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include the information reported pursuant to subparagraph (A) in the triennial report under section 403.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBF33BD31E8D4971B302DA966FA7670A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collaborative Centers for Neurodegenerative Disease Environmental Research</header><paragraph id="H9440A637944A43FF90889BF34A181B57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide for the establishment of research centers, to be known as Collaborative Centers for Neurodegenerative Disease Environmental Research (in this section each referred to as a <quote>Collaborative Center</quote>) at institutions of higher education, medical centers, and other appropriate entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEF8DDC90C664FFEBD43272F2CB6CCFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>With respect to neurodegenerative disease, each Collaborative Center shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF85D4ABDA5244ED0BBDE82D017CF7417"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct and support basic, applied, and clinical research on the effects of environmental risk factors (including environmental toxicants), including with respect to disease progression;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H264A5B8B34F541BA8A701AE44C051411"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use the facilities of a single institution or a consortium of cooperating institutions to administer the Collaborative Centers and meet such qualifications as may be prescribed by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7B7C1F5768C4DEAAEA41E09AAFB34B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be anchored in population-based, environmental health research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6061F9EDC5F4F1999C6054FED8B8AD3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct interdisciplinary and collaborative research that spans basic, applies, population-based, or clinical research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE260BE84A5B42459A105688353C13D4"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with existing intramural and extramural efforts of the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7DD583CB435453E84CA21C7096D8F3A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>collaborate with relevant partners and stakeholders, including researchers, health professionals, nonprofit organizations, patients, and caregivers, to understand the effects of environmental risk factors (including environmental toxicants) of neurodegenerative disease and progression thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7574FB989BC46EA92FB59E3E9BC4800"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Discretionary activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to neurodegenerative diseases, each Collaborative Center may—</text><subparagraph id="H11AA8508BF284A8FAB46B0C5FF9572DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide career enhancement and training opportunities for scientists, researchers, environmental professionals, and health professionals, including through the provision of stipends;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45C0981D610342438A15400F7A0BA1E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct programs to provide information and continuing education to health professionals, including through the provision of stipends;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF807C3E4856C448BA8D04A8F999D1D84"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct programs for the dissemination of information to the public regarding research findings and proposed prevention strategies when appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAAB2E748E6340CCB5919F6327FC8570"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separately or in collaboration with other Collaborative Centers or governmental agencies, establish a nationwide data system that—</text><clause id="H2817E23714EE4EB89F05C9FEA5600E47"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes data derived from comprehensive and representative patient populations with neurodegenerative diseases; and</text></clause><clause id="HB1FE442AC18D4D6F85A4391DBF6544BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>where possible, compares relevant data involving general populations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE6594423594BB0B2F43658F2EF84FA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separately or in collaboration with other Collaborative Centers, establish a clearinghouse, to be known as the Environmental Contributions to Neurodegenerative Disease Information Clearinghouse, to facilitate and enhance knowledge and understanding of environmental risk factors of neurodegenerative diseases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC7384A081B54511A4E53EA538CF674E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separately or in collaboration with other Collaborative Centers, establish a national education program that fosters a national focus on environmental risk factors of neurodegenerative diseases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD5268AB5CC442B862B331BCAC8BBAD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration of support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The period of support for a Collaborative Center under this section shall not exceed 5 years, except that such period may be extended by the Secretary for one or more additional periods of not more than 5 years if—</text><subparagraph id="H7882E0ED39234482895D832793A129E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the operations of such Collaborative Center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD96DDFCE8472485F98EFD415B9EA1FF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such group has recommended to the Secretary that such period should be extended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90E8FA7844A6407F9AC5A7FB78BC2E6F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

