<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E8F38AA45C141FA8D18B66D35449CB7" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 885 IH: Supporting the designation of November 15, 2025, as “America Recycles Day” to raise awareness of, and promote a national discussion about, recycling, and advance the circular economy.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 885</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of November 15, 2025, as <quote>America Recycles Day</quote> to raise awareness of, and promote a national discussion about, recycling, and advance the circular economy.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, every year on November 15, the United States recognizes America Recycles Day to promote recycling, including composting and other circular solutions;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas recycling reduces waste, improves responsible materials management, and bolsters American manufacturing that supports good-paying jobs;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the American recycling sector involves materials across every supply chain, including metal, paper, glass, plastic, and textile, that are essential to the modern economy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the American recycling sector contributes more than $168,000,000,000 to the national economy and supports over 500,000 jobs across the United States;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the American recycling sector enhances national security through the reclamation and reuse of critical materials essential to the national defense;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the American recycling sector strengthens economic competitiveness by supporting domestic manufacturing, creating local jobs, and improving supply chain resilience;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas recycling and circular economy practices promote environmental sustainability by reducing harmful waste, improving energy efficiency in manufacturing, and preserving natural ecosystems;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas public awareness and participation in recycling is essential to achieving a more sustainable and circular future for all Americans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the American recycling sector is made up of stakeholders, including State, municipal, and Tribal governments, nonprofit organizations, private sector partners, communities, and individuals, working together to improve recycling access, education, and circular solutions; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, despite recent progress in recycling and materials recovery, the United States still requires significant investment to fully capture recyclable materials, build circular economies, and close accessibility gaps for all communities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H189F9600D26D4C0F8490EB1AEF8C8E5F"> 
<section id="H6029311256B44C3581FDEA1CFEC43298" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HDAF4E64D55674D9386CAFAAFDE73702D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>America Recycles Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E310D49DC3D4611AAC0E2B005F2311B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the contributions of the American recycling sector, including individuals and communities, in promoting recycling and advancing a circular economy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3E1D15BB2FC4B08A245A5664B1BBC38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to advancing policies and investments that improve recycling to support American manufacturing and environmental sustainability; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H121405785AE04D52883EAA489E61186B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages all Americans to reduce, reuse, and recycle.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

