<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H477257430A664A27BBE3C458629437BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 8686 IH: To amend the Military Land Withdrawals Act of 2013 to withdraw and reserve certain public land in the vicinity of Yuma Proving Ground, Arizona.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8686</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Military Land Withdrawals Act of 2013 to withdraw and reserve certain public land in the vicinity of Yuma Proving Ground, Arizona.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0A0EE4AEC9EB485DABF0E9B56BD3F7BA" style="OLC"><section id="H4C9D880AE99F401293BACB88B2DAA129" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Withdrawal and reservation of lands located on the Yuma Proving Ground, Arizona, to support military readiness and security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Military Land Withdrawals Act of 2013 (title XXIX of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/66">Public Law 113–66</external-xref>; 127 Stat. 1025) is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2567E17A6CD44F809F423B855223F7D3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subtitle id="HBB74371E8A464788A1045BB46AA3331B"><enum>H</enum><header>Yuma Proving Ground, Arizona</header><section id="H6074CE049D7B4B3E844D9DF36F1E1F91"><enum>2999B.</enum><header>Withdrawal and reservation of public land</header><subsection id="H47BD570284B049ED945B0EB7541205C1"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Withdrawal</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights and except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, the public land (including interests in the land) described in subsection (b), and all other areas within the boundary of the land depicted on the map described in that subsection that may become subject to the operation of the public land laws, is withdrawn from—</text>
                            <paragraph id="HAA7C8F86AE1343F7B418769193DA497A">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H6F2C8C9D5C1643519B550E9F3A59B984">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F030BA982CB4A2789C73EF88AC4E1CB"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection><subsection id="HBF6379DDDF85427A9F97DDC5AB861E24">
                            <enum>(b)</enum>
                            <header>Description of land</header>
 <text>The public land (including interests in the land) referred to in subsection (a) consists of—</text>
                            <paragraph id="H4F53A000CEE546649D907DD828406497">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the approximately 21,782.981 acres of Federal land—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D1088EBC9AA4BE7B792302AC719F09D"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">generally depicted as <quote>Highway 95 - Requested Withdrawal Area</quote> on of the map titled <quote>U.S. Army Yuma Proving Ground Withdrawal Highway 95 Withdrawal Area</quote>, sheet 2 of 3, dated March 12, 2025; and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                                <subparagraph id="H64E223FB3D2F46BF985C0E1407371DE4">
                                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>excluding the approximately 800 acres of subsurface estate owned by the State of Arizona within the area generally depicted as <quote>Surface Only Withdrawal/Subsurface Owned by Non-Federal Entity</quote> on the map described in subparagraph (A); and</text>
                                </subparagraph>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H26ABA51287FF425D8BA8D3DC8885C300">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the approximately 249.29 acres of Federal land generally depicted as <quote>Howard Cantonment - Requested Withdrawal Area</quote> on the map titled <quote>U.S. Army Yuma Proving Ground Withdrawal Howard Cantonment Withdrawal Area</quote>, sheet 3 of 3, dated March 12, 2025.</text>
                            </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="H732CF14EA235474B80068BF0CFB707B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reservation; purpose</header><text>The land described in subsection (b) is reserved for use by the Secretary of the Army for the purposes specified in Public Land Order No. 848 of July 1, 1952, and as authorized under section 2914.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5808938EB1DB40C89091E8B85DFADB9E"><enum>2999C.</enum><header>Management of withdrawn and reserved land</header><subsection id="H0F2A02F4FF654BD7ADD41093E518AD31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicable laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall manage the land withdrawn and reserved by section 2999B in accordance with—</text><paragraph id="H27615CA6E3944ABA867C03FEF7EA3506" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subtitle A and this subtitle;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H927EC480A06A4E688152A1A398969C36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85E57E5BDC234A439B76ECA4209619FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E679CE365B6401CB12692D8EE67748C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>To the extent consistent with applicable law and Executive orders, the land withdrawn and reserved by section 2999B may be managed in a manner that permits the following activities:</text><paragraph id="H89991FAFF06D4A8384071FA3B66843D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conservation of wildlife and wildlife habitat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35FE4F4051F94AB298469B4354E3D7A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Preservation of cultural properties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EA70979446B4BD1AD3C6A129D172E53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Management of wild horses and burros.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4621C3B1FB7249F48DBF9B60BD839FE2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Control of predatory and other animals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAA15645298A4D56BAF949B9766ED684"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recreation, public access, and hunting.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F1255AF2774C2DB25458DAE00A6AC3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Prevention and appropriate suppression of brush and range fires resulting from non-military activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H617575FB1D964B1B851224451CE7930F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nondefense uses</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), all nondefense-related uses of the land withdrawn and reserved by section 2999B, shall be subject to any conditions and restrictions that the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Army jointly determine to be necessary to permit the defense-related use of the land for the purposes described in this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2305D8B54C0447158086EF86FC3755B9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Issuance of leases and other land use authorizations</header><paragraph id="HA50C45FFCD7E4124A7C5CC88F89B8F88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall be responsible for the issuance of any lease, easement, right-of-way, permit, license, or other instrument authorized by law with respect to any activity that traverses both—</text><subparagraph id="H5381CFDDA4F84B30906F7A2F2073CC35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public land withdrawn and reserved by section 2999B; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E412C25E41F4A688D5FD739B5097AF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other land in the vicinity of the land withdrawn and reserved by section 2999B that is not under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Army.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H832FF149768247E08FBA2CFE65F23FCB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consent required</header><text>Except as specified in section 2999E, any lease, easement, right-of-way, permit, license, or other instrument issued under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3081CF8D9E53406DA0AE0649E19DF782"><enum>(A)</enum><text>only be issued with the consent of the Secretary of the Army; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C4ADFB3EA4743F3A440AFB3C47E9B8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be subject to such conditions as the Secretary of the Army may require with respect to the land withdrawn and reserved by section 2999B.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H298052F43E9C44B9AE41E3FA0D954D58"><enum>2999D.</enum><header>Assignment of management responsibility to Secretary of the Army</header><subsection id="H3C4D3B85BB3C44928F95126D5F430F55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To assign management responsibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior may assign the management responsibilities for the land withdrawn and reserved by section 2999B to the Secretary of the Army.</text></subsection><subsection id="H290317F9BFA740CEB5915179570F7588"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>On assignment of the management responsibility under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Army shall manage the land in accordance with—</text><paragraph id="H4434A00327EA4D96B8DF64BD37FCBE4B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>subtitle A and this subtitle;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D533DA4C73425589925AB98206F091"><enum>(2)</enum><text>title I of the Sikes Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/670a">16 U.S.C. 670a et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F7CE7B0A1B64264B78F1888F2DC4BA8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC29D2004B7E2425B976FB85B2FF323CE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>cooperative management arrangements entered into by the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of the Army; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7980CF1D24204DA1A499297345E9EA02"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H929B327EA94448DAB8AC88667FA5695C"><enum>2999E.</enum><header>Utility corridor</header><subsection id="H420D22E97DB44EE4B0B9DDD78B5A3BE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Issuance of utility rights-of-Way</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (c) and (d) of section 2999C, the Secretary of the Interior may issue rights-of-way within the Bureau of Land Management designated Parker-Blaisdell Utility Corridor under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) for any critical regional-grid level utility infrastructure to include above-ground transmission lines, consistent with the Memorandum of Understanding between the United States Department of the Interior Bureau of Land Management Yuma Field Office and United States Army Garrison Yuma Regarding the Yuma Proving Ground Highway 95 Withdrawal, dated February 28, 2025.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC3B3C10EFFEF41D2A0ECA7632C46F614"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on delegation</header><text>The authority to issue a right-of-way under subsection (a) may not be delegated below the level of the Bureau of Land Management State Director.</text></subsection><subsection id="H70207ED67A7B4BD6A14838D54F50FF60"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Army consent not required</header> <text>The decision to issue a right-of-way under subsection (a) is not subject to consent by the Secretary of the Army; however, the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of the Army, shall incorporate conditions in any right-of-way issued under subsection (a) as much as practicable to minimize impacts to the mission of the Army.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HA12E90502B4041EAA4BEEE42E6696B19"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The authority to issue rights-of-way under subsection (a) may not be assigned to the Secretary of the Army.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE605817BDC024ED3B4039533DD44A23B"><enum>2999F.</enum><header>Duration of withdrawal and reservation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The withdrawal and reservation of public land made by section 2999B shall be in effect for—</text><paragraph id="H5474C945D4784029B7527AA826597B88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an indefinite period; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H005996F5F6A04C1383B64C763F6FA381"><enum>(2)</enum><text>until the Secretary of the Army determines that there is no longer a military need for the withdrawal and reservation.</text></paragraph></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

