<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF26008-WGF-Y8-R69"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3734 IS: Close the Shadow Banking Loophole Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To address applications for deposit insurance submitted by industrial banks to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Close the Shadow Banking Loophole Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id14D2A59F32144BD6AC0BF5DE310BD60B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Industrial banks</header><subsection id="id24BE0DB5078641B7B45C54F19BB57956"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idE5C312731D4B4C6790B84AB669DF63EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate Federal banking agency</header><text>The term <term>appropriate Federal banking agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3(q) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(q)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD6820AF6F528411C96FC4B8AF43B54C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Corporation</header><text>The term <term>Corporation</term> means the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA0C14C776AC74C049DBD94FF0D79637E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Industrial bank</header><text>The term <term>industrial bank</term> means an entity described in section 2(c)(2)(H) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841(c)(2)(H)</external-xref>), as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75A7F56C2207411A81402CEED467AB4F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception from definition of bank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(c)(2)(H) of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841(c)(2)(H)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting after <quote>similar institution</quote> the following: <quote>which has been approved to receive deposit insurance from the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation on or before September 23, 2021 (or, with respect to such an entity to which section 2(c) of the <short-title>Close the Shadow Banking Loophole Act</short-title> applies, which is in compliance with such section 2(c)), and</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE85118474DDD4B9192DD6E18C2F664EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of deposit insurance applications pending on September 23, 2021</header><paragraph id="H452C9EA6B58C4E1D8E67B21699D5ADDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an industrial bank that, on the date of enactment of this Act, has an application to receive deposit insurance pending before the Corporation that was submitted on or before September 23, 2021, the Corporation—</text><subparagraph id="H7EB0F1D9C38F433C92E9F0811677D72C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall provide for a 90-day public comment period and a public hearing with respect to that application; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A6A5042CB344168B6D3AEE04E9E4966"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only approve that application by a <fraction>2/3</fraction> vote of the members of the Board of Directors of the Corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2001996A17D4A849F4D167F14D33FA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for approving application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Corporation does not approve an application described in paragraph (1) before September 30, 2026, that application shall be deemed to have been denied.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7A0F339CB47B4BBC8895F35B7016D800"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Except to the extent explicitly provided in this subsection, this subsection may not be construed to affect the authority of the Corporation to consider deposit insurance applications under sections 5 and 6 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1815">12 U.S.C. 1815</external-xref>, 1816).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6AA1D6C7C2C64CAFBB19D70BC8485F00"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Authority with respect To deposit insurance applications granted after September 23, 2021</header> <paragraph id="H6F5BEF46090643D191502176747532DD"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Definitions</header> <text>In this subsection:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H960067609C684250AB17301F6790CDBE">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Bank; depository institution</header>
 <text>The terms <term>bank</term> and <term>depository institution</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841</external-xref>), as amended by this section.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idB3501DFBA6994E34A4C36B1ABC921669">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Covered industrial loan company</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered industrial loan company</term> means an industrial bank that has an application to receive deposit insurance from the Corporation approved after September 23, 2021.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" id="id422C451A823040ACB3A1468C7E45A860">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
            <header>Parent company</header>
 <text>The term <term>parent company</term> means an entity that has control over a covered industrial loan company.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H41BA025DD1494A7887C105D7921EB3D6">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
            <header>Primary financial regulatory agency</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a parent company, the term <term>primary financial regulatory agency</term>—</text>
            <clause id="H428DB63C19F9441ABD83DE6D97E526A5">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref>); and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="HA9B9B80CB47442E7A67F4A98D44E605C">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a parent company for which clause (i) does not apply, means the Corporation.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HADCA336B0FA142638EBBBEE47212C8A4">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Authority</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The primary financial regulatory agency with respect to a parent company may take any of the following actions with respect to the parent company:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H05757F618C614C128CD2A3EF2136E71D">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Conduct such examinations of, and obtain reports from, the parent company or any subsidiary of the parent company (other than a bank) as the agency determines necessary or appropriate to assess each of the following:</text>
            <clause id="H6F1C62D6945948709BD62E32A64A90F1">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>The financial condition of the parent company or subsidiary.</text> </clause> <clause id="H827406B1915849CD87D3E0D55C020CDD"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The systems of the parent company or subsidiary for maintaining and controlling financial and operating risks.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="H0122963BACC54FA89234CC99C3E451F5">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The transactions of the parent company or subsidiary with depository institution subsidiaries of the parent company.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HF17ABDFC792649599370DF134F7B6E54">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Impose any conditions or restrictions on the parent company or any subsidiary of the parent company (other than a bank), including restricting or prohibiting transactions between the parent company or subsidiary and any depository institution subsidiary of the parent company, if those conditions or restrictions would promote the safety and soundness of the parent company or any of its depository institution subsidiaries.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id6F43D7C195564ECFA2721AF7E4783968"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Change of control</header><paragraph id="id4EA141A9528F4CD0A2752AE13BDA40A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the appropriate Federal banking agency shall disapprove a change in control, as provided in section 7(j) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1817">12 U.S.C. 1817(j)</external-xref>), of an industrial bank.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5CB12BEB1B2D40F29F7CBD81DE5780C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a change in control of an industrial bank—</text><subparagraph id="idC38D6A752203424AA724DF84BE40255B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="idE3BAE491621C49548F6DF1451AD45ECB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is in danger of default, as determined by the appropriate Federal banking agency, provided that the entity acquiring control of the industrial bank is an entity described in clause (iii);</text></clause><clause id="id34D78CEFDE7B452FA44DE96FF779EFB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>results from the acquisition of voting shares of an issuer that controls the industrial bank and the securities of which are listed on a national securities exchange, if, after the acquisition, the acquiring shareholder (or group of shareholders acting in concert) holds less than 25 percent of any class of the voting shares of, and does not otherwise exercise control over, that issuer; or</text></clause><clause id="id9DD3A52FBADD4D7B82225BA7746D14DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>will be controlled, directly or indirectly, by an entity subject to consolidated supervision by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System as a—</text><subclause id="id3CA255DB6A1F43C38CF29C1DDEA7DE9F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>bank holding company;</text></subclause><subclause id="idC07BF9DD5E074BCEBE771737B94BEB47"><enum>(II)</enum><text>savings and loan holding company; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id7372A236B4B74C2DBC9C1E23920F0AFC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>foreign bank that is treated, as of July 1, 2020, as a bank holding company under the International Banking Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3101">12 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74C6DF99AE6B4B80BE90E6B8E53F4F4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that has obtained all regulatory approvals otherwise required with respect to the change in control under any applicable Federal or State law, including section 7(j) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1817">12 U.S.C. 1817(j)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC178C7DCEDD649B4B8A6B65B75B92DEB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Supervision of parent companies of industrial loan companies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1841">12 U.S.C. 1841 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 5 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1844">12 U.S.C. 1844</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61EB68FDD59840B9A4FED9F567992D74"><section id="HDEC7997F878A44668561D1F195813D85"><enum>6.</enum><header>Supervision of parent companies of industrial loan companies</header><subsection id="id376EA04F560E4DA7AE76221EE2214B7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id4CE33F537B50449BB14DC5173A2E5365"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Corporation</header><text>The term <term>Corporation</term> means the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id090647D9CC89473CB1070356A1780212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Parent company of an industrial loan company</header><text>The term <term>parent company of an industrial loan company</term> means a company—</text><subparagraph id="id15ECE9B065144C2BACC487452796D308"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is not directly or indirectly subject to a primary financial regulatory agency (as defined in section 2 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5A8E4D6EDFD44EAA942346419E731771"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that has control over an entity that—</text><clause id="idF6307A0BD8474B96AC6482B8F95101EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an industrial loan company, industrial bank, or other similar institution;</text></clause><clause id="idF3EA4B0AD3D04C5EB38085A84ECE6079"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not a bank; and</text></clause><clause id="idB8DEE469D9E54BE79AF2276D811391FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not a person regulated by a State insurance regulator, as that term is defined in section 1002 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3573155A98B4E2F94084E58723FB2B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority relating to a parent company of an industrial loan company</header><paragraph id="H76A0BC3D5FEF475B8BACE780B2C786F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Corporation shall have the same authority to require a parent company of an industrial loan company (or a subsidiary of such a parent company) to make reports and submit to examinations as the Board has with respect to a bank holding company or a subsidiary of a bank holding company.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03FC619B7C8848549E5344D0BC98AEB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the report and examination authority described in paragraph (1) and with respect to the parent company of an industrial loan company that has been approved to receive deposit insurance from the Corporation on or before September 23, 2021, the Corporation shall tailor any requirements to the size, complexity, and nature of the business of that parent company.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF38B16E586E34C4B9FF8F743F003E04F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation may, using the authorities under section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818</external-xref>), enforce the report and examination authority under this section with respect to a parent company of an industrial loan company (or a subsidiary of such a parent company) to the same extent as the Board may enforce the report and examination authority of the Board with respect to a bank holding company or a subsidiary of a bank holding company.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H84C2DBC57AA248429EF5E312385422D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as a reduction of the authority of the Corporation, as in effect on the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id31A28FE94BE0450B95839095ECDA53F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation may issue rules to implement this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" id="HD6BA59CBF21F4AD8AB9FC1379632AD7A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Application with respect to contracts and other agreements</header><subsection commented="no" id="id824521A823A14E35BE3D630DEBF70AE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>industrial loan company</term> means an industrial loan company, industrial bank, or other similar institution.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id2C49382647B2455E96C637B35EFB90AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, may not be construed to affect or impair—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HF96B3E0FCE5A468BB3A422EAE4B9F44F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authority of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation to enter into any agreement with a parent company of an industrial loan company (as defined in section 6 of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956, as added by section 3 of this Act) or an industrial loan company, or to impose any condition in connection with the approval by the Corporation of an application; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD45213DE71A34D48B104D92A7E374C16"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the validity of any agreement described in paragraph (1) entered into before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

