<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B1A8683370A4D05A211F5F53A9C04CA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1198 IH: Recognizing that stable housing keeps families together.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1198</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001245">Mr. Menefee</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing that stable housing keeps families together.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas stable housing is defined as a fundamental human right, encompassing the right to access and sustain safe, affordable, and adequate housing;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas stable housing demands a secure and consistent space which enables individuals and families to rest, maintain personal hygiene, and pursue educational and employment opportunities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the definition of stable housing extends beyond homelessness to address challenges such as substandard living conditions, overcrowding, and the risk of eviction;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas a family is defined as a group of two people or more related by birth, marriage, adoption, or an affinity whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship transcending the boundaries of immigration status, race, color, religion, sex, sexuality, gender identity, economic class, or country of origin;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas stable housing keeps families together and is a foundational element for family well-being, emotional, and mental health;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Nation is facing a housing affordability crisis with safe stable housing out of reach for families across the country;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a family with mixed immigration status can be defined as a family whose members are a mix of United States citizens and individuals with various legal immigration statuses;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) recognizes in its analysis that removing mixed status families will decrease rather than increase affordable housing for everyone;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Trump administration’s proposal to ban families with mixed immigration status from HUD states HUD denies eligible individuals from living with their ineligible family members, forcing impacted households to choose between separating to keep their subsidy or face eviction and potentially homelessness as a family;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Trump administration is using the mixed-status rule to evict immigrant families from their homes and push their anti-immigrant agenda;</text></whereas> 
<whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the proposed rule does nothing to improve housing affordability across the country, and instead would cause nearly 80,000 families to lose their housing assistance, including nearly 37,000 children;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas housing providers would be forced to evict families with mixed immigration status instead of keeping properties safe and supporting residents;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas separating families with mixed immigration status would increase homelessness and make it harder for communities across the Nation to address the housing crisis;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this rule change would affect all HUD tenants, including millions of people who are citizens living in some of the biggest Federal housing programs, not just families who have mixed immigration status;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this rule change would subject HUD residents who are United States citizens to running their personal information through a flawed system at the Department of Homeland Security and jeopardize their housing security;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas ripping apart, evicting, or forcing families with mixed immigration status into homelessness would worsen the housing crisis;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas families with mixed immigration status in the United States seek the promise of freedom and opportunity that all of us cherish;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas housing stability cannot exist without policies that protect families of all immigration status, race, color, religion, sex, sexuality, gender identity, economic class, or country of origin; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States has the resources to ensure every individual and family, immigrant or otherwise, have the freedom to live where we want and take care of our families, without fear of being evicted: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD4CD36E5CDCF4C83A8106BDF9B34A201"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8C3429DD26DF485C9749E11906043EE3"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFA49B19EDED341E886AF25CA8CB466F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affirms that housing is a fundamental human right and that Federal housing programs keep families together, regardless of immigration status;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02E318F6A5A14DBF8321B74B5F10AC6C"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>affirms that families who have mixed immigration status should be able to continue receiving prorated benefits and living together in public housing and section 8 housing without the threat of forced separation or eviction in accordance with section 214 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1980 and the underlying congressional intent;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD86462D41D7343659D614838BBB4EEA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms that to address the housing crisis and ensure everyone in our nation has a safe and stable place to call home, the Trump administration should work with Congress to make significant new investments in the Federal housing programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF146D3AC7144219A38AE218C0CA73A9"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>condemns the Trump administration’s proposal circumventing this established law and prohibiting families with mixed immigration status from receiving prorated housing assistance or living in Federal housing programs like public housing and Section 8;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD149E0EF59234FA8A9BCCC8C14D03851"><enum>(5)</enum><text>condemns policies that scapegoat people who are immigrants, people of color, and low-income families for the housing crisis instead of addressing systematic causes such as wage stagnation, rising rents, and the lack of affordable housing supply;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28679CFA1E3948DFB037F1C82DD1EF22"><enum>(6)</enum><text>condemns policies that do not protect immigrants and keep families whole and housed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82C7EB79B6244C76AD288E0F5A6C4427"><enum>(7)</enum><text>calls on the Government Accountability Office to conduct oversight and issue a report on the impact of the Trump administration’s proposal on its effects on family separation, homelessness, and housing affordability, including to United States citizen children;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD88AAF755BA44CA869D481738B920B4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>calls on Congress to increase funding for Housing Choice Vouchers and Housing First initiatives to directly address the housing crisis;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B00F1E1440745F382AF4F8F6239DEA7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>condemns HUD Secretary Scott Turner for advancing policies that threaten family unity, worsen homelessness, and undermine the mission of HUD to provide safe, stable, and affordable housing for all; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4CE932B3FF7B4612BCF46259156ACA31"><enum>(10)</enum><text>calls on the Secretary of HUD to withdraw the proposed rule entitled <quote>Housing and Community Development Act of 1980: Verification of Eligible Status</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

