<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25M91-9K3-7V-DJH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3449 IS: Notification of Troop Involvement and Congressional Engagement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3449</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for limitations on domestic deployments of National Guard members.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idf969185498ef4cd5aa2ec11cc5f995ee" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Notification of Troop Involvement and Congressional Engagement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NOTICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69fe81cca1ae40fd85b53564ef8fc0f6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on domestic deployments of National Guard members</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12406 of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="ida631f3c66c714f898794d1e825e12933"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Whenever</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) <header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">In general</header-in-text>.—Whenever</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6273c23ca32c4a92bfd7ff1209ea9f36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30d74c8326964a07b58978c698977dd3"><subsection id="id11039DDEAC764AC691CC6E6388B77947"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3cd4dc94bc214d2a92c50d150e42f1cd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 24 hours before calling into Federal service members and units of the National Guard of any State under subsection (a), the President shall notify Congress of the planned deployment.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dc5aabb9109481eb08882f66b16b416" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall assert a good-faith claim for federalizing the National Guard and describe with specificity—</text><subparagraph id="id4d93a87e670546e18fa152a37a64d6d1"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idf25e2df327d34766b00f54a685407156"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the invasion, including the United States territory, the foreign power, and the act or acts of the foreign power that constitute an invasion necessitating the use of authority pursuant to subsection (a)(1);</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ab9eddf627944179faf3dc1f2c520ef"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rebellion against the authority of the Government of the United States, including the place and time of the rebellion, the person, persons, or group engaged in the rebellion, and the activities of those engaged in the rebellion necessitating the use of authority pursuant to subsection (a)(2); or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23264d1a28b24f3facc06bf46c0163c3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the laws of the United States which the President is unable to execute, the reasons that regular forces are unable to execute the law, and, where the President is taking such action without the consent of the Governor of the State, evidence of the Governor’s inability or refusal to provide for the safety and welfare of the public, or the Governor’s refusal to obey a court order, or other active steps the Governor has taken to obstruct the President from faithfully executing the law; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc3598f85c872402c99fb67514240941d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the geographical area where the National Guard will be called to and the duration of the federalization of the National Guard;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70c5472cde2342238bb099970d98adb5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the training received by the National Guard unit or units expected to be deployed and interacting with civilian populations, including restrictions under section 1385 of title 18; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8092fef35aa840b490eed041f1cffc1c"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the chain of command the National Guard unit or units will be placed under and their requirements to communicate with state and local forces.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9dc2bc77ca0c4e6cadeef2c633e280a9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification requirement for longer deployments</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id25ee1af839264ca682a48a09b61fc3d5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a deployment under this section lasts longer than 48 hours, the President shall notify Congress of the continued deployment in writing and provide subsequent updates every 72 hours thereafter.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef6313b4d5ab42f4a6f3f84ffe8dd058" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice required under paragraph (1) shall assert a good-faith claim for the continued deployment of the National Guard and describe with specificity the conditions described under subsection (b)(2), including any changes to the conditions since the prior notice.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

