<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON26285-770-RP-C7C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4582 IS: Ensuring Access to General Surgery Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4582</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to the designation of general surgery shortage areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H9789FE3718EF4E2E903B1E495164BCF9"><section section-type="section-one" id="H71808FA983BA470A90EA30D8E744CE65"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Access to General Surgery Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1C57CFB9E8FA467AB59D4D801E7C6E83"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HC424F209C46D4C88B7068E43C7303B48"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Bureau of Health Workforce, the United States faces a shortage of physicians.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id07af8d4e2d3045de8592880ff19ce2a3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A 2016 study entitled <quote>Supply and Demand of General Surgeons: Projections From 2014–2030</quote>, prepared by the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill for the American College of Surgeons, found that the supply of general surgeons will grow slightly by 2030 but will not keep up with overall growth in the United States population or demand for surgical services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c7ca832a31b4df990a4e25f377c018e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A 2021 report released by the Association of American Medical Colleges projects shortages in all surgical specialties of between 15,800 and 30,200 surgeons by 2034.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc23b5ed80b644d27a65d0fdd0a71dc8a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A 2020 report prepared by the Health Resources and Services Administration for the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate found a maldistribution of general surgeons nationwide, with rural areas having only 69 percent of the general surgeons needed to meet demand for care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf8cd031cbbad49f79ed24552a69755e8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In order to accurately prepare for future physician workforce demands, comprehensive, impartial research and high-quality data are needed to inform dynamic projections of physician workforce needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04435f43307a40af989b17499cf73ee4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A variety of factors, including health outcomes, utilization trends, growing and aging populations, and delivery system changes, influence workforce needs and should be considered as part of flexible projections of workforce needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6929db3198ee4043a4dc4b53b461d3d4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Given the particularly acute needs in many rural and other surgical workforce shortage areas, additional efforts to assess the adequacy of the current general surgeon workforce are necessary.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8AB0521F581749948A996E22013E9175"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on designation of general surgical health professional shortage areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE5698949964C414F82D505D360273231"><subpart id="id016C0AD576534BE5A7C78163F6208439" style="OLC"> <enum>XIII</enum> <header>General Surgery Shortage Areas</header> <section id="idBB10BD3A0A5141F8896E52B1B67BA70C"> <enum>340J.</enum> <header>Designation of general surgery shortage areas</header> <subsection id="H0DF80D8A506F4E7EA4089CB001D5F51F"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>General surgery shortage area defined</header> <text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>general surgery shortage area</term> means, with respect to an urban, suburban, or rural area in the United States, an area that has a population that is underserved by general surgeons.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H623BC07F391140AC9E55DAFC896A7834">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Study and report</header>
              <paragraph id="idEDDD1F1595EB47FBA21535C0058E42FB">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Study</header>
 <text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall conduct a study on the following matters relating to access by underserved populations to general surgeons:</text>
                <subparagraph id="id62125830c9ab4db1b34f6cb1b1fbdab8">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Whether current shortage designations, such as the designation of health professional shortage areas under section 332, results in accurate assessments of the adequacy of local general surgeons to address the needs of underserved populations in urban, suburban, or rural areas.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idc183e2f8974d4631b8121fa1bdc91283">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Whether another measure of access to general surgeons by underserved populations, such as one based on general surgeons practicing within hospital service areas, would provide more accurate assessments of shortages in the availability of local general surgeons to meet the needs of those populations.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="idf912afbe91324b4b989523a0051fec96">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Potential methodologies for the designation of general surgery shortage areas, including the methodology described in paragraph (2).</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HF10BAAF2215C48EB8B708B0299E4B432">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Methodology for the designation of areas</header>
 <text>Among the methodologies considered under paragraph (1)(C) for the designation of general surgery shortage areas, the Secretary shall analyze the effectiveness and accuracy of the following methodology:</text>
                <subparagraph id="H7EDB253991184A108125ABD8EA6BD936">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
                  <header>Development of surgery service areas</header>
 <text>Development of surgery service areas through the identification of hospitals with surgery services and the identification of populations by ZIP Code areas using Medicare patient origin data.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H580B4EAF868245268CD3EA44C0D3528E">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
                  <header>Identification of surgeons</header>
 <text>Identification of all actively practicing general surgeons.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB620A4949D44439B57901021B61960C"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Surgeon to population ratios</header> <text>Development of general surgeon-to-population ratios for each surgery service area.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HAAB2DC17918D448DA4449CA419D6AEC8">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
                  <header>Thresholds</header>
                  <clause id="idCD35435C13AC401996F3C3DAC17113B2">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Determination of threshold general surgeon-to-population ratios for the number of general surgeons necessary to treat a population for each of the following levels:</text>
                    <subclause id="H65A270393D7D4F16BEFD8F25F1C2EDC3">
                      <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Optimal supply of general surgeons.</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H43BA6FAA88914AD5B2008A028A656713"> <enum>(II)</enum> <text>Adequate supply of general surgeons.</text>
                    </subclause>
                    <subclause id="HC3953BE1325840FCB2A31393C2155C40">
                      <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>Shortage of general surgeons.</text> </subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7B5E3655021465E9356080588C62F0D"> <enum>(IV)</enum> <text>Critical shortage of general surgeons.</text>
                    </subclause>
                  </clause>
                  <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                    id="id0F48402D3FF54FC88CFFDF6FEE24E6AB">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
                    <header>Considerations</header>
 <text>In determining the thresholds under clause (i), the Secretary shall not assume that the current supply of general surgeons nationwide is the optimal or adequate level and shall consider additional factors such as wait times, health outcomes, ground transportation time to the nearest health care center with a general surgeon, critical access hospitals with surgical capabilities but lacking a general surgeon, and patient experience.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HD03DBC07FF4E457CA507E67D5E344219">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subpart, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under this subsection.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="idfe894c75ea054e64a50e78e3a7429dba">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
                <header>Consultation</header>
 <text>In conducting the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with relevant stakeholders, including medical societies, organizations representing surgical facilities, organizations with expertise in general surgery, and organizations representing patients.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="id225FBFF049CF429C94E9C040F98EB5EB">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
                <header>Publication of data</header>
 <text>The Secretary shall periodically collect and publish in the Federal Register—</text>
                <subparagraph id="id3E1E990CF89245A6A99163AD573FF735">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>data comparing the availability and need of general surgery services in urban, suburban, or rural areas in the United States; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id9E42C34F7E2D49628E57682840EA170A">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>if the Secretary designates one or more general surgery shortage areas under subsection (c), a list of the areas so designated.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="H5479283A81D04B3ABA65F81CD8A01F3A">
              <enum>(c)</enum>
              <header>Designation of general surgery shortage areas</header>
              <paragraph id="idf44a92f93c424d09a235d1c3db90331c">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>Methodology developed through regulation</header>
 <text>Based on the findings of the report under subsection (b)(3), the Secretary may establish, through notice and comment rulemaking, a methodology for the designation of general surgery shortage areas under this section.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="id32CC472E4B594567B8DF3EEB091C3385">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Requirements</header>
 <text>If the Secretary elects to develop a methodology under paragraph (1), the following shall apply:</text>
                <subparagraph id="ida19800a9f7814b9da28e944cf57250d6">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Using the methodology established under paragraph (1) and taking into consideration the data referred to in subsection (b)(5), the Secretary shall—</text>
                  <clause id="idbfe907bccb1b4e7697fcf2c3b3d78cbc">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>designate general surgery shortage areas in the United States;</text> </clause> <clause id="idf22976c4d6f946efa48b01db5a7a3913"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>publish a descriptive list of the areas; and</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="id246c31a0e27446cf8ca028e4e7e57a5c">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>review annually, and, as necessary, revise such designations.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id7f10c5088ba044b8b95db83096e64daa"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>The Secretary shall follow similar procedures with respect to notice to appropriate parties, opportunities for comment, dissemination of information, and reports to Congress in designating general surgery shortage areas under this section as those that apply to the designation of health professional shortage areas under section 332.</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3E3ADF7AE78E437FA5324617279958EA">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>In designating general surgery shortage areas under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with relevant stakeholders, including medical societies, organizations representing surgical facilities, organizations with expertise in general surgery, and organizations representing patients.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection>
          </section>
        </subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

