<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE5BF21007ED4497DAB3B9CA3D3EA50C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9656 IH: Illegal Alien Patient Reporting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9656</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require hospitals participating in Federal health care programs to report certain information related to immigration status.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H516707CC08D3480CB6966455F3F9DC04" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H62EF51DD339E4B6FBA974831C98CCABE" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Illegal Alien Patient Reporting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H06EF9D35DF80407A90F3E5865D02A87F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring hospitals participating in Federal health care programs to report certain information related to immigration status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title XI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1301">42 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 1128K the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H56311C526EFE41AEA3D6721C3287229E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HAEA06748F0FF4815ADC99396807F6466"><enum>1128L.</enum><header>Requiring hospitals to report certain information related to immigration status</header> 
<subsection id="HC03F5462E1174BAA9E3A3534B9D2F276"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall exclude a hospital from participation in any Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B(f)) if such hospital does not meet the requirements under <internal-xref idref="H03F135747F8A4852B7A990F880915753" legis-path="1128L.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H03F135747F8A4852B7A990F880915753"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Immigration status reporting requirements</header><text>For purposes of <internal-xref idref="HC03F5462E1174BAA9E3A3534B9D2F276" legis-path="1128L.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, the requirements under this subsection are, with respect to a hospital, the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB946FBF102C5475AACE1FCB2EBE0C7AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any admission, registration, or other intake form issued by the hospital includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H339089828B494B888C8D74BA5B0B4CE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a request that the patient (or the patient’s authorized representative) indicate the patient’s immigration status; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1A9EAE1ED276426AA3FFECC121969246"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement immediately following the request described in <internal-xref idref="H339089828B494B888C8D74BA5B0B4CE8" legis-path="1128L.(b)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> that the response to such request will not affect patient care or result in a report of the patient’s immigration status to a law enforcement entity unless the patient is an alien suspected of or charged with—</text> <clause id="H23C5CC6EA31B4704865539276D44BB05"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any State or local criminal offense; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD5D69AFEE04A4FA0B393C2094F5C3588"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any offense under section 274, 275, or 276 of the Immigration and Nationality Act or under title 18, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4149D589076A4ECAADE12207AC7B816A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In the case that a patient (or the patient’s authorized representative) indicates in response to a request under <internal-xref idref="H339089828B494B888C8D74BA5B0B4CE8" legis-path="1128L.(b)(1)(A)">paragraph (1)(A)</internal-xref> that the patient is an alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act, the hospital requests to review documentary evidence of such lawful admission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB07DF7A6F63A4B9AB60FE9EEB1BE6189"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Not later than 30 days after the last day of each calendar quarter, the hospital submits a report to the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Homeland Security that includes, with respect to all patients that were admitted to such hospital (or visited the emergency department of such hospital) during such quarter—</text> <subparagraph id="HB2011EEF3ECF485BA132378D6BE25006"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of patients that declined to respond to the request under <internal-xref idref="H339089828B494B888C8D74BA5B0B4CE8" legis-path="1128L.(b)(1)(A)">paragraph (1)(A)</internal-xref>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBB8FC597A7F4174B22DB2D1D2368266"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of patients that indicated in response to such request that they were—</text> <clause id="H8DB9407A3C794ABBA5063274D5B1DD36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a citizen or national of the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H03FA72CF0F334A29B30E6BD2891EEA8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who is lawfully admitted for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></clause> <clause id="H18A4A1870A3E43738FF6054F68222584"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>lawfully present in the United States with status as a nonimmigrant;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H7BE60A51A1214E78B5099EF0048C3A51"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>otherwise lawfully present in the United States, including on the basis of—</text> <subclause id="H917D382B3A8044F0881DF09673653B71"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">temporary protected status granted under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDEACDC44EFFE4C8789D22979B5E145AE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>deferred action or deferred enforced departure, including pursuant to the memorandum of the Department of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion with Respect to Individuals Who Came to the United States as Children</quote> issued on June 15, 2012;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2D35A2BAFB054AD899FE86A1B7BCD4F8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>asylum granted under section 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAEB6B270462143DF9C54E6B31EAF2DAA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>parole granted under section 212(d)(5) or 236(a)(2)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD70604CFCAC74FE2AA40D98EFB0D2864"><enum>(V)</enum><text>withholding of removal granted under section 241(b)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H517FD45BB1B2482D8765BB1CB4814FC5"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>status as a Cuban and Haitian entrant, as defined in section 501(e) of the Refugee Education Assistance Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/422">Public Law 96–422</external-xref>);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD66B7DEA49F5465B8ED95D2F1B17A4E3"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>special immigrant juvenile status granted under section 101(a)(27)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF95E290CA76B4700809B85D565E80BFA"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>protection under the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9113D2A07E2A4703BFF35771BFB66C4F"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not lawfully present in the United States (including whether they were an unaccompanied alien child (as defined in section 462(g)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002)); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75ABF40E7D934B518350F515092526D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of patients that indicated in response to such request that they were an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act, and failed to provide documentary evidence of such lawful admission in response to the request under <internal-xref idref="H4149D589076A4ECAADE12207AC7B816A" legis-path="1128L.(b)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H63E502747DCF42FDA5535FD8A9D1AFB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than October 1 of each year (beginning with 2026), the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H822B18F54C074733955E04D7A90A9795"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the information reported by all hospitals under <internal-xref idref="HB07DF7A6F63A4B9AB60FE9EEB1BE6189" legis-path="1128L.(b)(2)">subsection (b)(2)</internal-xref>, aggregated over the preceding calendar year; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77EE004B69574071AE4F1657409A3F3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information related to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE7D76ADF7D2A4DCDB9327E97ECA164B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs of uncompensated care for individuals who are not lawfully present in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0D976F3824F4EDD892090E5F6973815"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact of such uncompensated care on hospitals’ ability to provide services to the public (and the cost of such services);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F16C3C545404824AFF65C11CD5D4A7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hospitals’ funding needs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE3878FCEF234C5999AB973326732B56"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other related information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H244C5B51C6944D14803A2444D384FD5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, may issue such rules as are necessary relating to the requirements under <internal-xref idref="H03F135747F8A4852B7A990F880915753" legis-path="1128L.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>. Such rules may not require hospitals to disclose to either Secretary any patient names or other personal identifying information.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

