<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26681-YFD-J0-C7D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S5018 IS: Disaster Relief Fairness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 5018</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To approve certain requests for a major disaster declaration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disaster Relief Fairness Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id97e671d397234a48aaa66265876ace67"><enum>2.</enum><header>Approval of major disaster declaration requests</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id106ef6d7e0a54246996b22d4b155b75a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87f58d3b63b2412bb6b6e65d2ee4b7be"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Covered period</header> <text>The term <term>covered period</term> means the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on January 20, 2029.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2495621a708d43b0a5ee75d156ff9019"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered request</header><text>The term <term>covered request</term> means a request for a declaration by the President that a major disaster exists that is submitted by the Governor of a State or a Chief Executive of an Indian tribal government under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>) during the covered period.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id518a8cee873c402a8c3728a99186fb61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Governor; Indian tribal government; major disaster; State</header><text>The terms <term>Governor</term>, <term>Indian tribal government</term>, <term>major disaster</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 102 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dabb82d2e6345f0b347f50e06e7fbf4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Declaration of major disasters during covered period</header><text>Notwithstanding the last sentence of subsection (a) and subsection (b)(1) of section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>), for purposes of assistance provided under that Act—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b3fb7f24ba8403e942849e27e9cfc89"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any covered request shall be deemed to have been approved by the President; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id097dacd591ea4335a09b57be6f69c935"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the President shall provide the assistance requested in the covered request—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf140be87ee944f3893eab0d7b84af49b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the incident in the covered request, based on the joint preliminary damage assessment of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, meets or exceeds the per capita indicators or cost of assistance estimates for public assistance under section 206.48(a) of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f1647cd862449a59f90a3e134e64195"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Regional Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for the region in which the incident in the covered request occurred determines that individual assistance is warranted, according to the factors outlined in section 206.48(b) of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28c2655c795c455f8a3f3d6cc4a9411d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No denial of assistance</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may not withhold or deny assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to a covered request solely due to a missed deadline relating to that assistance.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

