<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A30CEA821D1485B99142E80FE902CCE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6981 IH: Streamlining Home Installation of New Energies Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6981</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108">January 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to further develop and support the adoption of a voluntary streamlined permitting and inspection process for authorities having jurisdiction over the permitting of qualifying distributed energy systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H51EE59B7BE684306B860E17C76123A5C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB8DEC7E956214DE88F3CAD0443EA74FD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Streamlining Home Installation of New Energies Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SHINE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE27022ADA0D9476598C2E46CF2629C67" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of program to facilitate voluntary streamlined process for local permitting of qualifying distributed energy systems</header> <subsection id="H836585BE74924994AA48F2E1F0E3AEB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7AAB946828264944A373A49C31EE91F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority having jurisdiction</header><text>The term <term>authority having jurisdiction</term> means any State, county, local, or Tribal office or official with jurisdiction—</text> <subparagraph id="H3656877189D94E2BAAC6BFB62CB6D772"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to issue permits relating to qualifying distributed energy systems;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BEFC77A033241C9BFD35961368F3ACC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conduct inspections to enforce the requirements of a relevant code or standard relating to qualifying distributed energy systems; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40A807401A8C4BA3B29A75ED4BCB8017"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to approve the installation of, or the equipment and materials used in the installation of, qualifying distributed energy systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CE8B9AD7B6945878CB11FBEBE554959"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying distributed energy system</header><text>The term <term>qualifying distributed energy system</term> means any equipment or materials installed in, on, or near a residential building to support onsite or local energy use, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H08217E96B9C14B6488DB3D5EE98A736B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to generate electricity from distributed renewable energy sources, including from—</text> 
<clause id="H65FDEDB159244F47A86407A175170B7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>solar photovoltaic systems or similar solar energy technologies; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5EB849054F52483DADB9F8475A526695"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>wind power systems;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B6ABEC4982A4A5BBB59F765B0F9F869"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to store and discharge electricity from batteries with a capacity of at least 2 kilowatt hours;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E9F426855384940B0DDE3606E247C16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to charge a plug-in electric drive vehicle at a power rate of at least 2 kilowatts; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61B35C959D5B49CEA5E49828317806C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to refuel a hydrogen fuel cell electric vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F42D5D069274C928FA53884FBC2C6F0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H271CFE64F8DD40B29A3F491E40A8DB08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with trade associations and other entities representing distributed energy system installers and organizations representing State, local, and Tribal governments engaged in permitting, shall carry out a program to further develop, expand, and support the adoption of a voluntary streamlined permitting and inspection process for authorities having jurisdiction to use for the permitting of qualifying distributed energy systems.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H95A0C887F3984F048582A21F26790DC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities of the program</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H98030962C5A64F389CE929638140F4F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>further develop and expand an exemplary streamlined permitting process that includes an online permitting platform—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E41C11B5184489192A62B7492DA1724"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for expediting, standardizing, and streamlining permitting; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2FD808F737F4AD088E29DF1DE841564"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that authorities having jurisdiction may voluntarily use to receive, review, and approve permit applications relating to qualifying distributed energy systems;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F6E467639C248BCBBD96ECD111098FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish targets for the adoption of a streamlined, expedited permitting process by authorities having jurisdiction;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6091DE2B992446E7BD27EA577D2755C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance and training directly or indirectly to authorities having jurisdiction on using and adopting the exemplary streamlined permitting process described in paragraph (1), including the adoption of any necessary building codes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD343C860A7294B2F9C1BEA1BCFBD1AB3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop a voluntary inspection protocol and related tools to expedite, standardize, and streamline the inspection of qualifying distributed energy systems, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H61BF38B0F5474C728D5E548FA8DD514A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by investigating the potential for using remote inspections;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9C4EFED5FE34C639155AC88B6D82BD3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by investigating the potential for sample-based inspection for distributed energy system installers with a demonstrated track record of high-quality work; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB2F319120904B8D8E977F0748BEEE03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by investigating opportunities to integrate the voluntary inspection protocol into the online permitting platform described in paragraph (1) and the platforms of government software providers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD640CE6C00BB4675998525F3D615BC50"><enum>(5)</enum><text>take any other action to expedite, standardize, streamline, or improve the process for permitting, inspecting, or interconnecting qualifying distributed energy systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A799CD4F369450295D81B5E9EB3168B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support services</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H226076940A43497585F518AA6B305504"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the provision of technical assistance to authorities having jurisdiction, any administrator of the online permitting platform described in subsection (c)(1), government software providers, and any other entity determined appropriate by the Secretary in carrying out the activities described in subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H539475997D1F410A943FCE25514C9127"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide such financial assistance as the Secretary determines appropriate from any funds appropriated to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3F3AE3D1B50340149C620CE89C78120D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authority having jurisdiction certification program</header> <paragraph id="H4396F9113418491F83A951E963BE4120"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may certify authorities having jurisdiction that implement the exemplary streamlined permitting process described in subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6DB0FDC8F5748E89EC1AAF94D22ACC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The Secretary may confer a certification under paragraph (1) through existing programs within the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24048D1B9DD841588FA843B299973B1F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prizes</header><text>The Secretary may award prizes to authorities having jurisdiction, using funds appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section, to encourage authorities having jurisdiction to adopt the exemplary streamlined permitting process or the voluntary inspection protocol established under paragraphs (1) and (4) of subsection (c), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E6F85498969435FBD3F1591243D5D37"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

