<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H34C6E1D88EB04CBEA4D04651F28B96E2" public-private="public" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 146 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States requiring Members of Congress to demonstrate competence in American civics.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">2d Session</session>
        <legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 146</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20260130">January 30, 2026</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</sponsor> submitted the following joint
                resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee
                    on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United
            States requiring Members of Congress to demonstrate competence in American
            civics.</official-title>
    </form>
    <resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment" id="HAE9A6CD824494D3C8955582A6F508767">
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H85328B66AB414267B3C47CA6A6A1693B">
 <text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures or conventions of three-fourths of the several States:</text>
            <quoted-block style="traditional" id="H15D6BD685100449E8C8F7FD7AB0BC0C1" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <constitution-article id="H1234">
                    <enum> —</enum>
                    <section id="HCB2856AB3F9446E4A595B7339640742A" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>1.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress shall establish, for each term of ten years for which a census or enumeration is conducted for the apportionment of the Representatives in the Congress, an examination for the demonstration of competence, to a standard expected for a citizen of the United States, on the system of government under the Constitution of the United States, and each House of the Congress shall publish the questions and answers for the examination in the Journal of its proceedings and choose such Officers who shall from time to time jointly and regularly administer the examination, which shall be without any cost to any person who takes the examination, and provide to any such person who demonstrates competence under the examination such certificates necessary to prove such demonstration.</text>
                    </section>
                    <section id="HAB49B7ECE4B24A01B5CEEB32D278A40D" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>2.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person shall be a Representative or Senator who shall not have demonstrated competence on the system of government under the Constitution of the United States under the examination in effect at the time of the election or appointment, but each House of Congress shall afford any person elected or appointed to be a Member of the House, without having demonstrated competence before the election or appointment, the opportunity to demonstrate such competence, whether under the same examination or by another means approved for such purpose by law.</text>
                    </section>
                    <section id="H570EC3C824CB4F25B6433A9DC768984A" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>3.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress shall have power to enforce this article by appropriate legislation, and such legislation shall not require the approval of the President before taking effect.</text>
                    </section>
                </constitution-article>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

