<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG26331-75H-6W-3X9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4618 IS: Elementary and Secondary School Counseling Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4618</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To effectively staff the high-need public elementary schools and secondary schools of the United States with school-based mental health services providers.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3C625FA656CE4EE49194FA542DEB1BE0"><section section-type="section-one" id="H2080E42519954CBFAFA194168385E34E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Elementary and Secondary School Counseling Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD361291A04F74696877E3D4E062AB70A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H8D698BBC914D480B968EE3DC27568F62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nearly one in 5 children ages 13 through 17 has been diagnosed with a mental, emotional, or behavioral health condition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDF8126DDC96453C916355F826FAFF06"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>According to data from the National Center for Health Statistics, in 2021 through 2023, 20 percent of adolescents in the United States ages 12 through 17 reported symptoms of anxiety in the preceding 2 weeks and 18 percent reported symptoms of depression in the preceding 2 weeks.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H604CC2E11535406CA940F5A338DF0C76"><enum>(3)</enum><text>50 percent of all lifetime cases of mental illness begin by age 14. More than 50 percent of students with a mental health condition age 14 and older drop out of school, which is the highest school dropout rate of any disability group.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H724731DECC6D487FBDD888A4EC1874D0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Between 50 and 70 percent of youth in the juvenile justice system have a mental illness compared to 9 to 13 percent of youth who are not in the juvenile justice system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07350327BA514B8AAE51D6DADFAA0311"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Youth with access to mental health services in school-based health centers are 10 times more likely to seek care for mental health or substance abuse than youth without access.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ABFDEC9E2B64A4E9B7C45EDDB3274DB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The leading counseling, guidance, and mental health organizations, including the American School Counselor Association, the National Association of School Psychologists, the National Association of Social Workers, and the School Social Work Association of America, recommend that schools maintain—</text><subparagraph id="HD624B2F21EB1455A89FB3CEE9CCEC76A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a maximum student to school counselor ratio of 250 to 1;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B2BD417C14E471FAE936EEEFBA5C187"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a maximum student to school psychologist ratio of 500 to 1; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H354D41EC754642F9AFFBB70F1F9C4159"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a maximum student to school social worker ratio of 250 to 1.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HCF513DBAF6264E6284E326041DBED1DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H5513FEF7FEC64E4099556DCA0A8DF497"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA Definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>State</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22FA402A5CFB48C7BC0ED57EF7CA6399"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High-need school</header><text>The term <term>high-need school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2211(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6631">20 U.S.C. 6631(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EDCA7C9ACCF4517922AF0757D13A612"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Outlying area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>outlying area</term> means an outlying area specified in section 8101(36)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801(36)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0848B050E6254F448249F7B36273003E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School-based mental health services provider</header><text>The term <term>school-based mental health services provider</term> includes a State licensed or State certified school counselor, school psychologist, school social worker, community-based mental health provider organization, or other State licensed or certified mental health professional qualified under State law to provide mental health services to children and adolescents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60BD8442BA0B42078855AB7B04F001CC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1C624B5F972E490B971B25EF35FF166E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants and subgrants to increase access to school-based mental health services providers at high-need schools</header><subsection id="H7622DF8B11304199A1D121CEA2727B35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservations and grants</header><paragraph id="H77BF0DFB1CBA418D9FF5B225BDC4F783"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text>From the total amount made available under section 5 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text><subparagraph id="H27026B9BB07C4FEC9C63023EBB5E24D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one-half of 1 percent for the Secretary of the Interior for the activities described in subsection (e)(1) in schools operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34EC951A6E89479984FED37BAE468242"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one-half of 1 percent for allotments for the outlying areas to be distributed among the outlying areas on the basis of their relative need for assistance in carrying out the activities described in subsection (e)(1), as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD471C155EEE244BFBAF64DB81719BED7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent for the administration of this Act, and to provide technical assistance relating to this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H740EF5B6F0654BA392193B3DFD5C60AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants</header><subparagraph id="H41911A47F18F4501B57A04EBE02AAF5D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the total amount made available under section 5 for a fiscal year and remaining after funds are reserved under paragraph (1) of this subsection, the Secretary shall award grants to States in accordance with subparagraph (B) to enable the States to award subgrants to local educational agencies in order to increase access to school-based mental health services providers at high-need schools served by the local educational agencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6BB45452D154640B44C6E2EFE1EC731"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall award a grant to each State with an approved application under subsection (d) in an amount that bears the same relationship to the remaining amount described in subparagraph (A) as the amount such State received under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>), as determined on the basis of the most recent fiscal year for which data are available, bears to the amount received under such part (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) by all States with such an approved application, as so determined.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F2988F0BCFF4FDE8EFF187E8CAB499C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Small state minimum</header><text>No State receiving a grant under this paragraph shall receive less than one-half of 1 percent of the total grant amount awarded under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9F5855B2674245E68C3A5B581A289C00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>An allotment awarded under this section shall be for a 5-year period and may be renewed for additional 5-year periods upon a showing of adequate progress on meeting the goals of the allotment, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H786B0D3762A74CF2A42D23BB5B0C2352"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching requirements</header><text>In order to receive a grant under this Act, a State shall agree to provide matching funds, in an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount of the grant amount, toward the costs of the activities carried out under the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE86CE0D88BC7437FAC6A3436A0201B42"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any State desiring to receive a grant under this Act, the State educational agency shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Each application shall include, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="HAD465AD2BBCC4CF0872B69C6BBA9DB11"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that the State will use the allotment only for the activities described in subsection (e)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12FC1D05858447CCB1D7509C590C3C79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how the State will award subgrants to local educational agencies under subsection (e);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2FB55CAAEB44943948DD4B66A0B9CCA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how the State will disseminate, in a timely manner, information regarding the subgrants and the application process for such subgrants to local educational agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE00AA40709324296AA87B4A72B6C0FDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ratios, as of the date of application, of students to school-based mental health services providers in each public elementary school and secondary school in the State, in the aggregate and disaggregated to include—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD9F3BF636F7C40149978C5DD9B3AA0A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ratios of students to school counselors, school psychologists, and school social workers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H443A535C17304279A34E69DC2024BB7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as applicable, the ratios of students to other school-based mental health services providers not described in subparagraph (A), in the aggregate and disaggregated by type of provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H736E385D8DB04153B8769F500E8AED9A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F424AFF61054304B7C3E8BB11450921"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State receiving a grant under this Act shall use such grant to award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to local educational agencies in the State, to enable the local educational agencies to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4BD0BDD9C354348A7418B71964875CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recruit and retain school-based mental health services providers or contract with community mental health centers to work at high-need schools served by the local educational agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H940FACB23BC741178473EB8ACB0ED22F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work toward effectively staffing the high-need schools served by the local educational agency with school-based mental health services providers, including by meeting the recommended maximum ratios of—</text><clause id="H5B2CA1508F9C4A628F9290B9F2CF92A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>250 students per school counselor;</text></clause><clause id="HCEFB3072A79F49AE9E6067BB33F1B805"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>500 students per school psychologist; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BB22B20DAAD41B6991A54795F424D2F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>250 students per school social worker.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD139EE62FF124B2787B0FEC1CE61F4E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding subgrants under this subsection, a State shall give priority to local educational agencies that serve a significant number of high-need schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD22EE8C811504CC78F8936D2E6F0932F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency desiring a subgrant under this subsection shall submit an application to the applicable State at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State may require, including information on how the local educational agency will prioritize assisting high-need schools with the largest numbers or percentages of students from low-income families.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF338F311F14F443BB6EA4B563F307AF4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Allotment and subgrant requirements</header><paragraph id="H88AF0F7B647F4691B8F1F42F826A7DDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts provided as a grant to a State or as a subgrant to a local educational agency under this section shall supplement, and not supplant, any other funds available to such State or local educational agency for school-based mental health services.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H068E99D8E1874405AD5210DA98A18FA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Combining funds allowed</header><text>A State receiving a grant under this section may combine funds made available under this section with State or local funds to carry out the activities described in subsection (e)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6760DD0B126D4C809E42689B0133DB04"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H9E74FFC37C8D4DC7B6E4F29E5C86EB07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agencies</header><text>A local educational agency that receives a subgrant under this section shall submit an annual report to the State that awarded such subgrant on the activities carried out with the subgrant funds. Each such report shall—</text><subparagraph id="H98526DCAC757425BAACDB8A5D65B0C66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the activities carried out using subgrant funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB580F0893BEB4ED8A45009A36DE84183"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enumerate the number of school-based mental health services providers (in the aggregate and disaggregated by each type of provider listed in subsection (d)(4)) who—</text><clause id="H9FE1CC3320354E85BDE1EE6488F8FBA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>were employed by or otherwise served in high-need public elementary and secondary schools under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency for the year covered by the report; and</text></clause><clause id="H6521EC93DFBD41258E75F21983AF4BEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>were supported with funds from the subgrant or matching funds during such year; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38814983A5EF412D963116DFBD3AF1F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include the most recent student to school-based mental health services provider ratios listed in subsection (d)(4) for each high-need school under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency that was supported with the subgrant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE20C1BBFB9824721AE5928A4BE118046"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State educational agencies</header><text>A State receiving a grant under this section shall annually prepare and submit a report to the Secretary that—</text><subparagraph id="HFEA3DAFBC51A447691D238C3D4D0F389"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluates the progress made in achieving the recommended maximum student to school-based mental health services provider ratios described in subsection (e)(1)(B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2584AD3265994330ABAA9F3A5F818909"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the most recent student to provider ratios, in the aggregate and disaggregated as provided in subsection (d)(4), for public elementary schools and secondary schools in the State that were assisted with such allotment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F512E9928234DA7B7AE3A4E294179D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describes any other resources needed to meet the recommended maximum student to school-based mental health services provider ratios described in subsection (e)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H951EB3B30A5A403E908AA4C2DD73A8FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC62D023DA1A945DD8621BCE00A2EECF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives, each report received under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7B4B4BD9F814904AAC5DD52FCA29DB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make such reports available to the public, including through the website of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H00C5E60D14C343B0BE406F4FD0B38B23"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H6C308D81DED14048A7E7A786627EE290"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2027; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD2F165EADD604BAF954DC1229A1C4593"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

