<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C0119B1C1C149DEB3F2B215B98859FB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6679 IH: Tech Wellness for Young Men Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6679</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a comprehensive study on the mental, social, and developmental impacts of screen addiction among young men, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H470E072194CF47F197108CA773B47575" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3C373571CC58410480CF73228BF0489B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tech Wellness for Young Men Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBF189CC72D5C499FA6AEACCCFF14E56A"><enum>2.</enum><header>National study on screen addiction in young men</header> <subsection id="HB48D54A6E61A4AC983DF8E8765416224"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health and the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, shall conduct a comprehensive study on the mental, social, and developmental impacts of screen addiction among young men in the United States aged 12 to 25.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA6772AFA6A414A6B9F8E6B0045A32BD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study, the Secretary shall examine—</text> <paragraph id="H03F20389EA7E4B5BB277B044A9CDA532"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relationships between excessive screen use and increased rates of depression, anxiety, suicidality, violent tendencies, and social withdrawal;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC23942F0206491CAA0E0C45C4C70ACD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impacts on emotional development, impulse control, academic performance, and attention span;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABCCFDE6EB954D488A9E73A037E1E504"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the erosion of interpersonal relationships, including friendships, dating, and family communication;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H701FB4F1DA4245DE92D5E01368D2AE08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>patterns of digital dependency, including compulsive use of gaming, streaming, and social media; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE535E49510754DC087814B8E934BB111"><enum>(5)</enum><text>broader social effects, including disengagement from school, extracurricular activities, civic participation, and physical activity.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDACBC0036A0B4160842DB6ECA05F1C67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study, the Secretary shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="H5B2FD95D514745BF896126839896E408"><enum>(1)</enum><text>experts in adolescent psychiatry, developmental psychology, addiction science, and behavioral health;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DF0D9DBD0614C24BAE12CB86FDE0C9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>community organizations, school-based health centers, and youth-serving nonprofit organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H371E588EF54B49F1AC26FA4896E46793"><enum>(3)</enum><text>professionals in human-computer interaction, gaming design, and social media ethics.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A11AED4DDA14EAFB1A4BCEE338CED6E">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Report to Congress</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and publish on the public internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services, a report containing a summary of the findings of the Secretary based on the study, including an identification of the subgroups of young men that are most affected by excessive screen use.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

