<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H682989BECE4F499285729CC04F5E3197" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8650 IH: Medicaid Outreach and Assistance for Communities Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8650</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to increase payments to States with respect to outreach and enrollment under the Medicaid program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9DB8D06A21CB4EE2B11A4E76583631D3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB18D7DB27F984FD980B692324C14442E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Outreach and Assistance for Communities Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H793D1E2D10584175BC3DDD9851961962"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HACBF2C46A9044A5E848E1966C697FE57"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research has shown that access to health insurance coverage reduces financial hardship, increases utilization of preventive and primary care services, improves management of chronic conditions, and is associated with better overall health outcomes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26C6B770331147E39F096130DC89DE03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Medicaid coverage in particular produces meaningful health and financial benefits, especially for vulnerable populations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2C0DEBA05EC40399739373921943FA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2025, Congress passed <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref> that imposed many barriers to accessing Medicaid, including work reporting requirements and more frequent eligibility redeterminations in sections 71119 and 71107.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48054E42164549A494879737E1FFAAD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Evidence from jurisdictions that have adopted work requirements has shown that many individuals do not enroll or lose coverage at renewal, despite being eligible and compliant, because of administrative complexity and documentation burdens.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F0F633EFCE84869B2B0854E5F3B55F7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Effective outreach programs can help individuals navigate these new systems, increasing enrollment and retention among eligible individuals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46F34CC4D90043718B7BE3B594D7A9E9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>States have systems in place to help individuals navigate the Medicaid enrollment process but need additional support to handle these new requirements. Navigators extend the capacity of State government by helping to offset the additional administrative burden and need for assistance that State eligibility and call center workers will encounter when work requirements and semi-annual renewals are implemented.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECE8A4085091427EB83FA820E5044DCC">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>Without additional navigation support, eligible individuals will go without insurance coverage, jeopardizing the health, well-being, and financial security of children, working families, and older adults.</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD29F4A2C5B09417EBF7F725DE623EBC4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increasing payments to States for Medicaid outreach and enrollment</header> 
<subsection id="HA319C383050B42AB89C56416002FFA3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increased payments for outreach and enrollment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1903(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2E7E0D990BBA424FA6715FF9EF01B09F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H401252935CE4487896603CFC52EF9E5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCA19622E06164628A69A8511A3BAE744" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H0FD2C6349D9D43E09CBB5410F52116E6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to 100 percent of the sums expended during such quarter which are attributable to the costs of outreach to and enrollment of individuals eligible for medical assistance under this title or for child health assistance under title XXI (including individuals described in section 1943(b)(1)(F)).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD9345E2DAAA4387BA7F5394B923002F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to calendar quarters beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

