<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D7A942FDA1641E5BCEC9BF510A4A89A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6804 IH: Rural Hospital Flexibility Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6804</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to strengthen Medicare rural hospital flexibility program grants.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H093A9BC0DAE94AF4A53F1F51A741BEC5" style="OLC"><section id="HD8527201A88B48CCAC8D82CAA72039E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Hospital Flexibility Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAC6778C2E6864BF4B5D9CE2AA1A8D619"><enum>2.</enum><header>Medicare rural hospital flexibility program grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1820(g) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-4">42 U.S.C. 1395i–4(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H35540CF982774719BFD3D9645AFB52B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1)(D) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H51856847313C49B4ADBF7E7AD2C41A22" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HF409093AD93B4F14BFA5DD40C5B173DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing support for critical access hospitals, certified rural health clinics, and rural emergency hospitals (as defined in section 1861(kkk)(2)) for quality improvement, quality reporting, performance improvements, benchmarking, addressing population health, transforming services, and providing linkages and services for behavioral health and substance use disorders responding to public health emergencies.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A49BAC46B8A462F8B18078F994028CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (7) as paragraphs (4) through (8), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35B8E81707CC441798DE95AF0058C012"><enum>(3)</enum><text>after paragraph (2), by inserting the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFD8D37DB16F14CA789AA9DE6AB1ADA0C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H50CC887F2C5A49B6B2655CC98DCBE53C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Activities to support carrying out other grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants or cooperative agreements to entities awarded grants or agreements under other provisions of this subsection for purposes of supporting such entities in carrying out activities under such other grants or agreements by providing technical assistance, data analysis, and evaluation efforts. An entity seeking a grant under this paragraph shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D12F1F909CC43F3A006574F2DE19D1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), as redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="H28523ADF9C0646EEAE5A35DE3D3D43E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H11D05A88A4FF4D6E87FFB0BB46FD7DF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the header, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">hospitals</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">State Offices of Rural Health</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HDC11B503CE8B43CC93AB30E1A1DAA3B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>grants to hospitals</quote> and inserting <quote>grants to State Offices of Rural Health</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB0C2B80EDBC4140A0C0F8F4AF55828E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="HEF705DE1B2544AC4940DC41AC803AC7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively;</text></clause><clause id="H9E382A2CC3B145239150DC4ED8F853A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>means a non-Federal</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H81CD07BC82A04CDB919B5C504D113C4C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>means—</text><clause id="H424B7BD667C14BAAA46CD414DA01A06E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a non-Federal</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="HA02BCCB44F99449CBC9EE0549B44851B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3418EC8040344E2BA5D339283CD3C175" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>; or</text><clause id="H9E702EC647834A838069FBDA40A9785B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a rural emergency hospital (as defined in section 1861(kkk)).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD833E6707634055A8ED6C953B0F71DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (C) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE6DE532DB2D5421EA2934126B56B7309" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H45711DC8BB5D4248857ECA0C65C76FB7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The State Office of Rural Health shall submit an application to the Secretary on or before such date and in such form and manner as the Secretary specifies.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AEEF538645C4033AF72AE0F471037CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (D) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFF4B596780364CD7A9401D11D120C20A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HE37599DCAF8C4F0599E17A92346EFFD7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to funds made available to make grants under this paragraph in a fiscal year, the amount awarded to a State Office of Rural Health shall bear the same ratio to the total amount of such funds so made available as the number of eligible small rural hospitals in such State bears to the total number of eligible small rural hospitals in all States receiving a grant under this paragraph for such fiscal year propose. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD67E2420B8204FC9806C22AA1702CCBC"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subparagraph (E) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H64854DE59232420FBF90A5F58C6C12F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H28A5E954728443EE8DF735CF1A122866"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State Offices of Rural Health may use the funds received through a grant under this paragraph for the purchase of computer software and hardware on behalf of eligible small rural hospitals, for the education and training of eligible small rural hospital staff on billing, operational, quality improvement, and related value-focused efforts, and for other delivery system reform programs determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BB8E3DC513B4A549B34F86CABBFB6BC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F)—</text><clause id="HEEFCCDA1317348D7AC7AF79CB9C02E48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>A hospital receiving a grant under this section</quote> and inserting <quote>An entity receiving a grant under this paragraph</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H88A8D21A90F14BF9BC5A9D11094C6464"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>section</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>paragraph</quote> in each such place;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E0DD72B59D4D85B23DD200037AE61A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), as redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (1) or (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1), (2), or (4)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA5175D050214DFF9F59DCD7A5CD5FC0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H218F9AC13CBA4B78BC9D8B925846D489" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H13207D5FA8704D788C99B1B5DBF59414"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Rural Health Transformation Grants</header><subparagraph id="HB3351682C4E54A8EA89BA3DDC86B41C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary may award 5-year grants to State Offices of Rural Health and to eligible rural health care providers (as defined in subparagraph (D)) on the transition to new models, including rural emergency hospitals, extended stay clinics, freestanding emergency departments, rural health clinics, and integration of behavioral, oral health services, telehealth and other transformational models relevant to rural providers as such providers evolve to better meet community needs and the changing health care environment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77C9E7B592344808B19532D149A3DC99"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible rural health care provider, in consultation with the State Office of Rural Health in the State in which the rural health care provider seeking a grant under this paragraph is located, shall submit an application to the Secretary on or before such date and in such form and manner as the Secretary specifies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73E62FB528714EAD9F2743FF6C21E220"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>The Secretary may not award a grant under this paragraph to an eligible rural health care provider unless—</text><clause id="H12255119EBA94B2491E770055C50DB78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>local organizations or the State in which the hospital is located provides support (either direct or in kind); and there are letters of support from key State payers such as Medicaid and private insurance; and</text></clause><clause id="H0FF0287A441A48A38D8C5C8B8D5F72A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicant describes in detail how the transition of the health care provider or providers will better meet local needs and be sustainable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46E00CCFDA8A440997CB51D0BEF3D4B4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Eligible rural health care provider defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>eligible rural health care provider</term> includes a critical access hospital, a certified rural health clinic, a rural nursing home, skilled nursing facility, emergency care provider, or other entity identified by the Secretary. An eligible rural health care provider may include other entities applying on behalf of a group of rural health care providers such as a State Office of Rural Health, a State or local health care authority, a rural health network, or other entity identified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H228DD47C7739426D93B7D82089C88EB0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Rural emergency hospital technical assistance</header><subparagraph id="HA5B7FD992077438DB5D54BEDA3740ED8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities (as determined by the Secretary) for the purpose of providing technical assistance, data analysis, and other support to hospitals that are seeking to be designated, or are currently designated, as rural emergency hospitals (as described in section 1861(kkk)(2)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A1E6AF28C0144E3B740AB1BCBA481E6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity seeking a grant under subparagraph (A) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such form and manner as specified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

