<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D90C4DE1A994A68A262C11B052E06E4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6733 IH: VISN Reform Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6733</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements to the administration of Veterans Integrated Service Networks under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6177E95D39124E8396861110B69D7B8F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H17BAED13BEF341E89FD587CA5EB2B06A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VISN Reform Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDDDBC62F67D2482392E5C017645D6AAE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Administration of Veterans Integrated Service Networks</header> <subsection id="H6F42EA9CF5D145B3A93129C9D7F490B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Veterans integrated service networks</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7305">section 7305</external-xref> following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H4EE7926F7BA94113AF0106046514496B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H2F0E34173862451F986EE5A5E4503B34"><enum>7305A.</enum><header>Veterans Integrated Service Networks</header> 
<subsection id="H610298D7379245B9B2A891AF2876984D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Organization</header><text>The Secretary shall organize the Veterans Health Administration in eight geographically defined Veterans Integrated Service Networks (hereinafter referred to as <quote>VISNs</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC02CDA097D0841D3B33060486783B50B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alignment with mission of department</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the employees, services, and programs of each VISN are aligned with the mission of the Department and the specific health care requirements of each population of veterans in each Network.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H25BAA5C04EE54F46907F3D1009DB42D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Integrated health care system</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain a regional integrated health care system within the geographic area served by each VISN by—</text> <paragraph id="H0B6A01B596384F3FB02F305EC8D24EAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entering into agreements with such other governmental, public, and private health care organizations and practitioners as the Secretary considers appropriate to meet the needs of veterans who reside in the geographic area served by the VISN;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E196CFBAFC7497EB12A7FA5E100337A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing oversight and management of, and taking responsibility for, a regional budget for the activities of each VISN that—</text> <subparagraph id="H47A973CDFA7244AF809D3C060EB17D3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is aligned with the budget guidelines of the Department and the Veterans Health Administration; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEF52F52E3064BE78ED49AAC1B0E090F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is balanced at the end of each fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FB06CEFEC024668957E09C89D9AE1F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>using national metrics to develop systems to provide effective, efficient, and safe delivery of health care that is rated as highly satisfactory by patients and families of patients.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H675C1B22E3444554A9BE02BC37986EFB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reduction in duplicate functions</header><text>The Secretary shall identify functions that are duplicated across the clinical, administrative, and operational processes and practices of the Veterans Health Administration and operate the system of VISNs in a manner designed to reduce the duplication of such functions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4D29E509281345AB9D247DA27E4C637D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Collaboration and cooperation</header> <paragraph id="HD85C53731A7D4C839B870F91D94F33C5" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall operate the VISN system by working to achieve maximum effectiveness with respect to the provision hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care, graduate medical education, and research; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H868D23D168F448B399D1F1A26A4604A1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall assess, on an ongoing basis, the consolidation or realignment of institutional functions, including capital asset, safety, and operational support functions, in collaboration and cooperation with other VISNs and the following offices or entities within the geographic area served by the VISN:</text> <subparagraph id="H94EF51BC87CB44E2BCD3B62C8E398052"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The offices of the Veterans Benefits Administration and the National Cemetery Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H487791211AFD4309BAFF584C74E34117"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Offices of State and local agencies that have a mission to provide assistance to veterans.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDE6237270C84A2AB100E45A504BD175"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Medical schools and other affiliates.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3D57B260E0C4B42BC15DD67F82AE9D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local emergency preparedness organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4780B962229E4967A926285D78950638"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other offices of the Federal Government as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H633532BFC2F846A8B0CFD6BA011D378D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Director of each VISN shall be responsible for oversight and for the enforcement of Department policies authorities applicable to medical facilities of the Department with respect to such medical facilities located in the geographic area served by such VISN.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCBB02E101F43425EA4024624592E926D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Headquarters</header> <paragraph id="HB9E4ED983EB544D686FBBAE096776938" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There shall be only one headquarters office for each VISN. The Secretary shall choose the location of each such office and shall ensure each such office is colocated with a medical center of the Department.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB654872A34B4B9994201313FCFB9BFA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="HADF3274803814961B6C099DED4FFA1E1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each headquarters office established under paragraph (1) shall have not more than 50 full-time employees. Of such 50 full-time employees, not more than 10 shall be contractor employees.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B7C7DFE3C6540B9A07EBE690E111011" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="H2F1ED4A434C642EB8D17C536D53186ED" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary may waive the limitation under subparagraph (A) with respect to a VISN headquarters if the Secretary—</text> 
<subclause id="HE7702D9A260B40258EC9070A1FA4588A" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determines the waiver is necessary to maintain essential operations of the VISN headquarters during the implementation of the plan required under paragraph (3); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9681215E6B6F47E89216925CCC838B86" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before the date on which the waiver becomes effective, submits to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a written certification of such determination.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H5C3DB72EF4FF4F3EB7E534BE4359DEE8" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The term of any wavier issued pursuant to clause (i) may not exceed one year.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75D990E185E948DFBFB9B62BB9D72585" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Not less frequently than once each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on employment at the VISN headquarters offices during the preceding fiscal year. Each such report shall include the following for the year covered by the report:</text> 
<clause id="HCDD7595E415E4123BCC99E43869D2DFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of individuals employed at each VISN headquarters office.</text></clause> <clause id="HE829F763930F49BAB8C2F9CC5A93C860"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of individuals employed by the Veterans Health Administration in each VISN who are not employed at the same location as the headquarters office of that VISN.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E865D6A774C486998050A7A730AEFBC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The title for each position of employment at a headquarters office.</text></clause> <clause id="HF323113C28DC47EE9AD970FE152B5C3D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The title for each position of employment with the Veterans Health Administration in each VISN whose duty station is not at the same location as the headquarters office of that VISN.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H739575BEF26546BCA6C7FD94E02044B4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>An assessment of the effect of the employment of individuals at VISN headquarters offices on the budget of the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD577BCA9C0DE4827B17C8A7BAFFA5232" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph id="H8DBBD81988EC4DB5B99B85AF24C66B09" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall develop and submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a comprehensive plan for the reorganization and right-sizing of the workforce of each VISN headquarters to achieve compliance with the limitation under paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EDD4D8575C741528D6A2ED8B0EEA1AE" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The plan under subparagraph (A) shall include, for each VISN headquarters—</text> <clause id="H707B1C122A034F1C9761CFB6D927EFB5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of all positions currently assigned to the headquarters, including duty location, occupational services, pay grade, and primary function;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF7CB83B7B0B44557B90DE12071943BC0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a determination of which positions—</text> <subclause id="HA03D5BBB678145BB93AB32287545F8EB" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are essential to execute the mission of the VISN; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAE1F9A92820F4B9E8EE9D019E3C0830C" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are duplicative or administrative in nature;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H47A9577480114FFF996B24625E86FDBE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a phased implementation schedule for such plan;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H429C7F94D6594B8F93BAED07D7661D6F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of any workforce realignments, reassignments, or separations required to comply with the limitation under paragraph (2)(A), including voluntary separation incentive payments or retraining opportunities under title 5; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9D8D328DE205424A86CC1EF9F74D2169" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a certification that the implementation of such plan will not result in a reduction in access to care or services furnished to veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C048A657C194E8C90EA24FBED5FA962" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In developing and implementing the plan required under this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HE00A5026332846C7AC94D30325E62E2E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensure that each VISN headquarters is in compliance with the limitation under paragraph (2)(A) not later than the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this section; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFF8F35C281064BB69216E5F453EA4F65" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, offer each employee of a VISN headquarters who is a licensed physician, nurse, psychologist, or other healthcare professional such the opportunity to transfer, without loss of pay or benefits, to a position appointed under chapter 74 of this title to furnish direct patient care or clinical support at a Department medical facility.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H66318920DA8542A4A683BD7BD43F6315"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Personnel</header> <paragraph id="HB28FAD7C07BF4F29B0A3C502F780A22F" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each VISN shall be the Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The position of Director of a VISN shall be a noncareer appointee position. The Director of a VISN shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6A43D453D784441482D97FA72F1A5601" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be responsible for the functions of the VISN; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C9B8365FE404B59AECE0012F48C14AD" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have the authority and responsibility to enforce the policies and standards of the Department with respect to all Department personnel employed within the VISN.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83572C37B31D4D2696A000264E254A8F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each employee employed at a facility of the Veterans Health Administration located in the geographic area served by a VISN shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9300F3DD88664376A5460EA41F594CD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report directly to the Director of the VISN;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E52B5A8B9BD4A82B914468DB9BF4373"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an employee who is licensed to practice in a hospital, work at least one day each week in a Department medical center located in such geographic area; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA2E62962E293487086597DA070646AF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>visit routinely with service line chiefs at Department medical centers, as directed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H885E3CDCC7734641843DB5BB3BE22182"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Triennial structure review, reassessment and report</header> 
<paragraph id="H40B30B2F6D1442E8B2210E1E2EB81A97" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this section, and not less frequently than once every three years thereafter, the Secretary shall conduct a review and assessment of the structure and operations of the VISNs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCA1ABFC85FC4C91B4E8BAF4F5A18713" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after conducting a review and assessment under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on such review and assessment, which shall include such recommendations for legislative or regulatory action as the Secretary considers appropriate to improve the VISNs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H167A39A3500E40DF8CEDA57D50DE1EEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 73 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7305 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block id="H5BC7869E3D524E61B62274D9A3E60222" style="OLC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">7305A. Veterans Integrated Service Networks</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HF22609395F6E4644931CC2A285D7D433"><enum>3.</enum><header>Consolidation of Veterans Integrated Service Networks</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In order to comply with section 7305A of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 2, not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall geographically realign and combine the Veterans Integrated Service Networks in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act into geographically defined Veterans Integrated Service Networks as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H371D287BA42C44A2AA234C37F5E2F4D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans Integrated Service Network 1, Veterans Integrated Service Network 2, and Veterans Integrated Service Network 4 shall be Combined into a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H467941DC4B7F4ED881179E23063773D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Veterans Integrated Service Network 5, Veterans Integrated Service Network 6, and Veterans Integrated Service Network 9 shall be combined into a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21540534A43F4A07BE8B91FC4CE968F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Veterans Integrated Service Network 10, Veterans Integrated Service Network 12, and Veteran Integrated Service Network 23 shall be combined into a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DD9B2474574429D9C5048654C5EB39D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Veterans Integrated Service Network 7, Veterans Integrated Service Network 8, and Veteran Integrated Service Network 16 shall be combined into a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79C635E11F4C4F3792ABE5068DB07024"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Veterans Integrated Service Network 15 and Veteran Integrated Service Network 19 shall be combined into a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99D13BE3FA2D4E5A91A3D0FE11A8EB15"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Veterans Integrated Service Network 17 and Veteran Integrated Service Network 22 shall be combined into a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C945D17F4E14E0B9482948BAD661D4A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Veterans Integrated Service Network 20 shall remain a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H592AE645C6C748209E3C76573BBF169A"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Veterans Integrated Service Network 21 shall remain a single Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

