<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL26366-T24-K3-HMT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4732 IS: Wildfire Smoke Emergency Declaration Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4732</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the President to declare a smoke emergency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Smoke Emergency Declaration Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1CA97AC30A154BA08B5A7ED9C8DC399E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assistance for smoke emergency declaration</header><subsection id="id80E001F217DB4AD0BD878C0CE13CC20A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may declare a smoke emergency in any State in which the President determines there is, or anticipates there will be, a significant decrease in air quality due to wildland fire smoke in one or more States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8540C8F73AC24041A624064B225349BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Request from Governor</header><text>The Governor, or other appropriate agency, of a State that is or will be affected by a significant decrease in air quality due to wildland fire smoke may request a declaration under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id30FC5F3EA9C644E0882E80198446811A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>If the President declares a smoke emergency under subsection (a), the President, acting through the Federal Emergency Management Agency and other appropriate Federal agencies, may provide smoke emergency assistance to States and local communities that are or will be affected by the smoke emergency, including grants, equipment, supplies, and personnel and resources for establishing smoke shelters, air purifiers, and additional air monitoring sites.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6A64A5F272564AC0BD8A9E1D1969B987"><enum>(d)</enum><header>SBA grants</header><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration may provide grants to any small business concern, as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>), that loses a significant amount of revenue due to wildland fire smoke in an area in which the President has declared a smoke emergency under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idFDA2A1500795470F8723B3CFDE13D4EB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id44478A3CEC83444D91F7428E5AAB57B0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Budget adjustment for smoke emergency assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 251(b)(2) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/901">2 U.S.C. 901(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD43FEFE85C704EE2BDD51F7DA0893C47"><subparagraph id="idB9945E46A8B549FCAA27BD814FDE946B"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Smoke emergency assistance</header><clause id="idE776784F70D04D598B745434A978A890"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If, for any fiscal year, appropriations for discretionary accounts are enacted that Congress designates as being for smoke emergency assistance in statute, the adjustment for a fiscal year shall be the total of such appropriations for the fiscal year in discretionary accounts designated as being for smoke emergency assistance.</text></clause><clause id="id6753158B235C4FA7A0E0CC605091785F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>smoke emergency assistance</term> means assistance provided under a determination under section 2 of the <short-title>Wildfire Smoke Emergency Declaration Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID94C9D1B2ED194E75B88AAA4DDF435C3A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations considered smoke emergency assistance under this subparagraph in a fiscal year shall not be eligible for adjustments under subparagraph (A) for the fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

