<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0346DA46D8647C2B908557CC9D5E27F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9400 IH: American Rescuers of the Holocaust Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9400</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal, collectively, to Americans who were active in rescuing and aiding Jews and other refugees during the period of Nazi Germany’s genocidal <quote>Final Solution</quote> policy to murder every Jew in Europe, in recognition of their contributions, which resulted in tens of thousands of Jews and others being spared from almost certain death.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H339074CCC75648E1819A07927F1F3FC2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFDB401114932465BB3E8D98BF7BA3D97" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Rescuers of the Holocaust Congressional Gold Medal Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFC19CD7D4260471EA2FD3D72AA32653E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA12A76D1C1514F528694A15FB93D6448"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Between 1933 and 1945, United States rescue and relief organizations were responsible for saving many thousands of Jews and other refugees during the Holocaust. American groups sponsored, financed, and organized numerous rescue and relief efforts in Nazi-occupied and neutral Europe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA141D6D433E455997E69FFD9A6CA29B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These organizations operated in every country in Europe. There were hundreds of American citizens involved in this effort.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95F1DAA8946244F489E69C2B22A0F868"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Jewish refugees and others who were saved from almost certain death immigrated to the United States, Israel, and other parts of the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD085D49258204AC5A25FA9C98676AFA7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Refugee agencies worked in the face of opposition to the resettling of Jewish refugees. In 1939, Congress rejected proposals to offer asylum to 20,000 Jewish children. In the same year, the United States refused asylum to Jewish refugees aboard the S.S. ST. LOUIS, who were forced to return to Europe, and 254 of whom died in the Holocaust.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7715600AAB474E9982CD87C7098E0C13"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In addition, public opinion in America was largely against aiding refugees, especially through immigration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB18853A055D540928739B3983B8BD595"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The rescue of Jews and other refugees was, in some cases, extremely dangerous, especially when conducted in Nazi-occupied territories or in collaborator nations. A number of rescuers were arrested, imprisoned, and some were killed.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BFED1D1CE894D468246ED05990C4C3D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Many of these individuals and agencies aided in the relief and resettlement of Jewish refugees and others after the war.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD8559AAD4E6459C92E98B548AE02656"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Among the most prominent was the War Refugee Board, which was responsible for saving the lives of 200,000 Jews and 20,000 non-Jews.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4A7C9D07B5B402FB0D3CEE541A62C57"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A number of these organizations to be honored are still in existence and are continuing efforts to help refugees throughout the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5341ACDA5D944C238DD8B4EC728ACB26"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individuals being honored include any American who participated in the rescue or relief of Jews or other refugees who were in danger as a result of the Nazi genocidal policy against Jews and others in Europe, from 1933 to 1945.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB8D6145DB9554BC58549507BF14F5EB2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> 
<subsection id="HD78F7E37ADF44E66A61CA5DC17D6FB09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration of the Americans who were active in rescuing and aiding Jews and other refugees during the period of Nazi Germany’s genocidal <quote>Final Solution</quote> policy to murder every Jew in Europe, in recognition of their contributions, which resulted in tens of thousands of Jews and others being spared from almost certain death.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H91C4DD4B5C8F4AA29C176F44E28DFAB7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike the gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H15E38D1378CF4BE5B74BD67CB19D3536"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United states holocaust memorial museum</header>
<paragraph id="HB875943B0E194317AC520DA41928B246"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, where it shall be available for display and research in accordance with the Museum’s policies regarding materials in the Museum’s care.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC3F5F175E5C40AF90969B897249D9D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, in accordance with the Museum’s policies regarding materials in the Museum’s care, at other appropriate locations, including those associated with commemoration of the Holocaust and other relevant entities, that may make such a request.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H278A550909E34E07AFFAD3256049E1C5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="H33623BE881AC4169B06D17199F6C2353"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> <subsection id="H78FB3CA8256F4078A6AA4A31A0128881"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD99BCDAD336B42DA986F132CC01BD693"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HEC4C6A48DE7341AF8F6C70B73848CAAA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> <subsection id="HB946D4D376824E41B6452DDC65FE01A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF7E33F12B90145A4860F817AA7750077"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>The amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

