<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25935-1Y5-N9-HCN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3257 IS: Mental Health in Aviation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3257</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to revise regulations for certain individuals carrying out aviation activities who disclose a mental health diagnosis or condition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health in Aviation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id4b731086732a4b54831094636823fcd9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idd528eba4d0364e35941a178230d9d0da"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0cf7ed89be0e439cac069405af11e5de"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="iddfb86260c62c48238753d27f7ea97c3d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31a667d87c0348db89c48df78769cb31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabfad5ba56dc47d3ae14acbee581819b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide6d4c24c2c344629b7f26c398b38541b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7743187c26554b4a95e356c8d02b659f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>FAA</header><text>The term <term>FAA</term> means the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7db84ddf5f84918b3da0dd15ff47b20" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special issuance</header><text>The term <term>special issuance</term> has the meaning given such term in section 67.401 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id38bc5dae3dcc49a892993ccd7148db66"><enum>3.</enum><header>Regulations for individuals carrying out aviation activities</header><subsection id="idc1a7d46b618e4005b39dd75f402eb6dd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall update regulations, including in part 67 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and issue relevant guidance as appropriate to encourage individuals to—</text><paragraph id="id0f949c388c834357be4b2bacda9cc198"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek help for mental health conditions or symptoms of mental health conditions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16db41806a78493c9411e476695e592a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to disclose conditions or symptoms described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd2b25d3557643029b8a826bc21665b7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation; report requirements</header><text>Section 411(d) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4dfe52244c68410bb13f20e7b0f64c2d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9594c288e9f3487ebc67d8f23647e29b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraphs (A) and (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67c65a57000b4077bd11d0f0c9eace9c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6a2d6de310d435b90b7643077bcceca"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc4227c37bd8466cbae92f6df2f04eb5"><subparagraph id="id845d6db33f73407e9ee5c5f3b49d6f48"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a review and evaluation of any recommendations reached by the National Transportation Safety Board related to aviation workforce mental health; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2f5b94aef9cf4534b3b1c89751ac3bca"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of relevant clinical studies, research, diagnostic manuals, and protocols used by the licensed professionals as of the date of the enactment of this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ed16a7f494d4265b69b88fbc49cc8e8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75fb8986aab94cea83f406e52a13c49c"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c4eadbe7ceb4153b96f778a3f4bf2db"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the task group shall consult with relevant stakeholders from the aviation and medical communities, as necessary, including—</text><subparagraph id="ideef42e17265e43979329f6a8c2b3fcc1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exclusive bargaining representatives of air traffic controllers of the FAA certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97f76fd5e6c84c27af3bb90f5144c3c2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>organizations representing collective bargaining representatives of airline pilots;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccd3a2353f3d4d07b422fb4054ac1760"><enum>(C)</enum><text>institutions of higher education that are accredited by the Aviation Accreditation Board International; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc0c318a0b6094435b3b366b5cbeee894"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other stakeholder determined relevant by the task group, including any stakeholders described in paragraph (3)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf3c3ecab9434b11afb61283cbd35954"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="id1b27ac2004334a8bb62f0b4ed3c14e2b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and for any report issued thereafter, not later than 180 days after the submission of each report required under section 411(f) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note), the Administrator shall take appropriate action to implement the recommendations of such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id621ecf91fc8444bd81aaae045d532784"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>In the event that the Administrator decides not to implement a recommendation described in paragraph (1), the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress the justification for such decision not later than 90 days after receiving the report containing such recommendation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8a61de28f95b4498828e1368307c49ab"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual review of mental health special issuance process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the Administrator submits the first report pursuant to section 411(f) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note), and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall conduct an annual review of the special issuance process, and update, as appropriate, the applicable regulations, policies, orders, and guidance on mental health-related special issuance for pilots and air traffic controllers to—</text><paragraph id="id3dfcf677f573452592564efdcd17e02f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider the reclassification of additional medications and evidence-based treatments that may be safely prescribed to treat mental health conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd28b57ad877f4b5ca9061dae1719b817"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve mental health knowledge and training for aviation medical examiners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddee677a45a0f4fadb9c425dc3819521b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if the Administrator determines appropriate, expand mental-health related situations in which an aviation medical examiner may issue a certificate consistent with the recommendations of the Mental Health and Aviation Medical Clearances Rulemaking Committee described in section 6; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03bd4b5108454042a82e72393765adf3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improve the special issuance process for pilots and air traffic controllers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idd56b0e4783f84b5fa4f1cef65327a3d0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Improving capacity for the Office of Aerospace Medicine</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Of the amounts made available pursuant to section 106(k)(1) of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator shall designate not more than $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 to—</text><paragraph id="id85eac257d2e64dc7ba2de91d2344f19c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recruit, select, and train additional aviation medical examiners and human intervention motivation study aviation medical examiners, including those who are psychiatrists;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc038a7e319a24038b1984ebda891e74b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expand capacity to provide oversight of aviation medical examiners and clear the backlog of special issuance requests and cases awaiting review at the Office of Aerospace Medicine of the FAA;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id629b17588d584587ab2a5599a56baad3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide enhanced mental health training to aviation medical examiners to ensure such personnel have requisite knowledge and the ability to appropriately evaluate individuals for FAA medical certification; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd38031ed86d546638c8cbfe05f01aa77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support any other related activities, as determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id336ff04b28824421bb8e53ee8d09cbf2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Implementation of aviation rulemaking committee recommendations</header><subsection id="idc5dda5612eda42f38f20dc0c8cc9e6c7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall implement, as appropriate, the recommendations of the Mental Health and Aviation Medical Clearances Aviation Rulemaking Committee, which were submitted to the Administrator on April 1, 2024.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7edada9ea28b4e96ba9ee198128e0afe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with the stakeholders described in section 411(d)(5) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (as added by this Act).</text></subsection><subsection id="id2f59255d128243b3a40bf794a6dd6371"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>If the Administrator decides not to implement a recommendation described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress the justification for such decision not later than 90 days after the deadline described in such subsection.</text></subsection></section><section id="id12e632b8811847c28da26c666ff4818b"><enum>7.</enum><header>Public information campaign</header><subsection id="id8dc1547869b94c98b3d88fa42cceea2d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the amounts made available pursuant to section 106(k)(1) of title 49, United States Code, the Administrator shall designate not more than $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029 for a public information campaign or similar public education efforts to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id395e637013134e8584a8dee5381db3ca"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">destigmatize individuals in (or interested in joining) the aviation industry who seek mental health care;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided35b5bb54bf4138b2b6c956160d0adb"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">broaden awareness of available supportive services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0197d71436b44254986faf33c5b42103"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve trust between the FAA and pilots and air traffic controllers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id34dcd43cbc3247aeb36a507193c5cf92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The public information campaign or similar public education efforts described in subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="id0967157c68de492dad91753cc6c0e695"><enum>(1)</enum><text>making publicly available (in an easily accessible format and location online)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d61df3f2d264a20afe3ae4c85a7a8c9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information that would help destigmatize the reporting of mental health concerns impacting the aviation workforce, and encourage individuals to seek help for such concerns; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43a1a04a89fc400a8533d1922a683ff3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other information to effectuate the outcomes described in subsection (a);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7193c2c2e6334ab68d37142417581791"><enum>(2)</enum><text>posting the information described in paragraph (1) at Aviation Medical Examiner offices; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc2a21d0d696e43458c423d29ece8a085"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collaborating with air carriers (as defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code), flight training institutions and entities (as described in parts 61 and 141 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations), and small, medium, and large hub airports (as defined in such section 40102) to encourage such entities to make such information easily accessible to airmen and air traffic controllers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0d3e559b57b4474b957f0ace1006aeec"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing and report to Congress</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a666afd0e4a47f5999f7b6402443436"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Briefing</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the Administrator establishes the public information campaign described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on the actions taken to develop the campaign and the plans to implement the campaign.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c16f4f60028472c83f9ebd4325cc927"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the Administrator implements the public information campaign, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the engagement and outreach resulting from such campaign, including a description of any applicable feedback from aviation industry stakeholders on the efficacy of the campaign.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

