<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV26333-L7M-67-WCW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 612 IS: Acknowledging the fourth anniversary of Russia’s illegal invasion of Ukraine, reaffirming support for the people of Ukraine, and emphasizing the importance of robust United States security guarantees within a transatlantic commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 612</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Acknowledging the fourth anniversary of Russia’s illegal invasion of Ukraine, reaffirming support for the people of Ukraine, and emphasizing the importance of robust United States security guarantees within a transatlantic commitment to Ukraine’s sovereignty.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 24, 2022, the Russian Federation launched a full-scale, unprovoked, and illegal invasion of Ukraine, following its illegal annexation of Crimea in 2014 and its illegal occupation of parts of the Donbas region in 2014;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the international community and the United States recognize the sovereignty, independence, and full territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized 1991 borders;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ukraine has withstood four years of brutal aggression, suffering military and civilian casualties and widespread destruction of infrastructure and communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Russian forces have repeatedly struck Ukrainian civilian targets, including maternity hospitals, trains, residential buildings, and schools;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Government of the Russian Federation has forcibly abducted at least 19,500 Ukrainian children, with the total number likely much higher;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in recent years, the Government of the Russian Federation has specifically targeted United States companies operating in Ukraine to discourage American investment;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ukrainian forces, with the support of transatlantic partners, have demonstrated resilience and recently made notable battlefield gains, recapturing territory and slowing Russian advances;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Russian forces are facing casualties of 35,000 per month and Russia’s economy is stagnant, with spiraling inflation of 20 percent, and in February 2026, Russian oil related taxes declined by 50 percent year on year due to increased economic pressure on Russia’s oil exports;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas European partners provide more military, economic, and humanitarian aid to Ukraine than the United States, with European security assistance to Ukraine increasing 67 percent and nonmilitary aid increasing 59 percent in 2026 over the 2022–2024 average and collective transatlantic support amounting to hundreds of billions of dollars, including billions in advanced weapons systems, air defense, training, and financial assistance;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas effective deterrence and defense of Ukraine require sustained, predictable security guarantees and backstops from both the United States and European allies to ensure that Ukraine can maintain its territorial defense and strengthen its integration with Euro-Atlantic structures; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ensuring security guarantees for Ukraine advances the security interests of the United States and its NATO allies by deterring broader aggression from revisionist states and strengthening collective defense postures: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id44b49269bf8d4135a96cc4e34260407f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms unwavering support for the sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity of Ukraine within its internationally recognized borders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1325cc576c843f49b901b32e94c8e6a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses deep condolences for the loss of Ukrainian lives and the suffering inflicted on civilians and service members by the Russian Federation's ongoing aggression;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41fa1c8094a14a0ca2901f1c77c85bf6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the bravery, heroism, innovation, and resilience of the Ukrainian people and Ukraine’s armed forces for their sustained defense of their homeland and Ukraine’s democracy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id511b764b11914f8babbb3a17b8feeca3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>condemns the Russian Federation's brutal attacks on Ukraine, including its increased attacks on Ukraine’s energy infrastructure during Ukraine’s harshest winter in decades;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f546347c6f84e229c55cb517b4b93be"><enum>(5)</enum><text>condemns the Russian Federation's deliberate and targeted destruction of United States companies in Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id54113100e0a549319aebb6a0e67f4028"><enum>(6)</enum><text>rejects the Government of Russian Federation's attempts to unilaterally change borders by force and its broader aggression that threatens European stability and international law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id208cccdd2c60481e80794d78d5e4331d"><enum>(7)</enum><text>affirms that any negotiated settlement must respect Ukraine’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and include Ukraine as the central party to discussions regarding its future;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28ece9d290594bb1b4181a5a43bda8c2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>encourages continued strong cooperation among NATO allies, the Ukraine Defense Contact Group, and other partners in providing comprehensive security assistance, including advanced air and missile defenses, artillery systems, drones, training support, and intelligence sharing to Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id28e0d582d39c483f8912787e198ecbc7"> <enum>(9)</enum> <text>underscores the importance of coordination with NATO, European, and other like-minded allies to work together as part of any coalition to defend Ukraine intended to deter future Russian aggression against Ukraine and bolster Ukraine’s long-term defense capabilities;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idc0dbeb5cfdc14173bb7e6b43ba79f988"><enum>(10)</enum><text>calls upon Congress and the President to impose additional financial pressure on Vladimir Putin’s government and third-country enablers of Russia’s war to deter further unnecessary aggression against the Ukrainian people and force Mr. Putin to meaningfully engage in peace talks for a lasting peace;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8afbc2af5f4e49b2934779f6ebf483aa"><enum>(11)</enum><text>recognizes President Trump’s continued efforts with international partners to achieve a sustainable peace which requires a strong United States security guarantee for Ukraine, which is necessary for Ukraine to reach a durable peace deal with a belligerent Russian Federation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id233d5ae26c584ee8b35de49e6985dc6e"><enum>(12)</enum><text>underscores that Ukrainian children forcibly abducted by the Government of the Russian Federation must be unconditionally returned home for any peace to be just.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

