<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H846367D9EE1948F8BFA2318C00F8897C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6203 IH: United States Cadet Nurse Corps Service Recognition Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6203</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to recognize and honor the service of individuals who served in the United States Cadet Nurse Corps during World War II, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5018C6866F994F1BB1F7B414F3116F8E" style="OLC"><section id="H9A8393F84EEF4C34AA351F254BDADA53" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Cadet Nurse Corps Service Recognition Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H95B4F1C0F63B4C96BA8F8F38DB37CF97" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recognition and honoring of service of individuals who served in United States Cadet Nurse Corps during World War II</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H6F696E59233C4504AAEC0504D4AD9917" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7D790AD484D44DAC9ED9E3C764E0CDE8"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF80D1891776D4A2589C1FCAF4C969506"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDE7D8AA39101408488592F1B84EA3402"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Service as a member of the United States Cadet Nurse Corps during the period beginning on July 1, 1943, and ending on December 31, 1948, of any individual who was honorably discharged therefrom pursuant to subparagraph (B) shall be considered active duty for purposes of eligibility and entitlement to headstones, markers, and other benefits under chapters 23 and 24 of this title, other than such benefits relating to the interment or inurnment of the individual in Arlington National Cemetery solely by reason of such service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA6910566868419E92777F9D0E8C5100" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFC1E3DF065404E6A90755B775BCDE6EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Defense shall issue to each individual who served as a member of the United States Cadet Nurse Corps during the period beginning on July 1, 1943, and ending on December 31, 1948, a discharge from such service under honorable conditions if the Secretary determines that the nature and duration of the service of the individual so warrants.</text></clause><clause id="H48B9E860EBCF4DC689FA04F31D0B7573" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A discharge under clause (i) shall designate the date of discharge. The date of discharge shall be the date, as determined by the Secretary, of the termination of service of the individual concerned as described in that clause.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD38068A712F436192C97D02D9F2EB59" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who receives a discharge under paragraph (1)(B) for service as a member of the United States Cadet Nurse Corps shall be honored as a veteran but shall not be entitled by reason of such service to any benefit under a law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, except as provided in paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADE99307711E4F8D9A7AA9518766B046" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may design and produce a service medal, memorial plaque or gravemarker, or other commendation to honor individuals who receive a discharge under paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

