<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD2B817A2C1764272BAA76630FCCDDA6D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8446 IH: Family Farm Transition Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8446</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program to connect individuals seeking to transition away from farming with individuals seeking to become farmers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC522F3C54D83465CB3B86903290CFB44" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H86B54515F9C045D8A694C83B54C3B9D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Farm Transition Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF6376B00D3264DE982EADE5D0C3AF9D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Farm land link program</header> <subsection id="H8EEC6C3C410F418A8C202D5D6D5E3D77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a program to connect individuals seeking to transition away from farming with individuals seeking to become farmers.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E3B016DD27B4E879BE9E1C6C4E2086B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the program under subsection (a) by—</text> <paragraph id="H572F3F3375EE4E39B507F4E6C72E831D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining a database of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H28C477BD2FD0468E9503B9F4FFEA0963"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals seeking to transition away from farming; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H035B59065AA84C1CAD9A02DE1F8B9FE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals seeking to become farmers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A511ED45C2847EFB8155BBDEE44C4B4">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating the transfer of farm businesses and properties from individuals seeking to transition away from farming to individuals seeking to become farmers; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F453DA97D5B4DBBAD19AA26EA767435">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>publishing guidance on the transfer of farm businesses and properties.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HCEA1419DD95949F382A0E83CA681F4FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Commission on Farm Transitions study results</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Secretary shall consider the results of the study under section 12609(b) of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2ADCE8B9CDA0452ABCF90D6BADEEBEBF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of program</header> 
<paragraph id="H7D0B85BAFD094DC294E5347885D5F5B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the program under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D42BFF23E5D4ED6B1A8B1B7FABB4D3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days before any date on which the program under subsection (a) is scheduled to terminate, the Secretary may extend such program for an additional period of 5 years.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H51B84AB506074B0C940A71DB5E087D5A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H52157310070142B5A734F2B9274105B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biennial reports</header><text>Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date on which the program terminates under subsection (d), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing any steps taken to implement the program under subsection (a) and any results achieved by such program during the 1-year period ending on the date that is 180 days prior to the submission of such report.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F457A4413FC441E92F6B587FC182DB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the program terminates under subsection (d), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing any steps taken to implement the program under subsection (a) and any results achieved by such program during the period beginning on the date of the last report under paragraph (1) and ending on the date on which the program terminates under subsection (d).</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

