<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H93C72D27AA0B4D239A193888B9B94B87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8422 IH: Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8422</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enact House Resolution 895, One Hundred Tenth Congress,
                  (establishing the Office of Congressional Ethics) into permanent
                  law.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA8EA91AE0F0B4750B6F270F7FDFCD45C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5B2CE09758134E3A8F340A0444611FAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Legislating and Ethical Accountability Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H358086D24C77440DAFCCF19B50C3B9E0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enacting House Resolution 895 into permanent law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">House Resolution 895, One Hundred Tenth Congress, is hereby enacted into permanent law, except that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE77164A1842B450AB692BD3E634B137E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Office of Congressional Ethics shall be treated as a standing committee of the House of Representatives for purposes of section 202(i) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4301">2 U.S.C. 4301(i)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F6C30348B564E0F91C35D9C18ADB463"><enum>(2)</enum><text>references to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct shall be construed as references to the Committee on Ethics;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE7B06BAE5C5401285EA4EE7F4D79BC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no person shall serve as a member of the board for more than 4 2-year terms;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99CD682F21214BF9B9BEA9AD24E429CD" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a vacancy on the board shall be filled not later than 60 calendar days after the date any such vacancy occurs, including any vacancy that is the result of term limits;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF74BDD2580F4461E9DEAB812E54733BC" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>if a vacancy on the board is not filled pursuant to the deadline under paragraph (4), the board shall not be prohibited from operating unless there are fewer than 3 members on the board;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9D967A265F64B8191DF01F37CD479BE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any member of the board currently serving a term in excess of the limitations under paragraph (3) shall be removed from the board not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2CAF785EA3F4CA79A3652886985EC23"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any individual who is the subject of a preliminary review or second-phase review by the board shall be informed of the right to be represented by counsel and invoking that right should not be held negatively against them; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5DA38CA13444620B18A05110495FED1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Office may not take any action that would deny any person any right or protection provided under the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

