<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25931-82D-NH-KRX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3258 IS: Aviation Medication Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3258</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to publish the list of medications that the Administrator has compiled for purposes of the medical certification of airmen and air traffic control specialists, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aviation Medication Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idabcacb52b40546e1917e759596d865b8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Aviation medication transparency; list of approved medications</header><subsection id="id8bcf8562ee734e1f9b38785c895e3f4f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to ensure that aviation stakeholders, including airmen, air traffic control specialists, and individuals training to become airmen or air traffic control specialists, who are applicants for medical certification are informed, in a user-friendly and accessible manner, of the medications they may be safely prescribed.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24753701868c4303bbb44c0c45b0c55d"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall publish and maintain on a publicly available website of the Federal Aviation Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>FAA</quote>) a list of medications that the Administrator, as of the date of publication, has—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2176f16a83874902ac87b15e6cb76af8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determined may be safely prescribed to an applicant for medical certification to treat certain medical conditions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5f7c5fe47284c10a3ffd50601ad87be"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approved for purposes of the issuance of a medical certification to an airman or air traffic control specialist.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2a2cdc031a8b4920b6a8e2a48c7d8697"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>To ensure medical appropriateness, user-friendliness, and appropriate dissemination, the list required under subsection (b) shall—</text><paragraph id="id19b0b7d8c17144d6a88a11c9ebbd35d0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be drafted in consultation with—</text><subparagraph id="id6a1e5ed0b231497b80032d35b40998d4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Aeromedical Innovation and Modernization Working Group (established under section 411(a) of the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44703">49 U.S.C. 44703</external-xref> note)) (in this section referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6270f6de32ef41dfb337a97d93372748"><enum>(B)</enum><text>institutions of higher education that are accredited by the Aviation Accreditation Board International;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95d0b0062f36462193416f3cfbea9a5f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the certified exclusive bargaining representatives of air traffic controllers of the FAA certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7bc74222907349fa97b971bf3126495d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>organizations representing certified collective bargaining representative of airline pilots; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7cabe8ef2efd4e378a7aaead7da0276d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other stakeholder determined relevant by the Working Group;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb843732b0ed498f971af0a2b6782253"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cover all medications approved by the Administrator, including prescription medications and over-the-counter medications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id09941945e1c148c18234ed27dfb17dc1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be drafted in a user-friendly and accessible manner and provided to airmen, air traffic control specialists, and individuals training to become airmen or air traffic control specialists at the time when any such individual first seeks a medical certification;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idebfcba49605349e39f1f80999223aa71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if applicable, indicate the minimum and average period of time an airman or air traffic control specialist is required to have limited or no duties to stabilize on an approved medication;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4e8a7122b914cb89c92d8a00cb4f69c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include the list of medications that the Administrator has designated as <quote>Do Not Issue</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idddb471a186c44b03a46951e87f8057a7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>include information for doctors or medical providers to contact the FAA regarding questions related to such list, including through a new or existing mechanism that is accessible to such doctors and medical providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2935316c44894241a6cdedbd1351c6b2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>include any additional information that the Administrator determines is appropriate to provide with respect to what conditions a certain medication may or may not be used to treat, as well as any information to explain why a medication is allowed or prohibited by the FAA; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8d6d855bd934b2a96c20570db681cac"><enum>(8)</enum><text>include any other information or clarification that the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf990af01cee24ffcbaee7dbf7cbfdff6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual update</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of publication of the list required under subsection (b), and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall update such list, as appropriate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

