<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H683319F0145A477282BDEADA250CDCCA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 946 IH: Honoring the accomplishments and legacy of Rita Moreno.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 946</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the accomplishments and legacy of Rita Moreno.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Rita Moreno was born Rosa Dolores Alverío on December 11, 1931, in Humacao, Puerto Rico;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Rita Moreno migrated to the United States with her mother at the age of 5 and grew up in New York City, where she began studying dance and performing at a young age;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Rita Moreno began her career in Hollywood during the 1950s, where she faced deep-rooted racial and gender stereotypes in the film industry;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, despite limited and typecast roles for Latina actresses, Rita Moreno persevered and became the first Latina woman to win an Academy Award, receiving the Oscar for Best Supporting Actress in 1962 for her role as Anita in <quote>West Side Story</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Rita Moreno is one of the few performers and first Hispanic person in history to achieve the legendary EGOT status in 1977, having won an Emmy, Grammy, Oscar, and Tony Award, in addition to being recognized with the Screen Actors Guild Life Achievement Award in 2013 and a Peabody Award in 2019;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Rita Moreno has been recognized with the Nation’s highest honors, including the Presidential Medal of Freedom in 2004, the National Medal of Arts in 2009, and the Kennedy Center Honors in 2015, for her extraordinary contributions to American culture and the performing arts;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, beyond her acclaimed career on stage and screen, Rita Moreno has been a tireless advocate for women’s rights, civil rights, and equity in the arts, serving as a role model for generations of performers; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas her life story, from her humble beginnings in rural Puerto Rico to her rise as a celebrated national icon, embodies the American dream, artistic excellence, and the contributions of Latinas to the cultural fabric of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE04BE60A03864ADBA3FD8B41361EFAE7"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCFF1426ED1614A95879BC5C179578DA6"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H4DF155BBA5834B43ABA00C5F6960CFED"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the accomplishments and enduring legacy of Rita Moreno, a pioneering Latina artist, proud Puerto Rican, and cultural icon of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5AF0E0D6875433A8C32B0EF3D94176B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends Rita Moreno for her lifelong contributions to the arts, civil rights, and Latino representation in American media; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43093FAD4F8344D8AE9D04DDFF9BF7F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon the people of the United States to celebrate and honor the life and work of Rita Moreno, whose remarkable journey continues to inspire and enrich the Nation.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

