<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2792EDF7C1014D8EA4F6B0724DC64EE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9268 IH: Stop Crypto ATM Scams Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9268</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Bank Secrecy Act to require the registration of digital asset kiosk operators and to require such operators to comply with anti-money laundering and anti-fraud requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC6B47165FA47427D95751858F579E9D2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF5CF9BE3F9D44CB3B578F752E6B9FDED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Crypto ATM Scams Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB49F52CBE03D4A09B986BBE0750E06CB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Registration of digital asset kiosk operators</header> 
<subsection id="HCEEB7FAB51384AB3B83F56FFA7C2F0EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5330 of title 31, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H7FB38D2B61CB49C69AB90B5F757AF5CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57A6F0C52D9243F8987389DF6C2706D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(A), by inserting <quote>, any digital asset kiosk operator,</quote> after <quote>similar instruments</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7384B0F8518D465F935DFA895852FF45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H936CA0514B5F43BF8C424811418749FB"> 
<paragraph id="H401619397DA7498EA230BBF2DED1D598"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Digital asset kiosk terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>digital asset kiosk</term> and <term>digital asset kiosk operator</term> have the meaning given those terms, respectively, under section 5337(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C6BFF4956F24A80B53BDF1554299BE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE726BDE8949469F8E124E35A2427C38"> 
<subsection id="HF394746B7C284B0C85211C71A5E13081"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Registration of digital asset kiosk locations</header> 
<paragraph id="H3E3DAD6567FF44B9A5248D35EC099313"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall require a digital asset kiosk operator—</text> <subparagraph id="H3ADA2A0040D24A1D9D1996216D6E4E59"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before beginning to operate a digital asset kiosk, to submit a list containing the physical address of each digital asset kiosk owned or operated by the digital asset kiosk operator; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2E9A3DE8FE64C5C951F41F15CFD2779"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than once every 90 days thereafter, to submit an update to such list.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BF1EC7E41CE4ECE80E32F2DE8201B51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form and manner of registration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each submission by a digital asset kiosk operator pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E8FC501D8284A2AB4D2EF08A13D4078"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the legal name of the digital asset kiosk operator;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H76187711A531412A8732DE3B7118F2BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the physical address of each digital asset kiosk owned or operated by the digital asset kiosk operator that is located in the United States or the territories of the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H526B8E59E8924651ACD03CF5A61EA7FB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">up-to-date contact information for the digital asset kiosk operator’s compliance officer described in section 5318(h)(1)(B);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4106CE0C0182409FA56E4D91BB300BD2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the start date of operation of each digital asset kiosk; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H445D8993A4AE4FB2B5B3F3A288A6FD91"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the end date of operation of each digital asset kiosk, if applicable.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EDD51D2E4CE47A29993C619CCB825CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>False and incomplete information</header><text>The filing of false or materially incomplete information in a submission required under paragraph (1) shall be deemed a failure to comply with the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H345BADE3B86C4E3AA6C80A1A287A64F6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall make all information submitted under this subsection available to the public, including on a website of the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H277AA6F86E6541B79506D6C204599E62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of application for existing digital asset kiosk operators</header><text>A person who is a digital asset kiosk operator (as defined in section 5337(a) of title 31, United States Code) on the date of enactment of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4445EDC069F24CC89043FE500E37283C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, not later than the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, submit the initial list described in such section 5330(f)(1)(A); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB09C69DBA7204122ADE162C6AD789D75"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, not later than 90 days after the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, submit the first update of such list.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H67B90EB7C7444706BE093AEB97F4C947"><enum>3.</enum><header>Anti-money laundering and anti-fraud requirements for digital asset kiosk operators</header> 
<subsection id="HE18108B39D114783BD1AD2AB6BBC2AF5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HE70827F7A107493CBD299704617D7170" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H366D3AEE5C094A7CB2D0791644B20C10"><enum>5337.</enum><header>Anti-money laundering and anti-fraud requirements for digital asset kiosk operators</header> <subsection id="HB529B5F1F5234EFB895DF840AB83D730"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7C59E56C6F084DBBABBE1AAA85669BEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Charge</header><text>The term <term>charge</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H03A30278E9B64781BBF24049AAA280BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fees or expenses paid by a customer; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8215A3B19DDE4ACA89B17749BDEEF19F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the difference between the market price of a digital asset and the price of the digital asset charged to the customer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF919152B2C246B79E5977D52C6762CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>digital asset</term> means any digital representation of value that is issued or transferred using a cryptographically secured distributed ledger, blockchain technology, or any other similar technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83C7494182064F68BC690EF6D6CE4B30" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Digital asset kiosk</header><text>The term <term>digital asset kiosk</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H16CD110857204C13989721D23B40B4BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an automated teller machine that facilitates the buying, selling, or exchange of digital assets for fiat currency or other digital assets; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5DE8776344994C43B31F31D4A6CA8D58" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a digital or mobile application that facilitates the buying, selling, or exchange of fiat currency for digital assets at a participating physical location in an organized merchant network.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D922D55AEB945239A3E4C28A822804A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Digital asset kiosk operator</header><text>The term <term>digital asset kiosk operator</term> means a person that owns or operates a digital asset kiosk.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04DDE5ADB40B405F980C9E63B637B0F0" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Digital asset wallet</header><text>The term <term>digital asset wallet</term> means a software application or other mechanism that provides a means for holding, storing, and transferring digital assets.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55EFCFFD643449B1937EE88BF78E20B2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Digital asset wallet address</header><text>The term <term>digital asset wallet address</term> means an alphanumeric identifier that is associated with a digital asset wallet and represents a potential destination for a digital asset transfer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDF0F8C26457464BA9DAF2006DC833B5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Extended business hours</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>extended business hours</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HF9F2DF675D834C2AA10A49E369A8CA9F"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the hours between 8:00 a.m. and 8:00 p.m. local time on business days; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87BE081BCD9542F2B4AD04E1283EF994">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the hours between 9:00 a.m. and 5:00 p.m. local time on weekends and holidays.</text>
                </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C0725A7ABA1448690B5356EF6EA3AA5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Market price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>market price</term> means, with respect to a digital asset, the current market price of a particular digital asset publicly quoted on a digital asset trading platform that is registered with the Department of the Treasury for a particular time.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33123CF8ED034E9AAEF0DBFE3544703F" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>New customer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a digital asset kiosk operator, a person is a <quote>new customer</quote> of the digital asset kiosk operator if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H85CF5BC9446C42BF80A0F1E7A80B862C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person has never previously transacted with the digital asset kiosk operator; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87D728C0B0954BCFB4FF0A452573C372"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">less than 14 days have elapsed since the person entered into their first transaction with the digital asset kiosk operator.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2B3F3873C6634E9693321FBC6731A781">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>Anti-Money laundering program</header>
              <paragraph id="H892C3628D2F04693A6DCBF5D74160BFF">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>A digital asset kiosk operator shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HFDFF36EE8F974CD69687AE4C65F3798B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, implement, and routinely update an anti-money laundering program described in section 5318(h), and file a copy of such program with the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H064D7DFE3DEB496CA14BB1CF3096424D">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be subject to the requirement to report suspicious transactions described in section 5318(g); and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H3CCB512802EC4805B949B47171E70961">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>be subject to the requirements described under this subchapter to file currency transaction reports.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="HDADFE502479A405991EB4690AF56D30F">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Risk-based requirements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue rules to require a digital asset kiosk operator, in implementing an anti-money laundering program required under paragraph (1)(A), to adopt controls that are reasonably designed to—</text>
                <subparagraph id="H869A2272A0714D6EBEEE7F41C06349F2">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">verify a customer’s identity, including during any online pre-registration process and at the physical digital asset kiosk location;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H7E77D96CD0CA49A6978212E46911ACD3">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>monitor for digital asset kiosk transactions involving a digital asset wallet directly or indirectly associated with any digital asset wallet address listed on any relevant sanctions lists through the use of blockchain analytics tools;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H9DA66D5C19D3475AAC53EE1596409690">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>assess the risks associated with and the likelihood of future illicit activity in connection with digital asset kiosk transactions through the use of blockchain analytics tools; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="HCE0A041FE0E44890B94C1EB1E666B064">
                  <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain restrictions that prevent more than one customer of such digital asset kiosk operator from using the same digital wallet address.</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5A15579BE2044F0B64FE541FA2D8CFE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limits for digital asset kiosk transactions</header> 
<paragraph id="H5BB20227C2874A608A8195FF2B67FC3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Daily limits for new customers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A digital asset kiosk operator may not accept one or more digital asset kiosk transactions on behalf of a new customer that have a total monetary value of more than $2,000 during a 24-hour period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA929F0EB216E42FCAD7A27FC3A6E3862"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Total limits for new customers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A digital asset kiosk operator may not accept digital asset kiosk transactions on behalf of a new customer that have a total monetary value, in the aggregate, of more than $10,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H746712921FFD4AF0883BC38231FB9B84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Daily limits for existing customers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a customer that is not a new customer, a digital asset kiosk operator may not accept one or more digital asset kiosk transactions on behalf of the customer that have a total monetary value of more than $7,500 during a 24-hour period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H456B6D3075A742FDA98C90CD8BCD3E64"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall update the dollar amounts in this subsection every 5 years to reflect the change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F0E7BEC766D405EB7D0C74FB15A3BAC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury may issue rules to adjust the transaction limit amounts described under this subsection, as the Secretary determines are reasonably necessary to deter fraudulent activity and illicit finance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8CC249E8EE1B450EBAA0A54A4EE1B976"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Disclosures for customers</header> <paragraph id="HF8B3C16A88AF41818E7F722856474987"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A digital asset kiosk operator shall take reasonable steps to provide written disclosure to any customer prior to initiating a digital asset kiosk transaction, in English and in the same language principally used by the digital asset kiosk operator to advertise or solicit customers, including by displaying the disclosure in a prominent, conspicuous, easily readable manner, that contains the terms, conditions, and itemized elements of the transaction and contains the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H75AA3FB37E1249BDB37C896732B84EB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A warning written prominently in bold type stating the following: <quote>Warning: Losses due to fraudulent or accidental transactions may not be recoverable and digital asset kiosk transactions are irreversible.</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B778597E9364850B30A43CA06560D13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The following statement: <quote>Digital assets are not legal tender. Digital assets are not backed by the full faith and credit of the United States Government or guaranteed by the United States Government. Digital asset wallet accounts and digital asset balances are not subject to FDIC insurance or NCUA insurance.</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB275FAE59B364EC2A20B9E2DFE5D29AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The amount of digital assets involved in the transaction and the type of digital assets involved in the transaction, including the ticker or symbol that is used to represent a digital asset.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2388DABCED04B2F99634D61672400B0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The U.S. dollar price of the digital assets involved in the digital asset kiosk transaction that is charged to the customer and the current U.S. dollar market price of such digital assets, as is quoted on at least one digital asset trading platform that is registered with the Department of the Treasury and is identified by name, at the time the disclosure is provided.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H279E421CAC2444818A8808B7578DB088"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of charges collected from the customer by the digital asset kiosk operator, which shall be—</text> <clause id="HB9BB35B2FBA34D1EB997EB7ED069360D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>displayed prominently in bold type on a dedicated disclosure screen; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7B51F065AF0746DD922AEDE37A924ED0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>presented as an itemized list that separately identifies—</text> <subclause id="H77AD105516294CC7AE712D76B8D26BA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any fees or expenses paid by the customer, expressed in United States dollars and as the percentage of the transaction; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9B42E69F49374AD9855DB2F268CBBF39"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the difference, expressed in United States dollars, between the current market price of the digital assets involved in the transaction and the price of such digital assets charged to the customer.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA11065FE550640D2B1E59CE55EB9FEE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Federal Trade Commission and the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, shall issue guidance to assist digital asset kiosk operators with providing disclosures described in paragraph (1) that are effective, clear and conspicuous, easily understandable, and displayed in a standardized format.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B97DBE542704F27BC31BB6E7EA32C74">
              <enum>(e)</enum>
              <header>Anti-Fraud measures</header>
              <paragraph id="H8C1FFC68C50046948706E3946F1A9735">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>A digital asset kiosk operator shall take reasonable steps to detect and prevent financial fraud, including by taking the following steps:</text>
                <subparagraph id="HAA76EFBCD6B241A9A7F2AF487B26980F">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Providing clear scam warnings to customers before entering into a digital asset transaction that, at a minimum, address the following common fraudulent tactics:</text>
                  <clause id="H021852710B3B482E8378812E3661DA60">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payment requests to an individual the customer has never met.</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H28490E776F3541E0A69A2527115DBAC4" commented="no">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initial contact via social media, online dating, or other messaging applications.</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H59A9B08B59AF4038A62BF2A70B1D8072">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Impersonation of representatives from government agencies, financial institutions, credit unions, or other legitimate organizations or businesses.</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H001A375BABD2494EA1699308D55FBC80">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Urgent or emergency requests.</text> </clause> <clause id="H7F912232173D404E9B8893245BECF569"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>Utilizing a scannable code associated with a digital asset wallet that is not owned by the customer.</text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H92A7051E9B0C4BA1A3D1880F581EA191">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Updating, on an annual basis, the warnings described in subparagraph (A), which shall be informed by the annual fraud alerts or notices described in subsection (k).</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H361B294F580C43BEB27D94CBC2076A8A">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
                <header>Anti-fraud policy</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue rules to require a digital asset kiosk operator to develop, implement, and routinely update an anti-fraud policy that—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HBBF030CFFAE44DD5968FAFAD33EFAB0C">
                  <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is in writing and available for inspection by the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary’s designee;</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H174971555095417F8B25AB4325AED4AF">
                  <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is signed by, certified by, and accountable to senior management of the digital asset kiosk operator; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H2714C881E1464B65AD8C25DE6CA98E91">
                  <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>includes policies, procedures, controls, and monitoring mechanisms to address the fraudulent practices described in paragraph (1)(A).</text>
                </subparagraph>
              </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0DDD6F1CE89A4370A4264A0633E5AC89"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Acknowledgment of disclosures</header> 
<paragraph id="HE7C195F016E0410A9FB18174B60C809F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each time a customer uses a digital asset kiosk, the digital asset kiosk operator shall ensure acknowledgment of all disclosures required under subsection (d) and fraud warnings under subsection (e) via confirmation of consent of the customer at the digital asset kiosk.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8D34438F5664377822389078D7F5BBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for new customers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to initiating a digital asset kiosk transaction on behalf of a new customer, a digital asset kiosk operator shall obtain confirmation from the new customer that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H72811BCCC7604C408F44F9E014CB1BAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the new customer has reviewed the disclosure of charges described in subsection (d)(1)(E); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2338AFDFCBF4494AA9805A65F794B4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the new customer understands the total charges as a percentage of the transaction amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H909D53D7E06045209C3E7038285887F0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of constructions on customer remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An acknowledgment described under this subsection shall not be construed to waive, nullify, or limit any right to a refund or other remedy available to a customer under applicable State or local law.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7EC45AE229694EB2BDE284886CAD822B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Receipts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completion of each digital asset kiosk transaction, the digital asset kiosk operator shall provide the customer with a physical or electronic receipt, which shall include the following information:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF57DE80B71E840D097406DFE8C4B4B60"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name and contact information of the digital asset kiosk operator, including a telephone number for a customer service help line.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC172CD147C6479EB034D4B164765023"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The name of the customer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C9311022DA54E2AB0269B0549CAD225"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The type, value, date, and precise time of the digital asset kiosk transaction, and each applicable digital asset wallet address.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H818BD9C85AB14E52811C2D282CE06657"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The amount of United States dollars or other fiat currency involved in the transaction.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E4C25B4D8C841CF8011F512D932BE10"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount, in United States dollars, of any charges collected by the digital asset kiosk operator in relation to the transaction, presented as line-items summed within the total transaction.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AD342B5A52F4971A256DF02C850AA67"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A statement that the customer should contact law enforcement if they suspect fraud or scams, including the contact information for the relevant local law enforcement agency and for applicable State and Federal law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1102C7D74BCF43B6B29BA6A15DA27D6D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any additional information the digital asset kiosk operator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5CF0A7CFCA3A4830A53383A940EA12B1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Customer service help line</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A digital asset kiosk operator shall provide live customer service during extended business hours and display the phone number for such service in a clear, conspicuous, and easily readable manner upon each digital asset kiosk.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEEC91EB049B6460B9A6C07515756630B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Refunds for charges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A digital asset kiosk operator shall issue a refund for charges collected from a customer in connection with a digital asset kiosk transaction within 30 days if—</text> <paragraph id="H90B8222242E34AF5AF950CAFFD85A690"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the customer was fraudulently induced into engaging in the digital asset kiosk transaction; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B3E0F61A81B448384E4C5DB1F146F59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the customer files a complaint to the digital asset kiosk operator, which includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H4D7FB8461022427CB057FACB497750D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, address, and phone number of the customer;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7898A4784DB402E91C140A9B6276D48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information that establishes the type, value, date, and time of the digital asset kiosk transaction; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2DC23B49D824300BB6CE9A447F2BCE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a copy of a report to a State or local law enforcement agency or a Federal or State authority made not later than 90 days after the digital asset kiosk transaction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50AB1EA9F35C4C25B9E9B6FD71331A04"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Communications with Financial Crimes Enforcement Network and law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall issue rules to require a digital asset kiosk operator to provide the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network and other relevant law enforcement and government agencies with a dedicated and frequently monitored phone number and email address to facilitate communication with the operator in the event of reported or suspected fraudulent activity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5B28E6101E624E2293EA7FAC53BBAB73"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Fraud scheme alerts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this section, and for each calendar year thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Federal Trade Commission, shall issue an alert or notice to assist digital asset kiosk operators in—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1617D8E1DC0947858FF4923C91F06056"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying emerging fraud schemes involving digital asset kiosks; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5ABB60B3B0CE47DF919859A4E49405DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>filing suspicious activity reports.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB37818922104C50AE8BB231F00D4E76" commented="no"><enum>(l)</enum><header>State regulatory authority</header> 
<paragraph id="H15204C25C2864D18872DC5107FC1FD0D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effect on State licensing laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of a State regulatory agency to require a digital asset kiosk operator to ensure registration, licensing, and compliance related to applicable State laws.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6693DB9366C84CC1B870CBB48333BC96" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State-issued decals for compliant digital asset kiosks</header><text>A State regulatory agency may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5E6625E2839F4F9BB5066FA806E56DD3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue a decal or physical sign that can be affixed to a digital asset kiosk, in a form or manner determined by the State regulatory agency, to signal compliance with applicable State and Federal laws, including whether—</text> <clause id="H226C8FA756D245369A560990FC78018D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the physical location of such digital asset kiosk has been filed with the Secretary of the Treasury; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3DEC11E1735E47D4928E4446C91B48B9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the operator of such digital asset kiosk is registered with the Secretary of the Treasury and has obtained the appropriate licensing from the State regulatory agency;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7627194DB854CC49DD0E008211FB0A6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administer a process through which a digital asset kiosk operator is issued such decal or sign for affixation to the digital asset kiosk; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43A68DE7C4FF49968C326D5DEBA1DB5A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impose penalties for any false advertising, misuse of signage, or misrepresentations of regulated or compliant status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA0575E3A580487BA22BE279BA02A6A2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with State regulators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, may enter into agreements with State regulatory agencies to facilitate the supervision of digital asset kiosk operators and enhance compliance with Federal standards, including agreements relating to the coordination of examinations and the sharing of supervisory information for the purposes of enforcing applicable Federal standards.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95033B0493774DD4BD977127CFD54791" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect on State law</header><text>This section—</text> <subparagraph id="H0A24D1BA7ED74642BDB9B3E9AE294E8F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall supersede any applicable State or local law with respect to restrictions or requirements established after the effective date of this section on the total monetary value that any customer may exchange in one or multiple digital asset kiosk transactions within a defined time period;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96C9CEF27728445B879D96236D49CAB2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be construed to limit the authority of a State regulatory agency or local authority to impose other requirements in order to protect consumers or prevent fraudulent or money laundering activity;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB965407FC324CB7A245505D1B5FD26E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be construed to permit a digital asset kiosk operator to operate or otherwise conduct business in a State without obtaining the appropriate licensing from the applicable State regulatory agency and complying with other applicable State laws; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H166A075EE4D3492AA827D3900D0B93B8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (A), may not be construed as altering, limiting, or affecting the authority of a State attorney general or any State regulatory agency to bring an enforcement action or other regulatory proceeding arising solely under the law in effect in that State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1126B4042626498590C1DF43DE55999C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5337 of title 31, United States Code, shall take effect at the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A7DAD8533664690841153BCC7B2B3B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/5336">section 5336</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H8ED3FB235DE244DEBD9A591AF0734919" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">5337. Anti-money laundering and anti-fraud requirements for digital asset kiosk operators.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

