<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06A26B545A07474299E61375F4680AE4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9747 IH: Welcome Back to the Health Care Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9747</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for career support for a skilled, internationally educated health care workforce.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3BB140D747954EB6BC890866E352A938" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H1CAABC843F284E69A91453DA8476F6A8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Welcome Back to the Health Care Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7F41F01C0BD49A2957B5E17A55B13A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Support for skilled internationally educated health care workforce</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H302ACFE8CD48441A92FA3B2A3144C976"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part E of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295f">42 U.S.C. 295f et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6E6363C198D4AC0B15A2267F6BD6A3D">
<section id="HEF5CFE0F47DF4451AF0E5FDEC4D814EA"><enum>779.</enum><header>Support for skilled internationally educated health care workforce</header>
<subsection id="H2DAEB0D9887948FFA1239EE4008C877E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
<paragraph id="HEBDF714C0CD740A3BBC53D40022FACEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Welcome Back to the Health Care Workforce Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to provide career support for internationally educated health care professionals to integrate into, and expand, the health care workforce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15FBDE3F1A4D4B188CD8E48CA98739DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Before awarding any grants under this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9F987F23CCB54A788F792E331C24ED26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header>
<paragraph id="H085BE43A25014041A16484BA059BA4BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA52D1EC46A444809308DB7ED65C158C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H513C31BB99304EC5AD4B17B4200D3A61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of each project described in subsection (d) that the eligible entity proposes to develop or continue under the grant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7A0D8FD40D44E62B58BFAD0F3EFB71B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information demonstrating that the eligible entity has the capacity to fully carry out and administer such projects;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H111502D9C56247E0AAC751B1C014D0A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan for the proposed projects that includes, at a minimum—</text> <clause id="HB9834F38808B4C1ABCB15C401E0BA2BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demographic information regarding the population to be served by the grant and how the current health care workforce, as of the date of application, is not meeting the health needs of the community to be served, including information on the health care workforce shortages in the area to be served by the grant; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H141950EBAB6E4A3FA8A88C92C69F2616"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity will make use of grant funds to support the identification and advancement of internationally educated health care professionals in the geographic area to be served by the grant;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52BBC3DD3E3248C29749A3746179329A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the eligible entity's experience in working with internationally educated health care professionals;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2C0EC1073A8F4649801E8623F4C912F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the partnership the eligible entity has formed with various entities, including institutions of higher education and health care employers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H560CCBDF137C407DBEEBE5D08F0A383A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any additional information determined relevant by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H13ADCCBA98174DADA489E6DEC99FF62A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities whose projects support the recruitment and retention of—</text> <paragraph id="HF7B95F5054CB4E0D95510C27994B81ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>internationally educated health care professionals in professions in communities experiencing gaps between their existing health care workforce, as of the date of the application for the grant, and the needs of the community; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H208C0F8783CB47F6B9F42FD033E7BDB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>internationally educated health care professionals in rural communities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE0B88DDB13F44174930D3DDDE20C47C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> <paragraph id="HF20D6F9FCC7E4B1E847491184392D320"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supported projects</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFD002F27AE94A27A326DEB591FDE388"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use grant funds to carry out—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E9094B6F57E4A0286EF946B462A12D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 or more system-level improvement projects described in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DE9B15273B8426692CEECD01956A3A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 or more individual-level improvement projects described in subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4D26810A684449E5BB62A37394B2AD86"><enum>(B)</enum><header>System-level improvements</header><text>A project described in this subparagraph expands culturally and linguistically competent supports for internationally educated health care professionals, which may include—</text> <clause id="H338CD0162FE54EE38852F6FD9BF7E473"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establishing a network of partners that offer prerequisite educational opportunities and continuing education opportunities;</text></clause>
<clause id="H784413AA3B9C40F788B67FB471166840"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>developing peer support and mentoring opportunities;</text></clause> <clause id="HD5895CFCC75E413EA4835A7B33D4073C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>educating employers regarding the abilities and capacities of internationally educated health care professionals;</text></clause>
<clause id="H45BA485B86364370A198E16185398590"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>developing career ladder opportunities for internationally educated health care professionals, such as—</text> <subclause id="H0EF247D99C474DE9AED52829D1E9B840"><enum>(I)</enum><text>developing a system to provide ongoing supportive services once employment is obtained;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HAA09CA2CC14D4B6EA401C453D3F8EF1D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>funding leadership development, continuing education, preparatory classes, examinations, and licensing and certification costs, in order to support health care workforce advancement; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H08D8470C0D3E40E1B1A7E76F6B43B74B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>education and support on how to serve as an educator in a clinical or academic setting; or</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H9493940BEFA94B9E8E4FEA2C974669B7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>creating and carrying out projects for the purposes of increasing the retention of internationally educated health care professionals in the health care workforce.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H433D902AB44E4467A8E0738646BE0674"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Individual-level improvements</header><text>A project described in this subparagraph tailors individual support for internationally educated health care professionals, which may include—</text>
<clause id="H88FE8F008041488990A166B7668A8F3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support for the licensing process;</text></clause> <clause id="HAFBDBCA36EAF45C6AF5F0FA85A5F2E3C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>funding and facilitating access to accelerated and contextualized courses on English as a second language and board or licensure examination preparation;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4C7E7C1D46144B299318DE9C78BF23A0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>culturally competent individualized career counseling and coaching;</text></clause> <clause id="H7D8C9C55F09542AAADF01360C8E379E7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>individualized guidance and support for the credentialing evaluation process;</text></clause>
<clause id="H006AC9EC50134C8A9F1880BA8BD23C0A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>providing individualized work-readiness supports and clinical experience and training for internationally educated health care professionals who need such supports, experience, or training;</text></clause> <clause id="HBDBF58209E5848CBB263DA102462EB30"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>educating internationally educated health care professionals employed by the eligible entity on their rights as employees;</text></clause>
<clause id="H222EC8C6433E4B02ABA6DD327838932D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>providing individualized supportive services to internationally educated health care professionals in order to support their employment, retention, or career advancement, which may include support for living expenses, health care, or transportation; or</text></clause> <clause id="H9FAA18FBCB104F7D91383E4685FA6B99"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>assisting internationally educated health care professionals in obtaining overseas academic or training records.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36D3420F7F754456BBEA7548FAAE9D64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use for administrative costs</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may use not more than 10 percent of the grant funds for costs associated with the administration of the projects under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1767811086745D58614D0BA073F9E74"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum requirement to provide direct support</header><text>Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use not less than 20 percent of the grant funds to carry out projects described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEE601AF44F15469C933CABD70471B40D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use such grant only to supplement, and not supplant, the amount of funds that otherwise would be available to address the recruitment, training and education, retention, and advancement of internationally educated health care professionals in the health care workforce of the State or region served by the eligible entity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0B2D20BE7B2E458385F10742BAB2002D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluations and reports</header> <paragraph id="HFC0C5522864942C095B1EC83B5AA9397"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting requirements by grant recipients</header> <subparagraph id="H1969D9D57CD243C2A8C8177C5DCC4353"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall annually provide a report on the grant to the Secretary, at such time and containing such data and information as requested by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB3901114995945A9824D1ED0B6C50431"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15710CA8D55D452CAD3BE696122FFBD3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of internationally educated health care professionals who participated in the projects supported under the grant; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA0E59EB3844409CB508E8FE1948C9EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each project carried out under the grant, in the aggregate and disaggregated by the demographic categories as required by the Secretary—</text> <subclause id="HB1ED9EC5A6FF48378B350A9139201EB7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of internationally educated health care professionals who accessed services, benefits, or supports through the project;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H2453B68527BB475193BE8C95C58A8DDD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of internationally educated health care professionals who through the project attained employment in the health care workforce, in the aggregate and disaggregated by occupation and industry;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H23498A2698D1408BB8986A336B3C41C7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the number of internationally educated health care professionals who participated in the project and withdrew, unsuccessfully attempted to obtain board certification, or were terminated from the project without completing training or attaining employment in the health care workforce; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HFD149634A38140B4A5DCD5D28FC2EA01"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>data on the country of education of the participating internationally educated health care professionals.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDEF79C01D7042428A1B08D91DC39C66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress by Secretary</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Welcome Back to the Health Care Workforce Act</short-title>, and each year thereafter until all projects supported under this section are completed, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to Congress a report on the progress of each project supported under a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5F98434592E04E6B9FCEAC91C300713F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H55F476C8B3BB4882B30CC98D7A54834F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a consortium of 2 or more of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H4FBA6CE50E134B6CB5D63E03E9CB1710"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A hospital, health system, or other entity that provides health care.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93111AA41A694F95A887A34B22A6E7BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A community-based or other nonprofit entity with experience in clinical health or public health services.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9BF37CB7B9744218ACEC2DFC06DEF982"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E1C87FA20354D95AC98011225C8ABE9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An area health education center.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8E15866097CA4C9BA9FDD46B313CD2B4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A State government, local government, or Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85B0E31FCCB3441DA0E209DC55C6E378"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A Federally qualified health center.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC83E58689D3B49D39E273B6578A066BA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other type of entity determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3044077996FA4B99A4AC7D7B23B67F76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employ; employer</header><text>The terms <term>employ</term> and <term>employer</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H47C0F30A95434E4E8889BF2977E5DBDB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health care workforce</header><text>The term <term>health care workforce</term> means the workforce comprised of health care providers with direct patient care and support responsibilities and public health workers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C955EFF6D70421BA40B6602C95CF3DE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the <act-name parsable-cite="ISDA">Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act</act-name>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H733E0A887B1141299419CA501F664925"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDB61E91E388492889C4744A44B6C8A6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Internationally educated health care professional</header><text>The term <term>internationally educated health care professional</term> means an individual who—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6DB9529217FF4FA3B5B1EFAB626BCB75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>completed the education requirements for a health care workforce profession in another country; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0AFDBC3A038B40D780D6B29ACFAEC8B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text>
<clause id="H0B17110A3A1E4F868E738EABC427DEB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lawfully admitted for permanent residence;</text></clause> <clause id="HFC7175FC1049494FB21E5381E7030D3A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>admitted as a refugee under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></clause>
<clause id="H63F89895C529404C95D93AF2E3F79DA1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>granted asylum under section 208 of such Act; or</text></clause> <clause id="H551670A1DAE6445296A1AD455935D4C6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an alien otherwise authorized to be employed in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2EDE3E8A5A874BBF8696ADE10A5B6EBB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

