<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC376C97233744C2489165CF2D9E05F29" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8597 IH: Air Traffic Situational Awareness Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8597</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to acquire and install certified airborne position reference tools at air traffic control towers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H16E4F52584994D5BAC8D303A0E0481F8" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H41D5FB9C7B1947E0A5340B2E31DAC567"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Air Traffic Situational Awareness Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ED1AED682F94B898A6F14C466BAD394"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to air traffic situational awareness</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H634B417550AF4186A500E9FE4A6FD27E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Airborne position reference tool installation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall acquire and install certified Airborne Position Reference Tools at air traffic control towers of the Federal Aviation Administration that are—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3F99BD41DA641C9848188FA9E8D3136"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operating under contract with the Federal Aviation Administration pursuant to section 47124 of title 49, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19A31F8B7EDE4895B26FF6F7CB486580"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not equipped with Standard Terminal Automation Replacement Systems or other situational awareness tools.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H88E0E5984AB647A7A22E0937414A7408"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Standard Terminal Automation Replacement System installation and maintenance</header><text>Section 47124(f)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21F9495A18F84B23A8F2131CDF036624"> <paragraph id="HFD7F003396C4419E9E5C8ED28991D1F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Installation and maintenance</header><text>For any tower operated under the Contract Tower Program that is not equipped with Standard Terminal Automation Replacement Systems or other situational awareness tools as of the date of enactment of the <short-title>Air Traffic Situational Awareness Enhancement Act</short-title>, not later than 1 year after such date, the Secretary shall purchase a Standard Terminal Automation Replacement System, or any equivalent system, and install and maintain such system using services directly from an original equipment manufacturer or services of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE606010326B943F4BBD474DC677C13A0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standard Terminal Automation Replacement System funding</header><text>Section 47124(f)(3) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE2100E94D494BD7BD75C8B05809A0FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C0402B27F2D40A6AAA7107561D768FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraphs (C) through (E) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD736090672224DD9ABE35321CA0CEF69"> <subparagraph id="HF0986873CECF430687E9AFA868942803"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall establish, in consultation with contract tower operators, an appropriate training program to periodically train air traffic controllers employed by such operators to ensure proper and efficient integration and use of the situational awareness equipment and technology described in paragraph (1) into contract tower operations.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD033D34B37864153B908AC88878B8710"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Retroactivity</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Transportation shall provide to any airport sponsor or air traffic control tower described in subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82519E3206984BD0A1B8156575BD84FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reimbursement for any certified situational awareness system (including Airborne Position Reference Tools in accordance with subsection (a)) that was independently acquired and installed prior to the date on which the Administrator installs any such system under subsection (a); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD922B23E18754B26B29A6BD094C8C301"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reimbursement or retroactive grant funding in accordance with section 47124(b) of title 49, United States Code, for any certified situational awareness system (including a Standard Terminal Automation Replacement System) that was independently acquired and installed prior to the effective date of the amendments made by subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6ADF9A9434FB45CA80BF9267B2E0EB9E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorized expenditures for air navigation facilities and equipment</header><text>Section 48101(c) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBCA2C926EAE4C6685624CC35BCC8A5D"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA647AA8F61ED4537A9BA2CAE05BB6695"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The acquisition, installation, and annual operating expenses of certified Airborne Position Reference Tools at air traffic control towers that are operating under contract with the Federal Aviation Administration under section 47124 and are not equipped with Standard Terminal Automation Replacement Systems or other situational awareness tools.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

