<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26G62-NS9-MY-KG8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4894 IS: Feedstocks. Uniformity, Safety, and Energetics Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4894</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a pilot program on safety and qualification of printable energetic feedstocks for additive manufacturing.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id4f98d2d0a3914b1a8a3ec948bc60a4d8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Feedstocks. Uniformity, Safety, and Energetics Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FUSE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id010729b9d6204b448c2a923c892408b0"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pilot program on safety and qualification of printable energetic feedstocks for additive manufacturing</header><subsection id="idcdbee080ae6c4b66a7b1fc9d09963c4c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program, to be carried out by the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, in coordination with the Capability Program Executive, Ammunition and Energetics (or successor organization) and appropriate service acquisition executives, to evaluate the safety, quality, and qualification pathways of printable energetic feedstocks for controlled additive manufacturing applications.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb2fd179965204ac39d26da7c009dda76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purposes of the pilot program are—</text><paragraph id="id02a1512e48a64d66b00f1824c207dc98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to determine whether the use of printable energetic feedstocks can improve handling safety, process stability, lot-to-lot consistency, and supply chain resilience relative to traditional energetics manufacturing and handling methods;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c65e9f4ac0445dabf113c758d211550"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to analyze logistics impact on throughput, waste, defect rate, and constituent material availability versus state-of-the-art legacy processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1478e6da37e045eba0ad410a440ac6de"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to develop and validate new test and evaluation methods, if necessary, including metrology and digital quality assurance, suitable for assessing printable energetic feedstocks for Department of Defense use;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2ecba76febf420d917459dc72b1c51f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to assess applicability of printable energetic feedstocks to existing or planned munition and energetics modernization efforts, consistent with explosive safety, security, and environmental requirements, that provide an advantage in performance or logistics; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1b5b2d05ff2430a9adc9349d27338b5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to identify barriers to adoption, including infrastructure, standards, certification, and workforce requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3768fb41bbab49009f12794139e6d398"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>Activities under the pilot program may include—</text><paragraph id="id3dcfbbda7482467d98244fa47381c574"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification, assessment, and characterization of representative printable energetic feedstocks and their performance consistency under controlled conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide679be56701a4d86ba878421bdc68497"><enum>(2)</enum><text>development of qualification criteria and data packages to inform safety releases, waivers, or certifications as appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb0a6bfc18fc247b8a1e8fa1886f10214"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limited demonstrations at Government facilities or contractor facilities that meet all applicable explosive safety and security requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id206215293d234b97b6c7fe82dd7a2133"><enum>(4)</enum><text>development of nonproprietary standards, metrology approaches, and digital thread quality controls for printable energetic feedstocks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id518018fbb90342abbe21ac9bd9907fac"><enum>(5)</enum><text>analysis of operational impacts via wargaming or mission/campaign modeling and experimental performance data.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id509bb823b9bd4217a9eb36eb19aebd3c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Comparative safety assessment required</header><text>As a core element of the pilot program, the Secretary of Defense shall conduct a comparative assessment of the safety of the use of printable energetic feedstocks relative to traditional energetics manufacturing and handling, including, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="id305758feeb64452e804a2ac85a9b6aa0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hazards and risks associated with storage, transport, handling, and processing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8ce4e35603a7465b9916c86a6b726726"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sensitivity and response to credible stimuli (including thermal and mechanical stimuli) using appropriate test standards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide9e0cdea80d24134baea8c9575e44270"><enum>(3)</enum><text>process safety considerations, including potential failure modes and mitigations for controlled additive manufacturing workflows;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e360d8599194d87b4c0be8c43036ad8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>accident and incident risk modeling (including qualitative and quantitative risk assessment where feasible); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id631244f681dd4f6b97e4009a2914a221"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommended safety controls, facility requirements, and operational constraints for any future operational use.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0a59eee461514ca798df371711580867"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Safety and security requirements</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that activities under the pilot program—</text><paragraph id="id5848c8ee2be9416fba17802721302031"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are conducted only at facilities compliant with applicable explosive safety siting, storage, handling, and operating requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf509e807255b4242a374038ac286aa55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate counter-diversion safeguards, inventory accountability, and chain-of-custody controls;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24ed376086884311bc4fe8595886bfbd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>apply cybersecurity and access controls for any digital manufacturing files, process parameters, and quality records; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7fa9ace3567a4eb7a74d7d7de76ad225"><enum>(4)</enum><text>do not authorize dissemination of restricted manufacturing parameters outside approved Government and cleared-industry channels.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide275ab1e90204239b3473501effd921c"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 180 days after initiation of the pilot program, and annually thereafter for the duration of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as that term is defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code) a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="id589f1b017244485b835e42140b8a2518"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pilot objectives, participants, test locations, and safety governance structure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8222967ced9243dc9f225625163674cd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>test methodologies, standards used, and key safety and quality metrics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id425990e9bfb44a71ab6a224250454902"><enum>(3)</enum><text>results of activities conducted under subsection (c), including identification, assessment, and characterization of representative printable energetic feedstocks, demonstrations, qualification criteria, data packages, and standard development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0adef1eff261417d9bf5151ccf7d2c0b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>results of the comparative safety assessment required under subsection (d), including identified hazards, mitigations, and residual risk;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idebd678d518f4492986f9d2a7c080954d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assessment of cost, schedule, and scalability relative to traditional energetics manufacturing and handling;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3b0eec94ccb43a3aec5276b06d83333"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recommended qualification and certification pathways, including any standards gaps; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id989247e6976e46a4bc5866dec44f837b"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any recommended legislative, regulatory, or resourcing actions required to enable safe adoption.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9889994f300840fabfc9be9d3a0a949e"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The pilot program shall be carried out for not more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

