<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26930-XJM-WF-9JS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4792 IS: Protection of Lawful Commerce in Stone Slab Products Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4792</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260616">June 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit civil liability actions from being brought or continued against manufacturers and sellers of stone slab products for damages, injunctive, or other relief resulting from the misuse of their products by others.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section id="HC7F025E6B39D4FBCA446508210872071" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protection of Lawful Commerce in Stone Slab Products Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1E59A3BC6E644E45875E641DC8E25613"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header><subsection id="H971F206726E346E9A7062556CEEB5C90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF260E1C9D8684546A6E45F7AD7A25995"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Civil actions have been commenced against manufacturers and sellers of certain stone slab products, including those used for kitchen countertops and similar applications. These products are not inherently dangerous and upon their manufacture and entry into the stream of commerce, they do not pose an inherent risk of injury to human beings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B249D2E372C43809C233BDF600F03E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These civil actions seek money damages from manufacturers and sellers by persons who claim personal injuries as a result of exposure to silica dust produced during the alteration of such products in the course of their employment by third-party fabricators. The manufacturers and sellers of these products have no control over these fabricators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF82A600DFCB6464CA346840F55F57693"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The alteration of such products is heavily regulated by Federal and State workplace safety laws and regulations, including section 1910.1053 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, and California Labor Code Section 5204, which require a variety of safety measures that fabricators must employ in order to mitigate the risk of potential injuries posed by silica dust. However, some fabricators fail to comply with these requirements and thereby expose their employees and others to the potential harms that these laws and regulations are intended to prevent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9C60996460748DAB6BE6AEC26595D59"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Businesses located or conducting business in the United States that are engaged in interstate and foreign commerce through the lawful design, manufacture, marketing, distribution, importation, or sale to third-parties of certain stone slab products are not responsible, and should not be held liable, for the alleged injuries caused by those who alter the product in a way that is unsafe or violates Federal and State laws and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC22ECD226E4BF695B53CE7C97623EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The possibility of imposing liability on an entire industry for alleged injuries that are solely caused by others is an abuse of the legal system, erodes public confidence in the laws of the United States, invites the disassembly and destabilization of other industries and economic sectors lawfully competing in the free enterprise system of the United States, and constitutes an unreasonable burden on interstate and foreign commerce of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D496B9323CE4E3B96622B96C33C981B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A proliferation of frivolous lawsuits against manufacturers and sellers of stone slab products for alleged workplace injuries caused by the actions of third-parties unrelated to and beyond the control of these manufacturers and sellers may further limit access to courts by straining the resources of the legal system and depriving deserving parties of their legitimate rights to relief.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F5F26800CB84DA1ABB2C98D2A53F30E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are as follows:</text><paragraph id="H28FD949BD9BD42E292973C0CFC19FDFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To prohibit civil actions against manufacturers and sellers of stone slab products for injuries caused by exposure to respirable silica or other substances arising from or relating to the fabrication of such products by third-parties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB67CC60F9E8E40F9924C091A60750DF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To preserve the access of consumers to a supply of stone slab products, to protect manufacturers and sellers from frivolous civil actions alleging liability for such injuries, and to preserve a lawful industry that employs tens of thousands of people of the United States in several States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA178E89C4B94BB58D2C943371BADB7C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To prevent the use of such civil actions to impose unreasonable burdens on interstate and foreign commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6A4D28D980942EDA7A57FBC97C05D8A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To exercise congressional power under the Full Faith and Credit Clause of section 1 of article IV of the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE235E5C85AE44EB1AF2AC93CE4774427"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on bringing of qualified civil actions in Federal or State court</header><subsection id="H7F8B5A6D834C48B09EBB8A9178F6F1F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified civil action may not be brought in any Federal or State court.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC968DA991AAE47CCA4E4478DC0EBEA1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dismissal of pending actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified civil action that is pending on the date of enactment of this Act shall be dismissed, as soon as is practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, by the court in which the action is pending.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9D2E4E92A9514B5B82C45B4E5DDC59A5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H17EBE1C22E3F4A068F14D67FB9C9DCDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fabrication</header><text>The term <term>fabrication</term> means the process of altering a qualified product by cutting, drilling, shaping, polishing, grinding, or other similar means.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H431C7E8F6CBE4ADDAC2166B8C4891E4C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified civil action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified civil action</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb7ecdb606544efaaaed8654e908874b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a civil action brought against a manufacturer or seller of a qualified product for harm suffered from silicosis or another condition relating to or associated with silicosis resulting or arising from the occupational exposure to crystalline silica or other substances generated during fabrication of a qualified product; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida196d5ef5c324a338b68d1c08707448e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include an action in which a manufacturer or seller of a qualified product was an employer of the injured party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86A51FEDAA184F008980F02330119449"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified product</term> means a stone slab product, including such a product made with or containing quartz, mineral, crystal, glass, porcelain, or other stone, ceramic or similar material, that has been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce, the fabrication of which is subject to Federal or State occupational health and safety statutes and regulations, including those pertaining to respirable crystalline silica.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA93F2D635EE64137B874DBDE1FF544E7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Seller</header><text>The term <term>seller</term> means an importer, a distributer, a retailer, or a supplier of a qualified product.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EA1BF8BDB134260ACCF93B26F1E1AC7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States, and any political subdivision of any such place.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

