<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H189A836CBB884F40AA75496E9E9E6063" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6630 IH: Expanding Mental Health Access for Cyber Command Personnel Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6630</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Department of Defense to carry out an initiative to understand and address occupational resiliency challenges of the Cyber Mission Force.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H427439A2DE1447F0B1327F3437F3D36F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H414D820BBACF4C64A25908F39B17F6B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Mental Health Access for Cyber Command Personnel Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H7FFD01B5B9E549F287D9D1B974D9C8A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Occupational resiliency of the Cyber Mission Force</header> <subsection id="HD09640C948884A1E912D227773D2D07E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness and the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy, in coordination with the Principal Cyber Advisors of the military departments and the Commander of the United States Cyber Command, shall jointly carry out an initiative to understand and address occupational resiliency challenges at the duty locations of the Cyber Mission Force by ensuring that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC5890D3EC5BA48F196E5ABDE991D5CE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">behavioral health professionals are assigned to the operating locations of United States Cyber Command and the Cyber Mission Force; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8AFB256D987451996A11E427E389AFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each such professional holds the security clearance necessary to provide treatment to the members of the Armed Forces assigned at such duty locations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3BB7AC3FEFB4BBDA9E92C87147CF4AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><text>On an annual basis during the three-year period beginning on the date on which the initiative under subsection (a) commences, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness and the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Cyber Policy shall jointly provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on the following:</text> <paragraph id="H182715953E0E495689B7198043D90A18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The status of carrying out such initiative.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H12569CEFF89D4E87B704A96490BAC557"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Validation of the security clearances held by behavioral health professionals assigned under such subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07C5658D76804A37B10F539BC74C34A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An analysis of clinical acuity being treated by such professionals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36842F608ACD498FBEBFAAE801615AE6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Identified challenges to carrying out such initiative.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H955E3BF925FD48C987490EC9DEC5FAF5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Efforts to improve the awareness by members of the Armed Forces assigned to the Cyber Mission Force with respect to the availability of appropriately cleared behavioral health professionals who can treat such members.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H490EDC753666437997D4D3FFF7E056A9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other information the Under Secretary or the Assistant Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2396904834514C8CBF5ABA9216DB123E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Occupational resiliency challenges defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>occupational resiliency challenges</term> means behavioral health challenges relating to an occupation and work-related stress.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body></bill>

