<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16F938CF70474FD688F9C46E7F70265D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6529 IH: Protecting Families from AI Data Center Energy Costs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to hold a technical conference on protecting residential ratepayers from increased costs associated with large loads, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H97B6487E9BA344FDA090F1CC6920AE38" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCC929B326C394A34A8524E614CB4784B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Families from AI Data Center Energy Costs Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H259CB14A2B70472BAE7BD6B2811A89C7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission technical conference on increased costs associated with large loads</header> <subsection id="HA6A7C8C2F13B4870A3DCD50BE3F02CF5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall hold a Commissioner-led technical conference with representatives from the Department of Energy, public utilities, transmission providers, State regulators, ratepayer advocates, large loads (including data centers used for artificial intelligence models), and such other participants as the Commission determines appropriate, on strategies and rate structures for protecting residential and small commercial ratepayers from increased costs associated with large loads.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D5611EC3957465EBDA97CC5BA6200E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the technical conference under subsection (a) concludes, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report containing recommendations and best practices resulting from such technical conference.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

