<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H1116A04F86B14B259B0E3DD9CC6315C8" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8879 : Oversight and Transparency for Small Business Certifications Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8879</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSSB00">Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to require a report on small business concern participation in a covered contracting programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3A71106A22234AF2B417A3C518855643" style="OLC"><section id="H319B4AE767AE4A879C71166DA210EBA6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oversight and Transparency for Small Business Certifications Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H64A4EA3C00A24289BC28E6CF3248989C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on small business concern participation in a covered contracting programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10(c) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/639">15 U.S.C. 639(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1933666D3CC04881B9D93C589EC01FEB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H48FB8390F97B430BAF9A7799202F37CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certification reports</header><paragraph id="H5C803B5C70464ED99AE1AC996E89C383"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Along with the submission to Congress of the budget of the President for each fiscal year pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, the Administrator shall submit a report on small business concern participation in a covered contracting program during the year covered by the report that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB009718E511947F0A0CD2D3172C74B75"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total number of unique small business concerns certified for participation in a covered contracting program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC963F07CDD649668F1B4FDC5D5271C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to applications of small business concerns for participation in a covered contracting program—</text><clause id="H5AF30F9770A44F93BD65B1FB138D69C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of applications for participation that have sufficient information for the Administrator to issue a certification determination, disaggregated by—</text><subclause id="H6EA5F4C40BBF49938A4CF7F3BD251CD2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of applications certified for each covered contracting program; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0AD044694B434EEBA36B3BF820B1AC15"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of applications for which a determination has not been made for any covered contracting program;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEBA387AD9E4E425DA34942D0FDF56C4E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of applications for certification for two or more covered contracting programs and the percentage of total applicants that received two or more certifications;</text></clause><clause id="HB2FBF58F08154CA398B4CC3A59B72210" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of applications received through the single, unified platform established by the Administrator for receipt of certification applications; and</text></clause><clause id="H91CB0E5F3B044DEAB49AFB132E7D3F2C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of small business concerns certified for participation in a covered contracting program for which such certification documentation is contain in a system other than the platform described in clause (iii), disaggregated by covered contracting program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H023C8091A71B4167B4953D11B2BF399E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to applications of small business concerns for certification as a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans that have sufficient information for the Administrator to issue a certification determination—</text><clause id="H287E408CEA7646A1A98F5D3980BD54E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of applications certified;</text></clause><clause id="H70DD9B717185471A9D9A4BD16F006B6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of applications denied; and</text></clause><clause id="HB34D7A9AE2024EBAA38CEE8259707AD1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of applications for which a determination has not been made.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC246E1E8A6A94BA4BB15C19DFE6AB8AC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each application of a small business concern for certification as a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, the timeframe between the date of submission of a completed application and the issuance of a certification or recertification determination, disaggregated by—</text><clause id="H0C3AA8EE2C874C5B9305051DD8976199"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number, expressed as a percentage, of certification determinations made within the timeframe established by the Administration;</text></clause><clause id="HC665DE39A5564F579916992BB1F42240"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average time for a first-time applicant to receive a certification determination; and</text></clause><clause id="HF13BBFDDD99A4FE8A863C3C893A7E496"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average time for an applicant that is a small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans to receive a recertification determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6B2AE9AEB104C53B86D3696059A414D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>With respect to applications of small business concerns for certification as a small business concern owned and controlled by women that have sufficient information for the Administrator to issue a certification determination—</text><clause id="H8080855631D84F05860566155FDE5F27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of applications certified;</text></clause><clause id="H23791525A7264B8EAF15EEE047382AC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of the applications described in clause (i), the number certified that are eligible for award of a sole source contract under section 8(m)(7);</text></clause><clause id="H819ADA59990C448F83ABF7EC6120A749"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of applications certified that were processed by a national certifying entity described in section 8(m)(2)(E);</text></clause><clause id="HD2D249DDD2C34A4AA59A402C6CA87671"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of applications denied; and</text></clause><clause id="H74E9A474FCD0425180BB5CA7B07285A8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of applications for which a determination has not been made.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F3FB0E7AF824DDFBDC09FE36B9D4A2C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Of the applications described in subparagraph (E)(ii), the number of such applications that initially did not include sufficient information for the Administrator to issue a certification determination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0B049A30040404CA5F99F9F3DA6EEBB"><enum>(G)</enum><text>With respect to each application of a small business concern for certification as a small business concern owned and controlled by women, the timeframe between the date of submission of a completed application and the issuance of a certification or recertification determination, disaggregated by—</text><clause id="HB6A8C0EFE1BD4DACA991DEDCBEAE9D66"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number, expressed as a percentage, of certification determinations made within the timeframe established by the Administration;</text></clause><clause id="HB7EF36D3921F40F1BA30784BEA1BC621"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average time for a first-time applicant to receive a certification determination;</text></clause><clause id="HBC261D2930FD45A5943F6DD6D2E4C220"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the average time for an applicant that is a small business concern owned and controlled by women to receive a recertification determination; and</text></clause><clause id="HE9415B19B4AC402183E225C75395BA12"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the average time for an applicant certified by a national certifying entity to receive a determination from the Administrator, disaggregated by initial certification applications and recertification applications.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CE4F6800B5E422DBD4789FE8428F05B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>With respect to applications of small business concerns for certification as a qualified HUBZone small business concern that have sufficient information for the Administrator to issue a certification determination—</text><clause id="HDA0A89394A8B481B9BE1AEB5C9A1FFD8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of applications certified;</text></clause><clause id="H913D8A9D410740B080C730118654740A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of applications denied; and</text></clause><clause id="HE6D3E70322414B968B598BB0D02D19B5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of applications for which a determination has not been made.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C79BA7106D349DDACE77752878B7E60"><enum>(I)</enum><text>With respect to each application of a small business concern for certification as a qualified HUBZone small business concern, the timeframe between the date of submission of a completed application and the issuance of a certification or recertification determination, disaggregated by—</text><clause id="HE17BFA40A5E94955B2CE84546693E9DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number, expressed as a percentage, of certification determinations made within the timeframe established by the Administration;</text></clause><clause id="HEFBBAC38F45146FB97EB27C51E7172D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average time for a first-time applicant to receive a certification determination; and</text></clause><clause id="H5770F54640794B5C90CBE5EADA7A6755"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the average time for an applicant that is a qualified HUBZone small business concern to receive a recertification determination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE11736DB2F2448C9AC5E92A484F42824" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered contracting program defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>covered contracting program</term> means contracting assistance provided by the Administrator under following:</text><subparagraph id="H126702E5B96C4F379AC4A154D0CA7B74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 8(a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC152E4B66374594B33BEFC322302372"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 8(m).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE2C4243C0748089E027E3409B03B38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 31.</text><pagebreak></pagebreak></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H542E51F59ED44995835B5CC82500C9BE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 36.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260623" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 23, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

