<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H1BD2B2337B134EBD88B87B5366C2F980" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9022 RH: Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2027</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 581</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9022</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–667]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20260522">May 22, 2026</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00"> Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, reported the following bill; which was committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2027, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body changed="not-changed" id="H30BEDDA835934497B73DCE1E523ECE66" style="appropriations"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H15E78F8560FD40568C92FCD8684DBEE1" section-type="undesignated-section"> <text>That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2027, and for other purposes, namely:</text> </section> <title id="H7FD52646FA99445E8DAEE395CE52BF81" style="appropriations"><enum>I</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">CORPS OF ENGINEERS—CIVIL</header><appropriations-major id="HB6583C5AE1E649589B88C7C8CDAD67F2"><header>DEPARTMENT OF THE ARMY</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H9A4101B5F91E4FF8AFC95D3F0CE2E1AB"><header>Corps of Engineers—Civil</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following appropriations shall be expended under the direction of the Secretary of the Army and the supervision of the Chief of Engineers for authorized civil functions of the Department of the Army pertaining to river and harbor, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related efforts.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H3BE6B1E21C4944B5B9A7C1804938116B"><header>INVESTIGATIONS</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HCBCB9194284D40C89EFB298E8965C642"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary where authorized by law for the collection and study of basic information pertaining to river and harbor, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related needs; for surveys and detailed studies, and plans and specifications of proposed river and harbor, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, and aquatic ecosystem restoration projects, and related efforts prior to construction; for restudy of authorized projects; and for miscellaneous investigations, and, when authorized by law, surveys and detailed studies, and plans and specifications of projects prior to construction, $175,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That the Secretary shall not deviate from the work plan, once the plan has been submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H557C8619762B41E1A78DF651AA355FC5"><header>CONSTRUCTION</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H4250DDC12CD94F599A6CB35AEF361B93"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the construction of river and harbor, flood and storm damage reduction, shore protection, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related projects authorized by law; for conducting detailed studies, and plans and specifications, of such projects (including those involving participation by States, local governments, or private groups) authorized or made eligible for selection by law (but such detailed studies, and plans and specifications, shall not constitute a commitment of the Government to construction); $2,382,000,000, to remain available until expended; of which $70,000,000, to be derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund, shall be to cover the Federal share of construction costs for facilities under the Dredged Material Disposal Facilities program; and of which such sums as are necessary to cover 25 percent of the costs of construction, replacement, rehabilitation, and expansion of inland waterways projects shall be derived from the Inland Waterways Trust Fund, except as otherwise specifically provided for in law: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That the Secretary shall not deviate from the work plan, once the plan has been submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress. </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H60E3936A010D495B9F28783EC8DCC9BD"><header>MISSISSIPPI RIVER AND TRIBUTARIES</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H2032C42D61944CCC9AB211FF98886561"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for flood damage reduction projects and related efforts in the Mississippi River alluvial valley below Cape Girardeau, Missouri, as authorized by law, $470,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $6,551,000, to be derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund, shall be to cover the Federal share of eligible operation and maintenance costs for inland harbors: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That the Secretary shall not deviate from the work plan, once the plan has been submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H9F7A5300565C4C369241F13CBFA6CE88"><header>OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HAB7966082F3F4FC7A1C8D4AD6EA19316"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the operation, maintenance, and care of existing river and harbor, flood and storm damage reduction, aquatic ecosystem restoration, and related projects authorized by law; providing security for infrastructure owned or operated by the Corps, including administrative buildings and laboratories; maintaining harbor channels provided by a State, municipality, or other public agency that serve essential navigation needs of general commerce, where authorized by law; surveying and charting northern and northwestern lakes and connecting waters; clearing and straightening channels; and removing obstructions to navigation, $6,255,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $3,487,449,000, to be derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund, shall be to cover the Federal share of eligible operations and maintenance costs for coastal harbors and channels, and for inland harbors; of which such sums as may be necessary shall be derived from amounts collected in this or prior fiscal years under section 210 of the Flood Control Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460d-3">16 U.S.C. 460d–3</external-xref>) and are not otherwise appropriated shall be for resource protection, research, interpretation, and maintenance activities related to resource protection in the areas at which outdoor recreation is available; of which such sums as become available from fees collected under section 217 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/303">Public Law 104–303</external-xref> shall be used to cover the cost of operation and maintenance of the dredged material disposal facilities for which such fees have been collected; and of which $64,000,000, to be derived from the general fund of the Treasury, shall be to carry out subsection (c) of section 2106 of the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2238c">33 U.S.C. 2238c</external-xref>) and shall be designated as being for such purpose pursuant to paragraph (2) of section 14003 of division B of the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/136">Public Law 116–136</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That funding derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund for donor and energy ports shall be allocated solely in accordance with section 2106 of the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That 1 percent of the total amount of funds provided for each of the programs, projects, or activities funded under this heading shall not be allocated to a field operating activity prior to the beginning of the fourth quarter of the fiscal year and shall be available for use by the Chief of Engineers to fund such emergency activities as the Chief of Engineers determines to be necessary and appropriate, and that the Chief of Engineers shall allocate during the fourth quarter any remaining funds which have not been used for emergency activities proportionally in accordance with the amounts provided for the programs, projects, or activities: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the Secretary shall not deviate from the work plan, once the plan has been submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HE1A5CA9215AF4AE1B2B47DBC2457EA39"><header>REGULATORY PROGRAM</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for administration of laws pertaining to regulation of navigable waters and wetlands, $223,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H832D75D1BFB341F5ABDF23924F2E6D13"><header>FLOOD CONTROL AND COASTAL EMERGENCIES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary to prepare for flood, hurricane, and other natural disasters and support emergency operations, repairs, and other activities in response to such disasters as authorized by law, $40,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H968D08361F7C46EDAFDF025E162F8EA9"><header>EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the supervision and general administration of the civil works program in the headquarters of the Corps of Engineers and the offices of the Division Engineers; and for costs of management and operation of the Humphreys Engineer Center Support Activity, the Institute for Water Resources, the United States Army Engineer Research and Development Center, and the United States Army Corps of Engineers Finance Center allocable to the civil works program, $218,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028, of which not to exceed $5,000 may be used for official reception and representation purposes and only during the current fiscal year: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That no part of any other appropriation provided in this title shall be available to fund the civil works activities of the Office of the Chief of Engineers or the civil works executive direction and management activities of the division offices: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That any Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies appropriation may be used to fund the supervision and general administration of emergency operations, repairs, and other activities in response to any flood, hurricane, or other natural disaster.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HF2C60FED9E334F9BB83EE3C8F3782505"><header>OFFICE OF THE ASSISTANT SECRETARY OF THE ARMY FOR CIVIL WORKS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/7016">10 U.S.C. 7016(b)(3)</external-xref>, $7,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That not less than $1,000,000 shall be for activities related to serving as a liaison to improve communication with Congress: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That not more than 75 percent of such amount may be obligated or expended until the Assistant Secretary submits to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress the report required under section 101(d) of this Act and a work plan that allocates at least 95 percent of the additional funding provided under each heading in the report accompanying this Act, to specific programs, projects, or activities.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H7E5B67350BFC4C8FA0B01357ACA2A08E"><header>WATER INFRASTRUCTURE FINANCE AND INNOVATION PROGRAM ACCOUNT</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For administrative expenses to carry out the direct and guaranteed loan programs, notwithstanding section 5033 of the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014, $5,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028.</text><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, fees authorized to be collected pursuant to sections 5029 and 5030 of the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 shall be deposited in this account, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HCDBC3C4090444E339B470210C60DDE44"><header>GENERAL PROVISIONS—CORPS OF ENGINEERS—CIVIL</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-small id="HE11AD8DAEE314E7BBBAC84342EA7D834"><header>(INCLUDING TRANSFERS OF FUNDS)</header></appropriations-small> <section id="H0B941E20300E491B88A883E1F5C773F7"><enum>101.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H62FB38ECCE2E4F7CAA1EA18FA40C076F"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds provided in title I of this Act, or provided by previous appropriations Acts to the agencies or entities funded in title I of this Act that remain available for obligation or expenditure in fiscal year 2027, shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds that:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7C9BEF3C30F3495581CB40FF2EAD8C46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates or initiates a new program, project, or activity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3BDFDDAA26344E568B888044A0459EB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>eliminates a program, project, or activity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAD69CFDEC45402AB1A240247B8C1A20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increases funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted by this Act, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63D4FFABA7874DE1A8ABB54CB8B04868"><enum>(4)</enum><text>proposes to use funds directed for a specific activity for a different purpose, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA07F0DEAA9554C71A1F70836E2376E93"><enum>(5)</enum><text>augments or reduces existing programs, projects, or activities in excess of the amounts contained in paragraphs (6) through (10), unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0452A8069A1B456F9EE80949BA6984F6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text>For a base level over $100,000, reprogramming of 25 percent of the base amount up to a limit of $150,000 per project, study or activity is allowed: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That for a base level less than $100,000, the reprogramming limit is $25,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That up to $25,000 may be reprogrammed into any continuing study or activity that did not receive an appropriation for existing obligations and concomitant administrative expenses;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19BF7B752B5F4541B8AC63085B57C8F1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>For a base level over $2,000,000, reprogramming of 15 percent of the base amount up to a limit of $3,000,000 per project, study or activity is allowed: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That for a base level less than $2,000,000, the reprogramming limit is $300,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That up to $3,000,000 may be reprogrammed for settled contractor claims, changed conditions, or real estate deficiency judgments: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That up to $300,000 may be reprogrammed into any continuing study or activity that did not receive an appropriation for existing obligations and concomitant administrative expenses;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B8F976EAA4843CFA6633EC71E71AC4B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance</header><text>Unlimited reprogramming authority is granted for the Corps to be able to respond to emergencies: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That the Chief of Engineers shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress of these emergency actions as soon thereafter as practicable: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for a base level over $1,000,000, reprogramming of 15 percent of the base amount up to a limit of $5,000,000 per project, study, or activity is allowed: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for a base level less than $1,000,000, the reprogramming limit is $150,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That $150,000 may be reprogrammed into any continuing study or activity that did not receive an appropriation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7093B20CC3794229984ACC6058A0526B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Mississippi river and tributaries</header><text>The reprogramming guidelines in paragraphs (6), (7), and (8) shall apply to the Investigations, Construction, and Operation and Maintenance portions of the Mississippi River and Tributaries Account, respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H254FAAED216C44CD843E847DA96908A8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Formerly utilized sites remedial action program</header><text>Reprogramming of up to 15 percent of the base of the receiving project is permitted.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26B190257D084BBA90C9D8A64F931EA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>De minimus reprogrammings</header><text>In no case should a reprogramming for less than $50,000 be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0C549EF2AA0F4072A38D9E439DC93F82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continuing authorities program</header><text>Subsection (a)(1) shall not apply to any project or activity funded under the continuing authorities program.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA1EE26D7F8B470D8186A74B619E6C7A"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress to establish the baseline for application of reprogramming and transfer authorities for the current fiscal year which shall include:</text> <paragraph id="H3BD7611EF34049FFACFA110D063EBC9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A table for each appropriation with a separate column to display the President's budget request, adjustments made by Congress, adjustments due to enacted rescissions, if applicable, and the fiscal year enacted level; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4731C63DEF344E1B9207B6CC80AC08C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A delineation in the table for each appropriation both by object class and program, project and activity as detailed in the budget appendix for the respective appropriations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1F25AB6661E40C48CB521E883B15C9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of items of special congressional interest.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7CAFCFC1EAE44389BAC659C03ABD1AAB"><enum>102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall allocate funds made available in this Act solely in accordance with the provisions of this Act and in the report accompanying this Act, including the determination and designation of new starts.</text></section> <section id="H3146968A9E7D49B793676446874B3994"><enum>103.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this title may be used to award or modify any contract that commits funds beyond the amounts appropriated for that program, project, or activity that remain unobligated, except that such amounts may include any funds that have been made available through reprogramming pursuant to section 101.</text></section> 
<section id="HBFC711B0CAA14540A615558290B37047"><enum>104.</enum><text>The Secretary of the Army may transfer to the Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Fish and Wildlife Service may accept and expend, up to $8,733,000 of funds provided in this title under the heading <quote>Operation and Maintenance</quote> to mitigate for fisheries lost due to Corps of Engineers projects.</text></section> <section id="H43CC3DBA78B143D1876EED99E84FF08B"><enum>105.</enum><text>None of the funds in this Act shall be used for an open lake placement alternative for dredged material, after evaluating the least costly, environmentally acceptable manner for the disposal or management of dredged material originating from Lake Erie or tributaries thereto, unless it is approved under a State water quality certification pursuant to section 401 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1341">33 U.S.C. 1341</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That until an open lake placement alternative for dredged material is approved under a State water quality certification, the Corps of Engineers shall continue upland placement of such dredged material consistent with the requirements of section 101 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2211">33 U.S.C. 2211</external-xref>).</text></section> 
<section id="H372DF1E0DA1B4A9B99E18A7C7C755B51" commented="no"><enum>106.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to carry out any water supply reallocation study under the Wolf Creek Dam, Lake Cumberland, Kentucky, project authorized under the Act of July 24, 1946 (60 Stat. 636, ch. 595).</text></section> <section id="H64332B2E0EFB4AD6A1B882CB279A220D" commented="no"><enum>107.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Additional funding provided in this Act shall be allocated only to projects determined to be eligible by the Chief of Engineers.</text></section> 
<section id="H47F4905D858043D39C1C7E5FE02AE26F" commented="no"><enum>108.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of the date of enactment of this Act and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of the Army shall not promulgate or enforce any regulation that prohibits an individual from possessing a firearm, including an assembled or functional firearm, at a water resources development project covered under section 327.0 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act) if:</text> <paragraph id="H8F5DEA37D37B48C2A3865D2BF93731D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing a firearm; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B1FED293E7E4D2A8DD4CDA0A044C59F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the possession of the firearm is in compliance with the law of the State in which the water resources development project is located.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HB21C2113141F4ABABF55D0A8632E40F3" commented="no"><enum>109.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to prevent the access of Congress to basic, factual information, such as project schedule statuses, budget justification materials, statutorily required execution reports, damage repair estimates, project capabilities, and other budgetary and nonbudgetary project information in a timely fashion.</text></section></title> 
<title id="H4278C831AF3544018C36D5AD98D0E633" style="appropriations"><enum>II</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</header><appropriations-intermediate id="H2D7081024D1D4EECAEF40B6689ED1328"><header>Central Utah Project</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HEEFC9EEF770B46139BA176011A99C441"><header>CENTRAL UTAH PROJECT COMPLETION ACCOUNT</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For carrying out activities authorized by the Central Utah Project Completion Act, $23,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $3,800,000 shall be deposited into the Utah Reclamation Mitigation and Conservation Account for use by the Utah Reclamation Mitigation and Conservation Commission: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of the amount provided under this heading, $1,900,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for expenses necessary in carrying out related responsibilities of the Secretary of the Interior: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for fiscal year 2027, of the amount made available to the Commission under this Act or any other Act, the Commission may use an amount not to exceed $2,310,000 for administrative expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H96182B967AB74E6CA5A94AA237FF8FF0"><header>Bureau of Reclamation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following appropriations shall be expended to execute authorized functions of the Bureau of Reclamation:</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HAA75657F59FD4860B62E67962C39D200"><header>WATER AND RELATED RESOURCES</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H782A4E25984F4A40A4E279D5A05F8038"><header>(INCLUDING TRANSFERS OF FUNDS)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For management, development, and restoration of water and related natural resources and for related activities, including the operation, maintenance, and rehabilitation of reclamation and other facilities, participation in fulfilling related Federal responsibilities to Native Americans, and related grants to, and cooperative and other agreements with, State and local governments, federally recognized Indian Tribes, and others, $1,675,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which $23,355,000 shall be available for transfer to the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund and $112,611,000 shall be available for transfer to the Lower Colorado River Basin Development Fund; of which such amounts as may be necessary may be advanced to the Colorado River Dam Fund: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That such transfers may be increased or decreased within the overall appropriation under this heading: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That of the total appropriated, the amount for program activities that can be financed by the Reclamation Fund, the Water Storage Enhancement Receipts account established by section 4011(e) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/322">Public Law 114–322</external-xref>, or the Bureau of Reclamation special fee account established by 16 U.S.C. 6806 shall be derived from that Fund or account: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That funds contributed under 43 U.S.C. 395 are available until expended for the purposes for which the funds were contributed: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That funds advanced under 43 U.S.C. 397a shall be credited to this account and are available until expended for the same purposes as the sums appropriated under this heading: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That of the amounts made available under this heading, $5,053,000 shall be deposited in the San Gabriel Basin Restoration Fund established by section 110 of title I of division B of appendix D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/554">Public Law 106–554</external-xref>.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HE66879664AFF41F1AAA8E774735123DC"><header>CENTRAL VALLEY PROJECT RESTORATION FUND</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For carrying out the programs, projects, plans, habitat restoration, improvement, and acquisition provisions of the Central Valley Project Improvement Act, such sums as may be collected in fiscal year 2027 in the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund pursuant to sections 3407(d), 3404(c)(3), and 3405(f) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/575">Public Law 102–575</external-xref>, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That the Bureau of Reclamation is directed to assess and collect the full amount of the additional mitigation and restoration payments authorized by section 3407(d) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/102/575">Public Law 102–575</external-xref>: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That none of the funds made available under this heading may be used for the acquisition or leasing of water for in-stream purposes if the water is already committed to in-stream purposes by a court adopted decree or order.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H10CC03C2BF244C629A604129C42EACFF"><header>CALIFORNIA BAY-DELTA RESTORATION</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H1121DE11C02C4E6DB2EEBFE2B2023C0D"><header>(INCLUDING TRANSFERS OF FUNDS)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For carrying out activities authorized by the Water Supply, Reliability, and Environmental Improvement Act, consistent with plans to be approved by the Secretary of the Interior, $32,000,000, to remain available until expended, of which such amounts as may be necessary to carry out such activities may be transferred to appropriate accounts of other participating Federal agencies to carry out authorized purposes: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That funds appropriated herein may be used for the Federal share of the costs of CALFED Program management: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That CALFED implementation shall be carried out in a balanced manner with clear performance measures demonstrating concurrent progress in achieving the goals and objectives of the Program.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H395E12FED83C4A96ACA598ADE866C6FD"><header>POLICY AND ADMINISTRATION</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for policy, administration, and related functions in the Office of the Commissioner, the Denver office, and offices in the six regions of the Bureau of Reclamation, to remain available until September 30, 2028, $64,000,000, to be derived from the Reclamation Fund and be nonreimbursable as provided in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/377">43 U.S.C. 377</external-xref>, of which not to exceed $5,000 may be used for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That no part of any other appropriation in this Act shall be available for activities or functions budgeted as policy and administration expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HFA75431691724A479E2C5893E827A202"><header>ADMINISTRATIVE PROVISION</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Appropriations for the Bureau of Reclamation shall be available for purchase and replacement of not to exceed 30 motor vehicles, which are for replacement only.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H201428DABC774F369CF9A21E8A5F2D20"><header>GENERAL PROVISIONS—DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</header></appropriations-major> <section id="HC7CF8C0482EA47B6B7384347E96B1607"><enum>201.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H09288EEF5D004BCBB09CCEA94D567BCD"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided in title II of this Act for Water and Related Resources, or provided by previous or subsequent appropriations Acts to the agencies or entities funded in title II of this Act for Water and Related Resources that remain available for obligation or expenditure in fiscal year 2027, shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E29749E09974B528526D7BCFF7E4C14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>initiates or creates a new program, project, or activity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6A2370A62004748ABA93D44C3B8D25E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>eliminates a program, project, or activity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2059504030942BD84FEFF2C56726E84"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increases funds for any program, project, or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted by this Act, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65DBACB7662847B1BDB0325B59BA099E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>restarts or resumes any program, project or activity for which funds are not provided in this Act, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB9083E8A6E44134807B537A1A7BF8DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>transfers funds in excess of the following limits, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress:</text> <subparagraph id="H9401F04ABF9B42CB8E3EC8E0596F2B3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>15 percent for any program, project or activity for which $2,000,000 or more is available at the beginning of the fiscal year; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0EFB76C2565C49F7AFE4DCE03D024213"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$400,000 for any program, project or activity for which less than $2,000,000 is available at the beginning of the fiscal year;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H081E8EF215204AE498F541A89EED7A1A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>transfers more than $500,000 from either the Facilities Operation, Maintenance, and Rehabilitation category or the Resources Management and Development category to any program, project, or activity in the other category, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38C02E229DBD46969A135EAB870AF9F1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>transfers, where necessary to discharge legal obligations of the Bureau of Reclamation, more than $5,000,000 to provide adequate funds for settled contractor claims, increased contractor earnings due to accelerated rates of operations, and real estate deficiency judgments, unless prior approval is received from the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0D761B09C7264051BBF49C47B310A96E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Subsection (a)(5) shall not apply to any transfer of funds within the Facilities Operation, Maintenance, and Rehabilitation category.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7E9766D9234F4F06851BFE0D33622AFE"><enum>(c)</enum><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>transfer</term> means any movement of funds into or out of a program, project, or activity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8492998306A84064A469D55CDA9EB519"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsections (a) and (b), the amounts made available in this title under the heading <quote>Bureau of Reclamation—Water and Related Resources</quote> shall be expended for the programs, projects, and activities specified in the <quote>House Recommended</quote> columns in the <quote>Water and Related Resources</quote> table included under the heading <quote>Title II—Department of the Interior</quote> in the report accompanying this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97F6911FFAEC456B8505E13C6D20D1BE"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The Bureau of Reclamation shall submit reports on a quarterly basis to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress detailing all the funds reprogrammed between programs, projects, activities, or categories of funding. The first quarterly report shall be submitted not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HACD5D96B10234045B802BD0D39A8F116"><enum>202.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1ED11F65DC674BE399435D267972A524"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until development by the Secretary of the Interior and the State of California of a plan, which shall conform to the water quality standards of the State of California as approved by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H922AB91D51184C00990E97865F7B8CCE"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and the costs of the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program shall be classified by the Secretary of the Interior as reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid pursuant to the <quote>Cleanup Program—Alternative Repayment Plan</quote> and the <quote>SJVDP—Alternative Repayment Plan</quote> described in the report entitled <quote>Repayment Report, Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program, February 1995</quote>, prepared by the Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation. Any future obligations of funds by the United States relating to, or providing for, drainage service or drainage studies for the San Luis Unit shall be fully reimbursable by San Luis Unit beneficiaries of such service or studies pursuant to Federal reclamation law.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC6D055407F494EFCA9DA68251A7A0CFE" commented="no"><enum>203.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD1195E809F6E42B384C48DB9B44484F5"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of Subtitle J of the Water Infrastructure Improvements for the Nation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/322">Public Law 114–322</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H63CC9727E27249CDB80922BB2A07AC7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 4007(i), by striking “2021” and inserting “2027”; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1ACBD688728D4E549502A3C66E6D89C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 4013—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H56996068579B4BCCBA8D0157558088B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by deleting “section 4004, which shall expire 10 years after the date of its enactment” and inserting “section 4004, which shall expire on December 16, 2034”; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89A9BAF7584647AE852F3CFDDA548E99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting “on or before December 16, 2026” after “4009(c)”.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H49FC6447F90F4123B4D5AC3BA5DCAD5D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1602(g)(1) of the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/390h">43 U.S.C. 390h</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$50,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$177,500,000</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5196473873AE4839BF1E97A801B1A16E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(a)(2)(F)(i) of the Water Desalination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10301">42 U.S.C. 10301</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/298">Public Law 104–298</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$30,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$106,500,000</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1B63C9E0061B4D6CB3C391B81FC0947F" commented="no"><enum>204.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7F8F68883E014A47B27961216C79146B"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/361">Public Law 108–361</external-xref> (the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act) (118 Stat. 1681), as amended, shall be applied by substituting <quote>2027</quote> for <quote>2022</quote> each place it appears. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HD6EA7288D0484221A35AD30929329A31" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 103(f)(4)(A) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/361">Public Law 108–361</external-xref> (the Calfed Bay-Delta Authorization Act) (118 Stat. 1681) is amended by striking <quote>$32,600,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$40,000,000</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H1844E33EEEE24B509DFA1711C1D6E6FC"><enum>205.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFA488F3CA3E54E0DB7E2AF9B5668F3DA"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10609(a)(1) of the Northwestern New Mexico Rural Water Projects Act (subtitle B of title X of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/11">Public Law 111–11</external-xref>)—</text> <paragraph id="H9136AFC6F40A4A5890C38087B1B7DCFE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is amended by striking <quote>$1,815,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,970,000,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E334A25EAFE47D5AFF664127C4400C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be applied by substituting <quote>2027</quote> for <quote>2024</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H12E333F05E2A4BF3B648AF0C7E306641"><enum>206.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 9 of the Fort Peck Reservation Rural Water System Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/382">Public Law 106–382</external-xref>) (114 Stat. 1457; 123 Stat. 2856; 128 Stat. 164; 132 Stat. 2906) is amended, in each of subsections (a)(1) and (b), by striking <quote>2026</quote> and inserting <quote>2028</quote>.</text> </section></title> 
<title id="HC53929DFEEAF4AC5BB1C794D9D96F447" style="appropriations"><enum>III</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</header><appropriations-major id="H7EDD132E479E451F8F929D8A24328D6A"><header>ENERGY PROGRAMS</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H32093D460E6345A1BCE7AC753785D12E"><header>Critical Minerals and Energy Innovation</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H8300AF89296046789CFF56F1C11109DF"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment, and other expenses necessary for activities that advance critical minerals supply chains and accelerate next-generation energy innovation technologies in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $1,850,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $177,742,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HDD83FF6B0F2B490E9FCF832747C812A3"><header>Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment, and other expenses necessary for energy sector cybersecurity, energy security, and emergency response activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $190,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $24,000,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H8899BB303A284F0DBBC1469549E1F76B"><header>Electricity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment, and other expenses necessary for electricity activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $235,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $21,877,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HA4677B8EDC0046C380D33C32234CFE9A"><header>Nuclear Energy</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HD97CC20CDE1244B2A626AA02DC5C5339"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment, and other expenses necessary for nuclear energy activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $1,800,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $92,000,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for the purpose of section 954(a)(7) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005, as amended, the only amount available shall be from the amount specified as including that purpose in the <quote>Bill</quote> column in the <quote>Department of Energy</quote> table included under the heading <quote>Title III—Department of Energy</quote> in the report accompanying this Act.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H2B20666779DE4000B8CC8F9E84BE43AF"><header>Hydrocarbons and Geothermal Energy</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H84187A2BD81A443AB3794AE5CED2BCBD"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary in carrying out hydrocarbons and geothermal energy research and development activities, under the authority of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition of interest, including defeasible and equitable interests in any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition or expansion, and for conducting inquiries, technological investigations and research concerning the extraction, processing, use, and disposal of mineral substances without objectionable social and environmental costs (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/3">30 U.S.C. 3</external-xref>, 1602, and 1603), $700,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount $75,000,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H6987776ED24F42DEBEC33FD2F4FED51A"><header>Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary to carry out naval petroleum and oil shale reserve activities, $13,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding any other provision of law, unobligated funds remaining from prior years shall be available for all naval petroleum and oil shale reserve activities.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H4D6AC217163E422BA7342F5D66846212"><header>Strategic Petroleum Reserve</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary for Strategic Petroleum Reserve facility development and operations and program management activities pursuant to the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6201">42 U.S.C. 6201 et seq.</external-xref>), $225,000,000, to remain available until expended. </text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H7532863F9B93477EA2ED5EB9B0E93916"><header>SPR Petroleum Account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the acquisition, transportation, and injection of petroleum products, and for other necessary expenses pursuant to the Energy Policy and Conservation Act of 1975, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6201">42 U.S.C. 6201 et seq.</external-xref>), sections 403 and 404 of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6241">42 U.S.C. 6241</external-xref>, 6239 note), section 32204 of the Fixing America’s Surface Transportation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6241">42 U.S.C. 6241</external-xref> note), and section 30204 of the Bipartisan Budget Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6241">42 U.S.C. 6241</external-xref> note), $100,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HC0B5DC5C6B454B71A66B98102F312CC4"><header>Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary for Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve storage, operation, and management activities pursuant to the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6201">42 U.S.C. 6201 et seq.</external-xref>), $7,150,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HFF772B4EA5514FE39D08DD17E0B2D626"><header>Energy Information Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary in carrying out the activities of the Energy Information Administration, $135,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HB670F0823A6E4AABB53C5BAF4AFD2A8D"><header>Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses, including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment and other expenses necessary for non-defense environmental cleanup activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $322,371,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That in addition, fees collected pursuant to subsection (b)(1) of section 5 of the Mercury Export Ban Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6939f">42 U.S.C. 6939f(b)(1)</external-xref>), and deposited under this heading in fiscal year 2027 pursuant to section 309 of title III of division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref> are appropriated, to remain available until expended, for mercury storage costs.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HDFDBA40F40804B63A004687B9DF154EA"><header>Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary in carrying out uranium enrichment facility decontamination and decommissioning, remedial actions, and other activities of title II of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, and title X, subtitle A, of the Energy Policy Act of 1992, $821,209,000, to be deposited into and subsequently derived from the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund, to remain available until expended, of which $0 shall be available in accordance with title X, subtitle A, of the Energy Policy Act of 1992. </text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H4410A7528BA646D7AE52DADF166544AE"><header>Science</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HE472B0950B434FC2980D290EF7330543"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment, and other expenses necessary for science activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, and purchase of not more than 35 passenger motor vehicles, $8,525,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $213,320,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H0E2664E6F5E342538D869805CF982A6C"><header>Nuclear Waste Disposal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary for nuclear waste disposal activities to carry out the purposes of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/97/425">Public Law 97–425</external-xref>, as amended, $12,040,000, to remain available until expended, which shall be derived from the Nuclear Waste Fund.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H354AE7C5D7D24E66854FAAA7D0CDA651"><header>Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary in carrying out the activities authorized by section 5012 of the America COMPETES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/69">Public Law 110–69</external-xref>), $300,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $40,000,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H5731FA6D273947408483AAF0AF540DFA"><header>Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HA2B9AE26693F4BD7A4149258CC2D516D"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Such sums as are derived from amounts received from borrowers pursuant to section 1702(b) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 under this heading in prior Acts, shall be collected in accordance with section 502(7) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That for necessary administrative expenses of the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program, as authorized, $35,000,000 is appropriated, to remain available until September 30, 2028: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That up to $35,000,000 of fees collected in fiscal year 2027 pursuant to section 1702(h) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 shall be credited as offsetting collections under this heading and used for necessary administrative expenses in this appropriation and shall remain available until September 30, 2028: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That to the extent that fees collected in fiscal year 2027 exceed $35,000,000, those excess amounts shall be credited as offsetting collections under this heading and available in future fiscal years only to the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated from the general fund shall be reduced (1) as such fees are received during fiscal year 2027 (estimated at $90,000,000) and (2) to the extent that any remaining general fund appropriations can be derived from fees collected in previous fiscal years that are not otherwise appropriated, so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation from the general fund estimated at $0: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the Department of Energy shall not subordinate any loan obligation to other financing in violation of section 1702 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 or subordinate any Guaranteed Obligation to any loan or other debt obligations in violation of section 609.8 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small commented="no" id="HF8CCDC6BB2014037A408B61D0C447D1B"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition, $100,000,000, to remain available until expended, for the cost of loan guarantees for the construction of small modular reactors or advanced nuclear reactors eligible under section 1703(b)(4) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16513">42 U.S.C. 16513(b)(4)</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That the amounts provided under this paragraph are in addition to those provided in any other Act: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for amounts collected pursuant to section 1702(b)(2) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005, the source of such payment received from borrowers may not be a loan or other debt obligation that is guaranteed by the Federal Government: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That none of such loan guarantee authority made available under this paragraph shall be available for commitments to guarantee loans for any projects where funds, personnel, or property (tangible or intangible) of any Federal agency, instrumentality, personnel, or affiliated entity are expected be used (directly or indirectly) through acquisitions, contracts, demonstrations, exchanges, grants, incentives, leases, procurements, sales, other transaction authority, or other arrangements, to support the project or to obtain goods or services from the project: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the preceding proviso shall not be interpreted as precluding the use of the loan guarantee authority provided under this paragraph for commitments to guarantee loans for:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9BF83B9BE74D49ED9EEEDC09FC967970"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projects as a result of such projects benefitting from otherwise allowable Federal income tax benefits;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BBC0366402F46B38C8A69EFBB4B850D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projects as a result of such projects benefitting from being located on Federal land pursuant to a lease or right-of-way agreement for which all consideration for all uses is: </text> 
<subparagraph id="H9AC97DA156134119BBBE7D2FEF280DCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paid exclusively in cash; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9E2ED7657D64818975B5BDEF6597244"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deposited in the Treasury as offsetting receipts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2324D6BB84634D238F99C37F95F6EF81"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">equal to the fair market value as determined by the head of the relevant agency; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33C3839C5BC444FEB799BDAD1A5A5D16"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projects as a result of such projects benefitting from Federal insurance programs, including under section 170 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2210">42 U.S.C. 2210</external-xref>; commonly known as the <quote>Price-Anderson Act</quote>); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A4E84295B614888A57347C1A6D2B7E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">electric generation projects using transmission facilities owned or operated by a Federal Power Marketing Administration or the Tennessee Valley Authority that have been authorized, approved, and financed independent of the project receiving the guarantee:</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="appropriations-small"> <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That none of the loan guarantee authority made available under this heading shall be available for any project unless the Director of the Office of Management and Budget has certified in advance in writing that the loan guarantee and the project comply with the provisions under this heading.</continuation-text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HF4583A51330A4EA2B8B48F0135C448D4"><header>Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy administrative expenses necessary in carrying out the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program, $9,500,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H01E21CCD5F0C45BFB7A3B80AC97C2D49"><header>Tribal Energy Loan Guarantee Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy administrative expenses necessary in carrying out the Tribal Energy Loan Guarantee Program, $6,300,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H7F93C73027BB44459F7AA18BBA83AD34"><header>Indian Energy Policy and Programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses for Indian Energy activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), $75,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of the amount appropriated under this heading, $14,000,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H1F9A8D08FCE3496C8883121C54C728D7"><header>Departmental Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For salaries and expenses of the Department of Energy necessary for departmental administration in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), $333,546,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028, including the hire of passenger motor vehicles and official reception and representation expenses not to exceed $30,000, plus such additional amounts as necessary to cover increases in the estimated amount of cost of work for others notwithstanding the provisions of the Anti-Deficiency Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1511">31 U.S.C. 1511 et seq.</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That such increases in cost of work are offset by revenue increases of the same or greater amount: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That moneys received by the Department for miscellaneous revenues estimated to total $100,578,000 in fiscal year 2027 may be retained and used for operating expenses within this account, as authorized by section 201 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/238">Public Law 95–238</external-xref>, notwithstanding the provisions of 31 U.S.C. 3302: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated shall be reduced as collections are received during the fiscal year so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation from the general fund estimated at not more than $232,968,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H220756757998441F81F5A25D3FAAF082"><header>Office of the Inspector General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Office of the Inspector General in carrying out the provisions of the Inspector General Act of 1978, $80,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="H8BACD6D7EEA14617B48C49C171E72E47"><header>ATOMIC ENERGY DEFENSE ACTIVITIES</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-major id="H7272E9D5336D4A9DAC4CD8E99500990B"><header>NATIONAL NUCLEAR SECURITY ADMINISTRATION </header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H93B558B75B17416E9A6CF617D7DB0520"><header>Weapons Activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses, including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment and other incidental expenses necessary for atomic energy defense weapons activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $22,068,542,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $143,996,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HF79E0614C0FE4B0E81B0A0548C61795E"><header>Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses, including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment and other incidental expenses necessary for defense nuclear nonproliferation activities, in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $2,084,844,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H92B230B0BADB4A5C91850E0314737613"><header>Naval Reactors</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H0EF5882B365741008D4BA0D2EEC81EF8"><header>(INCLUDING TRANSFER OF FUNDS)</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HDC4112D87ADB45F1999391732BB797F4"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses necessary for naval reactors activities to carry out the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition (by purchase, condemnation, construction, or otherwise) of real property, plant, and capital equipment, facilities, and facility expansion, $2,393,692,000, to remain available until expended, of which, $98,770,000 shall be transferred to <quote>Department of Energy—Energy Programs—Nuclear Energy</quote>, for the Advanced Test Reactor: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount made available under this heading, $71,841,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H04A662111B0C47DCB8593ECA91581679"><header>Federal Salaries and Expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for Federal Salaries and Expenses in the National Nuclear Security Administration, $525,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028, including official reception and representation expenses not to exceed $17,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="H2105EB606ED4435B92F4E3E98A4F4CC9"><header>ENVIRONMENTAL AND OTHER DEFENSE ACTIVITIES</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H875801B09142455FACF8D700F54C9127"><header>Defense Environmental Cleanup</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses, including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment and other expenses necessary for atomic energy defense environmental cleanup activities in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $6,555,922,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $297,318,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H0F085E0416D04171B3636994D6EE97BC"><header>Other Defense Activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For Department of Energy expenses, including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment and other expenses, necessary for atomic energy defense, other defense activities, and classified activities, in carrying out the purposes of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including the acquisition or condemnation of any real property or any facility or for plant or facility acquisition, construction, or expansion, $1,170,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of such amount, $352,979,000 shall be available until September 30, 2028, for program direction.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="H450AAF260CC64B9D88D11FCD3C855342"><header>POWER MARKETING ADMINISTRATIONS</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H7D4D09C641F948B19943D29E839203E2"><header>Bonneville Power Administration Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Expenditures from the Bonneville Power Administration Fund, established pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/93/454">Public Law 93–454</external-xref>, are approved for the Spokane Tribal Fisheries Operations Center: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That expenditures are also approved for official reception and representation expenses in an amount not to exceed $5,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That during fiscal year 2027, no new direct loan obligations may be made.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H9A5E47F548674251B1EBC725213E8D7B"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Southeastern Power Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for operation and maintenance of power transmission facilities and for marketing electric power and energy, including transmission wheeling and ancillary services, pursuant to section 5 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/825s">16 U.S.C. 825s</external-xref>), as applied to the southeastern power area, $9,285,000, including official reception and representation expenses in an amount not to exceed $1,500, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding 31 U.S.C. 3302 and section 5 of the Flood Control Act of 1944, up to $9,285,000 collected by the Southeastern Power Administration from the sale of power and related services shall be credited to this account as discretionary offsetting collections, to remain available until expended for the sole purpose of funding the annual expenses of the Southeastern Power Administration: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated for annual expenses shall be reduced as collections are received during the fiscal year so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation estimated at not more than $0: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3302">31 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>, up to $81,819,000 collected by the Southeastern Power Administration pursuant to the Flood Control Act of 1944 to recover purchase power and wheeling expenses shall be credited to this account as offsetting collections, to remain available until expended for the sole purpose of making purchase power and wheeling expenditures: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for purposes of this appropriation, annual expenses means expenditures that are generally recovered in the same year that they are incurred (excluding purchase power and wheeling expenses).</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HC04FC7E4B41B44FF996F58978EFF997E"><header>Operation and Maintenance, Southwestern Power Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for operation and maintenance of power transmission facilities and for marketing electric power and energy, for construction and acquisition of transmission lines, substations and appurtenant facilities, and for administrative expenses, including official reception and representation expenses in an amount not to exceed $1,500 in carrying out section 5 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/825s">16 U.S.C. 825s</external-xref>), as applied to the Southwestern Power Administration, $61,798,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding 31 U.S.C. 3302 and section 5 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/825s">16 U.S.C. 825s</external-xref>), up to $51,398,000 collected by the Southwestern Power Administration from the sale of power and related services shall be credited to this account as discretionary offsetting collections, to remain available until expended, for the sole purpose of funding the annual expenses of the Southwestern Power Administration: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated for annual expenses shall be reduced as collections are received during the fiscal year so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation estimated at not more than $10,400,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3302">31 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>, up to $80,000,000 collected by the Southwestern Power Administration pursuant to the Flood Control Act of 1944 to recover purchase power and wheeling expenses shall be credited to this account as offsetting collections, to remain available until expended for the sole purpose of making purchase power and wheeling expenditures: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for purposes of this appropriation, annual expenses means expenditures that are generally recovered in the same year that they are incurred (excluding purchase power and wheeling expenses).</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H3714EFBC3591491CBBEF9AD5423540C8"><header>Construction, Rehabilitation, Operation and Maintenance, Western Area Power Administration</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H91D6D5F511D04B8D87D789D1664A206B"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For carrying out the functions authorized by title III, section 302(a)(1)(E) of the Act of August 4, 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7152">42 U.S.C. 7152</external-xref>), and other related activities including conservation and renewable resources programs as authorized, $321,775,000, including official reception and representation expenses in an amount not to exceed $1,500, to remain available until expended, of which $321,775,000 shall be derived from the Department of the Interior Reclamation Fund: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3302">31 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>, section 5 of the Flood Control Act of 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/825s">16 U.S.C. 825s</external-xref>), and section 1 of the Interior Department Appropriation Act, 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/392a">43 U.S.C. 392a</external-xref>), up to $258,387,000 collected by the Western Area Power Administration from the sale of power and related services shall be credited to this account as discretionary offsetting collections, to remain available until expended, for the sole purpose of funding the annual expenses of the Western Area Power Administration: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated for annual expenses shall be reduced as collections are received during the fiscal year so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation estimated at not more than $63,388,000, of which $63,388,000 is derived from the Reclamation Fund: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3302">31 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>, up to $350,000,000 collected by the Western Area Power Administration pursuant to the Flood Control Act of 1944 and the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 to recover purchase power and wheeling expenses shall be credited to this account as offsetting collections, to remain available until expended for the sole purpose of making purchase power and wheeling expenditures: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for purposes of this appropriation, annual expenses means expenditures that are generally recovered in the same year that they are incurred (excluding purchase power and wheeling expenses). </text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H603CD236DDE4449EA2FA61C9966EF15F"><header>Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For operation, maintenance, and emergency costs for the hydroelectric facilities at the Falcon and Amistad Dams, $6,422,000, to remain available until expended, and to be derived from the Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund of the Western Area Power Administration, as provided in section 2 of the Act of June 18, 1954 (68 Stat. 255): <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding the provisions of that Act and of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3302">31 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>, up to $6,194,000 collected by the Western Area Power Administration from the sale of power and related services from the Falcon and Amistad Dams shall be credited to this account as discretionary offsetting collections, to remain available until expended for the sole purpose of funding the annual expenses of the hydroelectric facilities of these Dams and associated Western Area Power Administration activities: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated for annual expenses shall be reduced as collections are received during the fiscal year so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation estimated at not more than $228,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for purposes of this appropriation, annual expenses means expenditures that are generally recovered in the same year that they are incurred: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That for fiscal year 2027, the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration may accept up to $1,872,000 in funds contributed by United States power customers of the Falcon and Amistad Dams for deposit into the Falcon and Amistad Operating and Maintenance Fund, and such funds shall be available for the purpose for which contributed in like manner as if said sums had been specifically appropriated for such purpose: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That any such funds shall be available without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation for use by the Commissioner of the United States Section of the International Boundary and Water Commission for the sole purpose of operating, maintaining, repairing, rehabilitating, replacing, or upgrading the hydroelectric facilities at these Dams in accordance with agreements reached between the Administrator, Commissioner, and the power customers.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HB79FFFBF161B4E53A558E2BBB80441A1"><header>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HFF7D67D50EE94DB7AD339A9531CFDBC2"><header>SALARIES AND EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to carry out the provisions of the Department of Energy Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7101">42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), including services as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3109">5 U.S.C. 3109</external-xref>, official reception and representation expenses not to exceed $3,000, and the hire of passenger motor vehicles, $520,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding any other provision of law, not to exceed $520,000,000 of revenues from fees and annual charges, and other services and collections in fiscal year 2027 shall be retained and used for expenses necessary in this account, and shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated from the general fund shall be reduced as revenues are received during fiscal year 2027 so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation from the general fund estimated at not more than $0.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H3676559A80A24391A29ECD444D71F570"><header>GENERAL PROVISIONS—DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-small id="H6B2C466EC6B94D7EA65879012C4E2EBC"><header>(INCLUDING TRANSFERS OF FUNDS)</header></appropriations-small> 
<section id="H3F411C78A71F4029AB6FCC1F6E8D40AF"><enum>301.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF3343D52BBF3474796840AB1CBD46CFC"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No appropriation, funds, or authority made available by this title for the Department of Energy shall be used to initiate or resume any program, project, or activity or to prepare or initiate Requests For Proposals or similar arrangements (including Requests for Quotations, Requests for Information, and Funding Opportunity Announcements) for a program, project, or activity if the program, project, or activity has not been funded by Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD14ECCCDCAEA4938B76B6B145C243497"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1A3941E2DE794CF185D00019B20E3A07"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unless the Secretary of Energy notifies the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 3 full business days in advance, none of the funds made available in this title may be used to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2F4969361D2D484BBC6DEBE019E6491F" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make a grant allocation or discretionary grant award totaling $1,000,000 or more;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H569AF6C521FA49C1932F5F488557336C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make a discretionary contract award or Other Transaction Agreement totaling $1,000,000 or more, including a contract covered by the Federal Acquisition Regulation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEAEB8743FED943BEA42672D7D88E34BF" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide nonoperational funding through a competition restricted only to Department of Energy National Laboratories totaling $1,000,000 or more;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8811C19573F3456A935663A5EE47FDDD" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide nonoperational funding directly to a Department of Energy National Laboratory totaling $25,000,000 or more;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DBAFAD15E5942AEA163FD89B0177B88" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>issue a letter of intent to make an allocation, award, or Agreement in excess of the limits in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D); </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" id="HB4FE3C78F6254E0F8F31E34527107EF8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>announce publicly the intention to make an allocation, award, or Agreement in excess of the limits in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE2E6201E2274031BC2C8BE87F95C6AC" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>issue a letter to terminate an allocation, award, or Agreement in excess of the limits in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D5DBD0AD0214AA7B57C56143CCF215E" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress within 15 days of the conclusion of each quarter a report detailing each grant allocation or discretionary grant award totaling less than $1,000,000 provided during the previous quarter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D302568E22641D3BBB5FE87CD3CA6F5" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The notification required by paragraph (1) and the report required by paragraph (2) shall include the recipient of the award, the amount of the award, the fiscal year for which the funds for the award were appropriated, the account and program, project, or activity from which the funds are being drawn, the title of the award, and a brief description of the activity for which the award is made.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7104A73110B447C592636376F6D074E6"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Department of Energy may not, with respect to any program, project, or activity that uses budget authority made available in this title under the heading <quote>Department of Energy—Energy Programs</quote>, enter into a multiyear contract, award a multiyear grant, or enter into a multiyear cooperative agreement unless—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9ED18DAFF80E4BA1979BB81D8A9819AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement is funded for the full period of performance as anticipated at the time of award; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88B239BB90C54E509D707C2910F49F66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement includes a clause conditioning the Federal Government's obligation on the availability of future year budget authority and the Secretary notifies the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 3 days in advance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF0E74B0F156943E584C1392E8B4B9A3C"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsections (e), (f), and (g), the amounts made available by this title shall be expended as authorized by law for the programs, projects, and activities, and in the amounts, specified in the <quote>Bill</quote> column in the <quote>Department of Energy</quote> table included under the heading <quote>Title III—Department of Energy</quote> in the report accompanying this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9C981E93128C4E9CB68EC2E0AA2F750D"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The amounts made available by this title may be reprogrammed for any program, project, or activity, and the Department shall notify, and obtain the prior approval of, the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 30 days prior to the use of any proposed reprogramming that would cause any program, project, or activity funding level to increase or decrease by more than $5,000,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less, during the time period covered by this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F490E9ECAC84A80B946CCDC6729BA50"><enum>(f)</enum><text>None of the funds provided in this title shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds that—</text> <paragraph id="H4A7268B770804D13858AB9205FC15870"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates, initiates, or eliminates a program, project, or activity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H691A23946C8B480A953B2EB83C443A59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increases funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are denied or restricted by this Act; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE91F02E8BA5646B9BDCF8CF729D2D249"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reduces funds that are directed to be used for a specific program, project, or activity by this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2109FC3C2EE14E68A3E844487474CF8A"><enum>(g)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H894F201845B04341ADD32E0AC46EAC79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy may waive any requirement or restriction in this section that applies to the use of funds made available for the Department of Energy if compliance with such requirement or restriction would pose a substantial risk to human health, the environment, welfare, or national security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C71A2F0753C485893A68F27567C5135" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress of any waiver under paragraph (1) as soon as practicable, but not later than 3 days after the date of the activity to which a requirement or restriction would otherwise have applied. Such notice shall include an explanation of the substantial risk under paragraph (1) that permitted such waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFF62E64D0E2D4B4E84226A48FFC4D8AB"><enum>(h)</enum><text>The unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this Act may be available to the same appropriation accounts for such activities established pursuant to this title. Available balances may be merged with funds in the applicable established accounts and thereafter may be accounted for as one fund for the same time period as originally enacted.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAC9B520D850B47BC9B3516C29C84976C"><enum>302.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated by this or any other Act, or made available by the transfer of funds in this Act, for intelligence activities are deemed to be specifically authorized by the Congress for purposes of section 504 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3094">50 U.S.C. 3094</external-xref>) during fiscal year 2027 until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for fiscal year 2027.</text></section> 
<section id="H41F6A3AC48A3453581A6F105ECED0476"><enum>303.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this title shall be used for the construction of facilities classified as high-hazard nuclear facilities under 10 CFR Part 830 unless independent oversight is conducted by the Office of Enterprise Assessments to ensure the project is in compliance with nuclear safety requirements.</text></section> <section id="H54203F36C65A403599C8E642BD28C41A"><enum>304.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this title may be used to approve critical decision-2 or critical decision-3 under Department of Energy Order 413.3B, or any successive departmental guidance, for construction projects where the total project cost exceeds $100,000,000, until a separate independent cost estimate has been developed for the project for that critical decision.</text></section> 
<section id="HA6A7B3409CDD425E9ADD717DF6B88C06"><enum>305.</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this title may be used to support a grant allocation award, discretionary grant award, or cooperative agreement that exceeds $100,000,000 in Federal funding unless the project is carried out through internal independent project management procedures.</text></section> <section id="H412EF481D8904FF7B1075CC42FD882F2"><enum>306.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds shall be transferred directly from <quote>Department of Energy—Power Marketing Administration—Colorado River Basins Power Marketing Fund, Western Area Power Administration</quote> to the general fund of the Treasury in the current fiscal year. </text></section> 
<section id="H9F5A7E30446144EF874CE8ACFE7CBF8F"><enum>307.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to draw down and sell petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (1) to any entity that is under the ownership, control, or influence of the Chinese Communist Party; or (2) except on condition that such petroleum products will not be exported to the People’s Republic of China.</text></section> <section id="H647FEE1AF8554EFFB459A0A3E8BB9029"><enum>308.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8FD81A9CB5F64098BB8C3F1D35719E25"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used by the Secretary of Energy to award any grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or loan of $10,000,000 or greater to an entity of concern as defined in section 10114 of division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/167">Public Law 117–167</external-xref>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBAF634CD9AFE4BDCAE5B31BC85DA640B"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement the requirements under subsection (a) using a risk-based approach and analytical tools to aggregate, link, analyze, and maintain information reported by an entity seeking or receiving such funds made available by this Act. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H59E337A3EA3841CD8709F5B7C4FED253"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall be applied in a manner consistent with the obligations of the United States under applicable international agreements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB9BC591A883944AEA8B0EB314C6B07A4"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall have the authority to require the submission to the agency, by an entity seeking or receiving such funds made available by this Act, documentation necessary to implement the requirements under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCEA041B55FA44580A909ACD9B27E48B5"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), shall not apply to the implementation of the requirements under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H96BAE605C95249DEB7B259B98A90E8CE"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and other Federal agencies shall coordinate to share relevant information necessary to implement the requirements under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA7129D0623E8447AB9B8112BD744BBE5"><enum>309.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used to admit any non-U.S. citizen from Russia or China to any nuclear weapons production facility, as such term is defined in section 4002 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2501">50 U.S.C. 2501</external-xref>), other than areas accessible to the general public, unless 30 days prior to facility admittance, the Department of Energy provides notification to the Committees on Appropriations and Armed Services of both Houses of Congress.</text></section> 
<section id="H2776AB9C236E4ABBBEB6C7DE456CB5F5"><enum>310.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available in this title under the headings <quote>Critical Minerals and Energy Innovation </quote>, <quote>Electricity</quote>, <quote>Hydrocarbons and Geothermal Energy </quote>, <quote>Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response</quote>, and <quote>Science</quote> that are allocated for the purposes of section 9 of the Small Business Act, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/638">15 U.S.C. 638</external-xref>), including for Small Business Innovation Research and Small Business Technology Transfer activities, or for the purposes of section 1001 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005, as amended (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16391">42 U.S.C. 16391</external-xref>), for Technology Commercialization Fund activities, may be reprogrammed within each account without being subject to the restrictions in section 301 of this title: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That the administration and selection of awards pursuant to such sections will be in coordination with the offices that oversee the appropriations accounts to which the relevant funding was originally appropriated. </text></section> 
<section id="H84207A4DD8A349D5B1690B93703BB136"><enum>311.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to finalize, administer, implement, or enforce the final rule entitled <quote>Clean Energy for New Federal Buildings and Major Renovations of Federal Buildings</quote> published by the Department of Energy in the Federal Register on May 1, 2024 (89 Fed. Reg. 35384).</text></section> <section id="HF4B02ECB68CC491DABD0259DE6EB805A"><enum>312.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making Federal financial assistance, the Department of Energy shall continue to apply the indirect cost rates, including negotiated indirect cost rates, as described in section 200.414 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations, including with respect to the approval of deviations from negotiated indirect cost rates, to the same extent and in the same manner as was applied in fiscal year 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That none of the funds appropriated in this or prior Acts or otherwise made available to the Department of Energy may be used to develop, modify, or implement changes to such negotiated indirect cost rates.</text></section> 
<section id="H1AEE09DD3F66480A902741367DDDF0ED"><enum>313.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCBE77D2C4D2844DFA20311DD548F5115"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts specified in subsection (c), $2,675,000,000 shall be transferred to, and merged with, amounts provided in this Act under the heading <quote>Nuclear Energy</quote> that remain available until expended, and in addition to amounts otherwise available, shall only be available for the not more than two competitive awards for Generation 3+ small modular reactor deployment projects described in section 311(a)(1)(A) of division D of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/42">Public Law 118–42</external-xref>), the two awards for demonstration projects made prior to the date of enactment of this Act under the Advanced Reactor Demonstration Program, as authorized under section 959A of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16279a">42 U.S.C. 16279a</external-xref>), and Risk Reduction for Future Demonstrations, as described under the heading Advanced Reactor Demonstration Program in the explanatory statement accompanying division C of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>). </text></subsection> <subsection id="H083C799356924B778F3E59446287F167"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts provided in the second paragraph under the heading <quote>Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program</quote>, $100,000,000 shall be derived by transfer from the funds specified in subsection (c).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H58DF10988F094E979D282D95F424CCA7"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The funds specified in this subsection are the unobligated balances from amounts provided in title III of division J of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>, as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H51D5E4A3B4DF42499C3819F5D137A345"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$594,613,407 of the amounts provided under the heading <quote>Energy Programs—Carbon Dioxide Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Program Account</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H835AB8090ECA4599B0D17D4B78E4C091"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$590,900,593 of the amounts provided under the heading <quote>Energy Programs—Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7ACDBCDAB474AC6B5681EBDFA39245F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$439,486,000 of the amounts provided under the heading <quote>Energy Programs—Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCC5A7E651B7462B89B6E83CCF4961F0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,150,000,000 of the amounts provided under the heading <quote>Energy Programs—Fossil Energy and Carbon Management</quote>.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HDEA97E822E2E4882886C3D6C17C10BBE"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Department of Energy shall transmit to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress a report that details the amounts repurposed or transferred pursuant to this section: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That such report shall be delineated by both source and destination by Treasury Appropriations Fund Symbol and statutory authority (including by subparagraph for funds specified in subsection (d)(4)).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5AA525971D114BDB9008A2D5FCE84F78"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts repurposed or transferred pursuant to this section shall continue to be treated as amounts specified in section 103(b) of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/5">Public Law 118–5</external-xref>.</text></subsection></section> </title> <title id="H9C861D44562B404998F916B6E608EFCD" style="appropriations"><enum>IV</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">INDEPENDENT AGENCIES</header><appropriations-intermediate id="HDAAEB8B0171C48B1A8704C99C1582376"><header>Appalachian Regional Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary to carry out the programs authorized by the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965, as amended, and for expenses necessary for the Federal Co-Chairman and the Alternate on the Appalachian Regional Commission, for payment of the Federal share of the administrative expenses of the Commission, including services as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/3109">5 U.S.C. 3109</external-xref>, and hire of passenger motor vehicles, $200,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H32FF1DCFD472429EBB4A8B771EB33C77"><header>Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H4ED6DAC52B224C109E4DCFB14136B312"><header>SALARIES AND EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board in carrying out activities authorized by the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/456">Public Law 100–456</external-xref>, section 1441, $42,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028, of which not to exceed $1,000 shall be available for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HF8F5A70759B847E6A410A2BA40A4140F"><header>Delta Regional Authority</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HCB2847F7145E4AD1A964E79C813CF744"><header>SALARIES AND EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Delta Regional Authority and to carry out its activities, as authorized by the Delta Regional Authority Act of 2000, notwithstanding sections 382F(d), 382M, and 382N of said Act, $32,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H219DD29710244E99803EB266E44E5258"><header>Denali Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Denali Commission including the purchase, construction, and acquisition of plant and capital equipment as necessary and other expenses, $18,000,000, to remain available until expended, notwithstanding the limitations contained in section 306(g) of the Denali Commission Act of 1998: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That funds shall be available for construction projects for which the Denali Commission is the sole or primary funding source in an amount not to exceed 80 percent of total project cost for distressed communities, as defined by section 307 of the Denali Commission Act of 1998, as amended by section 701 of appendix D, title VII, <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/113">Public Law 106–113</external-xref> (113 Stat. 1501A–280), and for Indian Tribes, as defined by section 5304(e) of title 25, United States Code, and in an amount not to exceed 50 percent for non-distressed communities: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That notwithstanding any other provision of law regarding payment of a non-Federal share in connection with a grant-in-aid program, amounts under this heading shall be available for the payment of such a non-Federal share for any project for which the Denali Commission is not the sole or primary funding source, provided that such project is consistent with the purposes of the Commission.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HA15E0F9D56554F0A81D677BEED3FCD1A"><header>Northern Border Regional Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Northern Border Regional Commission in carrying out activities authorized by subtitle V of title 40, United States Code, $42,000,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That such amounts shall be available for administrative expenses, notwithstanding section 15751(b) of title 40, United States Code.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H942F09034AFD4E5F8963259A9364E96F"><header>Southeast Crescent Regional Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Southeast Crescent Regional Commission in carrying out activities authorized by subtitle V of title 40, United States Code, $20,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H7629C3D6C0004874B1D6C5BC0AC1E499"><header>Southwest Border Regional Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Southwest Border Regional Commission in carrying out activities authorized by subtitle V of title 40, United States Code, $5,500,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="HF0B9D27508794EA18AD3DCC4F9E1928C"><header>Great Lakes Authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Great Lakes Authority in carrying out activities authorized by subtitle V of title 40, United States Code, $5,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-intermediate id="H514BCE37C1B9428C89C2ADDC30E5F0F7"><header>Nuclear Regulatory Commission</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HFF3816FF99DC411BA3F93B9E68CBB29C"><header>SALARIES AND EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Commission in carrying out the purposes of the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 and the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, $878,104,000, including official representation expenses not to exceed $30,000, to remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That of the amount appropriated herein, not more than $11,662,000 may be made available for salaries, travel, and other support costs for the Office of the Commission, to remain available until September 30, 2028: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That revenues from licensing fees, inspection services, and other services and collections estimated at $744,750,000 in fiscal year 2027 shall be retained and used for necessary salaries and expenses in this account, notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3302">31 U.S.C. 3302</external-xref>, and shall remain available until expended: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated shall be reduced by the amount of revenues received during fiscal year 2027 so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation estimated at not more than $133,354,000.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H88F01900BF754FE2A2E1BE9B6AD2BAB0"><header>OFFICE OF INSPECTOR GENERAL</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Office of Inspector General in carrying out the provisions of the Inspector General Act of 1978, $14,245,000, to remain available until September 30, 2028: <proviso><italic>Provided,</italic></proviso> That revenues from licensing fees, inspection services, and other services and collections estimated at $11,444,000 in fiscal year 2027 shall be retained and be available until September 30, 2028, for necessary salaries and expenses in this account, notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That the sum herein appropriated shall be reduced by the amount of revenues received during fiscal year 2027 so as to result in a final fiscal year 2027 appropriation estimated at not more than $2,801,000: <proviso><italic>Provided further,</italic></proviso> That of the amounts appropriated under this heading, $1,345,000 shall be for Inspector General services for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="HA6C294C6619542DC9FB9BA9C5C316C4E"><header>Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H073E80BF53644A0D990C77091AAA880E"><header>SALARIES AND EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For expenses necessary for the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board, as authorized by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/203">Public Law 100–203</external-xref>, section 5051, $4,000,000, to be derived from the Nuclear Waste Fund, to remain available until September 30, 2028.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H73DBA5BD1CFD40D49AFE930921F32679"><header>GENERAL PROVISIONS—INDEPENDENT AGENCIES</header></appropriations-major> <section id="H890C10636B4E49A0B7DF0E14F99E4816"><enum>401.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall comply with the July 5, 2011, version of Chapter VI of its Internal Commission Procedures when responding to Congressional requests for information, consistent with Department of Justice guidance for all Federal agencies.</text></section> 
<section id="H52B5B200215F4CB3B28DA5F8FDC7E108"><enum>402.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAA5E6A8AF201444A9F275254AD0C6E33"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts made available by this title for the Nuclear Regulatory Commission may be reprogrammed for any program, project, or activity, and the Commission shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress at least 30 days prior to the use of any proposed reprogramming that would cause any program funding level to increase or decrease by more than $500,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less, during the time period covered by this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H73B7D1F616D04A019F21D07B8E3F8AC3"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92711BDD1A174D3F92BE514579041700"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Nuclear Regulatory Commission may waive the notification requirement in subsection (a) if compliance with such requirement would pose a substantial risk to human health, the environment, welfare, or national security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A51BEFE44D643E98A7AD2907B7F8C88" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress of any waiver under paragraph (1) as soon as practicable, but not later than 3 days after the date of the activity to which a requirement or restriction would otherwise have applied. Such notice shall include an explanation of the substantial risk under paragraph (1) that permitted such waiver and shall provide a detailed report to the Committees of such waiver and changes to funding levels to programs, projects, or activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE136FB46F4A1446DAD7FEA5C1CB6CA19"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsections (a), (b), and (d), the amounts made available by this title for <quote>Nuclear Regulatory Commission—Salaries and Expenses</quote> shall be expended as directed in the report accompanying this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC0559405E12340ABB7F96CC23D9888CE"><enum>(d)</enum><text>None of the funds provided for the Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds that increases funds or personnel for any program, project, or activity for which funds are denied or restricted by this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF30F185810E7419CA84288E182D769A9"><enum>(e)</enum><text>The Commission shall provide a monthly report to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress, which includes the following for each program, project, or activity, including any prior year appropriations—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD3B8C8291CF3459EA6D8ADE88AFDF477"><enum>(1)</enum><text>total budget authority;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA8F34EB053142019F6C661EEC6B39AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>total unobligated balances; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE928A818555D4515AE3FE5A20F76A0EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>total unliquidated obligations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title> <title id="H1E54E9F39A5A419F9726E03DC76FEC7A" style="appropriations"><enum>V</enum><header display-inline="no-display-inline">GENERAL PROVISIONS</header><appropriations-small id="HA287C235FDDD4A2F9BEBE539E67DEF34"><header>(INCLUDING TRANSFER OF FUNDS)</header></appropriations-small> <section id="H99755AEF3AF7416B8F9EB00F0415E1C1"><enum>501.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this Act may be used in any way, directly or indirectly, to influence congressional action on any legislation or appropriation matters pending before Congress, other than to communicate to Members of Congress as described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/1913">18 U.S.C. 1913</external-xref>.</text></section> 
<section id="H9F283192665B4EDCB0F76B74E0F16B45"><enum>502.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4D80EC1B5B5E494A95933AD09B800A59"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in title III of this Act may be transferred to any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government, except pursuant to a transfer made by or transfer authority provided in this Act or any other appropriations Act for any fiscal year, transfer authority referenced in the report accompanying this Act, or any authority whereby a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government may provide goods or services to another department, agency, or instrumentality.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H66B7084333004BD980C18FDB376313BB"><enum>(b)</enum><text>None of the funds made available for any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government may be transferred to accounts funded in title III of this Act, except pursuant to a transfer made by or transfer authority provided in this Act or any other appropriations Act for any fiscal year, transfer authority referenced in the report accompanying this Act, or any authority whereby a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government may provide goods or services to another department, agency, or instrumentality.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H28BF1133B4C242F2BF756A91DBD84938"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The head of any relevant department or agency funded in this Act utilizing any transfer authority shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of both Houses of Congress a semiannual report detailing the transfer authorities, except for any authority whereby a department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government may provide goods or services to another department, agency, or instrumentality, used in the previous 6 months and in the year-to-date. This report shall include the amounts transferred and the purposes for which they were transferred, and shall not replace or modify existing notification requirements for each authority.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3F0A1FE415BA40DAA21B3149BB68451C"><enum>503.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7BFD3FCCB18E4937A478365132F89D56"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to maintain or establish a computer network unless such network blocks the viewing, downloading, and exchanging of pornography.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59CE81C50E7049EC9D8C4C8D8646A0F2"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Nothing in subsection (a) shall limit the use of funds necessary for any Federal, State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agency or any other entity carrying out criminal investigations, prosecution, or adjudication activities.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H60D5F48B60A14A528B4FFB79032BBF65"><enum>504.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEAD6EB80B26948B88B705A1A46426387"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No federal monies shall be expended in furtherance of any agreement among private entities for consolidated interim storage of spent nuclear fuel that is not specifically authorized under federal law until such time that host state and local governments and any affected Indian tribes have formalized their consent.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H260ED89AAF294783A7D8B22D780C245A"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Provided that the prohibition provided for in this section shall not apply to facilities presently storing commercial spent nuclear fuel, pursuant to a license issued by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, as of the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H319A932518424303B99B14587FC3DF7F"><enum>(c)</enum><text>For purposes of this section, <quote>spent nuclear fuel</quote> shall have the same meaning as provided in section 2 of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><appropriations-small id="HAD2D64DADA81430BAE31C3AAD2351F4F"><header>SPENDING REDUCTION ACCOUNT</header></appropriations-small> 
<section id="HF155556658D74BFDB6F9855B3E37CA68"><enum>505.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$0</text></section><appropriations-small id="HF832CA82BEB246AD9A9821A4B2615907" commented="no"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2027</short-title></quote>.</text></appropriations-small></title> </legis-body> <endorsement> <action-date date="20260522">May 22, 2026</action-date> <action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

