<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBD470E508D9D496EB3C841F9C0A99BBF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8963 IH: Lance Corporal Dustin Sekula Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8963</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award the Congressional Gold Medal posthumously to Edinburg, Texas war hero Lance Corporal Dustin Sekula, in recognition of his heroic life.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H73ECD2F2C170424AAE61290076DA74B8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDF4D780DED4E4808BC3A97DE85016FE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lance Corporal Dustin Sekula Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H78B7888BEBC44E30A6B2D77607CFADC1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that:</text>
<paragraph id="HC96FEAA241914F2C8670CB0681D53DE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Dustin Sekula was born on June 8, 1985, in Edinburg, Texas, and graduated from Edinburg North High School in 2003.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4540A179CD824596A49D9D085D7A9E02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Dustin was a kind, loyal, and loving son and brother.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF271CFFCB78E4D9C9C05E35E1BB5B9DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Dustin was skilled at ranching and loved roping steers. He used his high school lunch period to practice roping on a fake steer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7F0429FE3334B58B5ABA5CB698CFC52"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Dustin turned down an agriculture college scholarship to join the Marines and serve his country at the age of 17.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3C502351FF2843D585A8581A49E77DB1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>At 18, an infantry mortarman of the 2nd Battalion, 7th Marine Regiment, 1st Marine Division, 1st Marine Expeditionary Force, Dustin died due to injuries sustained from enemy fire in Al Anbar Province, Iraq, on April 1, 2004.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAD7D3EF79DB47DEB48EEA64780C362C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>More than 1,000 people filled Trinity Worship Center for his funeral service.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD00A9F777EA54443B97B106DA2F3BE48"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Dustin is buried in Palm Valley Memorial Gardens in Pharr, Texas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68287AC1360845EB9336F465E499FF8F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Dustin Sekula Memorial Library (DMSML) located in Edinburg, Texas, is named after Marine Lance Corporal Dustin Michael Sekula.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89FC0D16CAF449A4973DD57EEC5B6282"><enum>(9)</enum><text>He was the first Edinburg native to be killed during Operation Iraqi Freedom.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9AA6A11DBB541E99F1478C79662001A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>He is not forgotten.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H3455C1DDCC8649BD9CF3D13060D9D845"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header>
<subsection id="H7EB8DFD63488458CB77A644DBF726F68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, to the family of Lance Corporal Dustin Sekula on behalf of the Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration of Lance Corporal Dustin Sekula, Edinburg, Texas war hero, in recognition of his heroic life.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBA8D0EDF86D14AF7B2362E4726DD474A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HF8B07EBA2C084B1FB436C9FDCBDBFD69"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="H711DBFD630E047CE98F24113D376F3C7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> <subsection id="H067CD6BCDA1543009830CDF75A186B4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck under this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H398A44CCBEC140D6853B08E5A4C85C13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0DCEBB2D17074B45AE3327FB1233527C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> <subsection id="HC80CBD64B6884B2C8C871918058A2740"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC21B343F0033417C8B03ED864EC00713"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

