<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD34D03713D094B4F83BF97E677DF7BD2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 963 IH: Condemning antisemitism in all its forms, including the proliferation and amplification of antisemitic content on artificial intelligence (AI) platforms, urging robust, transparent safeguards for AI, and recognizing stakeholders working to counter this threat.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 963</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000483">Ms. Friedman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning antisemitism in all its forms, including the proliferation and amplification of antisemitic content on artificial intelligence (AI) platforms, urging robust, transparent safeguards for AI, and recognizing stakeholders working to counter this threat.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas antisemitism represents prejudice, discrimination, or hostility directed at Jewish people, is generally based on negative stereotypes, myths, conspiracy theories, or misinformation about Jews, Judaism, or Jewish identity, and continues to harm Jewish individuals, and communities in the United States and around the world, at present, threatening American values, social stability, and American unity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas online platforms, including artificial intelligence (AI) and digital social platforms, have proven capable of facilitating the rapid dissemination and algorithmically charged amplification of content that drives antisemitic tropes, Holocaust denial and distortion, extremist content, conspiracy theories, harassment, and explicit calls to violence and celebration thereof;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas AI systems, including large language models, image and video generators, and automated moderation tools, can, if inadequately governed, generate, amplify, or normalize antisemitic content, deepfakes, synthetic media, and deeply anti-Jewish bias, and can be weaponized to target Jewish individuals and institutions, as well as American institutions, normalizing antisemitism and anti-Jewish bias en masse;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the widespread presence of digital antisemitism, anti-Jewish conspiracies, and bias has led to multiple instances of AI hallucinations and openly racist AI-generated responses and content, dating as far back as 2016 with Microsoft’s Tay Tweets;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, more recently, Grok, the AI assistant created by xAI and integrated into the social media platform X, has a history of spreading shocking antisemitic hate to its users, and in July 2025 produced multiple outputs that reproduced terminologies that are often used by antisemites and extremists to spew their hateful ideologies;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas documented research has shown that antisemitism can flourish in foundational, open source, and large language AI models without proper safeguards;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas academic researchers and civil society organizations have documented and warned that AI and algorithmic systems can reproduce harmful biases, generate or amplify antisemitic and extremist content, and be manipulated to bypass guardrails through AI applications and social media platforms;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas organizations have further warned of the intersection between AI and antisemitism, and called for enforceable standards, including recommendations on transparency, safety-by-design, and anti-hate enforcement;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the leaders of multiple technology companies have committed, including in statements by Microsoft in May 2021 and Google and Alphabet in October 2023, to keeping antisemitism off their platforms;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the development and ongoing improvement of voluntary standards by AI companies, created with input from industry experts, academics, civil society groups, and faith-based organizations, can offer valuable guidance on effectively combating antisemitism in AI products and platforms;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas successive United States administrations have recognized the importance of ensuring that AI development reflects American values, innovation, accountability, and safety; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas acts of antisemitism in all its forms, including through radicalization, harassment, and incitement to violence, are fundamentally opposed to the values and pursuits enshrined in the Constitution of the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H50D0654B00954EB3BAF2D2B47B315241"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H42405D202BA746E899CBDC6B414E8CAB"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HD8D3CCFB45F547AF86881C7190B3075C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemns antisemitism in all its forms, including its manifestation and amplification through AI and social media platforms, tools, and services, as it is fundamentally opposed to the values enshrined in the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H400AC38D70E6496B8A5F2B4EA130B7ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affirms that combating antisemitism is a national priority, and that technology companies developing or deploying AI systems bear a responsibility to implement robust safeguards (such as transparency, consultation and coordination with antisemitism experts, and prevention of algorithmic amplification of such content) to prevent their systems from producing or amplifying antisemitic content, harassment, calls to violence or symbols that encourage violent action, or targeted abuse;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BF5B5F9813647A69ED0759FEEF4E8D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages the development and adoption of standards, frameworks, and the development of supporting enforcement technology, red teaming methodologies, and datasets to guide risk identification, measurement, mitigation, and governance of AI systems with respect to antisemitism and other forms of hate;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB33CD50CE8C649E1B1B57345690485C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls for improved data sharing, researcher access, and privacy-protective mechanisms to study antisemitic content dynamics on AI-enabled platforms, evaluate interventions, assess consistency in platform reporting standards, support evidence-based policymaking, and scalable enforcement mechanisms;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H965EB3255E5849098A540CD9C46F33E3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports efforts, specifically among youth, to strengthen digital literacy, Holocaust remembrance, and public awareness initiatives to equip users, educators, and communities to recognize, report, and resist antisemitic narratives, including those propagated by AI-generated text, imagery, audio, and video;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74A8BBF3B20A4C72A7A4D67651D4740D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages collaboration among Federal, State, and local governments, civil society, academia, and industry to develop and test effective interventions against antisemitic content and coordinated harassment, including crisis protocols for violent threats;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD26AFD0CE6884F889643119EA94C66A1"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges periodic public reporting with standardized transparency metrics, such as prevalence, removal, recurrence, and visibility reduction, by AI platforms on the prevalence of antisemitic content or abuses of their platform to generate and amplify antisemitism, mitigation efficacy, and significant model or policy changes affecting safety outcomes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE535DE0D1D0F47DBB69F27FD8AB75BB7"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms that measures to address antisemitism on AI platforms must be consistent with the Constitution, protect civil liberties, due process, and privacy, and avoid discriminatory or overbroad enforcement; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0D0B59BEB634E918C66994BC646BD4F"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon all stakeholders to ensure the safety and dignity of Jewish individuals and communities, and to support innovation in AI that advance human rights, safety, and democratic values.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

