<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H28CF6340209F453295AAE16A3C13F8C6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6562 IH: United States Development Finance Corporation Effectiveness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6562</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 to provide for increased effectiveness.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3DBF6D1E1E3B40D085C215C4BCA6648A"><section id="H96FB129BDE4849FF92737C93368C969F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Development Finance Corporation Effectiveness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFEC0D389BDC44175A00E6079ED0A7650"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1443 of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9653">22 U.S.C. 9653</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB09752F3B32A4784BD7DE996DBA3CCE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HB6ED3E07227A4A9C9664D71A8AA59442"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D5FB644F1954E3C8CD9305D28093547"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD5AF81249F54CCD9F7310F6A206662D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H39249B7AE4244F1295EDFE81DFA3A7E8" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H11386F8B262947399C62CE92D6B51177"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States strategic, foreign policy, and development objectives advanced through projects supported by the Corporation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DEB9B9941B945E8A3D8773C874A5137"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the health of the Corporation’s portfolio, including an annual overview of funds committed, funds disbursed, default and recovery rates, capital mobilized, equity investments’ year on year returns, and any difference between how investments were modeled at commitment and how they ultimately performed, to include a narrative explanation explaining any changes.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54B978E0EBD94EABA671BEF69D5B7BD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H816E3B5A0E1B4241BDAC494914B93E8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking subparagraphs (A) and (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H20A3603E52DE488E822B74B33AB4E948" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HC83783A03B35429F8168D627DAA47399"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the desired development impact and strategic outcomes for projects, and whether or not the Corporation is meeting the associated metrics, goals, and development objectives, including, to the extent practicable, in the years after conclusion of projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE7B41170C1F4A8FB238564DE0FC0563"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the Corporation’s support for projects that focus on achieving strategic outcomes are achieving such strategic objectives of such investments over the duration of the support and lasting after the Corporation’s support is completed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C43C47157F4C0DAF43E4D10D865704"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the value of private sector assets brought to bear relative to the amount of support provided by the Corporation and the value of any other public sector support;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2422874A6DC840A88EC65B181913EC98"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the total private capital projected to be mobilized by projects supported by the Corporation during that year, including an analysis of the lenders and investors involved and investment instruments used;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EF22D26E07C447086F74B7924127F0D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total private capital actually mobilized by projects supported by the Corporation that were fully funded by the end of that year, including—</text><clause id="H0E860284190C43CDAABA38EB201B05EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an analysis of the lenders and investors involved and investment instruments used; and</text></clause><clause id="HFF490D51320644299FA48BE6572738D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a comparison with the private capital projected to be mobilized for the projects described in this paragraph;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC07C980BB287473FB44069B506E10D0F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a breakdown of—</text><clause id="HF26395967A35405691A3C5EDBA43E8C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount and percentage of Corporation support provided to less developed countries, advancing income countries, and high-income countries in the previous fiscal year; and</text></clause><clause id="H33257AC795B3455C9F9A052C5B5DC7F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount and percentage of Corporation support provided to less developed countries, advancing income countries, and high-income countries averaged over the last 5 fiscal years;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD624E6B75174081B687BE7FE312D3A7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a breakdown of the aggregate amounts and percentage of the maximum contingent liability of the Corporation authorized to be outstanding pursuant to section 1433 in less developed countries, advancing income countries, and high-income countries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD5BF2EBB492474AA5F1E3FC61D50F80"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the risk appetite of the Corporation to undertake projects in less developed countries and in sectors that are critical to development but less likely to deliver substantial financial returns; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E74C3C4987A48BB95E9CA322FD8AADE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>efforts by the Chief Executive Officer to incentivize calculated risk-taking by transaction teams, including through the conduct of development performance reviews and provision of development performance rewards;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28486F5AF3984BEDBF197A18BA3BE5AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB069D176D0864B8BAC3E79C636C49CF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87B963BC35234513BFEDC8FE825570BF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H9B6AEA2D79E94F03B4274CEFE551F772" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H3B8472FD186F46F5B2FB0F5BC1CF5CC8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, recommendations for measures that could enhance the strategic goals of projects to adapt to changing circumstances; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HCAED45983E27463EA193DD5F1BEBC6E9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Publicly available project information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1444 of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9654">22 U.S.C. 9654</external-xref>) is amended in paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H2575E9A2B1924D908DFF8B9EE99D8603" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H304BCA7EF93A4AF3AFA7B01D184BA780"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintain a user-friendly, publicly available, machine-readable database with detailed project-level information, as appropriate and to the extent practicable, including a description of the support provided by the Corporation under title II, which shall include, to the greatest extent feasible for each project—</text><subparagraph id="H5DD59D543C4A434B99387A50A45598F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the information included in the report to Congress under section 1443;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF125DA05F1C94A5B8BB8F182B05E2CC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>project-level performance metrics; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7089C7FDBD534F0D95C3054ECBA55708"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the development impact of the project, including anticipated impact prior to initiation of the project and assessed impact during and after the completion of the project; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

