<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H467B072662A8406E814E4350E09E07EC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8867 IH: Planning for Long-term Aging Needs Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8867</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260515">May 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and implement, as part of the National Clearinghouse for Long-Term Care Information, a public education initiative on the need for individuals to plan for their long-term care, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H54CA003A2E7949FA90BA7717170457A9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6ACFC5FA1ADF41F6B159BFAAA3388695" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Planning for Long-term Aging Needs Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PLAN Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9928192284254DAABFBF99C3F7E73D7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Long-term care public education initiative</header> <subsection id="HB040A6A4570843099B8BD36CFA4D07E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Clearinghouse for Long-Term Care Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6021(d) of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396p">42 U.S.C. 1396p</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7408CC8B22194734961FF125F35014D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H346E91329C4149B59BEEC0A10A040923"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H058BADDE72034E93A3C5264FF67168EB"> 
<paragraph id="H1434F0C08EB84B8EBAB98B385784D629"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Long-term care public education initiative</header> 
<subparagraph id="H184956DC2E8F4C108C45FAA8F3749F8D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As part of the National Clearinghouse for Long-Term Care Information, the Secretary shall develop and implement a public education initiative on the need for individuals to plan for their long-term care (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>initiative</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H136557443F7D42B4858A1C565EBA0223"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the initiative shall be—</text> 
<clause id="H0CDC42E3E1CF449A86F7796E591DFDEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to educate the public, including adults of working age (including individuals with disabilities), about the need to plan for future long-term care needs during retirement;</text></clause> <clause id="H301EA3241C244706B1A3E1010168502D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to ensure the public has accurate, objective information about their long-term care risks and care options, including home- and community-based services and institutional care;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2E707EA505D947A2BB05B6D35C770B01"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to provide objective and accessible resources to help the public evaluate financial, housing, caregiving, and service-related planning options related to long-term care, including advance planning before retirement age, information on long-term care partnership programs, and available Federal and State resources; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6F499F9AA4FF48799925C87EB361E62E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to make these resources accessible for family caregivers who may be helping a loved one plan for long-term care needs.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06B4CBD357AD46B7A78C050449F268C8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The initiative shall include—</text> <clause id="H79BC3426BF44488D8D501930804BAEFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">traditional media outreach through television, radio, digital platforms, and print materials;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF0D7E3365AF04A4084B35454DCF6A703"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">digital outreach, including social media outreach, using diverse engagement strategies that may include short- and long-form videos, interactive online resources, livestreamed discussions, infographics, visual storytelling, case studies of individuals with lived long-term care experiences, and other resources;</text></clause> <clause id="HD53121DCBD6744CCB6ADDED4D6B1AC52"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>community-based education programs delivered through partnerships with—</text> 
<subclause id="H7F9761E312DC4D12963782DC12546F23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>State governors, State and local elected representatives, and State and local government agencies;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2DEFF887E6444B0083C4D620E36D9160"><enum>(II)</enum><text>area agencies on aging, aging and disability resource centers, centers for independent living, State units on aging, State councils on developmental disabilities, and caregiver support organizations and resource centers;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD935BD65F75B4CE58440145B269ABDD2"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other Federal agencies, as necessary; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB62CA71FB894490C9DB148930E390847"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>other external partners, such as—</text> 
<item id="H7C0BCBCFD7F542159677FE9EC9F6B6E7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>healthcare providers, employers, insurers, financial advisors, and trade associations;</text></item> <item id="H2B50CAE1850A4FCDA55F2D8AE4AC7ED9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>community organizations, nonprofit organizations, and universities; and</text></item> 
<item id="H803A294971C7428293BF136611BE66D7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>non-traditional messengers, such as social media influencers and community leaders;</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA073F579064E4312AC9E56BD4D2D6537"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>linguistically accessible materials for different populations;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA9A39407735846E3A3FDFC206F4C5474"><enum>(v)</enum><text>online resources and planning tools accessible to individuals with disabilities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H29E51FF16FDF4752A858C4D654A302A4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>targeted outreach to populations at higher risk for long-term care financing shortfalls, such as low- to middle-income individuals who cannot access Medicaid but are unable to self-finance long-term care.</text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25F1011463D448C7A128BFC8CAD5D69F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish partnerships, including funding partnerships, with State and local governments, private sector stakeholders, and nonprofit organizations for the purpose of enhancing the reach and effectiveness of the initiative.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H447C91D3E0854519B5A73699F99F6EAF"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header> <clause id="H1D4BDE7E41D9420CA94C81D20B1FB179"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of the PLAN Act of 2026, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report containing a plan developed by the Secretary for implementation of the initiative, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H4A9D6B0DAE7A467986808148AB089476"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performance metrics;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE6D89DA74DA04466ABA065C63031502A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>target populations;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC672D9001F5649C09B29E13E1A560FDF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>anticipated outcomes;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD99BC3E7D25B40F896DFFD2470CCF7C5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of prior Federal and State public education efforts related to long-term care planning, including the Own Your Future Long-Term Care Awareness Campaign, and an assessment of how lessons learned from prior efforts should inform and improve the design and implementation of the initiative; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H88CA12590D004DF7806B329FEC9EA372"><enum>(V)</enum><text>opportunities to integrate long-term care education materials into Federal initiatives and communications to the public, such as retirement planning materials, outreach to new parents, financial literacy efforts, and web-based materials from government agencies, such as the Social Security Administration and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE2364AAD804243F084922D4B0E983CC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of transmission of the report under clause (i), and annually thereafter during the period of the initiative, the Secretary shall transmit to Congress a report on the progress made by the Secretary in implementing the initiative during the prior year, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H966D541E6F064EF7A4C42EAD6FBDED98"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data on the number of individuals reached by the initiative;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1AC96F87FAAA4981A4479BA43B4490BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on changes in the level of public awareness regarding the need to plan for long-term care;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H512A0E86F9EC4854A3109BE0776B0E03"><enum>(III)</enum><text>evidence of increased long-term care planning behaviors among target populations; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD32F2657FB2749AA8E5BAFE3848A783B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for improving the initiative in future years, including opportunities to enhance outreach for, partnerships for, and public awareness of long-term care planning.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1724B14A705C4D63B06C036EE4E7F622" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts appropriated to carry out section 411 of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3032">42 U.S.C. 3032</external-xref>) shall be available for conducting the activities under this paragraph.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1C421C544AC4A269CB6C6D0CCF3A7FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorization under Older Americans Act of 1965</header><text>Section 411(a)(9) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3032">42 U.S.C. 3032(a)(9)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7CD2B6D0A33747A0AEBBAAAF6C42B086"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1A6125A56B54C9CBF1B6C95910E8870"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3A4052023134F288E6234123968509C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD3D7AD8E5775464BA3B62C1571F6B219" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HF4A8044B29DE41869EF8F3B17B1C3649"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities to develop and implement the long-term care public education initiative authorized under paragraph (3) of section 6021(d) of the Deficit Reduction Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396p">42 U.S.C. 1396p</external-xref> note);</text> </subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

