<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H89EB7020D9074A4891BBE004E7EC12D4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 137 IH: Commending Sail250® for its advancement of goodwill among nations, its dedication to continuing the legacy of commemorating the history of the United States, and its effort to educate the next generation of Americans about the Nation’s maritime heritage.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 137</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending Sail250® for its advancement of goodwill among nations, its dedication to continuing the legacy of commemorating the history of the United States, and its effort to educate the next generation of Americans about the Nation’s maritime heritage.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Sail250® is dedicated to advancing the commemoration of the historic role that maritime services played during the American Revolution by hosting signature events in several port cities of the United States, including New Orleans, Norfolk, Baltimore, the Port of New York and New Jersey, and Boston;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Sail250® and its predecessors have worked in partnership with every American President since President John F. Kennedy to host the international tall ship fleets in brotherhood and sisterhood of the sea;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Sail250® builds on the great tradition of celebrating major milestones in United States history with gatherings of the world’s official tall ships, and will continue this great tradition with a gathering of ships in the five Sail250 Consortium ports to celebrate the United States of America’s 250th anniversary of independence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President has endorsed the Sail250® vision of gathering the tall ships of the world to mark America’s semiquincentennial, just as Presidents Kennedy, Ford, Reagan, Bush, Clinton, and Obama have endorsed the previous international tall ship gatherings to mark American milestones;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Port of New York and New Jersey will host the grandest international tall ship parade in American history and, in partnership with the United States Navy, will host an International Naval Review on July 4, 2026, to mark the Nation’s 250th anniversary of independence; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Sail250® promises to be the largest gathering in history of tall ships, naval, Coast Guard, and other vessels like those that have sailed the oceans for centuries: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0956AE480BE147C198090F97E823E915"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD1D3A6FF0BD24386874B93F51F1DEACA"><enum/><text>That—</text><paragraph id="H38AD4573577146C9A206CFE8D87ADBAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sail250® is commended for its advancement of goodwill among nations, its continuing commemoration of the history of the United States of America, and its commitment to promoting America’s rich maritime heritage and history;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H546E4168C8B64896A0370B5058F74676"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>all Americans and citizens of nations around the world are encouraged to join in the celebration of the 250th birthday of the United States of America and the international camaraderie that Sail250® and the International Naval Review will foster; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H5C9CFDAF75C84A49A0145CDEB93FD4B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sail250® is encouraged to continue promoting the naval heritage of the United States of America and the international tall ship community by organizing and participating in tall ship events such as Sail250®.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

