<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3FBDF407074E40DAA54628AA4AEF68A6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8513 IH: Providing Resources and Oversight to Ensure Confidentiality of Those who serve Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8513</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to disseminate guidance regarding certain best practices relating to the handling of personally identifiable information, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB925B664F99844CC8866EC923FB7C10F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA6CB1ABA0BC24848950AA01DFF514C08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Resources and Oversight to Ensure Confidentiality of Those who serve Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROTECT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H1D88DBA492DE49ED9012FF65F61E9EFC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Dissemination of DHS guidance regarding certain best practices relating to the handling of personally identifiable information</header> 
<subsection id="HD8B757FF7A5E44EF8B2518AD86375D41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and quadrennially thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall disseminate to Federal, State, and local government agencies and appropriate private sector entities guidance regarding best practices regarding the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC225F9C407304791848AD5771B0FB78B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The handling by such agencies and entities of personally identifiable information of officers, officials, employees, and contractors of such agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB965D782271144CE98D7C84168C361D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Actions such officers, officials, and employees can take to ensure their safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4F960A8EC56947688102B3C9F744D1AF" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>personally identifiable information</quote> means any information that permits the identity of an individual to be directly or indirectly inferred, including any other information that is linked or linkable to such individual, regardless of whether such individual is a United States citizen, lawful permanent resident, or visitor to the United States.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

