<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-NEW25898-H2Y-43-VRK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 420 ATS: Supporting the designation of September 19, 2025, as “National Concussion Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 420</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250929">September 29, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of September 19, 2025, as <quote>National Concussion Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas mild traumatic brain injury, otherwise known as a concussion, is an important health concern for children, teens, and adults;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to information from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention—</text><paragraph id="id69fead82a7a54980b22e7be31670375e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there are as many as 1,600,000 to 3,800,000 sports-related concussions annually;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id51de54f404714b068daeed9b1d2849a4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as many as 5,300,000 individuals live with the long-term effects of a traumatic brain injury;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id84ab874c9f654e3d9cbafae4f2b8ff56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>between 2010 and 2016, an estimated 2,000,000 children under age 18 visited an emergency department because of a traumatic brain injury sustained during sports- or recreation-related activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id622e7c0f08b84aacb7237b059931c959"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in 2023, there were an estimated 69,000 fatalities related to traumatic brain injuries;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idd213557c9dc84b37901bef6155707fef"><enum>(5)</enum><text>each year an estimated 283,000 children seek care in emergency departments in the United States for a sports- or recreation-related traumatic brain injury, with traumatic brain injuries sustained in contact sports accounting for approximately 45 percent of those visits;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id771c1f18772f4e73b7b5fcdb03b1ea6e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>7 in 10 emergency department visits for sports- or recreation-related traumatic brain injury are for children ages 17 and younger;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida49a185d041d4a1586b33b5327cce28a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>research suggests that many children with a traumatic brain injury do not seek care in emergency departments or do not seek care at all, resulting in a significant underestimate of prevalence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7D44E80932CE457880BB256E2B13549F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>approximately 15 percent of all high school students in the United States self-reported 1 or more sports- or recreation-related concussions within the preceding 12 months;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the seriousness of concussions should not be minimized in athletics, and return-to-play and return-to-learn protocols can help ensure recovery;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas concussions can affect physical, mental, and social health, and a greater awareness and understanding of proper diagnosis and management of concussions is critical to improved outcomes; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Senate can raise awareness about concussions among the medical community and the public: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id085e6b05b07d4f25a8886808b0b651d7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of September 19, 2025, as <quote>National Concussion Awareness Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcbb197a668c142e592c4f13d63d6bd3e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that mild traumatic brain injury, otherwise known as a concussion, is an important health concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id785e4bf29de046d09fa82392a99a65eb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commends the organizations and individuals that raise awareness about mild traumatic brain injury;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95e1ef6e4d2745fca27f3b7dbe2af12b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages Federal, State, and local policymakers to work together—</text><subparagraph id="id9e7f45185a674779824e6d989f56f259"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to raise awareness about the effects of concussions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a9f728b8dda4bd787e1966a767c237f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve the understanding of proper diagnosis and management of concussions; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2e4aff65614c4473bf03d311c8351b1a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages further research and prevention efforts to ensure that fewer individuals experience the most adverse effects of mild traumatic brain injury. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

