<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H648BEA28984C4AF28E6289AE8B0C56C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7502 IH: Recycled Materials Attribution Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7502</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit a person from making a misleading recycled content claim in advertising, marketing, selling, or offering for sale a product to a consumer, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0610943D165B4B7D86C3F87CDAAA44A1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5AE144CED52548F79D83DEE0890419FA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H4841798E5E2A42079FFB8D7B64E482BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recycled Materials Attribution Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7E9306E5821442498A6640775809DD77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H5AE144CED52548F79D83DEE0890419FA" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H214138124B6D4BF9A9CF080C6EEDE508" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7EAA4A73FFE94ED6A7D443B161C4DF68" level="section">Sec. 3. Recognition of mass balance accounting for recycled content claims.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2998F5DC48A94DCA98F70F0EFA8C1F11" level="section">Sec. 4. Recycled content claims.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H47DEB3F2466D462D98C477E4C8253D79" level="section">Sec. 5. Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDC013268A60A46108746A616EBA33494" level="section">Sec. 6. Preemption.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H493F613B5457498FB39F0AA6F3F28309" level="section">Sec. 7. Savings provision.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H214138124B6D4BF9A9CF080C6EEDE508"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HBD034DF6A89F4FDF9D4538B027B0A536"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9EEC97683C44223AE47695B67BE6028"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Competent and reliable scientific evidence</header><text>The term <term>competent and reliable scientific evidence</term> means any test, analysis, research, or study that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4284F6658C894F8EAA442A727C258522"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been conducted and evaluated in an objective manner by an expert in the relevant field;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46471C6A2A814E70B4105C406B3D32D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is generally accepted in the profession to yield accurate and reliable results; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DF40D4836AB4A9CB69C71EDB92EA866"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is sufficient in quality and quantity based on standards generally accepted in the relevant scientific fields to substantiate that a representation is true when considered in light of the entire body of relevant scientific evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F601046261E4C04B84686703A4B202C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mass balance accounting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mass balance accounting</term> means a valid chain-of-custody methodology that allows a manufacturing supply chain—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF158AA05C124EBFAA78C2D515DDFC0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to mix or co-process alternative feedstocks, including pre-consumer material and post-consumer material, with conventional feedstocks; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF92C66CE691F44DEA30E3B00FC20BC72"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allocate the mass of such alternative feedstocks to final products on the basis of documented inputs and outputs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0F2653948774C50851FDA19E2BCF010"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Post-consumer material</header><text>The term <term>post-consumer material</term> means material generated by a household or a commercial, industrial, or institutional facility as an end user of the product, including through returns of materials from the distribution chain.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37B3818966BD4F5E876E25A705DB4EFE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Pre-consumer material</header><text>The term <term>pre-consumer material</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H38EE659D43B94A218049BC0786D848D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means material diverted during a manufacturing process and not used and commercialized; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15333DF9A96549B49EDC374C475B6503"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include re-used material, including rework, regrind, and scrap, generated in a given process and capable of being reclaimed within such process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DF6B8C9EB8845C8B17B74BCED9FCF47"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recycled</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recycled</term> means a material that has been processed through recycling.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD1B68B8FB154992B3D1818D9DB1CB93"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Recycled content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recycled content</term> means the quantity of pre-consumer materials and post-consumer materials recovered or otherwise diverted from the waste stream through recycling, for use in the production of a new, salable product.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E76117AAB9848B7B0548B281FDE8681"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Recycled content claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recycled content claim</term> includes any claim or representation regarding the recycled nature of a product or material, including <quote>recycled content</quote>, <quote>recycled plastics</quote>, <quote>recycled materials</quote>, and similar terminology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72D41052F9CE42C79A5C8B505C12C29F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Recycling</header> 
<subparagraph id="H63D82CDFAA164FEBAB6634E646CB83BA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>recycling</term> means any process by which a material recovered or otherwise diverted from the waste stream, either during the manufacturing process (in the case of pre-consumer material) or after consumer use (in the case of post-consumer material), is reprocessed and converted into a raw material for the manufacturing of a new, salable product.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9482AB8753B5491FB6A2742F68727C76"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>recycling</term> includes the following:</text> 
<clause id="H17AB49A5890A43A19416071F52723E17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Mechanical recycling, in which a material is collected, sorted, cleaned, and reprocessed (without significantly altering the chemical structure of the material) for use in manufacturing products.</text></clause> <clause id="H879E413F77394912832516454EB9D1B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Non-mechanical recycling, in which a material is collected, sorted, cleaned, and transformed through technology that alters the chemical structure of the material and that produces an output used to manufacture products (excluding a waste-to-energy facility in which such a material is used primarily to generate process heat or electricity).</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H602DDEE8699A48EEB653385817BCFF95"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Third-party certification</header><text><quote>Third Party Certification</quote> means a written determination, verification, or attestation that a product, material, process, service, or entity meets specified standards, criteria, or requirements, issued by an independent organization that:</text> <subparagraph id="H1F0135CA919F4411B7F5FBCC756EFB34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not owned, controlled by, or under common control with the person or entity seeking certification;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27DD1FDF24B64DFDBA3C7B5476651A76"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not design, manufacture, sell, distribute, or market the product or material being certified;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD98BB7BD658D4A43881C9130051931E4"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>conducts its certification activities in accordance with objectivity, impartiality, and professional competence; and</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45E7DE2C27D743959C1B19365FE63B2D">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>does not have financial, commercial, or organizational interest that could compromise its independence or impartiality with respect to the certified product, material, or entity; and</text>
                </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18C71602A22745E0AC906341F2E7E726"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Third-party certification system</header><text>For the purposes of this Act, the term <quote>third-party certification system</quote> means an independently administered system that—</text> <subparagraph id="H8DED2FEE2C484502B525C40300259052"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishes a set of rules governing the implementation of mass balance accounting approaches; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE19D81EB89A74939BC49C1BC70ADDCC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides independent certification confirming that—</text> <clause id="H6CF6C72E95804E098851AC36681393D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the recycled content attributed to a product does not exceed the quantity by weight of recovered materials introduced into the manufacturing supply chain (accounting for process losses);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H62600174D9264A87ABC72FBF3EC8017C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an auditable chain-of-custody accounting methodology was applied that enables the attribution of the mass of inputs to 1 or more outputs in accordance with the rules of the system; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAAFDC2678F094AEEB6AF8E6590F9A4DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total mass of alternative feedstocks, including pre-consumer material and post-consumer material, introduced into the manufacturing supply chain has been quantified and appropriately allocated to final products.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7EAA4A73FFE94ED6A7D443B161C4DF68"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recognition of mass balance accounting for recycled content claims</header> 
<subsection id="H740518B820884C6FA476FC949B454CA6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recognition of mass balance accounting for recycled content claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mass balance accounting shall be an acceptable method for substantiating recycled content claims and analogous claims if the use of mass balance accounting complies with the requirements of a third-party certification system.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H2998F5DC48A94DCA98F70F0EFA8C1F11"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recycled content claims</header> <subsection id="H12A2841CB0C14A6CBA662CEE4F71B59A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph id="HA794A87F51C74722A1F5994AFDF33C6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A person may not advertise, market, sell, or offer for sale a product to a consumer using a misleading recycled content claim.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DE1837BE3174A0D99FF6CB8DF2F25B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Fuels produced and sold as an end product may not be marketed as <quote>recycled content</quote> under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE46CCA82484A4FFC8477353AFA4A2E27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header> <paragraph id="H1A9190C34DEE4F69991BED1652BFA2EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Update to green guides</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall update the Guides for the Use of Environmental Marketing Claims issued by the Federal Trade Commission (part 260 of title 16, Code of Federal Regulations) (commonly known as the <quote>Green Guides</quote>), to ensure that the Green Guides are consistent with and reflect the definitions, standards, and authorizations established under this Act, including the authorization to substantiate recycled content claims through mass balance accounting.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H264FE7BC97574F11A57B5D1D7F7549DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional guidance</header><text>The Commission shall issue guidance that establishes the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HBF21F768C2084154927FFD302830044D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Mass balance accounting as an acceptable method for substantiating a recycled content claim, if—</text> 
<clause id="H1F2D55A6906E46F18C3D6CF03E02E393"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of mass balance accounting complies with the requirements of a third-party certification system; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC60F6329548B4B6EB324634747621C07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any representation about mass balance accounting with respect to a recycled content claim is based on competent and reliable scientific evidence and presented in a manner that is not misleading.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54DA4AC6D4384B9CA6C4E49E2FDD377D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A clear and consistent framework with respect to a recycled content claim, establishing that a person can advertise, market, sell, or offer for sale a product using an accurate recycled content claim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4596D0B514149AE80A63A4204C95D08"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header> <subparagraph id="H12384315FF06488D84A47DCD3BE482D4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No conferring of rights or binding effect</header><text>Any guidance issued by the Commission with respect to this section shall not confer any rights on any person nor shall such guidance operate to bind the Commission or any person to the approach recommended in such guidance.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H125262C226784D8E82A23A6B51F363EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Basis of enforcement actions</header><text>In any enforcement action brought pursuant to this Act, the Commission shall allege a specific violation of a provision of this Act. The Commission may not base an enforcement action on, or execute a consent order based on, practices that are alleged to be inconsistent with any such guidelines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H47DEB3F2466D462D98C477E4C8253D79"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> <subsection id="HB50CCE484A7644F48315CC8EB329EA0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of section 4(a) shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H877348CC018F4EFDB8558153AA3614C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce section 4(a) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section, and any person who violates section 4(a) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDC013268A60A46108746A616EBA33494"><enum>6.</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No State, or political subdivision of a State, may maintain, enforce, prescribe, or continue in effect any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law that relates to the prohibition and enforcement provisions of this Act.</text> </section> 
<section id="H493F613B5457498FB39F0AA6F3F28309"><enum>7.</enum><header>Savings provision</header> 
<subsection id="H9BC93BFE1A13460A936883CDAFF0D012">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
 <text>If any provision of this Act, or the application of that provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, or the application of that provision to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is held invalid, is not affected thereby.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF34AA040813F46FF8AB4A64EC9D4D22D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
 <text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to modify, limit, or supersede any other Federal laws or regulations except to the extent expressly provided. The provisions herein establish uniform Federal standards for recycled content claims, recycling claims, recyclability claims, and analogous claims, and apply solely to the matters expressly addressed in this Act.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

