<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HD676BDFC073F43ACB106BB924341BA9D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2347 EH: Survivor Justice Tax Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2347</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income any damages, other than punitive damages, received on account of any sexual acts or sexual contact.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HBE9D067815CB455386076C7347853A81">
<section id="HF8BC05332476415D894F6D0894899438" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Survivor Justice Tax Prevention Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H00396EF9BFBC4955BDA521A33E2D8747"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income of any damages, other than punitive damages, received on account of sexual acts or sexual contact</header> <subsection id="HC0FFF36441E9488B856B03D96552B017"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/104">Section 104(a)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>on account of personal physical injuries or physical sickness;</quote> and inserting</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7250596E26B24CAEA494923CDD6259B5" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>on account of—</text> <subparagraph id="H380D5A5DD72A40E38291F062CD2D32D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">personal physical injuries or physical sickness, or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA3D7A21600E9465F91B5C0CEF3A0E334"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any sexual act (as defined in paragraph (2) of section 2246 of title 18, United States Code, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph) or sexual contact (as defined in paragraph (3) of such section, as so in effect), whether or not there are medical records or observable injuries of such act or contact;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H611370B0946249609FD6FE262BE0A5DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Burden of proof with respect to whether damages are on account of sexual act or sexual contact</header><text>Section 104 of such Code is amended by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e) and by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H72A2AC474371459B9EFE9F602AF6571B" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H6F944BA70AAE42EBBD275BFC868C83AB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Burden of proof with respect to whether damages are on account of sexual act or sexual contact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(2), if a decision or agreement states that any damages received therefrom are on account of a sexual act or sexual contact referred to in subsection (a)(2)(B)—</text> <paragraph id="HDCE4C6E1928D4EBB8BD09E0A84F3878F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such statement shall be treated as credible evidence that such damages are so on account for purposes of section 7491(a), and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H78E962C3E2F7465CAE4624A447B77237"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the taxpayer shall be treated as having met the requirements of section 7491(a)(2) with respect to the issue of whether such damages are so on account.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD5F57BC710B249A58292052F1C02D3A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header> <paragraph id="HF2500179966A4B248379DB6D4E5137B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts received pursuant to decisions made, and agreements entered into, after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD67AD7C0C26844B2A8425333B81CFBFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for decisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), a decision shall be treated as made after the date of the enactment of this Act if the first payment pursuant to such decision is received after such date.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H667366742F7745139A03F234D2FD416A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for agreements</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), an agreement shall not be treated as entered into after the date of the enactment of this Act if such agreement replaces, supersedes, or revises an agreement entered into on or before such date.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H751B249B6CA2486094863F4E78D7915F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No inference with respect to effect of medical records or observable injuries on determinations with respect to personal physical injuries or physical sickness</header><text>No inference may be drawn from the amendment made by subsection (a) (or from <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/104">section 104(a)(2)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by subsection (a)) with respect to whether the term <term>personal physical injuries or physical sickness</term> as used in section 104(a)(2) of such Code includes injuries or sickness with respect to which there are no medical records or observable injuries.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCB4389B4881B471B9FAA3DBBC27D2A71"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Promotion of public awareness of exclusion</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), in consultation with the Department of Justice Office on Violence Against Women and other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a program to promote public awareness of the exclusion from gross income provided by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/104">section 104(a)(2)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by this section.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260427" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 27, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


