<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26685-91Y-6Y-GTV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4270 IS: Nicholas Douglas Quets United States-Mexico Rapid Response for Victims of Crime Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the establishment of a binational rapid response protocol for serious crimes committed against United States citizens in Mexico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nicholas Douglas Quets United States-Mexico Rapid Response for Victims of Crime Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id76a44608742e4de9be109a43bba52d0e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc90987c9acc845b085cf11658863a5d0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On October 18, 2024, while traveling in the Mexican state of Sonora near Puerto Peñasco, Nicholas Quets was targeted by armed criminals associated with the Sinaloa Cartel and the 31-year-old American was tragically shot and killed in a violent attack.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id6a0e51264bb647e7a2a55ac6c8f55a42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The brutal murder of Nicholas Quets reflects the ongoing threat posed by transnational criminal organizations and cartel violence in the region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9afb1421620b4bc89d534115fddb5410"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The violence perpetrated by drug cartels and other criminal organizations endangers innocent civilians, undermines the rule of law, and threatens the safety of United States citizens traveling abroad.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5520e1f2ca0d40139ff3a49314a68ff9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Binational coordination in investigations like that of Nicholas Quets’ death can often be delayed or incomplete, which may deny the administration of justice for victims and their families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0fc319984e64728b1a2c03da0de4bd0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Each year, millions of United States citizens travel to Mexico for tourism, work, and family purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id348382c86f2d41f0b447b0c795aae416"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In certain cases involving serious crimes, including homicide, kidnapping, and organized criminal violence, delays or gaps in coordination between authorities may hinder investigations and the delivery of justice for victims and their families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id268b3c1ac4e14c4fb6e8dd606028c798"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Enhanced binational coordination, communication, and investigative cooperation is essential to ensure effective responses to serious crimes involving United States citizens in Mexico.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72883075c8994c0eb9986f0f2a603369"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that a robust, binational rapid response protocol is necessary to ensure efficient communication and coordination between United States and Mexican authorities when responding to serious crimes involving United States citizens in Mexico.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id79f8a2fbe16f4b26a7a68eaa2c10eee9"><enum>4.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id0e0a49e527f04436b1fc719affa4abf7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c4ab134c3e2425aa63a9a620810d189"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idece279eb34ac4736b194c75fd2ac7bd9">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b63ef5d8b82436681f835b02cde908f">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7ec069710fa4a47ab8ee247446c92c9">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id10b75e20af2a4606bfed5b874f5cc814"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Serious crimes</header><text>The term <term>serious crimes</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="id78caf2eac7aa445fbb8963507063dc4d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>homicides and suspicious deaths;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23174dcffecc436d83af9457aebace68"><enum>(B)</enum><text>kidnappings and abductions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide4280319099b44b2bc97a3929cf30286"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disappearances;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae98e624a618442fa5613cfd18439200"><enum>(D)</enum><text>violent crimes involving, or suspected to be involving, organized criminal groups or cartels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfac66cf3af7940fe845b781e0352698d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other violent crimes designated by the Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="id3657d6fe9b3c484f87c3376cb57a72fb"><enum>5.</enum><header>Binational rapid response protocol</header><subsection id="id434e4c64244c4a78825de1be887b30e3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, shall engage with the Government of Mexico to negotiate and establish a binational rapid response protocol for serious crimes committed against United States citizens in Mexico (referred to in this section as the <quote>Protocol</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id1c0f07ad8eb448da9017ff1d4abfc6cb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Protocol shall aim to ensure timely coordination between United States and Mexican authorities in responding to and investigating serious crimes committed against United States citizens in Mexico.</text></subsection><subsection id="id31fde9631c2446178acf16a2cddfa795"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommended elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In negotiating the Protocol, the Secretary of State shall seek to include procedures that provide—</text><paragraph id="id7ef74072a31841aca550152df290aa2c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>mechanisms for the prompt notification of relevant United States and Mexican authorities when a serious crime involving a United States citizen occurs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c2083ab77a045d5b9234ee0951acb63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>secure and reliable communication channels between designated law enforcement and diplomatic authorities in both countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id071bbce0a59a43128f64a18c9b38d3d9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>procedures to ensure the timely securing of crime scenes and the protection of relevant physical evidence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9f4d9ecb9b546a78f89c312fe4514f8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>agreed-upon standards and procedures for preserving and documenting evidence in a manner that supports potential prosecutions in either country's jurisdiction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f73563e61a248f9aabce6cbf0427493"><enum>(5)</enum><text>procedures to facilitate the timely sharing of investigative leads, intelligence, and forensic information between United States and Mexican authorities, consistent with the laws of each country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd7dea7da088f44a0a7959ec8c9ed7b36"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the designation of appropriate points of contact within the Government of Mexico and procedures to facilitate requests for international extradition and timely coordination for extradition to United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id256014ae5abe43d5bd74abb28b5c691f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the designation of appropriate points of contact within relevant United States and Mexican agencies responsible for coordinating responses to incidents covered by the Protocol;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04759469d4f34693a154f0387ff16086"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the designation of a point of contact within the United States Government responsible for communicating with the victim or the victim’s family and providing timely updates regarding investigative developments and available assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5de318f998a945a5b9017b1c7f0149b3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>procedures for coordination between United States consular officials and Mexican authorities regarding support for victims and their families; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb47a376b6fb7466db13090e3249a4ba2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>opportunities for joint training, planning, or exercises to ensure effective implementation of the Protocol.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb1ff7b6f4f134afdbf40fbc0da952f93"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subsection id="id7d64f90a314d4ffbadcdb8c05184a3b6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the binational rapid response protocol described in section 5 is established, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes—</text><paragraph id="id2fbf4b9044bb43bb9a740b515d739108"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the progress made toward negotiating such protocol;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaff5690c24f74e58988868a0d38c5b24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the status of cooperation with the Government of Mexico relating to crimes against United States citizens while they are in Mexico; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8c396b2dae742f1b0d2949ee59413a5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any additional legislative or diplomatic steps the Secretary determines would improve coordination and accountability in such cases.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide8881336596c45c3a3d2eae172ed239e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the binational rapid response protocol described in section 5, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes—</text><paragraph id="id485fbca864e14ab8ad8b597fac753fc9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of the implementation of such protocol;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1367753e397b4b0b925f2ad4245e89c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>actions taken by United States and Mexican authorities under the protocol;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3fc32d01b4164da3ac7010b79b08a13b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which the protocol has improved coordination in covered cases; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcec23ddd56a7464a9dc2083275e83849"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations for improving the protocol.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id101c7125347f42b88d2ae08e501ef536"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc597522b32d40d6b52fc2a92cdd2f4b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit the sovereignty of the United States or of Mexico;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5633d155ccb445b4a8fa1ec901bd7625"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require the Government of Mexico to adopt investigative procedures inconsistent with existing Mexican law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4108fed8283542c582025f0004559648"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to alter the existing authorities of United States law enforcement or consular officials.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

