<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT26051-VHT-H2-6SD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3717 IS: Opportunities in Organic Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3717</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260128">January 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to expand the national organic certification cost-share program into a comprehensive organic program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Opportunities in Organic Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id4f2b614029094e5ba6e4b68f953eb38b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Opportunities in Organic program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10606 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6523">7 U.S.C. 6523</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd65692f61ac94231badb412dd973e1dd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">National organic certification cost-share</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Opportunities in organic</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2da5d3d9d41443f7bf0fdbf7ce1df56a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3bea84f638964e8781c890a6b36272a6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb157b8348b24936b7d06983f4195f8a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking the subsection designation and heading and all that follows through <quote>Secretary of Agriculture</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id20C21611AA8E4F06929A386E23650C2A" act-name=""><subsection id="idB0E747F817324584B86C466E697F2B29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaebb01bd11cd4f43879a3b65769b8f70"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting before subsection (b) (as so redesignated) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id0FEF60A467C740AEA1E5FE699BA8DC69" act-name=""><subsection id="idC0F551D305AB4EC4BED76F76DD31E1FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idE44D6CE21DCD49A4AD528CD98D6C7C02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certified organic farm; certified organic handling operation</header><text>The terms <term>certified organic farm</term> and <term>certified organic handling operation</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2103 of the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6502">7 U.S.C. 6502</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id668B164DFDB7498A938CE89BCD18E20D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>eligible nonprofit organization</term> means a nonprofit organization (as defined in section 1619(b) of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5801">7 U.S.C. 5801(b)</external-xref>)) that primarily serves at least 1 of the following:</text><subparagraph id="idED7F59FA8C204794924B5AD8EFABFE14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9BA6D4CEF9864A08BED995283CBD2B29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Organic producers and handlers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCD28F4F867764F49B48E75AED3AC462F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 or more vulnerable agricultural regions, such as farms near schools, childcare providers, residential areas, or sensitive ecosystems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3008bac16b574fbeafba4b7b6e4f0c3d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>1 or more under-resourced agricultural regions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAAA9DDD600E84BC8957E245148A620AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Smaller nonprofit organizations (as so defined) that primarily serve the entities or regions described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), or (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11f77ef4b99b423bab1f461eff43f2e2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National organic production program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national organic production program</term> means the national organic production program established under the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6501">7 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDD64D1D56A4D4F25AB0D1F88BCC07E11"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Organic</header><text>The term <term>organic</term> has the meaning given the term in section 205.2 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id914c9bc0b1514dfb8408e9275bfda66f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program</term> means the Opportunities in Organic program established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a874bd8ae3f4beebffc96603ff6a3f8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69ae9184629d4cb5a5c40e4e5ff75f00"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher; socially disadvantaged group</header><text>The terms <term>socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher</term> and <term>socially disadvantaged group</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 2501(a) of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2279">7 U.S.C. 2279(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC06B911335EE4F35BDE131213C8A1237"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transition to organic</header><text>The term <term>transition to organic</term> means the steps required to become a certified organic farm.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d0072f2481b4dadb5d1c60e3725eab1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (b) (as so redesignated)—</text><subparagraph id="id7d35b5ef8f974a498398d4377f0d9e61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a national organic certification cost-share program to assist</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6b8420d4c20f48349dbd61485d8de490"><text>a program, to be known as the <quote>Opportunities in Organic program</quote>—</text><paragraph id="id65ce7723f681474481f113c9d4df05fe"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assist</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb70b6cb2216444c291bb9d769976efcb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) (as so designated), by striking <quote>program established</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>program; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfce72349aafb4e8c9ea1a126c6757f01"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a687e24dd494e7db0211f5f6c812525"><paragraph id="id9a51a91e8b3142ee934af84e51c6666a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to provide support and technical assistance for transition to organic and organic management.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7761302787d64a958405899d0265b8ac"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) (as so redesignated) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id484b8845b9614d5abd773f71016bd1fc"><subsection id="ida5e19128314d4dfe8b7e97b5132c9439"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Federal organic certification cost-Share</header> <paragraph id="ide2beb7ee528a4994a159235585a4271f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary shall pay under this subsection the costs incurred by a producer or handler in obtaining certification under the national organic production program, as certified to and approved by the Secretary.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id82fce0f88bcc46d9be410f0af08519d9">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Maximum amount</header>
 <text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the maximum amount of a payment made to a producer or handler under this subsection shall be $1,500.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idd375a3c5811d4b9798109226e8f0973a">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>Ensuring affordability</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), the Secretary may make payments that exceed the maximum amount under that paragraph to ensure that organic certification costs are not a barrier to organic production, including payment to a producer or handler who is—</text>
              <subparagraph id="id134e079a57f14bd4854913ece204d42c">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>located in a region with disproportionately high certification costs, as determined by the Secretary; or</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id14753b53ef7946299ec3c24064875224">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a member of a socially disadvantaged group.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection><subsection id="id9a5abe50d87340e28bca498881c92874"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support for transition to organic and technical assistance</header><paragraph id="idff79be6806d94194853679018ef710e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transition and resilience funding</header><subparagraph id="id6897aa52e12e47a5abd0e7a3e9ae5e32"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award funding to eligible nonprofit organizations—</text><clause id="id33952f9474c64f43828255a7ecfbe408"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to build capacity to support transition to organic in accordance with subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="id76fe285f59aa47a2ae3b48e654d1e8eb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to support transition to organic in accordance with subparagraphs (C) and (D).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd753990ea21248ddb234bcf04457629a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Activities to build capacity</header><text>An eligible nonprofit organization that is awarded funding under this subparagraph may use the funding for staffing, materials, activities, and partnerships (including partnerships with eligible nonprofit organizations described in subsection (a)(2)(E)) that support transition to organic and resilience of certified organic farms, including—</text><clause id="id1dc6e17c3ce5464fbae128e7db7b758c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the recruitment of producers to begin transition to organic;</text></clause><clause id="id1b6eb3c5ba324cb2961413c4e88e120e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>translation and communication support, including development of materials to increase understanding of the practices and processes required to become certified as organic;</text></clause><clause id="id8fddaca3e9c5433197752ea400a2bed8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assistance with applications, compliance, recordkeeping, and other aspects of the organic certification process and the transition to organic;</text></clause><clause id="ide531bf2aa8c44bc48c79f2503ef5eba7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>financial, business, natural resource conservation, and farm planning;</text></clause><clause id="iddf131f9d6936448b96a669ff1bbcb9cf"><enum>(v)</enum><text>support for fair contracting;</text></clause><clause id="ide068b897835340e38ffc18e9fbc4156c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>technical assistance with organic management practices, such as soil health, nutrient management, pest management, and other practices, as determined appropriate by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="id18e319263c654cc2b3a96b34b8d54c18"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>by providing training on organic certification requirements and organic management to agricultural advisors and consultants, including agronomists, crop advisors, pest control advisors, extension agents, farm consultants, and other technical service providers, and agricultural industry entities, such as seed dealers, equipment suppliers, and input suppliers;</text></clause><clause id="ide3d7133e3e9a481e88eb2c24fc85dffd"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>by facilitating paid mentor-mentee relationships between organic producers and producers in transition to organic, including stipends for all participants and training to support effective mentorship;</text></clause><clause id="id07db805c8dbe40c2928396d8e54b55c0"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>by assisting producers with accessing resources and funding for programs associated with organic management, including conservation programs, risk management tools, and organic support and research programs;</text></clause><clause id="id30f41d1939ac4a59a50775b227fb8d3f"><enum>(x)</enum><text>by establishing or expanding cooperatives, organic grower groups, certified organic processing, storage, refrigeration, freezer, and distribution facilities and equipment, food hubs, food security programs, additional programs under the Indigenous Food Sovereignty Initiative of the Department of Agriculture, organic-compliant composting services, and other regional foodshed and supply chain infrastructure, such as infrastructure for granaries and meat processing;</text></clause><clause id="idd517a3e56b8d42478d2c599a7f5c2aa0"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>on-farm research, including monitoring biodiversity, monitoring air and water quality, measuring changes in soil organic carbon and indicators of soil health, developing regionally adapted seeds and breeds, and carrying out trials and documenting the effectiveness of holistic approaches to pest, weed, and disease control;</text></clause><clause id="idcaae6128f3a14f33b25107dbad2608d7"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>recruiting and training organic certification staff and inspectors, with an emphasis on expanding opportunities for socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers and increasing diversity in the certification process;</text></clause><clause id="id9edf8e92aff34844a8ab6d5e8e5c8a3f"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>increasing access to land for socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers and small and mid-sized farms and ranches and promoting long-term organic management (such as purchasing land for incubator projects, promoting and supporting lease-to-own contracts, resolving heirs property issues, and establishing easements that facilitate long-term organic stewardship);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddf71a8fe9db5411fad407e111c1d5ffc"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>supporting tenant farmers, including through leasing options that serve tenants and landlords long term;</text></clause><clause id="idc20422dd47454f6bbfa6cb95d0ef43c9"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>hosting or supporting regional conventions, conferences, farmer-led training sessions and programs, field days, teach-ins, and other educational opportunities focused on organic production; and</text></clause><clause id="id165b6cf26489431089ed0328a4856c13"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>establishing infrastructure for interfarmer skill sharing and exchanges, including virtual forums.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd9306a417306417d8e7f93877a115a65"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Producer transition and resilience funding</header><clause id="id902b5acce38f4dcc9ea1c73590b30d99"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible nonprofit organization that is awarded funding under this subparagraph may use the funding to provide transition and resilience funding to existing organic operations, socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers, or small or mid-sized farms or ranches.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03489818c1834e89a22bfe090acbf94f"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Term</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id937e73ae475047639cff7fc58582593e"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Funding provided under this subparagraph shall be for a term of 4 years.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id709e97946a9346a0827b90d4d412f954"><enum>(II)</enum><header>1-time funding</header><text>The Secretary may not renew funding provided to a recipient under this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idba11cd0fce1f4282a5f24169ce2c98b0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funding awarded under clause (i) may be used to offset the costs of and reduce barriers to becoming or expanding a certified organic farm, including—</text><subclause id="ide7493b2759d9492e845330428e81e4c2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>creating or expanding an organic system plan (as defined in section 205.2 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Opportunities in Organic Act</short-title>)), including—</text><item id="idc4c7ad1144c94e599e56e29e4b50216f"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>completing organic certification documents, planning, and recordkeeping; and</text></item><item id="id9dbb354ac313425996fd23d2fef7254a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>developing a conservation plan to address all natural resources, including soil health;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id5b67ce5d5ad046f7b1cbbb8f6c270d1a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>adopting, improving, or expanding organic management, including—</text><item id="idbd90026e3c4c4f3f818fea955211bacb"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>eliminating the use of synthetic pesticides, synthetic fertilizers, or antibiotics;</text></item><item id="id5460581d202e4ae2abb50e11d8c3bab0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the implementation of cover cropping, crop rotation, or rotational grazing;</text></item><item id="id653e37228c844ba5a3bfd620545b568f"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the production and use of compost and manure (including purchasing tools, supplies, or storage);</text></item><item id="idb76be99aab6c471c99889ee50a051007"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>sourcing or producing organic seed and feed;</text></item><item id="idd5c5c7e3ffc34a12b575e7196ebdf9fa"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>hedgerow and ecosystem enhancement planting and design;</text></item><item id="iddf3224e0eb4143cbad1a5993e09eef33"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>purchasing supplies for intercropping and polycropping or other specialized equipment for use in organic management; and</text></item><item id="id813ef172bd93473eadb1f5e660c64df1"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>supporting beneficial predators, pollinator habitats, erosion prevention, or watershed restoration;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id268f072aef5440abb03a7dca6c216eb0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>paying for costs associated with processing, storage, and distribution equipment and facilities;</text></subclause><subclause id="id710aa1f017cc46dba9cec7d0224e9b51"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>carrying out on-farm research to monitor and document the impacts of transition to organic, including in partnership with an institution of higher education or another entity;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide9a6f02c7ddb44c6ac353c081cc3ef21"><enum>(V)</enum><text>soil testing;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6ce2487073154070a31d68789acb294e"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>debt relief to improve access to capital and financial stability;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc5f8d14827cf4686a307e65c4072fae2"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>forming a cooperative or farmer-to-farmer network;</text></subclause><subclause id="iddbfba217646a4a5d9b87c3f1ab172165"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>providing training to become an organic inspector to expand revenue and regional inspection capacity;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide0278c0bd2e2406b98fec6de071e8ecc"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>overcoming barriers to land access, including payments to secure longer leases and costs associated with accessing land that has not been treated with materials prohibited for use on a certified organic farm or transitioning land to organic management;</text></subclause><subclause id="ided597ad01f8844d1a58fb3278a1012cd"><enum>(X)</enum><text>paying for labor costs, including costs associated with improvements to workplace safety, compensation, professional development, and staff training on transition to organic implementation;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0f96325d9ea44bd2805703afa4be13b4"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>improving food safety practices and obtaining related certifications;</text></subclause><subclause id="id515a8da3960b4c67b3791f06041af42c"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>providing or participating in organic agriculture educational opportunities;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0f0254e3dbab4a37a637356641351c03"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>providing compensation for foregone income during transition to organic due to short-term changes in yield and limited market options;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8cdab5955ec64ba8b37acd494f3f0c16"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text>construction or improvement of housing for apprentices, trainees, or volunteers or other on-farm infrastructure; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idc7249b6788a544a196d46bdb1caf1b28"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>financial, business, and farm planning.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id924840e61aaf43698e096f32912a0761"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Organic system plan</header><text>As a condition of receiving funding under this subparagraph to carry out any of the activities described in subclauses (II) through (XV) of clause (iii), an organic operation, socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher, or small or mid-sized farm or ranch shall be required to develop an organic system plan described in subclause (I) of that clause.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe10cd5f936c4f56895422f4f52938ac"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Organic supply chain funding</header><clause id="ida8db6fb119e64d729ab34c7960cd7d68"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible nonprofit organization that is awarded funding under this subparagraph may use the funding to support organic supply chain development, including by providing the funding to other entities to support organic supply chain development.</text></clause><clause id="id474f09472f8f466683b11e4bf1e0c44d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funding awarded under clause (i)—</text><subclause id="id418dc2aa0b0b4f6fa4850193277d7b9d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may be used to strengthen organic capacity or expand access to certified organic handling operations, including—</text><item id="id76d220757b464cc894e7be686c39e1e3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>constructing, expanding, or improving access to a certified organic handling operation;</text></item><item id="ida092e61ca5174a30b3fe1cf5a576cec5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>purchasing farm equipment, value added supplies, and other materials that improve market access; and</text></item><item id="idd3f95d73174349d2a36b20d692ca0845"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>pursuing organic certification for an existing handling operation; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id1c310863374f46bea8463a45b1c44cb6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be used to strengthen opportunities in organic capacity for socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers, small or mid-sized farms or ranches, vulnerable agricultural regions (such as farms near schools, childcare providers, residential areas, and sensitive ecosystems), or under-resourced agricultural regions.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98ddd76fee7f4c94b0d0006a2dc7b775"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Communications; meetings</header><text>An eligible nonprofit organization that receives funding under subparagraph (B), (C), or (D) shall—</text><clause id="ida847048d985a472791e9301b8d7fb0d9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communicate not less frequently than once per quarter with each other entity awarded funding pursuant to those subparagraphs—</text><subclause id="id52f52f034dd842f3a268fc0e4d87cb13"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to monitor progress with respect to transition to organic and organic supply chain development;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6f7fe2db0fde4a4f858495329ee6bf2e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to address improvements and impacts of the transition to organic, including observed changes in biodiversity, soil health, pests, weeds, and disease occurrence, crop yield, and resilience;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1d6c1f62303b4ebc8f5d2d1f3a44ecaa"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to address challenges associated with transition to organic;</text></subclause><subclause id="id554b35cb051842058b7d21b9f329f4e7"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to consider market opportunities and the adoption of additional practices; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide7d82f0511bd47ddbd9e6cd57653df10"><enum>(V)</enum><text>to explore opportunities for coordinated farm team meetings with staff from relevant agencies and organizations to streamline agricultural assistance and improve farm viability while increasing adoption of on-farm conservation practices; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb66d9f7b21cc46e09584812f0ad39228"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meet not less frequently than annually for each year for which funding is provided with staff of the Department of Agriculture (as determined by the Secretary) to discuss program participation and impacts, demographics and scale of participants, transition to organic success rates, market opportunities, research results, and challenges identified in the transition to organic.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idda9ea76aa89e4db29b8a85e85dc38a27"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><subparagraph id="id52145ebb34d34023acc8bd42d25bee64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall increase regional resources to support organic management, including technical assistance, outreach, supply chain coordination, and activities described in subparagraph (B), through expanded organic-related capacity and partnerships at—</text><clause id="id937a2b0621004282b359c4b2bbc963e9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture, including within the Agricultural Marketing Service, the Farm Service Agency, the Natural Resources Conservation Service, the Risk Management Agency, the offices under the Undersecretary of Rural Development, the Food and Nutrition Service, and climate hubs, with an emphasis on local and regional offices;</text></clause><clause id="id25cee88c52964d8cb716e438db647963"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>universities and educational institutions, with an emphasis on institutions serving socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f89684bebbd4ed08ad5b82ca7271ed4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the cooperative extension programs of the Secretary, including the Federally Recognized Tribes Extension Program;</text></clause><clause id="idc005e0b9964d485fabfc2a2790b324c8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>State, regional, and Tribal departments of agriculture; and</text></clause><clause id="idf3a52fc37a164e6885496130f93f9e60"><enum>(v)</enum><text>eligible nonprofit organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id15924590bdf14036ac29e747e423a957"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>Activities carried out through the entities described in subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="id4e0099b7bfe14161a705696607568dee"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regional education sessions on organic management;</text></clause><clause id="id2208907d4f3d4ac088ad4275b21c65d8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the development of regionally tailored resources, technical assistance programs, and teaching farms for organic producers and producers in transition to organic, including tools to promote and facilitate participation of socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers and small and mid-sized farms and ranches in organic and complementary support programs;</text></clause><clause id="id8ba735205512499ebe6f541597a3a344"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ongoing outreach to and needs assessment of producers in transition to organic to identify barriers to organic production and mechanisms to address those barriers;</text></clause><clause id="ide6b2f3a54a18499898593fc8d7db68ea"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the identification of priority locations to promote transition to organic, including near schools and childcare providers, residential areas, and sensitive ecosystems;</text></clause><clause id="id65971a749d9b495c80f78c470a1f4a0b"><enum>(v)</enum><text>organic supply chain and infrastructure development;</text></clause><clause id="idef7a22cc09e34250810f97e0fe7e7144"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the expansion of organic and local supply chains and market opportunities, including establishing channels for producers to offer products to institutional buyers and supporting purchases through nutrition programs; and</text></clause><clause id="id00d1ad81787642d49be2de705779ab81"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>advancing food waste reduction strategies that support producer income and soil health, including—</text><subclause id="idda4728e3ef2344438eb8892c52fca639"><enum>(I)</enum><text>closed-loop programs that connect community composting and food scrap collection operations with farms; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id5c1db264903c44c1bfe798f5174723c3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>coordination to maximize use of farm products, composting, and waste reduction.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9b1cd468f844902a4071c730d17f33e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subsection (e) (as so redesignated)—</text><subparagraph id="idfa43359e4b214708a96e78f6ffe2da9b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>including the number</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id78b89b6cd4a7432c87f65cbf74035dac"><text>including—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id09bba2e35fe048f9bc87f8a50240cf48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36e02a4e4a1d4a61a539ebbb24392160"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) (as so designated), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2145c1434ed04dab897739c1ecde43e1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ed946e5b2594978b698bbecbdc01d15"><paragraph id="id69b1913f08fe4e72a70d0ce554b56391"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the demographics, acreage, and sales of producer participants that received support under the program, aggregated by region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id720f885b15b0459db34e162464a560da"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of producers and handlers that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82d9b2e0711644dba793665a7d55c58a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received support from the program in the previous fiscal year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b61ab1975fe47d28076a31c7fed969c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>began transition to organic; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2ab6aa8d920747d389101fdaffb14d02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>achieved new organic certification;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfaa2af697f2c484ea25db8afdfb0c236"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any barriers to achieving organic certification;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb695301c6164fc8bf7b438bdb3b2d3a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the transition to organic activities carried out by eligible nonprofit organizations and the metrics used to evaluate the success of those activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf529f8e287a475e880b58d804c45ce9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>research findings and best practices to support transition to organic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id671ad776283442cc9c8c648aed84035d"><enum>(7)</enum><text>changes in organic-relevant capacity at public institutions of higher education and eligible nonprofit organizations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b84cc4b9aea495d86498c4f684b2d39"><enum>(8)</enum><text>changes in availability of organic-relevant technical assistance.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2253242a875a4fde856a70df30c23716"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (f)(1) (as so redesignated), by striking subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21984195947a4408bdbe41a79636d241"><subparagraph id="id2f8cedfe9bce4579a467d6ecf304b904"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1335b372030248a5873ce5e6d76e3eb5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$80,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida0d7ea31ca93485b80e7be46591f99f8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2030 and 2031.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

