<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB466C2A84CC74AE385641A5B841E18C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8491 IH: Postal Alert and Weather Preparedness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8491</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the United States Postal Service to conduct a study on the feasibility of carrying out a program to provide electronic notifications to Postal Service customers regarding weather and mail delivery, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0D01721AEDF94F49B809872789492453" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2B5F1E44F47C4973BCE6C21EAB8D70CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Postal Alert and Weather Preparedness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H74E67C4F84504AB08119E07A62C07149"><enum>2.</enum><header>Feasibility study on program to send electronic notifications regarding weather and mail delivery to Postal Service customers</header> 
<subsection id="H3DF822372E9F40C1B0A341019D73E747"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Postmaster General shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6162563DA65342958D2256765B39504A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study to evaluate the feasibility of carrying out a program, using the United States Postal Service’s informed delivery platform, under which the Postal Service may send electronic notifications to Postal Service customers regarding weather and mail delivery, including notifications—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0F029FD751864741B9E5DEE1D13C23E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a delay in the delivery of mail as a result of inclement weather or natural disasters;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A9F05D9A2BB4449B111D3FE8AAF0990"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that post offices and other Postal Service locations may be closed or operating with limited hours and staffing as a result of inclement weather or natural disasters; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA90ED05332C149DC8A499F25D599AD82"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that property owners and renters should clear walkways to their doors and mailboxes for mail carriers in the event of the accumulation of snow, sleet, ice, or debris; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H523A00FB82C34557B5D0876E0E63AD26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report on such study to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H80EAD773CF114252BBE28907697DD858"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the study under subsection (a), the Postmaster General shall evaluate the following with respect to carrying out the program:</text> <paragraph id="H6045EC3693144EC29CFF700372EA00CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Methods of how the Postal Service would expand the ability of Postal Service customers to be enrolled in the informed delivery platform.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2E80321EDE544B38B33410165E8E555"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How electronic messages will be sent under the program, the criteria for sending messages and appropriate content of messages, and who will receive the message.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEF8100C35294420EA72648A52BE8FD05"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contact information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (b)(1)(B), the term <quote>contact information</quote> shall only include the name, mailing address, email address, or phone number of any Postal Service Customer.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1B7E3E5135041CF82A208C50A977CF6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program</header><text>On or after the date the report is submitted to Congress under subsection (a)(2), the Postal Service may carry out the program described in such study.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H11FEDD55A3EE49A3A8EDBDB025357184"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Application</header> <text>The Postal Service may carry out this Act notwithstanding section 552a of title 5, United States Code, (commonly known as the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>).</text>
      </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

