<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM26482-G6T-D2-LRT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4843 IS: Enhancing Mental Health and Suicide Prevention Through Campus Planning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4843</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to promote comprehensive campus mental health and suicide prevention plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HE43F381AF33A4906A6F53C6532B355F9"><section section-type="section-one" id="H98302E374ABD432F979925E379BD1AE1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Mental Health and Suicide Prevention Through Campus Planning Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H50D08BB71D37481B88FC1CC578234E6A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Encouraging campus comprehensive mental health and suicide prevention plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part L of title VIII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161l">20 U.S.C. 1161l et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB988E02BB424409F9358EC3AA289930A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 826 as section 827; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE153F7CAF964384A67771B5973319DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 825 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5D3D474FDAD74AE7BBD15EEF402F2941"><section id="HD0101D5444F04EE9B7A4245BB9CD26A9"><enum>826.</enum><header>Encouraging campus comprehensive mental health and suicide prevention plans</header><subsection id="id9c48ab51d20e4a3bad0c11cbcc621093"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Model plans</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7dc709b5b85477dab96369972999c13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration) shall develop and disseminate 1 or more evidence-based model mental health and suicide prevention action plans to serve as models for institutions of higher education that want to implement such plans. The Secretary shall ensure that those model plans are aligned with the evidence-based suicide prevention programs of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b24b9786fb94312b1f8907ea935fecb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 5 years, the Secretary shall update the model plans described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4e6876da2f7845d1889bf86df7b9f763"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>After developing and disseminating the model plans described in subsection (a), the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration), shall provide technical assistance to institutions of higher education that want to implement comprehensive mental health and suicide prevention plans modeled after the model plans described in subsection (a). In providing such technical assistance, the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="idb55e85561c3c47b4a117ad2388a7835a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take into consideration existing State efforts to address mental health and suicide prevention at institutions of higher education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb14e83b635e43faad21341b70d5fe8f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may collaborate with nonprofit organizations, community-based organizations, student organizations, or other experts and stakeholders in the field of mental health and suicide prevention at institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1840A8034F842B5B843B6DEDB718BDA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Secretary, or a designee of the Secretary, shall submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Energy and Commerce Committee of the House of Representatives, and the Education and Workforce Committee of the House of Representatives on the activities of the Secretary carried out under this section—</text><paragraph id="H6AA51FC1A8144E708F7092F14361CB51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the developing the first model plan described in subsection (a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DCCAF63FB8140F5B3DAE6FDB9153930"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after each update described in subsection (a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9B86574E4864B6BA842E9BE9721B52B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as creating new legal requirements for institutions of higher education.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

