<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3B74E147A28E4AC99D6D5C9773448AFB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8320 IH: USA 6G Global Leadership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8320</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require additional duties of the Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy with respect to United States diplomatic efforts ahead of certain international conferences, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4DCA3462686C4A599C9D34BFC2478EE5" style="OLC">
<section id="H84136934960344349275A02D2539680C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>USA 6G Global Leadership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7F2B3FABFA884E64A20AF9D1889F112C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the Sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC383B64F36E84599BA74483A8895C755"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States has a national security, economic, and foreign policy interest in winning the race for 6G global leadership;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07C98D6C14064E069BDA5A4AAAAC8B07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China’s (PRC) use of malign nonmarket practices to accelerate its development of 5G and 6G technology is coercive and constrains countries’ access to reliable and secure telecommunications services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8BA68027BB844678887305956135AE8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States government should leverage economic and diplomatic tools to ensure United States companies are positioned to compete as leading providers of 6G technology and are not unfairly disadvantaged by PRC based state owned enterprises;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H216BB472EED546129D4DF5FBF2A96DC7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>it is in the United States interest to engage at the International Telecommunications Union (ITU) and private standard setting bodies to ensure the United States is positioned to lead on the key telecommunications, information, and other emerging technologies, including artificial intelligence; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BCD61EE60BC475B9335E3757BF05512"><enum>(5)</enum><text>it is critical to cooperate with like-minded allies and partners, including through multilateral coordination, to promote secure telecommunications networks by achieving market leadership for trusted vendors.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC28A5F7B243A40F083384EC76924E991"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy responsibilities at Plenipotentiary Conference and World Radiocommunication Conference</header> <subsection id="HAF130E0B728144BF99A971803C0F120D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy (authorized under subsection (i) of section 1 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a(i)</external-xref>) shall coordinate and lead United States diplomatic efforts ahead of the Plenipotentiary Conference of the International Telecommunications Union (ITU) in 2026 and the World Radiocommunication Conference 2027.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5780424F976548B5AE7B03E5B11DF09E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the coordination required by subsection (a), the Ambassador at Large for Cyberspace and Digital Policy shall be responsible for—</text> <paragraph id="H7FB4266E253F4375AE31143FCF15654E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinating across the Department of State, the Department of Commerce, and other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, to promote candidates for election to the ITU’s leadership bodies that support the United States economic and security objectives for increased telecommunications security, digital freedom, and information technology governance and standards;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD00C0A430274489FAD989D830E6BD423"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consulting with United States private sector entities to ensure that views and perspectives are understood, incorporated, and represented as the Department of State engages in the ITU elections process;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB62F53928464D468FC485347DBE3D3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consulting with Congress by providing quarterly briefings on developments leading up to the ITU elections and the World Radiocommunication Conference 2027;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7A5028BE7DC49B8B7189B96E7750982"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinating across the Department of State, the Department of Commerce, and other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, to advance United States interests ahead of the World Radiocommunication Conference 2027;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9E80A0BF802440EA8977B00AF25A8BA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conducting diplomatic outreach to promote United States interests in the field of international telecommunications; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3E80C20B0EC4296984F86440800681F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other such duties that the Secretary of State may prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H213EC66DDEEC4CF38437F35187186DFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H60A24CD9B57F4E569309C221B254029D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on efforts by the People’s Republic of China and by the Russian Federation to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD7E613CCB6F84FEEA2E0E9C119D6D778"><enum>(A)</enum><text>leverage the ITU or other international forums to promote policies or standards that constrain digital freedom;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF4A13C2846A24E72BB4379F5748EE9F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expand the mandate of the ITU to cover internet governance policy, including by proposing internet governance standards at the ITU;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD36B95A128EF41819249A81D74D42772"><enum>(C)</enum><text>leverage their private sector’s influence over developing countries to compel such countries to deliver favorable decisions on standards proposals, election victories, candidate selection, and other decisions at the ITU; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H66C171E4149D48CF8D73F670E6882753"><enum>(D)</enum><text>use the influence of Chinese or Russian nationals serving in the ITU to advantage companies, standards decisions, and ITU leadership candidates that advance the interests of the People’s Republic of China or the Russian Federation, respectively.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68AABC7F53F84D2C994D39AC9FC12A6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97F98C23B5D342109C00343850D4C5D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H62F7D993268D40C79368C9DFD5220D99"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17A110DA6E8048348BAE42877910D4CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7EB36B848DCA469C9CB6FD01FBDCB489"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authorities and requirements under this section shall expire upon the conclusion of the World Radiocommunication Conference 2027.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9588385DB61045CCB515C39E0518D147"><enum>4.</enum><header>Project assistance</header> <subsection id="HE1DA26BA43914B809271259B8ED0A23A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Chief Executive Officer of the International Development Finance Corporation and the Director of the United States Trade and Development Agency, should carry out projects that assert United States global leadership in telecommunications infrastructure.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00E542D2FBC74AE9B737C778F907C5BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority projects</header><text>For assistance pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall prioritize projects that—</text> <paragraph id="H9125DCBB0A9D4C00AA78EC5DFD7D1B7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote connectivity and use of trusted vendors in developing countries; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE69D068788534A6BABB278C25871DC2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>use technology produced by United States companies or entities if not specifically important that they are incorporated or by companies organized under the laws of United States allies if United States technology goods and services are not available.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFD47597758394A13BC38A76AA70D089A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Forms of support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The projects carried under this section may receive support through the following methods:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD369D6959B384ACCBC187D1E1D2B9EBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Early-stage project development including feasibility studies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCB924A58F5B4BD498D8F4B8EDB9D5D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Development loans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83163AD859C5473E8A8C26C0131ACCEF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Direct investments in companies or projects that advance Unites States foreign policy interests.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53BF56203D37412EACE8380F98ACA46F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Other types of support as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2170734A9B85416AAD318D8312443918"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report that describes the projects undertaken pursuant to subsection (b).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0CB27168B2F8496E8B14813DFBA2CBF5"><enum>5.</enum><header>6G technology dominance strategy</header> <subsection id="HC0D8856D4D3C4D9290CE5545C74F6795"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy for 6G technology dominance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that details the United States strategy to promote and dominate 6G technology globally.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3264E77C49E4D3CB8DB4B52B39BA920"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall also include a description and analysis of the activities of the Department of State regarding—</text> <paragraph id="HD75ABEF4BF1847CFB28696216CE26955"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actions to deepen cooperation with like-minded countries to promote United States and allied market leadership in 6G networks and technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A0000A8F2284BBCB123749297EAFAA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efforts to coordinate and cooperate with relevant Federal departments and agencies as well as United States-based private sector entities to plan, strategize, and conduct diplomatic engagements at telecommunication standard-setting bodies and organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20897FC4E5DB4EC2AD1C22B631B50EA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the effects on and impact of competition in artificial intelligence and other critical or emerging technologies, including the role of low-earth orbit satellites, in ensuring that the United States remains the partner of choice in 6G infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDEA30FD9DBF640F3BF455CA0A8D841A8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

