<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC8F92C28150545BC8E01E8D1F5E89D9C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6216 IH: Support Our Troops Shipping Relief Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6216</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To exempt nonprofit organizations sending humanitarian care packages to members of the Armed Forces stationed overseas from certain tariff and postal reporting requirements, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H23E4546A40C147C1BCCD3BC439743563" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC0A4651DEF0248DDA661DBFBB89A94CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support Our Troops Shipping Relief Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0B684552D3224647880FB2BFD7A80A3F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H4289CF28DACF4258B807BF7A87D792F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFA3E776175FA4FD5A926FD6FFA2B6025"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nonprofit organizations, such as Operation Troop Support in Danvers, Massachusetts, have shipped millions of care packages to members of the United States Armed Forces deployed overseas, containing comfort items, personal supplies, and messages of encouragement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF15D1E86EEFC497D86C808D007A8230E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recent Customs and postal reporting requirements—such as the need to list six-digit Harmonized System codes and item-by-item country-of-origin data—were designed for commercial trade, not humanitarian parcels, and have unintentionally restricted the ability of volunteer organizations to send morale-support shipments abroad.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF1139E7D30C4929A75070E7EE313893"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These burdens have led to delays, returned packages, and significant cost increases for nonprofits relying on donations and volunteers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5881D6EC862340039A1EA2F7C7BA4F9B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Congress therefore intends to exempt qualified nonprofit troop-support organizations from unnecessary tariff and reporting requirements and to direct relevant agencies to simplify their documentation standards.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H408D1608FBBF4BB1B7DA3CF21CDE2D78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to remove unnecessary Customs barriers that hinder the ability of nonprofit organizations to send humanitarian care packages to members of the United States Armed Forces serving overseas.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF74C4CA9E7D64611B4AF9819D5A91665"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exemption under the Tariff Act of 1930 for humanitarian care packages for Armed Forces personnel sent by qualified nonprofit organizations</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Tariff Act of 1930 is amended by inserting after section 321 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1321">19 U.S.C. 1321</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB776372DE8BE4FC99192675B85F7D039" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H91BA8232BEA24242B796393AEE16D98B"><enum>321A.</enum><header>Exemption for humanitarian care packages for Armed Forces personnel sent by qualified nonprofit organizations</header> 
<subsection id="H0C875BF118D44095A1413BF707466DC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemption established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A shipment that meets the requirements of this section shall be exempt from—</text> <paragraph id="HB4A821ABA82847C58C0DFBACA1D5A1E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any tariff or duty otherwise applicable under any provision of law; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE066211BE1E404DBA7CBABEFC9410EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any requirement to provide—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC3B0620551144C6895E67E257D74066"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individual Harmonized System classification codes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DF55DDB5B05433C84EC1F146A4289F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>country-of-origin declarations; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF371FEDDCBAF42D4B34FE388FAC5561B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>commercial invoices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54BED746230E4EB4B2C5A6748CD29E79"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible shipments</header><text>A shipment shall qualify for the exemption under subsection (a) if—</text> <paragraph id="H094CB1A8D5BE4865BB9B7D6FFDB37D03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it originates from a qualified nonprofit organization;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78FC5A0562404A30A4C6E9432373FA76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>it is addressed to a military mail address or other destination authorized by the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94CF92F53F84459986418F28875A511E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the declared contents are humanitarian care packages as defined in section 3 of the Support Our Troops Shipping Relief Act of 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H192C8D3632C2431B93A4661F023C3E56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> 
<paragraph id="H02C18E960CAC4801A86BC18BE8EC2CFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit security screening or inspection authority under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4980A12872A4CAC8D4DEBF4932AF274"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional rule</header><text>To the extent this section is determined to be inconsistent with Universal Postal Union requirements or a Status of Forces Agreement negotiated by the Department of Defense, enforcement of any violation of this section shall be delayed until on or after January 31, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2D27B19C49504CC48AD16C38CF491778"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H44474F2E0E484CF2A659260FD3EECF2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term “Armed Forces” has the meaning given that term in section 101(a)(4) of title 10, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE64664132F53441B887B8E08FF1D7DD5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term “humanitarian care package” means a parcel containing donated goods intended solely for the comfort, welfare, or morale of Armed Forces personnel stationed outside the continental United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H976FB279DC974208A045BA8CCF9C3CBE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term “qualified nonprofit organization” means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that Code that primarily supports United States service members or veterans; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56D44930AD8C4CB1ADE4824634C2160C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term “military mail address” means an Army Post Office (APO), Fleet Post Office (FPO), or Diplomatic Post Office (DPO) address designated by the Department of Defense for receipt of mail by United States Armed Forces personnel abroad.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H0576F93C2AD4449B96F098CEFD497875"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation by the United States Postal Service and U.S. Customs and Border Protection</header> <subsection id="HCE6C52F48BAC4D5FB39487C5C30C8D74"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Domestic treatment of military mail</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Postal Service shall treat any shipment that meets the requirements of section 321A of the Tariff Act of 1930, as added by section 4, as domestic mail for all rate, tariff, and customs purposes, regardless of destination.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5A7D3DD31C74FAEBD3B18A8532EC326"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Postmaster General and the Secretary of the Treasury (acting through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection) shall jointly issue regulations to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9ACA11DAD0A64433A42143D78F303B57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Simplified manifest requirement</header><text>In implementing this section, the United States Postal Service and U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall accept simplified manifests for any shipments that meets the requirements of section 321A of the Tariff Act of 1930, as added by section 4, which may list categories of contents (such as “snack foods,” “personal hygiene items,” “letters and cards,” or similar general descriptions) in lieu of individual Harmonized System codes or country-of-origin information for each item.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


