<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9317CB7B490049D48CF4E5969D809410" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5922 IH: Improving Accessibility Through Microtransit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5922</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251104">November 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program for the provision of competitive grants to eligible entities for use improving the availability of accessible microtransit services to individuals with disabilities or mobility impairments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H538F4CDADDA5486F93A686CA1A2C267D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7E9E35A27C4B47E88AD7F98FD996DC63" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Accessibility Through Microtransit Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB2EC8F2C15AB449685617B406D453832"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for provision of grants to improve microtransit services</header> <subsection id="H2A9FD937C07745AFBDED9654F5FEDAD3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Transit Administration, shall establish a pilot program (herein referred to as the <quote>Pilot Program</quote>) under which the Secretary may make grants, on a competitive basis, to covered entities for use improving the availability of microtransit services to individuals with disabilities or mobility impairments, including individuals who use a wheelchair.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HECE1913370D64E828D658BC333FF3721"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> 
<paragraph id="H89D5A4B0653048F196205856FD6AED70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the Pilot Program, a covered entity must submit an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, and that includes the following information:</text> <subparagraph id="H087AB5E1F7AC4089ABA7685E865D931A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the types of disabilities or mobility impairments of individuals the covered entity expects to provide with microtransit services through the expenditure of grant funds.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5BD9B6002304C98A877739EA886212F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The approximate square miles of the geographic area in which the covered entity expects to provide microtransit services through the expenditure of grant funds.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3C67A6900264327935B79AB84A7B574"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any additional information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED93D0C36CD1448495B152F29A0E1907" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public-private partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity may submit an application on behalf of a partnership between a covered entity and a private entity for the provision of a microtransit service.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3EFB8E5E837247AA85876CC385AE0C00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header> <paragraph id="H60028F9FF9F24290905DE7DDF9A574B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In selecting applicants to receive a grant under the Pilot Program, the Secretary shall select a covered entity based on criteria established by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20C367EFDD8C46E8AD70DEC52738D476"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prioritize for receipt of a grant under the Pilot Program applicants—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F5B5C97516F4D7F89335ABBFE11C1E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose applications demonstrate how each microtransit service intended to be acquired or provided using grant funds will—</text> 
<clause id="H9C03647F7562445890F890A891500B6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide greater accessibility for individuals with disabilities or mobility impairments;</text></clause> <clause id="HFA975E01C97143C18FFE9B52FE0E3634"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address a lack of accessible service in the geographic area in which the covered entity expects to provide microtransit services through the expenditure of grant funds; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H12076CD98B244FAEAF193522D78A0794"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deliver economic benefits in such geographic area, such as improving access to jobs or promoting local economic development through enhanced mobility; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DCABB041EBF43F5882D2B1E92DAADE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that intend to use grant funds to—</text> 
<clause id="HAFE910E2A8E04DDFAFB8EF294E13C208"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide wheelchair accessible vehicles and accessible mobile applications for use in microtransit services;</text></clause> <clause id="H8BFD6FFDD3624A7386DDC013A75191DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enable low-income individuals, including individuals without access to smartphone technology or a credit card, to access any transportation services made available through the project;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4626FCB5E1E44422BC6D979CAA3A4920"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out an allowable use described in subsection (e) that improves the performance of the transit and microtransit services system of the applicant;</text></clause> <clause id="HD082BC33FBC148BABC21661FA1B5C6C9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accelerate the deployment of advanced transit technologies, including shared-use mobility services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H674868A05194407087D5C04F009A05EB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>improve safety within the area serviced by the applicant; or</text></clause> <clause id="H803128588217406B92665D36EB77E742" commented="no"> <enum>(vi)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly hire workers to perform microtransit services within the system of the applicant.</text>
                        </clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A16AFECBD75490C93B16566DEF8B501"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant amount limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Pilot Program, the Secretary may not issue a grant for an amount greater than $3,000,000.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE2E3B1BADA004D2DB11C5BC6FACD4D1F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Allowable uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a grant under the Pilot Program may use grant funds for the following uses:</text> 
<paragraph id="H018A5CAC2FD34BC0BB7C8FCA4AA83BE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To purchase or lease a covered vehicle for use in a microtransit service existing as of the date on which the recipient submits an application in accordance with subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC508C4F3FD7E4BA1AF80B3BE3A29AEC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To fund initial training for individuals to be able to drive a covered vehicle operating in a mircotransit service of the recipient.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H916D5A0970E24CA593336692F9810581"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To fund continuing education training for drivers of a covered vehicle operating in a microtransit service of the recipient.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA06983174E5140C7B0E63219ED137471"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To contract for the provision of activities necessary for the provisions of a microtransit service, including capital management and operations-related activities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EF5520985FB452C87A4C6D56310536B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To acquire software or license technology that facilitates microtransit services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43BF79C6EF284CBF839382DC855D18A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other uses determined by the Secretary to improve the accessibility or availability of microtransit services for individuals with disabilities or mobility impairments.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF29E128836645FE82DB8A5B1F7EBB85"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Camera system requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="HB4374C14981546A3897AE95149AA4ED1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Stipulation</header><text>As a condition of receiving funds under the Pilot Program, each recipient shall agree to install, if necessary, and maintain on each vehicle of the microtransit service of the recipient an interior camera system—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0B5FD6591C641429950E009ED121021"><enum>(A)</enum><text>capable of recording passengers and drivers on the vehicle; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1571578758EC48088564C1E22DA36026"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that may—</text> <clause id="HEAC858908F8F4B29A756558DEEC30572"><enum>(i)</enum><text>continuously record video and audio while the vehicle is engaged in passenger service;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF73CF2870F5A46079EE45A3B9DCA83B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be tamper-resistant;</text></clause> <clause id="HE58AF18CE9BC46DC861ADA9A56FBB8C1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>retain recordings for 30 days or more; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDD8AC44149F947E7B33BA4872064C70E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>produce recordings in a format accessible to the recipient and, upon lawful request, law enforcement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H749D956D1E6345EBB9F50ECBEB6D5741"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recording access limitations</header><text>A recording produced by an interior camera system maintained pursuant to paragraph (1) may not be released to the public and access to the recording shall be limited to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D35614BF956472CBA895A6D7C3CE732"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employees of the recipient who the recipient authorizes to access; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C0F6D5183474973B1264E9E5D5CFEDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>law enforcement pursuant to a lawful request.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A9877DC0EA9457AB7C9EA5A94B039AD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Labor standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall apply the requirements of section 5333 of title 49, United States Code, to projects financed with Pilot Program grant funds.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAE17257D922445118E8EDBD72C147E45"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to carry out the Pilot Program under this section shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Pilot Program commences.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3DBF0135F22247CDA6D1D5787178AC91"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $20,000,000 to carry out this section. Such amount is authorized to remain available through the fiscal year in which the Pilot Program is terminated pursuant to subsection (f).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE6A45453DCAD4066A51AE6BD82D821C4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2580CF94E21B4364A0DB301CF33AC792"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H6E5686E2447A49D6BA32F82AAB1B1B15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State government;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDCAB0125D4D249008675F53BE470D166"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36B777D1B26A40338E290D7CB795748B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Tribal organization; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE69FCD9BB9F54E9FB6EF3B5C50CAAC5C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC29EBC70216A430D91384DDE4127011B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered vehicle</term> means a multi-passenger vehicle that, to be accessible to individuals with disabilities or mobility impairments (including individuals who use a wheelchair), is equipped with handicap accessible designs, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB7EB32207B234653AF576AA3B9B0A504" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a ramp;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A07E40F9D584F36865B44B601870AEA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a hydraulic mechanism designed to load and unload a wheelchair; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE6F4E1EABC2446EA6A70A56D29DD3D8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other handicap accessible designs determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6D07BFEE0EA45C79AF2C63F51C395DF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fixed route system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fixed route system</term> has the meaning given such term in section 221 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12141">42 U.S.C. 12141</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29F6357E4F3F4F8C8AC187EA886BB6C5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Microtransit service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>microtransit service</term> means a technology-enabled, on-demand service with dynamically generated routing that uses a managed fleet of multi-passenger vehicles dedicated to that service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C52225DDD854ACD8E5FDC0DCFC503CE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>On-demand service</header><text>With respect to a microtransit service, the term <term>on-demand service</term> includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE820E3D1111D43F5BA6E2DADFF67FE4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A service to connect an individual from a starting point to a fixed route system or from a fixed route system to a destination of the individual.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB83DDB46A814D7D9DFCA62E49D562E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A hub-to-hub zone-based service.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F10CBF292DF4E229F9C1BC99640870F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A service that is a commingling of a general transit service and a paratransit or other special transportation service provided in accordance with section 223 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12143">42 U.S.C. 12143</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H47CC79D3A2E04ACF8D76518B50EAD361"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A point-to-point service within a specific zone or limited geographic area.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99848F87249D406FA46A4565338617BF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other similar service, as determined by the Secretary of Transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H77157EBCBA0F41E3A2E8D3B8031C9331" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

