<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H51271472A5404FF288E6570709873B58" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7431 IH: Congressional Civics Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7431</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To implement the proposed constitutional amendment requiring Members of Congress to demonstrate competence in American civics.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5C0B9BE227E84ACBA466B1EF10155EA3" style="OLC"><section id="H5AE189B145F6453D93F882D243EFBB79" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Congressional Civics Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H606A7074195A427789992810A3BBBCB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Implementation of eventual constitutional requirement that Members of Congress demonstrate competence in American civics</header><subsection id="H4E0FE060869E4826874A0A90FB189DD2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Congress shall establish and administer, for each census term, the examination required for Members of Congress to demonstrate competence on the system of government under the United States Constitution.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB0FD7E366C44B08AF0939FDF47B6BBE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Examination requirement for Members of Congress</header><text>A House of Congress may not seat an individual as a Member following the election or appointment of the individual, as the case may be, unless the individual can demonstrate, in accordance with the rules of the House concerned, that the individual has successfully completed the examination in effect at the time of the election or the appointment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7CFCC47A707A496DA1FF115A6C069D5E"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Effect of failure to comply with examination requirement</header> <text>An individual elected or appointed to be a Member of Congress who does not successfully complete the examination in effect at the time of the election or appointment may not become a Member until the individual successfully completes the examination, and a vacancy shall arise with respect to the election or appointment if the individual does not successfully complete the examination before two weeks after the election or appointment.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HDE534AAACAD84166BA53BAE2E97997B7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Content of examination</header><text>The examination shall consist of 25 questions randomly drawn from among 100 questions approved in accordance with this section, with 5 questions from each of the following topics:</text><paragraph id="H9E0534AB30E1482C9249ECF0249194A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The founding of the first colonies and factors contributing to American independence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC2218E8AA6941BEB6C28648344FA886"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Events in the American Revolution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08CDD92599714F0780499B55AD9619C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Constitutional Convention of 1787 and the ratification of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D4936CDE484991A01424897F52EB4D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Civil War and Reconstruction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H045ABF21B88542409DC796779117AD28"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The First World War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3EC8644F0A24FE590311D051916C520"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Second World War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5F2CA075E8D4583A0928F2BEA0998BC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Declaration of Independence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94DDA7D0D809445B98E7231278437B5B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Articles of Confederation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4192E023C9D4D6CBA055CB3854407E5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98CF980724C0451F9F0BA00174F49FCC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Bill of Rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD313D1DDDB8F457C84035098C8B81A6E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The constitutional amendments ratified following the Civil War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E03F1619E7D4FB5A3044E9838BB1FF8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The other amendments to the Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H792FC8F807B048039E0D5F68F7A92E8B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Civil rights and civil liberties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F6012CA774B48EB9AA71746967172C6"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Due process and the rule of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E9917CBD68A4865AB6CC34B9E283497"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Elections and the democratic process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D52E3F4D0CA4187B264A3C136C91B68"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Federalism, the relationship between the States and the Federal Government, and the relation between the United States and Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9541525FE062487D9EF84C6A6729B51F"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Separation of powers under the Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02D5617D016B45F1924ED8F648687B37"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9737BCFF3574459EAF1A0DE9D2335EFD"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The President and the executive departments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD396C797AFEB46488C49A23345D75F46"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The Supreme Court and the Federal judiciary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAC818289A414B899A0510477F5D377F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Correct answers</header><text>A response to a question in the examination shall be considered correct if the response is in accordance with the corresponding model answer to the question.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1A71E0B36E674283AC44DF81B0621405"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Committee report on proposed questions and answers for the examination</header><text>Not later than June 30 of the year preceding the start of a census term, the appropriate congressional committees shall jointly submit to the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the examination for the census term which shall include—</text><paragraph id="HDDD29B99D885406CA16DCC50B32AA023"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">questions and corresponding model answers in accordance with subsections (d) and (e);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H912F94748DC44391A3763F9CD37DF430"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of correct responses required for an individual taking the examination to successfully complete the examination; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E715CF2D45D4A459EAA5B2B1598AD29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the rules to govern the proceedings for the joint session of Congress under subsection (h)—</text><subparagraph id="H49CA16D7A43B447CBFA954F33D68FEA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to consider, make amendments to, or replace the questions and corresponding model answers described in paragraph (1) or the number of correct responses required for successful completion of the examination under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA3A48980BF645539DC26C0DE0547C02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to approve the examination after carrying out subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE20B5CA22458449D87E3B1C2940E095C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Member submissions of questions and answers</header><text>Not later than March 31 of the year preceding the start of a census term, a Member of Congress may submit to the appropriate congressional committees such questions and corresponding model answers for inclusion in the report under subsection (f).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA94F63CBFDF042DCAF0104B4092EC13C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Joint session of Congress for consideration and approval of the examination</header><text>Not earlier than two months after the submission of the report under subsection (f) and not later than October 31 of the year before the start of a census term, the House of Representatives and the Senate shall meet in a joint session of Congress to consider the report and approve the examination, in accordance with the rules to govern the proceedings for the joint session included in the report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H47CF7853C7454BD3B46AADA2A3816712"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Effective date of examination</header><text>The examination approved under subsection (h) in the year preceding the start of a census term shall be the examination in effect for the census term.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F2D3C6BC17348929E8724FA2BACF8D4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Publication of the questions and answers for the examination</header><text>On approval of the examination under subsection (h), each House of Congress shall cause the approved questions and corresponding model answers with respect to the examination to be published in the journal of proceedings of the House concerned, and the appropriate congressional committees shall make available to the public a report containing the approved questions and corresponding model answers which shall also include such other information reasonably necessary for an individual to successfully complete the examination.</text></subsection><subsection id="H92F9D08B3C724BF489CAA9159B5EE6F2"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Administration of the examination</header><text>The Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate, or their respective designees, shall—</text><paragraph id="H0DABEAD7D5D14DD0AB70346E6D4472ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>jointly administer the examination in accordance with this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB89E9C119C6D4CAAB15B6105460CC429"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to subsection (l), make the examination available, through a platform available on the internet, for any citizen of the United States to take at the discretion and convenience of the citizen, without cost to the citizen;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6EC15972C8402C8EF494A210D74B10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>maintain a database accessible to the general public of individuals who have successfully completed the examination; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A6438B1F80448309F6ED723D7C3CA62"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide to any individual who successfully completes the examination, on the demand of the individual, a certificate that shall serve as conclusive proof with respect to successfully completing the examination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H202E3A6BEB6B41F1BC0A2258ED1AC978"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Limit on examination sittings</header><text>An individual may not take the examination under this section more than 3 times each calendar year, but an individual elected or appointed to be a Member of Congress who does not successfully complete the examination before the election or appointment shall have the opportunity to take the examination at least once before a vacancy shall arise with respect to the election or appointment, notwithstanding any attempts to take the examination before the election or appointment.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB5402ABDFE88455BB7B3047FDDDA9966"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEF6C4E3E5A8B485E8A23035C364BB1E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF6AA505998264A0796989C9B3B093AF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H250729B8743F43BC9A0446CFDBBD5B93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFC8CE548BF54EED8FB7AB8E8626E106"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Census term</header><text>The term <term>census term</term> means a term of 10 calendar years that begins on the first day of a calendar year with a decennial census date under section 141 of title 13, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBEBB60439EF4B049BEB0FF72DB1914E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>The term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6A6B6F668E84A5D9EE69ED3E176E379"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the ratification of the article of amendment to the Constitution of the United States in H.J.Res. 146 of the One Hundred Nineteenth Congress, as introduced on January 30, 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB800EA8459884F3984FCA4F13B85E5F5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interim implementation of examination for committee assignments</header><subsection id="H69F349FA045A40EFADF608BF2C74FBDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each census term, each House of the Congress shall establish and administer an examination in accordance with this section, with respect to which a Member of Congress in the House concerned may not be assigned to a committee in the House or a joint committee of the Congress unless the Member can demonstrate, in accordance with the rules of the House, that the Member has successfully completed the examination in effect at the time of the committee assignment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H16A868E55F604353B759E7B8362A77BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exercise of rulemaking powers</header><text>This section is enacted by the Congress—</text><paragraph id="HF27914040FBD4E22B243C2385D96C8D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such it is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, and it supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDEEF9E94A1144A69BA26575D52BC98E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2EF85911D43486E82ACCC2E6C386FC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Content of examination</header><text>The examination shall consist of 25 questions randomly drawn from among 100 questions approved by the applicable House of Congress in accordance with this section, with 5 questions from each of the following topics:</text><paragraph id="H331A503E2A3F45B1B564D36980723C65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The founding of the first colonies and factors contributing to American independence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A66FE0A7B424866BBA2999A69EABD03"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Events in the American Revolution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA7A9E5393C34584906259CC3B67AB37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Constitutional Convention of 1787 and the ratification of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4DB24E5B128418B9821ACD227F5AB21"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Civil War and Reconstruction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90E1299740E54AF89D3CD36300DAC877"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The First World War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B414B8394BF4E7480E2C290D545F620"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Second World War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H809E6CF5B76E42B6B4DEE9F728FA5415"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Declaration of Independence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE3224D59FB742D9BFA7604D9610349B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Articles of Confederation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84288C00236B4D269E05DE6F52BB0259"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H833397062F0F4B39AB43BE8B3851B1FF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Bill of Rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4AB9931B22448F397AD81ADB6ABA70C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The constitutional amendments ratified following the Civil War.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDE3D42B83A34405B30DF8D200DAF7F0"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The other amendments to the Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27A7971899C34033AD9F282FB6E22BAC"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Civil rights and civil liberties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB2BDED8AD9D4C21A98EF1559FD19EB7"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Due process and the rule of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA8BCC2690004236BB824FADC037A16B"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Elections and the democratic process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37DB31FD09D948DBA17AC7799E1B6B49"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Federalism, the relationship between the States and the Federal Government, and the relation between the United States and Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBA55273F661411B90EDFEB24294EDAF"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Separation of powers under the Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0E96A1C3ADE4EAAAE9FD68EAC57F201"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C6E4634492A4932ACF5E98AC382FC6A"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The President and the executive departments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8D965BC14C14C6E8F99A05BFDEC6CCF"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The Supreme Court and the Federal judiciary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19B64FEF45DD4770816FC3C63C2A720F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Correct answers</header><text>A response to a question in the examination shall be considered correct if the response is in accordance with the corresponding model answer to the question.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD0C616067158460DBC6F12503EBD86F1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Committee report on proposed questions and answers for the examination</header><text>Not later than June 30 of the year preceding the start of a census term, the appropriate congressional committees shall jointly submit to the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the examination for the census term which shall include—</text><paragraph id="HD3FDD471F42742FBA8985DDAD888F1A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>questions and corresponding model answers in accordance with subsections (d) and (e); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CE3DB8D9D654ABBA11F061061AD1D8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of correct responses required for an individual taking the examination to successfully complete the examination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB2FE866A1594ED096F8AD029EB9B90B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Member submissions of questions and answers</header><text>Not later than March 31 of the year preceding the start of a census term, a Member of Congress may submit to the appropriate congressional committees such questions and corresponding model answers for inclusion in the report under subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF4BD57477D94B6081A5855761071E66"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Consideration and approval of the examination by each House of Congress</header><text>Not earlier than two months after the submission of the report under subsection (e) and not later than October 31 of the year before the start of a census term, each House of the Congress shall consider the report in accordance with the rules of the House concerned and approve the examination which shall be applicable to the House.</text></subsection><subsection id="H72D53C131DF7418A9C1BF62177693D12"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date of examination</header><text>The examination approved by a House of Congress under subsection (g) in the year preceding the start of a census term shall be the examination in effect for the census term with respect to the House.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF85B32C0986642FA9440134BFDD4A52C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Publication of the questions and answers for the examination</header><text>On approval of the examination under subsection (g), each House of Congress shall cause the approved questions and corresponding model answers with respect to the examination to be published in the journal of proceedings of the House concerned.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4756C4450E784010AC3680D81C9EED79"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administration of the examination</header><text>The Clerk of the House of Representatives, on the part of the House of Representatives, and the Secretary of the Senate, on the part of the Senate, shall each administer the examination applicable to the House concerned in accordance with this section and the rules of the House.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5E384D485633413098E9D4E2CB1F6CFB"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H90773F2199CE42A5AF8A8F3AC9EB0FED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFB0F5D39695846E49D3B80749E6328D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92D06187425C43FE903455B9B33DA08B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA89E642082554127B2DE62183A41E296"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Census term</header><text>The term <term>census term</term> means a term of 10 calendar years that begins on the first day of a calendar year with a decennial census date under section 141 of title 13, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15CAF67DC8D44DE9825E85C83B709028"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>The term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H754FEE6A1B35420FBB21696BDB3CD855"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subject to subsection (n), this section shall take effect with respect to the One Hundred Twentieth Congress and each succeeding Congress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H716D572E120544C9B125BFD4FB2AEB0A"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>This section shall terminate on the effective date specified in section 2.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

