<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H52036A75FD2D43578E791CE0302EC5AA" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1059 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the Department of Government Efficiency’s access to and usage of NUMIDENT and other personally identifiable information in the possession of the Social Security Administration.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1059</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. S&#225;nchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President of the United States to furnish certain information to the House of Representatives relating to the Department of Government Efficiency&#8217;s access to and usage of NUMIDENT and other personally identifiable information in the possession of the Social Security Administration.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB8A305F9005E44F6BB5836CAD3A627E7"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7720BA71715842D9B3952F55C76CD622"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President of the United States is requested to furnish the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of adoption of this resolution, copies of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), audit trails and audit logs, written agreements, or other communication in his possession, or any portion of any document, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), or other communication, that refers or relates to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H01DC4FD1CED6414E99F828C9EE9DFF11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Efforts by the Department of Government Efficiency (hereafter referred to as <quote>DOGE</quote>), Elon Musk, any member of his team, or any individual coordinating with the DOGE to communicate with a nongovernmental organization seeking to analyze State voter rolls or overturn election results in certain States, or to share information in the Social Security Administration’s Numerical Identification System (hereafter referred to as <quote>NUMIDENT</quote>) or other personally identifiable information in the possession of the Administration with such an organization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA5788A33CAC461C818F9152EF485A10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Efforts on or after January 20, 2025, to share NUMIDENT information or other personally identifiable information in the possession of the Social Security Administration with the Department of Homeland Security, including through an encrypted and password-protected file sent on March 3, 2025, from a member of the DOGE working at the Social Security Administration to the Department of Homeland Security and copied to Steve Davis.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H647B4B3996D0449BA64BD4ADA4E79C88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Use of Cloudflare or any other third-party server by DOGE members, including those working at or with the Social Security Administration, to share electronic files containing information in the possession of the Social Security Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD80433689D7406E89FD6E903DECB929"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Actions by the DOGE, Elon Musk, any member of his team, or any individual coordinating with the DOGE to access, use, or transmit NUMIDENT information or other personally identifiable information in the possession of the Social Security Administration in violation of any laws, outside of Social Security Administration policy, or in noncompliance with the temporary restraining order issued by the District Court of Maryland on March 20, 2025 and the preliminary injunction granted by the Court on April 17, 2025.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

