<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H59A89B4E952D4C02AFBCF9175D189484" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7207 IH: Presidential Conflicts of Interest Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7207</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require the President and the Vice President to disclose financial interests and divest of any financial interest posing a potential conflict of interest, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB20BC5FFAD074A79BB79C023640D5686" style="OLC"><section id="HBEA8C029F881456D9693B33856585C8F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Presidential Conflicts of Interest Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H14331FE8305C42FB8FC58C5ABE7FB4F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Financial interests of the President and Vice President</header><subsection id="HC2E3C88564524768B7496FA0715E774A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acts affecting a personal financial interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 208 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2876FE45662E48418318D7E9B8D3BB7E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H457A559DC9EB4A65A661A957E3D8E58B"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, the terms <term>officer</term> and <term>employee</term> shall include the President and the Vice President.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC4E197CE469845758FC76DC44B7C0846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on financial interests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2AA61E5BE8A14D3EA2585028A1A37CFF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H4CBADFD9C6AD4C028D60AEA11E5A1034"><enum>13147.</enum><header>Financial interests of the President and the Vice President</header><subsection id="HFCAD803A3FB34085BA0EDF6DB06ECD9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial financial disclosure</header><paragraph id="H721E1778E1B54A9D8A849E84D9C43BAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission of disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after assuming the office of President or Vice President, respectively, the President and the Vice President shall submit to Congress and the Director of Government Ethics a disclosure of financial interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95FD2F8BB806461097318FC839E1EC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The disclosure of financial interests submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD661CB4BF46643319A78004FEF018974"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe in detail each financial interest of the President or the Vice President, or the spouse or dependent child of the President or the Vice President;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB1339C4ED8D49C6B3B50DECD966D594"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at a minimum, include the information relating to each such financial interest that is required for reports under section 13103(d) of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98A32295703D405989EC32673E7E80C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include the tax returns filed by or on behalf of the President or the Vice President, as applicable, for—</text><clause id="HAD1A592A895E4F04837907ABC016BECE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the 3 most recent taxable years; and</text></clause><clause id="H1EDB9390CAB1485A880CCEECFC039CD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each taxable year for which an audit of the return by the International Revenue Service is pending on the date on which the report is filed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF7D89F916804CAD908B548725372D1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Divestiture of financial interests posing a potential conflict of interest</header><paragraph id="HFB7D3A63A1AF4D6DBE38606A114A7F7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, the Vice President, and the spouse and dependent child of the President and the Vice President shall divest of any financial interest posing a potential conflict of interest by transferring such interest to a qualified blind trust.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H278A9A5776CB4299AEB03D6DDFCEBB64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trustee duties</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date a financial interest is transferred to a qualified blind trust under paragraph (1), the trustee of the qualified blind trust shall—</text><subparagraph id="H59BE17647B9F48A685C837336687C396"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sell the financial interest and use the proceeds of such sale to purchase conflict-free holdings; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C710C5260004AC1989645489D26D4E6"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>sell the financial interest and return the proceeds of such sale to the President, the Vice President, or the spouse or dependent child of the President or the Vice President, as applicable.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A687BCF60684AF08108180D2BF65E4C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review by Office of Government Ethics</header><paragraph id="H9CE0E9C49311417A95AB9407695A1E36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall submit to Congress, the President, and the Vice President an annual report regarding the financial interests of the President, the Vice President, and the spouse and dependent child of the President and the Vice President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCE574644E8547D8BF17F19507DE9719"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8EC0D4523812455594154F4B711A70C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indicate whether any financial interest is a financial interest posing a potential conflict of interest;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9195ECB938242228FA2A6FA93413DB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate whether any previously held financial interest that was a financial interest posing a potential conflict of interest was divested in accordance with subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08F142C56EA34EFD92D63483EBBE7494"><enum>(C)</enum><text>redact such information as the Director of the Office of Government Ethics determines necessary for preventing identity theft, such as social security numbers or taxpayer identification numbers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88C9FC7745DF409BB159AE5EFBB0F57B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="HA20BB0449F0446A6BA393DB6CA46E25A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General or the attorney general of any State may seek declaratory or injunctive relief in a court of competent jurisdiction if—</text><subparagraph id="H066A5CBD8F0940BBA0915859AFED064F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Government Ethics is unable to issue a report indicating whether the President or the Vice President is in substantial compliance with subsection (c); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E29264EDA834C35A98116BE0C53CBCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is probable cause to believe that the President or the Vice President has not complied with subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8CA1A18CC304050A6DFF17196B8F755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fair market value</header><text>In granting injunctive relief to the plaintiff, the court shall ensure that any divestment procedure shall ensure fair market return for any asset that is liquidated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAF22F01760A40829F95177B06132B05"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="HFA99E30CDDA94AFCB20449B83043375D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text><subparagraph id="H2311BC9983014959B004D47BEBC8EF22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>conflict-free holding</term> means a financial interest that a reporting individual is not required to report under section 13104(f)(8) of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC460FC4EA7EB4C7A9CDCFA3E66B868B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>dependent child</term> has the meaning given that term in section 13101 of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DE3FD312C7B40AEB5A24251E32C10D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>financial interest</term> means the items required to be included in reports filed pursuant to section 1303(d) and (e) of this title under section 13104(a) of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0DBCB8C5F96440F89F21F498B463C7E"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>the term <term>financial interest posing a potential conflict of interest</term> means a financial interest of the President, the Vice President, or the spouse or dependent child of the President or the Vice President, as applicable, that—</text>
                                    <clause id="H5AB71C7B853648DFA1FE1004E9804121">
                                        <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constitutes a financial interest described in section 208(a) of title 18, without regard to any exception under subsection (b) of such section; or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="HAB98278D5CE144D88C290D17EE3F2261">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>constitutes a present, emolument, office, or title, of any kind, from any king, prince, or foreign state (including from an entity owned or controlled by a foreign government), within the meaning of article I, section 9 of the Constitution of the United States;</text>
                                    </clause>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1957E0BAEEB946919578462C4248480A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>qualified blind trust</term> has the meaning given that term in section 13104(f)(3) of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECC3353F5B3B43379AD981840CC917E7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the term <term>tax return</term>—</text><clause id="HFCC83CC837CC42F69C4951BC1492DFB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any Federal income tax return and any amendment or supplement thereto, including supporting schedules, attachments, or lists which are supplemental to, or part of, the return for the taxable year; and</text></clause><clause id="HE7CE3BB07E2E45058A0A3265A40F303E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes any information return that reports information that does or may affect the liability for tax for the taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86FF817CF6C547ECAF5363772617F1DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supervising ethics office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of the definition of <quote>qualified blind trust</quote> in this section, the term <term>supervising ethics office</term> in section 13104(f)(3) of this title means the Director of the Office of Government Ethics.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDFD837F30DA84345A1FD0F95E151CEE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of disclosure to sitting President and Vice President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who is serving as the President or the Vice President on the date of the enactment of this Act shall submit a disclosure of financial interests under section 13147 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section, not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H521ED410C40F41ACA121C16D8EEA58E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Office of Government Ethics shall issue rules for the implementation of section 13147 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0412D702AA4B488E800F36FA1B886ED8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for subchapter III of such title is amended by adding at the end the following item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8C2A2A8697704E7D8632904F41FD6CBE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">13147. Financial interests of the President and the Vice President.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

