<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5CB79F46F34E4860BB90176977E14678" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5886 IH: Warrior Road Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5886</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000622">Mr. Patronis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prioritize highway improvement projects that promote national defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2A9B01FE0F649E48CB344CE48184FE8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H50E2D1550C064865ACB53C44D19263E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Warrior Road Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HABE228019ED34BCAA33E6F9A727412E1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Civil defense</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 310 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>to consult, from time to time, with the Federal Civil Defense Administrator relative to the civil defense aspects of highways so constructed or reconstructed</quote> and inserting <quote>to develop a priority listing containing the 3 highest priority projects from each State relative to the civil defense aspects of highways so constructed or reconstructed. At least every 2 years, the Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to consider whether to update such listing or to reprioritize projects. The Secretary shall submit each listing, and any update carried out pursuant to this section, in an electronic format to each Member of Congress</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HF8682604EF7D45A1911BD45061B5BF3F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on highway improvement projects that promote national defense</header> 
<subsection id="HCB0A53115E204C54BC8F06AA4B9ED514"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of War, shall submit to Congress, including in an electronic format to each Member of Congress, a report that contains a list of highway improvement projects that—</text> <paragraph id="H796DC8A40323436B8D0FE9B08470726B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>would promote national defense consistent with the core purposes of highway funding; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4572383B02F41C793C19BDD2ECF01A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are designated as important to national defense pursuant to section 210 of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H85A7A67F83A44850B06D406086981B5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Highest priority projects in each State</header><text>The list compiled pursuant to subsection (a) shall include not less than 3 of the highest priority projects in each State.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HE088DDCEFD2B47E49B71EC0EFD3AB72A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prioritizing funding for national defense</header> 
<subsection id="H1EE0386CF0014BF8A15CD80CA9459897"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Discretionary grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding discretionary grants under title 23, United States Code, the Secretary of Transportation shall give priority to projects designated as important to national defense pursuant to section 210 of title 23, United States Code, and projects designated under section 311 of title 23, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H11317558154A4375BF7B4C419746E680"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Apportionment funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for disbursement of funds under section 104 of title 23, United States Code, a State or metropolitan planning organization shall ensure that such State or organization will give priority to projects designated as important to national defense pursuant to section 210 of title 23, United States Code, and projects designated under section 311 of title 23, United States Code.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H38A31751CEEB4C03BFFC1D0B5F3A3B65"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definition of State</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 23, United States Code.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

