<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB28801F817894BE8A229B147A93590B6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8426 IH: Crime Survivor Support and Stability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8426</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage States to provide rights to survivors of violence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE97A00BA534A43BDBD9880F794EC3194" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H89CAEDCB89CC48B39644AD244DF5A5DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crime Survivor Support and Stability Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HBBDA88ED64184199996AF0675DB5EDE2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rights of survivors of violence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that each State should review and revise, if necessary, its laws to ensure that survivors of violence receive the healing, safety, and support they require after a victimization, taking into account the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEB6919A1DC0D48FB9B0F9BE2B5C147D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A survivor of violence should be accorded the following rights:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H43CC200FFC8340248CEE87F0772767E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A right to trusted and accessible community-based help to heal from trauma, including for adult and minor survivors.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89BCF4B56E22457ABC60539110DD7308"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A right to programs that offer emergency and flexible financial help quickly, without burdensome administrative or exclusionary restrictions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40898162A9834A2BB8D8ACA19EB3E06F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A right to stable housing, including the right to break a lease without penalty, or be protected from eviction.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DE18632C3434C5895C9CDABCEEB8556"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A right to paid and job-protected leave time off from work to address safety, medical, financial, emotional, and other recovery, healing, and safety needs related to the victimization.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB303D200578B45AB9BE65E179E63868A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A right to debt forgiveness and financial recovery in the case of a debt that is related to the victimization.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9623F079B09E496C99E5897380A62365"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A right to legal assistance related to housing, job, immigration, or family legal issues.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0783B0755C4E4ECDB5D627E30A868605"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A right to request and access community-based alternative accountability or resolution processes, instead of prosecution in the criminal justice system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD8E308B18E8453386F35C7506956838"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A right to protection from arrest or conviction for survivors criminalized as a result of victimization, and to mitigated sentencing and record clearance for convicted survivors whose offense was related to trauma.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA5FF4F5083A435A980656DC6A09F01A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The rights of a survivor of violence under paragraph (1) should not be contingent on or in any way limited or restricted by the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HC1EAEF7377074D6BAF9909B39970FB87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A condition that the survivor or anyone else has reported the victimization to a law enforcement agency, court, or other local, State, or Federal agency designated to investigate or prosecute crimes, abuse, or violence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB857F65D3C1544719350C494BA8FC6D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A condition that the survivor or a family member of the survivor cooperate with a law enforcement agency, court, or other local, State, or Federal agency designated to investigate or prosecute crimes, abuse, or violence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B1990ACF84A4CB99D1B85B45B2FC1BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A survivor’s race, religion, national origin, sex, age, disability, sexual orientation, gender identity, marital status, immigration status, housing status, economic status, or family status.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H900D68344ED7458DAA3CF2A638BF2AB6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether a survivor has an arrest or conviction record, is or has been incarcerated, or is or has been under any form of correctional supervision.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30EA296442864175B8A3A956A70B7D0B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any allegation that the survivor contributed to the survivor’s own victimization.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EB415D3BB1F4166BD130E02EDFC647E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The identity of the person who committed the act of the violence (including whether the person is a law enforcement officer) or the relationship of the person to the victim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H17F5E5DCB7BD4538BEEB4ABEDC5378AC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Flexible assistance for survivors of violence</header> <subsection id="H19692785A1BD4280BD6AE060B18D92B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program established</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime of the Department of Justice (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), is authorized to award grants to community-based organizations for the purpose of establishing assistance funds to distribute direct cash assistance to survivors of violence, with the goal of improving safety, healing, and financial stability for survivors of violence, and family members of survivors of violence.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D3ECC348DAA4CF5BB4E75099B1DAA1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible community-based organization seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may reasonably require, including the following:</text> <paragraph id="H72D907D2A8DC4146A997DBA199991FF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the organization’s history serving one or more of the groups described in subsection (e)(4).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46018793CF584492B6F13AB6F0F677FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the community or communities the organization serves are impacted by violence and incarceration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE43FF8D28584C4392AA3D46D4D3D2EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The estimated number of survivors of violence or family members of survivors of violence the organization currently serves.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H513D1D4328F740258C928F2B8EC23BE5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The estimated number of survivors of violence or family members of survivors of violence to whom the organization anticipates it will distribute grant funds.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H074A63C71039463C9DEE50DF12E4ECB7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the organization plans to distribute cash assistance to survivors of violence or family members of survivors of violence to meet their immediate financial needs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF465F64BB544DA58B6738EBA2AC120F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>How the organization plans to minimize the burden on survivors of violence and their family members to provide excessive documentation or paperwork.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2AF3966C61334FCB9BAC0312A267040D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A community-based organization shall be eligible to apply for a grant under this section if the organization has a history of serving survivors of violence, and the majority of people the organization, or a project within the organization that will administer the grant, serves are survivors of violence.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9C6F3B1B8584167A717104E6A1DD7B5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>In administering the grant program under this section, the Director shall do all of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9A704272CDF045E69A134661FBF5A50A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Strive to minimize the paperwork burden on grant applicants and grantees.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23D0C2C28C7E40CE8D82645DDBB8FCBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Strive to develop application, awards, and reporting processes that are accessible to community-based organizations without past experience receiving a Federal grant award.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3104324CEDA94C06B3A31F610AB27104"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Develop a plan to publicize the grant program in advance of an application deadline.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A85EA3AD487480FB03B9FFC86E9128F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provide technical assistance and training opportunities to applicants and grantees.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE9D98E206D64E66A69D795112AD2807"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop tools to support applicants applying for a grant under this section, including, templates and sample applications, which shall be posted prominently on the website of the Office for Victims of Crimes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8C19EC563F94786B6934C40BFEF235A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Develop a website where survivors of violence and members of the public can locate contact information for community-based organizations receiving grants under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2988D8DC18644BD2B56A989CE0209595"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>When considering grant applications, the Director shall give priority to community-based organizations that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B73B09BA66E443BAEE146882C4453A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are located in, serve, and directly employ members of communities that experience disproportionately high rates of gun violence and imprisonment, as compared to such rates nationally, as evidenced by, during the prior 3-year period—</text> <subparagraph id="HD6A25CDE63CE49C8AC4D42A451D71987"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disproportionately high rates of individuals who have been injured or killed by a firearm, as compared to such rates nationally; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA414D6287A174DFC899C62404726E4E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disproportionately high rates of individuals who have been arrested or sent to jail or prison, as compared to such rates nationally;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83BEB8CF5CA84FA9A583C7495B3F570F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are led by, or employ, individuals who are survivors of violence or who are formerly incarcerated;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1804E9235E6849679D75A5BB6CCC2E12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are led by individuals who have proven ties to the community in which the organization operates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98D824701A844689A2757A1B9B79E63D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have a history of providing services focusing on vulnerable survivors of violence, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD807F8FF2FD940B0940847296BA8F1FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>survivors of color;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF649DC1533A450DA66F4EA74BD8E028"><enum>(B)</enum><text>survivors with disabilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF04BCD959164CB1A41958CF71EA490C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>survivors who are transgender or gender nonconforming;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF83F302126B4E0A9C8A0855036D83A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>survivors who have faced disproportionate police contact;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83723E0624A149459925035B96CA4DB3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>survivors who are formerly incarcerated or who have past arrests or convictions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H633FF2AE3F714A16948E576070AB2302"><enum>(F)</enum><text>immigrant survivors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H362A75BF7B514ABE904B4989B8E08D54"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Native American survivors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7BCF4A5C3A64D298294C09CA0F646AF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>survivors who are unhoused;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5116E8D36FF94276AEBAD5B2AD1C3C62"><enum>(I)</enum><text>survivors of firearm injuries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B45CC3C2F29490FBBE6A0D33575F43D"><enum>(J)</enum><text>survivors who have lost a family member to homicide;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6762AACF6E94A028F7AA91CE051CF8C"><enum>(K)</enum><text>low-income survivors; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD93AED97805A4954BA6DE0ACA2160033"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">geographically underserved survivors; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88C53BFA013F4E45A5F18B4E846DF6BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>have leadership that reflects the racial and ethnic diversity of the community in which the organization operates.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6A3D2C3F0CF41288DE7844906DE88D3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Geographic diversity</header><text>In selecting grant recipients, the Director shall ensure that, collectively, grantees represent a diversity of geographic areas.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5EB1FE26E03A4A90A6C2D3076FF9AC42"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="HDE3AFAF027AE4682A60B2818C38F690D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><text>An organization receiving a grant under this section may use the funds as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H1B41C24232CE430CA1A9B51F98E94810"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Distributing unrestricted cash assistance to survivors of violence to meet the financial needs of survivors or to cover the expenses of survivors, which assistance—</text> 
<clause id="H7FA32673D8BD45DFA325ED7907CFA38B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may be distributed at the discretion of the organization and in amounts determined by the organization based on the needs of survivors, and in a way that minimizes or eliminates the burden on survivors to provide external documentation of their needs or expenses;</text></clause> <clause id="HFBD4D16B9DC44942ACAEDE5DAF6119DE"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>may be distributed directly to a survivor, to the parent or guardian of a survivor if the survivor is a minor or dependent adult, or if the survivor or the parent or guardian of a minor or dependent survivor requests, to a vendor, business, or another third party to pay for an expense or purchase a product on a survivor’s behalf; or</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="H2B2763097B8041E48D0A37BC5D4A9758"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may be distributed in the form of cash, electronic transfer, check, direct deposit, prepaid card, or in another similar manner at the discretion of the organization and based on the needs of survivors.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA96779564E5049EEA8DF9C7B682421CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To establish and maintain a program to distribute the assistance described under subparagraph (A), including staffing, training, operational, and evaluation expenses, except that not more than 20 percent of the grant may be used for the purposes under this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE23EC711B0148E0AF906A87BF5123ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Policies and procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A community-based organization receiving a grant under this section shall establish and maintain policies and procedures for distributing cash assistance to survivors of violence that—</text> <subparagraph id="H55DD3C3C8967462C8DF5E1E30F8728EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote the distribution of cash assistance to survivors in a manner that meets the immediate needs of survivors quickly;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FCABF2A69B9482499B89C4BC71F27DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>do not require survivors to engage in other services or programs as a condition of receiving cash assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC5D2BC76EEF4C788DD73D8E075A8F2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>do not require survivors to provide or maintain burdensome documentation of their need or spending;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6336C0A132E54CCB97491419CC36FEAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>do not require survivors to report a crime to a law enforcement agency, court, or other local, State, Tribal, or Federal agency designated to investigate or prosecute crimes, abuse, or violence as a condition of receiving cash assistance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90C7749A685F466F93EF79ABB0B724F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>do not exclude survivors on the basis of citizenship or immigration status; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F104921B2F54A5C856E55521CCF9268"><enum>(F)</enum><text>do not exclude survivors on the basis of an arrest or conviction record, nor on the basis of a survivor’s status under correctional control or supervision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDEBC0B4D9E2F4188B0A7825CE13731E1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Grant duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be for a 4-year period.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H27A87E60C436422BA5082BD006B197E0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>First award</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, not later than 9 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall make the first grant award under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBFBB46C047394C1682CC6DB83F837D31"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Exclusion from income, resources, and assets</header> <paragraph id="H8BFBF84F8ADA49A2B95EB519888E025D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Flexible cash assistance payments excluded from income, resources, and assets for purposes of means tests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than section 1403 of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20102">34 U.S.C. 20102</external-xref>)), for the purpose of any maximum allowed income, resource, or asset eligibility requirement in any Federal, State, or local government program using Federal funds that provides medical or other assistance (or payment or reimbursement of the cost of such assistance), any amount of cash assistance received by a survivor of violence through the grant program established under this section shall not be included for purposes of calculating income, resources, or assets of the survivor, nor shall that amount reduce the amount of the assistance available to the survivor from Federal, State, or local government programs using Federal funds.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61C76F6F8EB04731A0059C6BE0AE9055"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flexible cash assistance payments not considered gross income</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any cash assistance received by a survivor of violence through the grant program established under this section shall be excluded from gross income under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/61">section 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H313B53EC763C4F8A95A3E5DD8FD16C90"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="HA7E7CBC0A49D42B09FE4E5C1381C8236"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to the Director</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving a grant under this section, and annually thereafter, each community-based organization that receives a grant under this section shall submit a report on the use of such grant funds to the Director, as required by the Director. Such report shall, at a minimum, include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3EC533CB5CB14DA39B4CCF5297FE0639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aggregate number of survivors of violence who received cash assistance through the grant program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA77950F62C74EE7AB39D809CA956069"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average amount of assistance each such survivor received through the grant program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD76D9D2A143A42D2BA04A7DFDCF9E8DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the first 4-year grant period under this section ends, and every 4 years thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress a report that, at a minimum, includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HBC938EE582E744D3A5CEF1F04829E8C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any findings resulting from reports submitted to the Director under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD1A1CABAEAB3467FB86FD31EE015141C">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>best practices for grantees under this section to implement flexible cash assistance programs for survivors of violence.</text>
                    </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H74E312934B904322A5A5EF690AC2483A"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Administration and evaluation</header><text>The Director may reserve up to 8 percent of the funds appropriated for the grant program each year for the costs of administering the grant program, including, without limitation, employing personnel, providing technical assistance or training to grantees or prospective grantees, contracting with independent researchers to evaluate the impact of the program, and issuing a report on the impact of the grant program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE21BA7062C624165A0379BE344480AE9"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to implement this section $40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBBF941E051D84597BE9010DD7FA5129D"><enum>4.</enum><header>State level supplemental victim surveys</header> 
<subsection id="H8038FB497FB545749047CF8D26A05C22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics of the Department of Justice (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), shall make grants to States to administer surveys to survivors of violence to determine their needs related to having been survivors of violence.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEACFF9EF30BF4ED4A7199CDFFB2978B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Director shall prioritize awarding grants to recipients that solicit information about one or more of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5081180B173F467EA9E3A515305873EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The types of services survivors of violence received related to having been victimized, and the experiences of such survivors while receiving such services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H170F48A01EBC454492C179F649990070"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether survivors wanted services that they did not receive.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H003087E239AF48A0AE673CE3B4822617"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The experiences of survivors with relocation, eviction, immigration, and housing following victimization.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05CE3203A47B4A54ABCD7DBDF1353342"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The experiences of survivors with the use of force by and injury caused by law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H705217893C124F09BD8F61485BF40E58"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prevalence of victimization and the post-victimization needs of—</text> <subparagraph id="HA135DB9C6B174DFD8F3F4F812472D737"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals who have been arrested or convicted of crimes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5479C185E8214683AA9EF3684EBE5218"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals who are unhoused; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDAE34EC6316147C5BF357D61091C09BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals who are living in institutions, including prisons, jails, medical or nursing facilities, or mental health facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H389731FE86F0460CA1FF669471441291"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="HD4EB48432B0A4950B68436702952B3CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, each State that receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Director a report documenting the results and findings from the survey funded by the grant.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FFEF941E9E64C85871BBD126C8E997E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication by Director</header><text>The Director shall make publicly available on the website of the Bureau of Justice Statistics the reports submitted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H559F4FCC99504772A24D869C7AA37EF4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2031.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE35A1FD571844C8A9F7DC683456445FB" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2337DC820AA94DF285DFE39754E8DB67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community-based organization</header><text>The term <term>community-based organization</term> means a nonprofit, nongovernmental, or Tribal organization that serves a specific geographic community. Such term does not include any law enforcement agency or any court, or any other local, State, or Federal agency designated to investigate or prosecute crimes, abuse, or violence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H235B5D54865F49F093B8A9C904776F26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Family member</header> <subparagraph id="H3ECC845EAD624105A6E2256C727EC1B9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>family member</term> means, with respect to an individual, any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H5657B04F3AE049A4BD40BCEB3387BD99"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A child (whether a biological, foster, adoptive, or step relationship), or a person who is under the legal guardianship of the individual or to whom the individual stands in loco parentis or has stood in loco parentis.</text></clause> <clause id="H629398C0C46A4110A5292F78D56D9028"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A biological, adoptive, or foster parent, stepparent, or legal guardian of an individual or an individual’s spouse or domestic partner, or a person who stood in loco parentis when the individual or the individual’s spouse or domestic partner was a minor child.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8AE579D268CB4AC0981F70EFAE2D85B6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A person to whom the individual is legally married under the laws of any State, or a domestic partner.</text></clause> <clause id="H6761B082DFAC4389A6FAF10AD51FDF84"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A grandparent, grandchild, or sibling (whether a biological, foster, adoptive, or step relationship) of the individual or of the individual’s spouse or domestic partner.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB680355EF0A04D4ABD58D294A974FF03"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A person who lives in the same household as the individual.</text></clause> <clause id="H5C8E0424EABC4BF9ACE15DAD164D2EF5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any other individual related by blood, adoption, or marriage or whose close association with the individual is the equivalent of a family relationship.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H09640B22FAF947BA994761710F7FDA98"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such term does not include a person who has committed an act or conduct described in clause (i) through (vi) of subparagraph (A) against the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A8376D113414D90B86B4C54183CF6FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Survivor of violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>survivor of violence</quote> means an individual against whom any of the following have been committed:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5DA71B44FD994804BF3E571750121443"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An act or conduct during which another person—</text> <clause id="HB7EF973B25454F16917F20A8265C2497"><enum>(i)</enum><text>caused or threatened to cause bodily injury to that individual;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDCC359574C3F4571ABCC4EEDC83C7AF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exhibited, drew, brandished, or used a firearm, or other weapon, against that individual; or</text></clause> <clause id="H91939B4DD7B749139CD31C008FA86779"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>used, or threatened to use, force against that individual to cause injury or death.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF365DA21C7FF4BB6AB6CE7EEC3A4CA2A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Dating violence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H11AD0FC6846B4BA3A8874EA8BC426B76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Domestic violence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H92769199B8544F8E89E86A4AEF88B235"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Family violence.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F4EB87433834C7DAFE4DD6A860773FE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Sexual assault.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F3B8969CF6F471B9171E4C49389F281"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Sexual harassment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H467DEA9BFA18402E8BF26611AC093CF5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Trafficking.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA66C20BB04024CFC83077E6CB9455676"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Stalking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFD3C8167A6B40528B8BC3649467F8A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>Tribal organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

