<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM25B61-4NF-3D-1WN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3252 IS: FSMA Fee Technical Corrections Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3252</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To make technical corrections to amendments made by the FDA Food Safety Modernization Act to allow the Food and Drug Administration to assess and collect food-related reinspection fees and recall fees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>FSMA Fee Technical Corrections Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd00c51439ec34da48772b3672e885dbf"><enum>2.</enum><header>Food-related fees</header><subsection id="id5f1d9e55defd4c568e9b5bb0d6299552"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 743(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-31">21 U.S.C. 379j–31(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c83d91194f046c29a5a86f17a9d7b52"><paragraph id="idc1380fa3a6cd43c0b17818d79bd70f67"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fee methodology; fee amounts</header><subparagraph id="idce3a95f8aed44b2daa90e1257e53a6cc"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to adjustments made by the Secretary in accordance with subparagraph (B), fees established for a fiscal year—</text><clause id="id3aa0ba00270e4f94afab41cb9e90ce24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under subsection (a)(1)(A) shall be in the amount equal to $15,000, multiplied, for fiscal year 2026 and each subsequent fiscal year, by the adjustment factor described in subsection (c)(3);</text></clause><clause id="id7bd30b27a46e411a9ccb522c1ee20cfa"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under subsection (a)(1)(B) shall be in the amount equal to $15,000, multiplied, for fiscal year 2026 and each subsequent fiscal year, by the adjustment factor described in subsection (c)(3);</text></clause><clause id="id5289dd65adc84d7e9ef8ce76aeb84cfc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>under subsection (a)(1)(C) shall be based on the Secretary's estimate of 100 percent of the costs of the activities described in such subsection for such fiscal year; and</text></clause><clause id="id88a6d2c3f26e445dadc58bd31951d7cd"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>under subsection (a)(1)(D) shall be in the amount equal to $15,000, multiplied, for fiscal year 2026 and each subsequent fiscal year, by the adjustment factor described in subsection (c)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc3e7896c9a6645bfb7b749ef60b67ec2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other considerations</header><clause id="idf0e86ecc44f14b1eb7cebc14b5bcde49"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Fee adjustment for small businesses</header><subclause id="iddd4338ec715b4d398d0491ee69b7f24d"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a facility or importer that, at the time of the reinspection or recall order, is a small business as defined in subsection (a)(2)(E), the amount of the fee under subparagraph (A), (B), or (D) of subsection (a)(1), for a fiscal year, shall be adjusted to be equal to <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the amount of the fee calculated under clause (i), (ii), or (iv) of subparagraph (A), as applicable, for such fiscal year.</text></subclause><subclause id="id518efd2ddd5b43dfb53a70b66f7dfa73"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Publication of schedule</header><text>The schedule of such adjusted fee amounts shall be published annually with the user fee notice under subsection (e).</text></subclause><subclause id="id91c70d80980146fbab429c5db3111e25"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>FSMA Fee Technical Corrections Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall publish guidance to describe how a food facility or importer may request a fee reduction under this clause, which shall be issued for immediate implementation to facilitate timely fee reductions, as applicable.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id969f1440af5f4e85aacf7a92731d4044"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Voluntary qualified importer program</header><text>In establishing the fee amounts under subparagraph (A)(iii) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall provide for the number of importers who have submitted to the Secretary a notice under section 806(c) informing the Secretary of the intent of such importer to participate in the program under section 806 in such fiscal year.</text></clause><clause id="id484deedb1f43419aa5f93bb92ce31bfc"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Crediting of carryover fees</header><text>In establishing the fee amounts under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall provide for the crediting toward fee revenue of estimated carryover fee collections from the previous fiscal year if the Secretary overestimated the amount of fees needed to carry out activities described in paragraph (3) for such previous year, and shall account for any adjustment of fees under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idbd82dc7e98d8416abb2cb475f7cf7894"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of fees</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 743(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-31">21 U.S.C. 379j–31(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66438f160264493cb0aa0b8737e4e7a3"><paragraph id="id5ff164b00da743608b21478d29404890"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of fees</header><subparagraph id="id2c667022e17f4cec92857be044d5d1f1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Oversight of facilities and importers</header><text>Fees collected pursuant to subparagraphs (A), (B), and (D) of subsection (a)(1) shall be available solely for the costs of oversight of foreign and domestic facilities and importers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0e97939b661f41ada2f4f81616078a96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Voluntary qualified importer program</header><text>Fees collected pursuant to subparagraph (C) of subsection (a)(1) shall be available solely for the costs of the voluntary qualified importer program under section 806.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id7c43928115cd44b1a11191dd3fc24699"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation on amount</header><text>Section 743(c)(4)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-31">21 U.S.C. 379j–31(c)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id65b7471f5bbe4562ab8b200bb3dfe337"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>$20,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$25,000,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23eb65a2595f4c3bb626dd25b6dfffde"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>$25,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$30,000,000</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5966fb22cde348a18ab9d742575af4e9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of reinspection</header><text>Section 743(a)(2) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/379j-31">21 U.S.C. 379j–31(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddede2167f2bf4774a6a20e33e3b8f63c"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subparagraph (A) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5aaab65e7ec4414b25af90547ecf8c4"><subparagraph id="id97d846bfae0c4e4db25419662b0b5d6c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>reinspection</term> means—</text><clause id="idbd316983cfd248fea94bde01b99a0518"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to domestic and foreign facilities, 1 or more inspections conducted under section 704 subsequent to an inspection conducted under such provision which identified noncompliance resulting in a classification of <quote>official action indicated</quote>, specifically to determine whether compliance has been achieved to the Secretary’s satisfaction; and</text></clause><clause id="id2e7506cf5af04aae8f6fd70b2dd5e359"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to importers, 1 or more inspections conducted under the foreign supplier verification program under section 805 subsequent to an inspection conducted under such provision which identified noncompliance resulting in a classification of <quote>official action indicated</quote>, specifically to determine whether compliance has been achieved to the Secretary’s satisfaction;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id585c8ec2a2924ff8a1a5737bda92c0b4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(ii), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6eb6e53debde4b47878c3149a699ebe2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfeb84e352fcf4473b48c553054ffed9e"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51388369d67d4550a7fc333c8887996d"><subparagraph id="id43e644ad1b4f4e55a4a20136a3e23de3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>importer</term> means an importer of human or animal food that is subject to the foreign supplier verification program requirements under section 805; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6e3e27e09cc4455af34b08e6b24de53"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>small business</term> means—</text><clause id="id0948b1dbe06d4494b2d8430ac3d363d0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a domestic or foreign facility, a business (including any subsidiaries or affiliates) employing fewer than 500 full-time equivalent employees;</text></clause><clause id="idf673738946b34bb28350ef3c58439e3e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to an importer of human food, an importer (including any subsidiaries and affiliates) averaging less than $1,000,000 per year, adjusted for inflation, during the 3-year period preceding the applicable calendar year, in sales of human food combined with the United States market value of human food imported, manufactured, processed, packed, or held without sale (such as food imported for a fee); and</text></clause><clause id="id05f22b4365e64ab7b167cfd173f648b9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to an importer of animal food, an importer (including any subsidiaries and affiliates) averaging less than $2,500,000 per year, adjusted for inflation, during the 3-year period preceding the applicable calendar year, in sales of animal food combined with the United States market value of animal food imported, manufactured, processed, packed, or held without sale (such as food imported for a fee).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

