<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAED22EB706FE4FB9854C51230BFBC4B7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7705 IH: Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7705</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat Indian Tribal Governments in the same manner as State governments for certain Federal tax purposes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H49BFD1010D164AA38D9EEA1E68C2D71C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H50630B57DA3C405E997A0502AD3DCC53" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HCF594DE2944643D0AD87FAB1918193DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Tax and Investment Reform Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6996F8BCCD044507B25877DBDACE2D4D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H50630B57DA3C405E997A0502AD3DCC53" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H5A313555441A46D9A7FC5CF5E2673470" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF1EFD6AD00CC49778F617C56CBBB5335" level="section">Sec. 3. Treatment of Indian tribes as States with respect to excise taxes and bond issuance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDFFCE5E41C4C44168FF8E5BAD9EF3452" level="section">Sec. 4. Treatment of pension and employee benefit plans maintained by Tribal Governments.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8D6CDE42DDCE4AC0A370BFE4D92FB4C2" level="section">Sec. 5. Treatment of Tribal foundations and charities like charities funded and controlled by other governmental funders and sponsors.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3A815F4CB5804A80B38F8A1E50731082" level="section">Sec. 6. New markets tax credit for tribal area investments.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HCAF91E7C014346A68C7CFF9C8D827B56" level="section">Sec. 7. Inclusion of Indian areas as difficult development areas for purposes of certain buildings.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H37620BC44EA6481B83A57AAD78B432C1" level="section">Sec. 8. Tribal general welfare and trust programs clarification.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HDED913D9A86A4248A76502C98C0B02AC" level="section">Sec. 9. Indian employment tax credit.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HB1D37586E0E64EEEBBB4DE6D30DB952D" level="section">Sec. 10. Exclusion from gross income for payments under Indian health service loan repayment program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA8DD79530B924C9D887ABEDBF87625A6" level="section">Sec. 11. Exclusion of certain amounts received under Indian Health Professions Scholarships Program.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H5A313555441A46D9A7FC5CF5E2673470" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H199A9018441A45A3B7DC70DEC53F80D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is a unique Federal legal and political relationship between the United States and Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H5313DF9A61824E5DA49317FB0D264C3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Indian Tribes have the responsibility and authority to provide governmental programs and services to Tribal citizens, develop Tribal economies, and build community infrastructure to ensure that Indian reservation lands serve as livable, permanent homes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09ACC95A98124CEFAC2606329A51844C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Constitution, United States Federal Court decisions, Executive orders, and numerous other Federal laws and regulations recognize that Indian Tribes are governments, retaining the inherent authority to tax and operate as other governments, including (inter alia) financing projects with government bonds and maintaining eligibility for general tax exemptions via their government status.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCE3731E31CAD4412AD079CFF9EE2D9B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Codifying tax parity with respect to Tribal Governments is consistent with Federal treaties recognizing the sovereignty of Tribal Governments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51771042217D4F06B3017621BB107945"><enum>(5)</enum><text>That Indian Tribes face historic disadvantages in accessing the underlying capital to build the necessary infrastructure for job creation, and that certain statutory restrictions on Tribal governance further inhibit Tribes’ ability to develop strong governance and economies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9ACB6B516E4A4EA2B4865112EBE63E1E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Indian Tribes are sometimes excluded from the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 in key provisions which results in unfair tax treatment for Tribal citizens or unequal enforcement authority for Tribal enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6202C53E2715469E91BDCD6CB36BEBB6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Congress is vested with the authority to regulate commerce with Indian Tribes, and hereby exercises that authority in a manner which furthers Tribal self-governance, and in doing so, further affirms the United States government-to-government relationship with Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF1EFD6AD00CC49778F617C56CBBB5335"><enum>3.</enum><header>Treatment of Indian tribes as States with respect to excise taxes and bond issuance</header> 
<subsection id="H1B8FF00F9C314EBDBB6EDE1567E33074" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of essential governmental function requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7871">Section 7871</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subsections (b) and (e) and redesignating subsections (c), (d), and (f) as subsections (b), (c), and (d), respectively.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H184B0B59DE164139B176176CF3742DAC"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Special rules for tax-Exempt bonds</header> <text>Subsection (b) of section 7871 of such Code, as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended to read as follows:</text>
                <quoted-block id="H8974F6EBD4374E889D44806E1EC08F55" style="OLC">
                    <subsection id="HB133DA50AFC744ADA843CA135FAC692F">
                        <enum>(b)</enum>
                        <header>Special rules for tax-Exempt bonds</header>
                        <paragraph id="H3213453152984885B33C87597D197BF2">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>In applying section 146 to bonds issued by Indian Tribal Governments—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="HFCB72D3726704B1A824305BEA745D413">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>there shall be a national bond volume cap for each calendar year after 2026 equal to $400,000,000, and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="HD4EE7BABE2F14ED3826E19546EF814BC">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the volume cap for any Indian Tribal Government shall be the portion of such national bond volume cap which is allocated by the Secretary (under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe) to such Indian Tribal Government.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H8FC7AB2D525442F088304475B30432AA">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Application of geographic restriction</header>
 <text>In the case of national bond volume cap allocated under paragraph (1), section 146(k)(1) shall not apply to the extent that such cap is used with respect to financing for a facility located on qualified Indian lands.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HEE65C8B6E15E4E47998EAF6CD21C706D">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
                            <header>Restriction on financing of certain gaming facilities</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No portion of proceeds from an obligation issued by an Indian Tribal Government (or subdivision thereof) under section 103 may be used with respect to the financing of any portion of a building in which class II or class III gaming (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2703">25 U.S.C. 2703</external-xref>)) is conducted or housed or any property actually used in the conduct of such gaming.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H3A6C846F990B4F9E89BC218AD0392129">
                            <enum>(4)</enum>
                            <header>Definitions and special rules</header>
                            <subparagraph id="HBA3A197CC7D54F9DAF6E61694198F08E">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
                                <header>Indian Tribal Government</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, subsection (e), and so much of subsection (a) as relates to paragraph (4) of such subsection, the term <term>Indian Tribal Government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>), including any agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of such governing body, and, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, any entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="HC70EE76843FB4154A01A561D4917DF2F">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Qualified Indian lands</header>
 <text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified Indian lands</term> means—</text>
                                <clause id="HA5EBB6A398C84F0A924166821E00949D">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian lands within the meaning of section 29(j)(8) of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3722b">15 U.S.C. 3722b(j)(8)</external-xref>),</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H4E1755A36A7346FB86371560EAC84E31" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>land held in fee simple by an Indian Tribal Government,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H5AB3833CF999495AB0542CCE3DB535EE">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each region in effect under subsection (a) or (b) of section 7 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606</external-xref>),</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H3DE01B47FF734AE183FDE0AC50CF8F00">
                                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hawaiian Home Lands (as defined in section 801 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221</external-xref>)), and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H1AA1DC43F37A4472ABC298CE4F15FDB4">
                                    <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, lands where the facility is to be placed in service in connection with—</text>
                                    <subclause id="HA7C935FBA3114E349463954738A1CA4F">
                                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the active conduct of a trade or business by an Indian Tribe on, contiguous to, within reasonable proximity of, or with a substantial connection to lands described in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv), or</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <subclause id="H48901367B52D492BBF631FB40CB3879E">
                                        <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">infrastructure (including roads, power lines, water systems, railroad spurs, and communication facilities) serving lands described in clause (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv).</text>
                                    </subclause>
                                    <continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">Such term
                                        shall not include any land which is not within the United
                                        States.</continuation-text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="H7E51DC9F098941C0B656BB1F965DAF66" commented="no">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
                                <header>Intertribal consortia, etc</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, an Indian Tribal Government (including any subdivision thereof), or any combination of such Indian Tribal Governments operating pursuant to a written agreement, may authorize any person to plan for, coordinate or otherwise administer services, finances, functions, or activities on its behalf under this subsection, except that the authorized person shall have the rights and responsibilities of the authorizing Indian Tribal Government (or Indian Tribal Governments) only to the extent provided in the authorizing resolution.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="HFDAAEB7E821D4983871341B6B82CCC8E">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
                                <header>Inflation adjustment</header>
 <text>In the case of any calendar year after 2027, the $400,000,000 amount in paragraph (1)(A) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
                                <clause id="H763EE68ABD9B4167B820652614A26D5F">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </clause> <clause id="H97B8DBEFA9AD4D23945FEEB6ACC4FED7"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting <quote>calendar year 2026</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text>
                                </clause>
                                <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">If any
                                    increase determined under the preceding sentence is not a
                                    multiple of $100,000, such increase shall be rounded to the
                                    nearest multiple of $100,000.</continuation-text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9B2F86781E5240DEAB5672C62179EF2C">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-Exempt bonds</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7871 of such Code, as amended by subsection (a), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1593C82BB0194D91887D19AFF6A06522"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <subsection id="HA0C0CB708F1043D6B3DBC2F216F7CAEB">
                        <enum>(e)</enum>
                        <header>Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-Exempt bonds</header>
                        <paragraph id="H4750D2E450E34580842883B9463D4A93">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
                            <header>Bonds treated as exempt from tax</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-exempt bond—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="H5315CA288C03486492699559A7CA7860">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>such bond shall be treated for purposes of this title in the same manner as if such bond were issued by an Indian Tribal Government, and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="H8DFB1674EF344C71918240E3B0204B50">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in applying section 146 to any issuer of such bond—</text> <clause id="H3CA71A646F62454A8732DD884169FBE3"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>there shall be a national bond volume cap for each calendar year after 2026 equal to $45,000,000, and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H99654DE78E6C45408BB2CCDDF26BF8EA">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the volume cap of such issuer shall be the portion of such national bond volume cap which is allocated by the Secretary (under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe) to such issuer.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HDE1BB718C86D41F391FFDE1ABECD7BC2" commented="no">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-exempt bond</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="HF97C0217317E4F049D68EDD51A9BA92C" commented="no">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-exempt bond</term> means any bond issued by an Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium if—</text>
                                <clause id="HD0DC4301092E41D29BF8A75A85F44838" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>such bond is a qualified bond (as defined in section 141(e), determined without regard to paragraph (2) thereof),</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H269DAFB7107941DAB3DB8DE968EE14A6">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>none of the net proceeds of such bond are used for the purpose of providing any facility, project, or program for which the proceeds of any bond to which subsection (b) applies are also used, and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H2170F57080924A85989023BEB990CCB2">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>such bond is designated as an Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-exempt bond by such Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="HB2ED253E7FA04648BFB596F1E5569B7E">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Exceptions</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-exempt bond</term> shall not include any bond issued as part of an issue if—</text>
                                <clause id="H316BC67D84D9438098E9DDD85C2DDEB1">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any portion of the proceeds of such issue are used to finance any portion of a building in which class II or class III gaming (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act) is conducted or housed or any other property actually used in the conduct of such gaming, or</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H6968DE2921AC4AD7916D67FE09350A8D">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>any portion of the proceeds of such issue are used to provide (including the provision of land for) any private or commercial golf course, country club, massage parlor, hot tub facility, suntan facility, racetrack or other facility used for gambling, or any store the principal business of which is the sale of alcoholic beverages for consumption off premises.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="H7866C2586A0B40E4857EBD64EB5CAEAA">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
                                <header>Limitation on amount of bonds designated</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum aggregate face amount of bonds issued by any Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium which may be designated by such Consortium under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall not exceed the amount of national Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-exempt bond limitation allocated to such Consortium under paragraph (1).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H022546793D0D49C8A6FD2FC08BF9B624">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
                            <header>Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium</header>
 <text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H9AFDF0BB301B4B5181D794B55157840C"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>The term <term>Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium</term> means—</text>
                                <clause id="HCF8FE3511B754AB287A7D94D5D363452">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>any combination of Alaska Native Tribal Governments operating pursuant to a written agreement, and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H84B6F774B879484290350BB0783DFC50">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>any Alaska Native regional non-profit organization.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB550B07607141618697B84236E5249E"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Alaska Native Tribal Government</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Alaska Native Tribal Government</term> means any Indian Tribal Government with respect to one or more regions in effect under subsection (a) or (b) of section 7 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606</external-xref>).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="HDF7DD43F50344EA2A9111D764749DD6C">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
                                <header>Alaska Native regional non-profit organization</header>
 <text>The term <term>Alaska Native regional non-profit organization</term> means—</text>
                                <clause id="H716088087F0E447EB3DE04226339502D">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Aleutian Pribilof Islands Association, Inc.,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H586323C74A5841B290E3BEABD9AFB28C">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the Arctic Slope Native Association,</text> </clause> <clause id="HDA4A16049A5D445DAB46C1481C1F9A68"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>the Association of Village Council Presidents,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H61037A235CD543F380B45429CD6A65BA">
                                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>the Bristol Bay Native Association,</text> </clause> <clause id="HA2434D46703745D083EE2D0C3391703E"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>the Chugachmiut, Inc.,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H7522CEEA1B294CFEB9422E782C6BE350">
                                    <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>the Cook Inlet Tribal Council,</text> </clause> <clause id="H65F6F68A35F245D3A1F5377ACDD3CE75"> <enum>(vii)</enum> <text>the Copper River Native Association,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H7162ED15199D4FEDAC0411A55C0CD3B0">
                                    <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text>the Kawerak, Inc.,</text> </clause> <clause id="HE0F810DAA86B4DC898D3F95FD5283737"> <enum>(ix)</enum> <text>the Kodiak Area Native Association,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H93135BE1AF3A4CD4A899FB27584F391C">
                                    <enum>(x)</enum>
 <text>the Maniilaq,</text> </clause> <clause id="H0BDD06A2BE524BF0A1A0E21D63EC5F9F"> <enum>(xi)</enum> <text>the Tanana Chiefs Conference,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HD9D9C5C9095E41798705B94957A4DB82">
                                    <enum>(xii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Alaska Native Tribal Health Consortium,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H69BE7CB5E9E049DFA5FD2469BDCECFC9">
                                    <enum>(xiii)</enum>
 <text>the Bristol Bay Area Health Corporation,</text> </clause> <clause id="HA6A7F371A1EA4C6CB5AE416D1137ABE6"> <enum>(xiv)</enum> <text>the Norton Sound Health Corporation,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HA3446CE32F9B417CA5FE5101346D8BBE">
                                    <enum>(xv)</enum>
 <text>the Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium,</text> </clause> <clause id="H4037A6BE461B4BE58EDFFF936659DE0F"> <enum>(xvi)</enum> <text>the Yukon Kuskokwim Health Corporation, and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="H112C70752B044BF48F1D20EFEB89BEDB">
                                    <enum>(xvii)</enum>
 <text>under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, such other organizations as may be identified by the Secretary, upon request by an Indian Tribal Government and after consultation with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, as Alaska Native regional non-profit organizations for purposes of this subsection.</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H162F491860DA463784002787BC48A34B">
                            <enum>(4)</enum>
                            <header>Application of certain rules regarding intertribal
                                consortia</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rules of subsection (b)(4)(C) shall apply with respect to Alaska Native Intertribal Consortiums under this subsection in the same manner such rules apply to Indian Tribal Governments under subsection (b).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H90862A57822249A589FA5DB054696D06">
                            <enum>(5)</enum>
                            <header>Special rules for Alaska Native Corporation</header>
                            <subparagraph id="HF5C6F2545D6448FA89D39D2744351F7B">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any Alaska Native Corporation participates with respect to any bond, such bond shall not be treated as an Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium tax-exempt bond unless such Corporation provides a written certification to the Secretary that the facilities or services provided with the proceeds of such bond will promote the economic, social, or cultural well-being of such Corporation’s shareholders pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="H69CCF3AACC8D487A9F9486E85043AE61">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
                                <header>Participation</header>
 <text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), an Alaska Native Corporation shall be treated as participating with respect to any bond if such Corporation—</text>
                                <clause id="HF6F04A86ED8243FCA133386175409364">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is part of any Alaska Native regional non-profit organization which is part of the Alaska Native Intertribal Consortium that issues such bond,</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HF8C4B2C470644F27A289A126F851759C">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>is authorized pursuant to paragraph (4) to provide any service described in subsection (b)(4)(C) with respect to such bond, or</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="HE2677775266849EBAB83DD0B3B5656DB">
                                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>receives any of the proceeds of such bond.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1303A2D67364E8A84EE54CF4EE9781A"> <enum>(C)</enum> <header>Alaska Native Corporation</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>Alaska Native Corporation</term> means any Regional Corporation, any Village Corporation, any Urban Corporation, and any Group Corporation (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H5DDABE10F19B41BDA062B54EC2C26AB1">
                            <enum>(6)</enum>
                            <header>Inflation adjustment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any calendar year after 2027, the $45,000,000 amount in paragraph (1)(B)(i) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="HED4B829BEDD3495695DD73C8F2B0D428">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C32478AFD60408CA2D595AAFA064424"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year by substituting <quote>calendar year 2026</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">If any increase
                                determined under the preceding sentence is not a multiple of
                                $100,000, such increase shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of
                                $100,000.</continuation-text>
                        </paragraph>
                    </subsection>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H76F7899AB086482380603F049BAFF7D0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of tribal economic development bonds</header><text>Section 7871(d)(3) of such Code, as amended by subsection (a), is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7485E2A7F0F5445C97A6487F0160687D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HB91F5CD24374400B9BB22353F89B5975"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>tribal economic development bond</term> shall not include any bond issued after December 31, 2029.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAC3E6060E2E94B8F8878B70636CCA146"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="HA79928E9AC254AFAB7C398B1414C13F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 7871(a) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B08364680EF405DB0B228704C757693"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by striking <quote>subject to subsection (b),</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89E32BBD746A4EBA811AC0E6FBEEC9AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28D45E619E3B4CA6842C6FA70E566118"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 45(c)(9)(B) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC29EE19974464A79979148296A5C2CD5" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="HA8E5B459A679498F95C9E5EF4746711B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means any Indian Tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD28E735CF16749BB92BA72C5725C04D1" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <paragraph id="H295E4C346923478E84558E7C6975A532"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this section shall apply to obligations issued in calendar years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H594C45F71A7C42D8AE27062C08615368"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excise taxes</header><text>The amendments made by subsections (a) and (e)(1)(A) shall take effect on and after the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning more than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="HDFFCE5E41C4C44168FF8E5BAD9EF3452"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of pension and employee benefit plans maintained by Tribal Governments</header> <subsection id="H0A1F70FE3AF5415A97D44AB8F1650159"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment of plans</header> <paragraph id="H2925CF0B547C4E7DBE24632974C985BD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified public safety employee</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/72">Section 72(t)(10)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (defining qualified public safety employee) is amended by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF94430E08C4E4D769B43C9AE7B016D21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>striking <quote>or political subdivision of a State</quote> and inserting <quote>, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribal government</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF0E5F47B4424BE6B7E952774EA17227"><enum>(B)</enum><text>striking <quote>such State or political subdivision</quote> and inserting <quote>such State, political subdivision, or Indian tribal government</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1137FAC8D9F14C1EB39B74A225666CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Governmental plan</header><text>The last sentence of section 414(d) of such Code (defining governmental plan) is amended to read as follows: <quote>The term <term>governmental plan</term> includes a plan established or maintained for its employees by an Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H429827EAC4A44F3AB7F2909B48FB9104"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exempt governmental deferred compensation plan</header><text>Section 3121(v)(3) of such Code (defining governmental deferred compensation plan) is amended by inserting <quote>by an Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing,</quote> after <quote>political subdivision thereof,</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78A60918F50744B685E627124E102282"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grandfather of certain deferred compensation plans</header><text>Section 457 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H89E8A0F667F84AF18C2848933C6669F2" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H892866515CF3464FB3CD88097BE3FE7D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Certain Tribal government plans grandfathered</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Plans established before the date of enactment of this subsection and maintained by an Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing, in compliance with subsection (b) shall be treated as if established by an eligible employer under subsection (e)(1)(A). A plan described in the preceding sentence may, at the election of the employer, continue to be maintained without regard to the preceding sentence or be amended if necessary to be maintained in compliance with this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFCBF8034EA145C6A62FED1C0AE0E2C6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Long-term, part-time workers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401(k)(15)(C) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA996B4013F794FE9A388347BAA08CBBD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HE57430C3E8494232AE1D42FA8366378E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application of standards to certain employees and plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of paragraph (2)(D)(ii) shall not apply to—</text> 
<clause id="H8883F4ECC84B4D9A97B451B50BF376FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employees described in section 410(b)(3), and</text></clause> <clause id="H42D51D26B26148D98CF0C017334F5608"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a governmental plan within the meaning of section 414(d).</text>
                            </clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3FE81167CEAE4096B0F82D92AF244025" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement moratorium related to Pension Protection Act of 2006</header> 
<paragraph id="H0D6E28083DF94337B68FF2D1995EEC5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, and an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing, shall not be subject to a Federal agency enforcement action based solely on the amendments made by the Pension Protection Act of 2006 to the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or the Employee Retirement Income and Security Act of 1974 with respect to any period prior to the publication of regulations with respect to such amendments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29BF14459D91448CA4CCA0CA2EF916F8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian tribal government</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>Indian tribal government</term> has the meaning given such term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(a)(40)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3324FAFE07E4DBC826ED3A78883D10F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Regulatory guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) and the Secretary of Labor shall, in consultation with Tribal Advisory Committee established pursuant to section 3 of the Tribal General Welfare Exclusion Act of 2014 and Indian tribal governments and relevant governmental agencies, issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6B252D1F966B4FF1BB781B9515C13945"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Uniform protections and fiduciary standards for tribal plans</header> <paragraph id="HF0C04F25FF414FF3BE4AF8EF8D534B9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 77 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA0B7DD763F5E4CF0B5C92F7BBD86CF4E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HA0293FAF70EA4384867738B86ECF8EDB" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7531.</enum><header>Uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans</header> 
<subsection id="H9A7D088286A647E29C7D1ACE2B38E2A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Tribal pension plan shall be subject to the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3F726ED1C49F4D08BA945BE4F199EF55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personal liability</header> <paragraph id="H48B03BD9461E4A31A23BBF643D9E6DC0"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Any person who is a fiduciary with respect to a Tribal pension plan who breaches any of the responsibilities, obligations, or duties imposed upon fiduciaries by the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans, shall be personally liable to make good to such plan any losses to the plan resulting from each such breach, and to restore to such plan any profits of such fiduciary which have been made through use of assets of the plan by the fiduciary, and shall be subject to such other equitable or remedial relief as the court may deem appropriate, including removal of such fiduciary.</text>
                                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1515EC098E604A90AF0EF683A0931D63"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No liability for prior breach</header><text>No fiduciary shall be liable with respect to a breach of fiduciary duty under this section if such breach was committed before the fiduciary became a fiduciary or after the fiduciary ceased to be a fiduciary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCFDBB99CA8BD4B8692A48A468305AB74" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header> <paragraph id="HC69B56557680440ABD5CB7745BA04410" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>No interference with protected rights</header> <text>It shall be unlawful for any person to discharge, fine, suspend, expel, discipline, or discriminate against a participant or beneficiary for exercising any right to which the participant or beneficiary is entitled under the provisions of a Tribal pension plan or under the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans, or for the purpose of interfering with the attainment of any right to which such participant or beneficiary may become entitled under such plan or the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans.</text>
                                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HADDAFC8A0A7F44A89DA841734ED4D185" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contributions or benefits provided under a Tribal pension plan shall not discriminate in favor of highly compensated employees (within the meaning of section 414(q)).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F2680B0D4B748CD90BEE98D6BF240AA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF7EB1D40DF864231A1C31C185A87AF40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tribal pension plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal pension plan</term> means any qualified employer retirement plan (as defined in section 72(d)(1)(G)) which—</text> <subparagraph id="H2EBACBA7BE634BAA83FF884AD7769C30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a governmental plan (as defined in section 414(d)),</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7BA75E8514504EAF929A32902ECA18AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has at least 500 active participants, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FDCB2A73D4D41C098D0C2622ABBDD92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is established or maintained for the employees of an Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H70BD8840234B48DCAC08E7F71EA8C1CD">
                                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                                    <header>Uniform protections and fiduciary standards for tribal
                                        pension plans</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans</term> means that in connection with a fiduciary’s duties with respect to a Tribal pension plan the fiduciary shall discharge those duties—</text>
                                    <subparagraph id="H0A28A20CD8FA4FDBA3D2BC29209C51BE">
                                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>solely in the interest of the participants and beneficiaries,</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H4165D378B26C42F4821B9F851BF01F07">
                                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>for the exclusive purpose of providing benefits to participants and beneficiaries,</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H1D5D245058B44187B16515D9110E9312">
                                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to defray reasonable expenses of administering the plan,</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H58279043E33249B9A032B28C7B7519D1">
                                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>with the care, skill, prudence, and diligence under the circumstances then prevailing that a prudent person acting in a like capacity and familiar with such matters would use in the conduct of an enterprise of a like character and with like aims,</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H1B39BDC2609F4F9F9AC885FE9328C324">
                                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>by diversifying the investments of the plan so as to minimize the risk of large losses, unless under the circumstances it is clearly prudent not to do so, and</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                    <subparagraph id="H2B3F5A0113BF4AE4816DA4DCCDC1AD6B">
                                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>in accordance with the documents and instruments governing the plan insofar as such documents and instruments are consistent with the requirements of the preceding subparagraphs.</text>
                                    </subparagraph>
                                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DB7963AC3DF4289A797A8C81A21382A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Control over assets by participant or beneficiary</header><text>In the case of a Tribal pension plan which provides for individual accounts and permits a participant or beneficiary to exercise control over the assets in their account, if a participant or beneficiary exercises control over the assets in their account—</text> <subparagraph id="HA47A9B1951DA46BC9CBA16038F639376" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such participant or beneficiary shall not be deemed to be a fiduciary by reason of such exercise, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD0288114CD347ECA427712438C439DA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no person who is otherwise a fiduciary shall be liable under this section for any loss, or by reason of any breach, which results from such participant’s or beneficiary’s exercise of control.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD467AB522B304D7EBD125E081B79B85E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan administrator for any Tribal pension plan shall cause to be furnished to each participant covered under the plan a summary plan description. The summary plan description and any notice of material modifications shall be provided or made available to participants within a reasonable period following the effective date of a participant’s coverage or the effective date of material changes to the plan, as applicable. The summary plan description shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE3681365C524405FAE0B5FA5990E514F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be written in a manner calculated to be understood by the average plan participant,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF228B7CB5ACC47A295D49B783FCDD58E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be sufficiently accurate and comprehensive to reasonably apprise such participants and beneficiaries of their rights and obligations under the plan, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H241B563691B74AD8A3F34C8CC1DAAF09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>specify any material modification in the terms to the plan made after the previous summary plan description.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE11BF1E72B7747D29E8F344CD9374857"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Persons empowered To bring a civil action</header><text>In the case of a Tribal pension plan, a civil action may be brought—</text> 
<paragraph id="H48F663A440AB409DA539261737B5F251"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by a participant or beneficiary to recover benefits due under the terms of the plan, to enforce rights under the terms of the plan, or to clarify rights to future benefits under the terms of the plan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3180DD5A87E34520AC2BD503E1A2E154"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by a participant, beneficiary, or fiduciary for relief for any loss for which a fiduciary is personally liable under this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86B0F2FEFA9B435493158029348E0FC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by a participant, beneficiary, or fiduciary—</text> <subparagraph id="H9404896CF3AE4ECAB23F357B5C3CAA5C"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>to enjoin any act or practice which violates any provision of the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans, or</text>
                                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8A04D93331E401A86563F25ED502570"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to obtain other appropriate equitable relief—</text> <clause id="H54FBE6E28EB644E9BD919EC214F01565"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to redress such violations, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9A8A9D8578544FB78E4799F66185CE70"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to enforce any provisions of the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans or the terms of the plan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA22DEB12E324461DB180A60F31CF71F7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Status of Tribal pension plan as entity</header><text>A Tribal pension plan may sue or be sued under this section as an entity. Service of summons, subpoena, or other legal process of a court upon a trustee or an administrator of a Tribal pension plan in such capacity shall constitute service upon the Tribal pension plan. Any money judgment under this section against a Tribal pension plan shall be enforceable only against the plan as an entity and shall not be enforceable against any other person or entity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1493B26F9F1841FF8956B7389BE96834"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement actions related to the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans shall be in the applicable Tribal court unless the Indian tribal government has opted to limit Tribal court jurisdiction for such actions in favor of Federal court enforcement. In the absence of an established Tribal court, or for Indian tribal governments who have elected to limit their Tribal court’s jurisdiction to exclude claims for enforcing the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans, a participant or beneficiary may seek enforcement in the district court of the United States for the district where the plan has its principal office, or in the United States District for the District of Columbia. When applicable, the district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction without respect to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBBD8B4FE898949A48005FB773D12FDE0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees and costs</header><text>The court, in its discretion, may allow an award of reasonable attorney’s fees and costs to a participant, beneficiary, or fiduciary who prevails in an action to enforce the uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1F36BD64EB6420292CD02F1BB88E8B7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Coordination with other tribal laws and protections</header><text>Nothing in this section shall preempt or otherwise prevent an Indian Tribe from adopting additional laws and protections not inconsistent with this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3EFC27D437AE466C9CA3112D148D4CA1"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall work with the Tribal Advisory Committee established pursuant to section 3 of the Tribal General Welfare Exclusion Act of 2014, and in consultation with Indian tribal governments and relevant governmental agencies, to develop regulatory guidance under this section, as well as the enforcement of such standards.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62AEB1AD185444279004CE856FC0E8C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for chapter 77 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9738419FCE564631A9CFED38B829A7BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HA0B7DD763F5E4CF0B5C92F7BBD86CF4E" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="HA0293FAF70EA4384867738B86ECF8EDB" level="section">Sec. 7531. Uniform protections and fiduciary standards for Tribal pension plans.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H53DBF82A7BFF4368850354DFF11A155B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The last sentence of section 3(32) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(32)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: <quote>The term <term>governmental plan</term> includes a plan established or maintained for its employees by an Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1394D94B04247E9AB9334D342A9E8AD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H53DB813D243E453782A5BCAD2BCA6379"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transition provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall, in consultation with the Tribal Advisory Committee established under section 3 of the Tribal General Welfare Exclusion Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/139E">26 U.S.C. 139E</external-xref> note), and in consultation with Indian tribal governments, develop guidance on the transition of plans to meet requirements added or changed by the amendments made by this section, including publication of transition relief if appropriate. The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) is authorized to extend deadlines imposed by the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reflect any such transition relief (and to coordinate such transition relief with relevant governmental agencies) as well as time for plan sponsors to adopt amendments and implement required changes.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H8D6CDE42DDCE4AC0A370BFE4D92FB4C2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treatment of Tribal foundations and charities like charities funded and controlled by other governmental funders and sponsors</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HE38F7956F4BA474C91DC9AEA68D70241"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">Section 170(b)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of clause (vi), the term <term>governmental unit</term> includes an Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HE9ACE0E2A37542BEB1F634D605E3DED8"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Certain supporting organizations</header> <text>Section 509(a) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>For purposes of paragraph (3), an organization described in paragraph (2) shall be deemed to include an Indian tribal government, an agency, instrumentality, or subdivision of an Indian tribal government, or an entity established under Federal, State, or Tribal law which is wholly owned or controlled by any of the foregoing.</quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="HD77A72B6EC394A70AE5096B4C541F1AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3A815F4CB5804A80B38F8A1E50731082" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>New markets tax credit for tribal area investments</header> <subsection id="HFD8BD1643E7E4CF585C70BCDF900B593"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional allocations for tribal area</header> <paragraph id="H2E2A07B00E394446BDF3315849FD89DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45D">Section 45D(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H596EF67FB36F4BD59D3B667D1A6488E7" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H22E18BB636EE435A97AC4F43293618E4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional allocations for tribal area investments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2C20E126B325464399A1F0BF11B584BD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of each calendar year after 2026, there is (in addition to any limitation under any other paragraph of this subsection) a new markets tribal area tax credit limitation of $175,000,000 which shall be allocated by the Secretary as provided in paragraph (2) except—</text> <clause id="HE6A164F223384A47A7A89D0E29C698F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that such allocation shall only be allocated with respect to qualified tribal area investments, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1040CA1C66F946BCB33A3853012BF8B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in addition to the priorities described in paragraph (2), the Secretary may give priority to any entity with a record of having successfully provided capital or technical assistance in tribal statistical areas.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67011320081949B7B4CAC9908C9DFFFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Carryover of unused new markets tribal area tax credit limitation</header> <clause id="H988EA62D8DC843C6B8FFD3F579B592A0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the new markets tribal area tax credit limitation under subparagraph (A) for any calendar year exceeds the amount of such limitation allocated by the Secretary for such calendar year, such limitation for the succeeding calendar year shall be increased by the amount of such excess.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFFF47B0352F744EC8B38F3FEE412CE87"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on carryover</header><text>No amount of new markets tribal area tax credit limitation may be carried under clause (i) past the 5th calendar year following the calendar year in which such amount of new markets tribal area tax credit limitation arose.</text></clause> <clause id="HF74409E19CA046278B615B12EA5580FF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Transfer of expired new markets tribal area tax credit limitation to general limitation</header><text>In the case of any amount of new markets tribal area tax credit limitation which would (but for clause (ii)) be carried under clause (i) to the 6th calendar year following the calendar year in which such amount of new markets tribal area credit limitation arose, the new market tax credit limitation under paragraph (1) for such 6th calendar year shall be increased by the amount of such new markets tribal area tax credit limitation.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB9D7709ED3B4033BC9D557E1355AA81"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allocations restricted to qualified tribal area investments</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <clause id="HC73FD17973CC409AA14A554A90C10AAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subsection (b)(2) shall be applied separately with respect to the new markets tax credit limitation under paragraph (1) and the new markets tribal area tax credit limitation under this paragraph,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HACD44BE05834404A8EB882F7B08F695B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any designation under subsection (b)(1)(C) shall indicate the source and amount of the limitation to which such designation relates, and</text></clause> <clause id="H6A0A9C0BB3FD47CE8DEBFD91AD8D5ECE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of any investment which is designated under subsection (b)(1)(C) using amounts of the new market tribal area tax credit limitation allocated under this paragraph, subsection (b)(1)(B) shall be applied by substituting <quote>qualified tribal area investments</quote> for <quote>qualified low-income community investments</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4AAF7A997AF74BCABB8462F53445F99E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Qualified tribal area investments</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>qualified tribal area investment</term> means—</text> <clause id="H100AA0DD93EB4661A6E621E2C572367C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any capital or equity investment in, or loan to, any qualified active tribal community business,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H52E5684846F54E19A0A217E722D4BD09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the purchase from another community development entity of any loan made by such entity which is a qualified tribal area investment,</text></clause> <clause id="HC62229EC6E3A4525B218FB889D949F7C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>financial counseling and other services specified in regulations prescribed by the Secretary to businesses located in, and residents of, tribal statistical areas, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5EDBF8190B5B4BCAA9FFEABFDAD45F14"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any equity investment in, or loan to, any qualified community development entity if substantially all of the proceeds of such investment or loan are used by such qualified community development entity to make qualified tribal area investments.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0935F81C25384351A4903193797B1074"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Qualified active tribal community business</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text> 
<clause id="H6A49F8652D3C4968A0502E0229609D5D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified active tribal community business</term> has the meaning which would be given the term <term>qualified active low-income community business</term> under subsection (d)(2) if <quote>tribal statistical area</quote> were substituted for <quote>low-income community</quote> each place it appears therein.</text></clause> <clause id="H7FD0F8EAF454420A9EF35BF6FB171DCE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain qualified active low-income community businesses which serve tribal areas</header><text>The term <term>qualified active tribal community business</term> includes any qualified active low-income community business which—</text> 
<subclause id="H389ED40ADA9144CBA9537EED121BCC3F" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides good or services to a significant population of Tribal, Alaska Native village, or Native Hawaiian community members, who are residents of a tribal statistical area, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB6E79A778D924BE383CBF969C5CCA499" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtains a written statement from one or more relevant Indian tribal governments (as defined in section 7871(b)(4)(A)) (or, in the case of Native Hawaiian community members, the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands, as defined in section 801 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221</external-xref>)) that documents the eligibility of such qualified active low-income community business with respect to the requirement of subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC43E4AFA554B4D719B4067BE44861465" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Tribal statistical area</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>tribal statistical area</term> means any low-income community which is located in any area determined by the Secretary, after consultation with the Bureau of the Census, as a Tribal Census Tract, Oklahoma Tribal Statistical Area, Tribal-Designated Statistical Area, Alaska Native Village Statistical Area, or Hawaiian Home Lands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1176FB1548DE49D7BAE742BBA2E938E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this subsection shall apply to new markets tribal area tax credit limitation determined for calendar years after December 31, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDD816A4400B242B9B8EBA884EA065B81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Educational and technical assistance related to qualified tribal area investments</header><text>Section 45D of such Code is amended by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (j) and by inserting after subsection (h) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4D1C3DE129AA4D179C012092B8A9415B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HD103AE9EDB6F42948AF672A30D7165F1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Education and technical assistance related to investments with respect to tribal statistical areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary, after consultation with the Office of Tribal and Native Affairs, the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund, and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall establish a program to provide educational and technical assistance to qualified community development entities with respect to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFBBF8CE58C6D4FF4AD866A257359449D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applications for, and the appropriate use of—</text> <subparagraph id="H3A313BC1B6744FDB9E67B90126858195"><enum>(A)</enum><text>new markets tribal area tax credit limitation, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H649580C5F63C43479786DF0A4CDE41B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>new markets tax credit limitation with respect to investments with respect to tribal statistical areas, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CE144635A964D09943065F48E56E053"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any qualified community development entity which has been allocated limitation described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1), technical issues specifically associated with investments with respect to tribal statistical areas.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCAF91E7C014346A68C7CFF9C8D827B56"><enum>7.</enum><header>Inclusion of Indian areas as difficult development areas for purposes of certain buildings</header> 
<subsection id="H6A049BE552D44C6E97EF71C614975200"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subclause (I) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42(d)(5)(B)(iii)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, and any Indian area</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H842B09D6FAB6450EB6C588E47B5089DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Indian area</header><text>Clause (iii) of section 42(d)(5)(B) of such Code is amended by redesignating subclause (II) as subclause (IV) and by inserting after subclause (I) the following new subclauses:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H82628A98A4344D00BE33BEFDE31AB111" style="OLC"> 
<subclause id="H96849298CC25482BA3DA972744E3B9D4"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Indian area</header><text>For purposes of subclause (I), the term <term>Indian area</term> means any Indian area (as defined in section 4(11) of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103(11)</external-xref>)).</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8E98E7BE06254085B23F16D116D19551"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Special rule for buildings in Indian areas</header><text>In the case of an area which is a difficult development area solely because it is an Indian area, a building shall not be treated as located in such area unless such building is assisted or financed under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4101">25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.</external-xref>) or the project sponsor is an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 45A(c)(6)), a tribally designated housing entity (as defined in section 4(22) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103(22)</external-xref>)), or wholly owned or controlled by such an Indian Tribe or tribally designated housing entity.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1DA768F7DCF34AFF8A13144C236B0FC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to buildings placed in service after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H37620BC44EA6481B83A57AAD78B432C1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Tribal general welfare and trust programs clarification</header> <subsection id="H7D2A059328F744D8A36DF96FBF68E964"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1612(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1382a">42 U.S.C. 1382a(b)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end of paragraph (25), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (26) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H05EA2E276A4D4455A671A31BB45AE45D" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H4709B67D203649109188830C273BF6B9"><enum>(27)</enum><text>any Indian general welfare benefit (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/139E">section 139E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4AC2E33C9E9E4EC691631287AB6D8EE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion from resources</header><text>Section 1613(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1382b">42 U.S.C. 1382b(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>; and</quote> at the end of paragraph (16) and by inserting after paragraph (17) the following new paragraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0EAB5449C3BB461296FDB104AAC7E0FA" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HE837193ACA094DBDBF602222832FA757"><enum>(18)</enum><text>for the 9-month period beginning after the month in which received, any Indian general welfare benefit (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/139E">section 139E</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F62D827C9294102BCD9A62686080347"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any grantor trust established by an Indian tribe for the benefit of Indians and for which the Indian tribe is the grantor (within the meaning of subpart E of part 1 of subchapter J of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDED913D9A86A4248A76502C98C0B02AC"><enum>9.</enum><header>Indian employment tax credit</header> 
<subsection id="HFBEFA02B72E34C45B20A7D2F44050422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45A">Section 45A</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subsection (f).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5D9A53DC0AAD4BC6BB9CF26AAE7DBBE9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of determination of amount of credit</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 45A(a) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD8D85B8AE54C4E39B4BE2EB88F509927" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HF3C20CD485DB49B0B3971B898A1308ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the quotient of—</text> <subparagraph id="H3618A319CF95404B9CC8E1543B593DAA"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the sum of the qualified wages and qualified employee health insurance costs which were paid or incurred by the employer (or any predecessor) during the two most recent calendar years ending before the beginning of such taxable year, divided by</text>
                        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H913D3F4455EC46349D21441CC8EBD77A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H441D325BAD184DFF8518F50786B52575"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increased limitation</header><text>Section 45A(b)(3) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>$20,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$30,000</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4C0C98C7EFF6408FBFC76223BC2574FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB1D37586E0E64EEEBBB4DE6D30DB952D"><enum>10.</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income for payments under Indian health service loan repayment program</header> <subsection id="H47D206447C48471880B5C8CCFE361810"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (4) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/108">section 108(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>under section 108 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act,</quote> after <quote>338I of such Act,</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H33791E1EB622446D8F01F1147011821D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The heading for section 108(f)(4) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">, Indian health service loan repayment program,</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and certain</header-in-text></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H91851C50F3EF4149A33D01C30293A5C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to payments made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA8DD79530B924C9D887ABEDBF87625A6"><enum>11.</enum><header>Exclusion of certain amounts received under Indian Health Professions Scholarships Program</header> 
<subsection id="HDC1AB2EEB08F47148B58B5C24AE8A371"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/117">section 117(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HC5CFA2F805C6428DA1FE47FBB33A6210" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H5B4BD03757CF409B9B3FAE321407A5D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Indian Health Professions Scholarships Program under section 104 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD2840149AD8F425FB548CBCBB308E12A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to amounts received in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

