<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFCF0EF1A82C94D11820397EA4978BC3B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1137 IH: Recognizing the 100th anniversary of the creation of the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers’ Institute, Inc., and commending its work establishing industry standards that ensure the safe interoperability of firearms and ammunition.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1137</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001240">Mr. McDowell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001222">Mr. Miller of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000405">Mr. Knott</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 100th anniversary of the creation of the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers’ Institute, Inc., and commending its work establishing industry standards that ensure the safe interoperability of firearms and ammunition.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1926, the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers’ Institute, Inc. (SAAMI), was founded at the request of the Federal Government to create and publish industry standards for safety, interchangeability and reliability of American firearms, coordinating technical data related to firearms with public and private stakeholders, and promoting safe and responsible firearms use;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the mission of SAAMI is to create and promulgate technical, performance, interchangeability, and safety standards for firearms, ammunition, suppressors, and components, and to be the preeminent global resource for the safe and responsible manufacturing, transportation, storage, and use of these products;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, for a century, SAAMI has coordinated with industry, the military, and domestic and international government bodies to create and maintain consistent safety standards;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to working with industry and governments, SAAMI has collaborated with domestic and international standards bodies like the American National Standards Institute (ANSI) and the Commission Internationale Permanente (CIP) to promote international safety and interchangeability of firearm components and ammunition;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas SAAMI’s work goes beyond the creation of industry standards for safety, to include contributions to conservation efforts by funding game research surveys conducted by Aldo Leopold, who is considered to be the father of modern wildlife management;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas SAAMI’s strategic goals continue the long history of promoting safety by creating and maintaining standards, educating and sharing expertise with policymakers, and improving the forum to analyze current standards, while addressing new challenges related to technological advancements and industry trends, all while maintaining its standing as the technical expert in the field of firearms and ammunition; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks the 100th anniversary of SAAMI’s founding and its century-long work toward the promotion of public safety, technological advancement, and the provision of standards to help guide the firearms and ammunition industry: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H4B8F7BB66122426D9B545DFD73EADF84"> <section id="H06559AF466FE4D95A93B5598680753D3" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC6C9E41555F24F2CBF3ABF9F663FC175">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>recognizes the 100th anniversary of the creation of the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers’ Institute, Inc.;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC193558B856437DAAB7E8294DEA3DA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers’ Institute, Inc., for a century of leadership in establishing standards that ensure the safe interoperability of firearms and ammunition;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF37048A514D4F288DFAEB940ACE1637"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers’ Institute, Inc.’s vital role in promoting public safety, scientific rigor, and responsible industry practices;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE593AE88114F48C4976A0624FEC1D4EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages continued collaboration among industry, government, and scientific organizations to advance safety and innovation in sporting arms and ammunition; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E0DB88EEEC44DEA9AF019F0C350166B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors all those who have contributed to the mission of the Sporting Arms and Ammunition Manufacturers’ Institute, Inc., over the past century.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

