<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26081-DPY-K0-Y16"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3840 IS: Health Investment Zones Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3840</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for the designation of areas as Health Investment Zones to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in such areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Investment Zones Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idba10ecb3f46447b7a69c1e043de06caa"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Health Investment Zones</header><subsection id="id1e6c4ea26c954390b0daffb554e2d5bf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><paragraph id="id19eeacd85be34cbc8ec6a27c0b232e42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, pursuant to applications submitted under subsection (c), designate areas as Health Investment Zones to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in such areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e4088cc526a4d01bba791ffef421038"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility of area</header><text>To be designated as a Health Investment Zone under this section, an area shall—</text><subparagraph id="id3c13cfdda8c14d30bf40c77d3a6ebfde"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be a contiguous geographic area; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00d87336f31d443fbba081406526eca3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have measurable and documented geographic health disparities and poor health outcomes, demonstrated by—</text><clause id="idee75519c15ff4bb9b5ee697a00a097e0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>average income below 150 percent of the Federal poverty line (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget based on the most recent data available from the Bureau of the Census);</text></clause><clause id="idf01a003736474ca1ab1f53c2478bcaca"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a rate of participation in the special supplemental nutrition program under section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>) that is higher than the national average rate of participation in such program;</text></clause><clause id="id4ab182d243184487b5c21ed08ea8efa2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>lower life expectancy than the national average;</text></clause><clause id="idb10393a3f5dd418b864438118344f068"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a higher percentage of instances of low birth weight than the national average; or</text></clause><clause id="id15544920ca874a538dc4bd38843616cb"><enum>(v)</enum><text>designation under section 332 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254e">42 U.S.C. 254e</external-xref>) as a health professional shortage area.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id97bd7de60c5a4a7a877ecde7d13e8ec6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication of designee information</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which all areas are designated as Health Investment Zones under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services—</text><subparagraph id="idd01306cfc6134948a80a2507757317a3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of each such Health Investment Zone, together with the names of each coalition partner; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5712bff8b824478a051bc1c6f21551d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of all areas so designated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida8f2e3f670a547eba444f5458bfe70df"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Solicitation of applications</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall solicit applications under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="idde8e226ec2a44ce283776835c0d76d7d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission of applications</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id394e8939ad9c450eb2d24f538cab295b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To seek the designation of an area as a Health Investment Zone, a community-based nonprofit organization or local governmental agency, in coalition with health care providers, hospitals, nonprofit community health clinics, health centers, social service organizations, and other related organizations, shall submit an application to the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id698a583d91fe4970808ad58db0c70ded"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications for grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of an application under this subsection, a community-based nonprofit organization or local governmental agency may include an application for a grant under section 4(a). Such community-based nonprofit organization or local governmental agency shall describe how the use of grant funds would be consistent with the plan submitted pursuant to subsection (d)(1) and whether such community-based nonprofit organization or local governmental agency intends to award subgrants or implement innovative public health strategies under section 4(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id50c39a075e8349f8b3c3f2aaffc2a732"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application under subsection (c) shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c790aa8f28e4539952d5d523073fe04"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include an effective and sustainable plan with respect to the area proposed for designation—</text><subparagraph id="ida45cee2e765c40a38f381b4f999b75a9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to reduce health disparities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6942823465104a30aa1ca18fe763756a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to reduce the costs of, or to produce savings to, the health care system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6060e17a1264f70a4a256db623d11a2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to improve health outcomes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id797dcc52fadb4106a3bf7777af6cd30d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to utilize one or more of the incentives established pursuant to section 5, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">section 51</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as amended by section 3(a)), for wages paid to qualified Health Investment Zone workers (as defined in section 51(d)(16) of such Code), <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/25G">section 25G</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by section 3(b)), or subsection (ee) of section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) (as amended by section 6) to address health care provider capacity, improve health services delivery, effectuate community improvements, or conduct outreach and education efforts; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idee38227826394183a1e5050aa26a8d15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify specific diseases or indicators of health for improvement of health outcomes in such area, including at least 1 of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id843d046ce2a746139fb875299fc25028"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Cardiovascular disease.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3049d7f651dc4ee9a64bb2424f0c96f3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Asthma.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc7ccd2e355f743adb6df71cbdfb7a90d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Diabetes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2cc9c2d0d0654ae088fe6042fee3cc55"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Behavioral health.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc43ee68cd6d74b17a989337c7f6b1e50"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Maternal and birth health.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id68829c89feed4c18a63bf393b9a6abd3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Obesity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8c6431c15e244415921ddea9042f8eb0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Secretary—</text><paragraph id="idbf54c2c692ba40eda39aeffe71950d30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall consider geographic diversity, among other factors, in selecting areas for designation as Health Investment Zones; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb75c5d8062e14d50a2cbfe9634c6ed03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may conduct outreach efforts to encourage a geographically diverse pool of applicants, including for designating Health Investment Zones in rural areas.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9671cb4cf01b40a18b1af80e9b8ac6f3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting areas for designation as Health Investment Zones, the Secretary shall give higher priority to applications based on the extent to which an area demonstrates the following:</text><paragraph id="id01ebda3dcc6443d393af6e800af9c725"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Support from, and participation of, key stakeholders in the area proposed for designation, including residents and local governments of such area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id814e9f00263e48128c4f299c3bb61995"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A plan for long-term funding and sustainability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb449c58b15084750922e1b30cc5ffe20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Integration with any applicable State health improvement process or plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf76ac416ad4a449eacd86eaae8433324"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan for evaluation of the impact of designation of such area as a Health Investment Zone.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a97d2334fd04089955e897151471c5e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan to utilize existing State tax credits, grants, or other incentives to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in the proposed Health Investment Zone.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb42696a677141b692d6dd4d923932a2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Such other factors as the Secretary determines are appropriate to demonstrate a commitment to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in such area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide6e1ed2e22b34f06bad1d2bd046a5f48"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Period of designation</header><text>The designation under this section of an area as a Health Investment Zone shall be in effect until the date that is 10 years after the date on which the first such area is so designated.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H604C301A4CC14A90A996F4AE30733C8B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tax incentives</header><subsection commented="no" id="H1EF0C8110D3E4472A1284843761816E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Work opportunity credit for hiring Health Investment Zone workers</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HBF19C102288D453C976A4BCF4A7BFA10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/51">Section 51(d)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (I), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (J) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DE1CBAD4A494985B4EBC665A07D3F99"><subparagraph commented="no" id="H55C9707BC13241689C329CD9DEAFDB3C"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a qualified Health Investment Zone worker, to the extent that the qualified first-year wages with respect to such worker are paid for qualified Health Investment Zone work.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA44C0B3C2AA54AD3BD2A8B4AB52BBC47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified Health Investment Zone worker</header><text>Section 51(d) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BA15CB248464D98A63F26CCE8550905"><paragraph commented="no" id="H21DF563F1EE0492B9D2564E7A3E3F6B5"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Health Investment Zones</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id08A939E0DC9047ACB1C37312FAAAAAF2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified Health Investment Zone worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified Health Investment Zone worker</term> means any individual who is certified by the designated local agency as having (as of the hiring date) a principal place of employment within a Health Investment Zone.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA48E0F1E99C04611B52325C5C9D03DCA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified Health Investment Zone work</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified Health Investment Zone work</term> means employment by a Health Investment Zone practitioner, the primary official duties of such employment being to promote access to healthcare in a Health Investment Zone.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1D157FFB66D94636AF326512D42691A6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Related terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the terms <term>Health Investment Zone</term> and <term>Health Investment Zone practitioner</term> have the same meaning given such terms under section 8 of the <short-title>Health Investment Zones Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H51D9489517944087B134BC1227EB7909"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act to individuals who begin work for the employer after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H0E40FD3F6DBA486E82A820AF0D5AFB0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit for Health Investment Zone workers</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB95C30033E1C422BB045028554DB270A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 70411 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>, is amended by inserting after section 25F the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HBF53201166284E35904834B11713D23B"><section commented="no" id="HE8018C11050F4456B37E7046C2B92008"><enum>25G.</enum><header>Credit for qualified Health Investment Zone workers</header><subsection commented="no" id="H3C7B094E410F464DB6C3020C4118AE20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualified Health Investment Zone worker, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for a taxable year an amount equal to 30 percent of wages received for qualified Health Investment Zone work during such taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9606543BCB3D4AF5AB8D8D1B902C7713"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H1E99B2F6F85D491BB40A419B3BBF0CC2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified Health Investment Zone worker</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified Health Investment Zone worker</term> means, with respect to wages, an individual whose principal place of employment while earning such wages is within a Health Investment Zone (as such term is defined in section 8 of the <short-title>Health Investment Zones Act of 2026</short-title>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11F983F31C144D8D9B80DB1CCBC1549B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified Health Investment Zone work</header><text>The term <term>qualified Health Investment Zone work</term> has the same meaning given such term in section 51(d)(16)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5E82223FFAF24AB39ABF9B96613FAEA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code, as amended by section 70411 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>, is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25F the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC621945E329E429FB8A96A11660F0A2F"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 25G. Credit for qualified Health Investment Zone workers.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3A200BCC93E4BA38E7B9629EFF58989"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to wages received after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8f29f5bb72a54d57818140dbd2018262"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants</header><subsection id="id5cb3a214a50f4004b9220a9e71b3c3ac"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>For each area designated as a Health Investment Zone, the Secretary may award a grant to the community-based nonprofit organization or local governmental agency that applied for such designation to support such applicant and its coalition partners in reducing health disparities and improving health outcomes in such area.</text></subsection><subsection id="id87b2b74034dd46d6b4c843ae06996b55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Programs and activities funded through a grant under this section shall be consistent with the grantee’s plan submitted pursuant to section 2(d)(1) and may include the following:</text><paragraph id="idcfadaa9c778d4bb3a14f530b3cede208"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Subgrants to health care practitioners</header><subparagraph id="idf13001cfecf142d7a3193a242739dd70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose of improving or expanding the delivery of health care in the respective Health Investment Zone, the grantee may award subgrants to Health Investment Zone practitioners to defray costs related to innovative strategies listed in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa183f5557f741adbd5473f235a453ac"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a subgrant pursuant to subparagraph (A), a Health Investment Zone practitioner shall—</text><clause id="id11bc8e5967a54a13878a9f4ee9e30f61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>own or lease a health care facility in the Health Investment Zone; or</text></clause><clause id="id2e2558db3bd94a968af3e62d6ea01b45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide health care in such a facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac98a8a4364a41feacab97af8ca208ff"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of a subgrant under subparagraph (A) may not exceed the lesser of—</text><clause id="ide6bbaf4066c54d77ad610780f1bc93b4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$5,000,000; or</text></clause><clause id="ida57d1fd97f9b443283f5563eefa3e781"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>50 percent of the costs of the equipment, or capital or leasehold improvements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id74166daded8146b78e36ec6f38fbcaf1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Innovative strategies</header><text>A grantee (or subgrantee) may use a grant received under this section (or a subgrant received under paragraph (1)) to implement innovative public health strategies in the respective Health Investment Zone, which strategies may include—</text><subparagraph id="id87623e3d58294738a2af576ab88feaf5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>internships and volunteer opportunities for students who reside in the Health Investment Zone;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57f107731e894bb2b810b0046a9ecca8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funding resources to improve health care provider capacity to serve non-English speakers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfac86ece8c2149aeae92b79c13ae5882"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operation of medical, mental and behavioral health, and dental mobile clinics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32eee10b23e94bb58fde825af22ab866"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provision of transportation to and from medical appointments for patients;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide731cb2b560243d8910fd1d8f1441117"><enum>(E)</enum><text>funding resources to improve access to healthy food, recreation, and high-quality housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id94b0187f08294960baa06f26c697558c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>capital or leasehold improvements to a health care facility in the respective Health Investment Zone; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ce2b7fccfa74091a3e57fa646d2a363"><enum>(G)</enum><text>medical or dental equipment to be used in such a facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3b299c699f1648e0a5574a6868e57165"><enum>5.</enum><header>Student loan repayment program</header><subsection id="ide5f80730547343dfa7b7653ea5a6ceb7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a loan repayment program under which the Secretary enters into agreements with eligible Health Investment Zone practitioners to make payments on the principal and interest of the eligible educational loans of such practitioners for each year such practitioners agree to provide health care services in a Health Investment Zone.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbee3d46342d245999d1da06e0f5aea47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>In entering into loan repayment agreements under this section, the Secretary may not agree to—</text><paragraph id="id42cea62710694e01887b36974d7c6283"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make payments for more than 10 years with respect to a practitioner; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id95b02036e0ab473090daa987b8635f26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pay more than $10,000 per year, or more than a total of $100,000, with respect to a practitioner.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide8e0e6f557ff4fe18e9792cb661ad2f8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Relationship to other benefits</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b8e65b9a5f84571abd862796675641b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Counting of payments</header><text>A payment made to, or on behalf of, an eligible Health Investment Zone practitioner under this section shall be considered a qualifying payment counted toward any total number of required payments for forgiveness or cancellation on an otherwise applicable student loan plan or program under the Higher Education Act of 1965 or the Public Health Service Act, such as under subsection (m) or (q) of section 455 or section 493C of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e</external-xref>; 1098e).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id903d4dede934460cb714650a805d3af5"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No double payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No borrower may, for the same service, receive a payment for an eligible educational loan under—</text><subparagraph id="id78f5d74cf6254b888dc8928bfd336ead"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1842094742d4a3db76399c1d000f930"><enum>(B)</enum><text>another federally supported loan program that provides a payment to, or on behalf of, that borrower.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc361ea7d48b45118366ee269f4571f5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible Health Investment Zone practitioner shall not receive a payment or reimbursement under this section for an eligible educational loan that has been forgiven, cancelled, or repaid.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida3b798097d8d4ea5a348d2c1c79d9d11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id28e858809b6346dcbf52319e162a2b29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible educational loan</header><text>The term <term>eligible educational loan</term> means any federally funded or guaranteed student loan, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25f0cff98fed415c81dfc66428c7b336"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible Health Investment Zone practitioner</header><text>The term <term>eligible Health Investment Zone practitioner</term> means a Health Investment Zone practitioner who—</text><subparagraph id="id6f4b3a7e44ee496986670dc1653b21c4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agrees to provide full-time health care services in a Health Investment Zone for a specified period that is not less than 1 year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72b717c91c6a4eac9bada07b131e56b7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has 1 or more eligible educational loans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idD8DD543761D341188CE94B2C3308E1E6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Incentive payments for Medicare part B items and services furnished in Health Investment Zones</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idD8C2C7CB65CD4B3DB9D0D97FF9E78C96"><subsection id="id1684D29F96D144078AB1A70AF3F34834"><enum>(ee)</enum><header>Incentive payments for items and services furnished in Health Investment Zones</header><paragraph id="id8DBE34B66BB34869B03EEE3C4E863D90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of items and services furnished under this part in an area that is designated as a Health Investment Zone under section 2(a)(1) of the <short-title>Health Investment Zones Act of 2026</short-title>, in addition to the amount of payment that would otherwise be made for such items and services under this part, there also shall be paid (on a monthly or quarterly basis)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98beead8b21642028077f3fd5772823a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an amount equal to 10 percent of the payment amount for the item or service under this part;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id354a5085013a473f9dc17a3a6df04ba6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for such an item or service furnished at a freestanding physician office or clinic (as defined in paragraph (2)) or a Federally qualified health center (as defined in section 1861(aa)(3)), in addition to any applicable additional payment amount under this paragraph, an amount equal to 5 percent of the payment amount for the item or service under this part; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1090814ea8304bf89cda36ddeca38299"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for an annual wellness visit (HCPCS codes G0438–G0439), diabetes self-management training (CPT codes 98960–98962), chronic care management (CPT codes 99487–99491), and a preventative screening such as a mammography or colorectal cancer screening, in addition to any applicable additional payment amount under this paragraph, an amount equal to 10 percent of the payment amount for such item or service under this part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd920d39e8a5499c8171d1ee4b17a852"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of freestanding physician office or clinic</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>freestanding physician office or clinic</term> means a clinic that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd786de37da304b0792d1552f8a22c8dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bills by place of service code 11 (office) or 22 (independent clinic) in the physician fee schedule under section 1848; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57c43f83d30e46e7b9b2e855a25207b8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not directly or indirectly owned or controlled by a hospital system enrolled in the Medicare Provider Enrollment, Chain, and Ownership System (commonly referred to as <quote>PECOS</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID193BBB06BB6B41C49FD1E923DEFE178D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with other payments</header><text>The amount of the additional payment for an item or a service under this subsection and subsection (m) shall be determined without regard to any additional payment for the item or service under subsection (m) and this subsection, respectively. The amount of the additional payment for an item or a service under this subsection and subsection (z) shall be determined without regard to any additional payment for the item or service under subsection (z) and this subsection, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id1a75c2b9a1a5486a97b1f8516a808f3c"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting</header><subsection id="id4340d311482747cc97535b84f9e7d91b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the day that is 10 years after the first Health Investment Zone is designated, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this Act (and the amendments made by this Act) and the results thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="id58ca33b16b3d478499014c0a5e24a4aa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id6ddf5041c7ea4b3faf865ce0e7b5dbee"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specify the number and types of incentives provided pursuant to this Act in each Health Investment Zone; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f8bde91130c4f9c9902c2efdaa89fd3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include evidence of the extent to which the incentives utilized by each Health Investment Zone have—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7132a9b029c04a55aa7da2a32dd5f503"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">succeeded—</text><clause id="iddb00cf9b5d8048cba26fab49a6b95eae"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in attracting health care practitioners to practice in Health Investment Zones;</text></clause><clause id="ide1513152b199460faf0582ffff127a88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in reducing health disparities and improving health outcomes in Health Investment Zones; and</text></clause><clause id="idd650a97a920a4de9bb576b5983976503"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in reducing health costs and hospital admissions and readmissions in Health Investment Zones; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e202af7b47b4e36811a436872e37f53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impacted access to primary care services and utilization of emergency room services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id7b79ad577fc84d0fba6a295d59112553"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id3eb28cf7d9a14068a59ccb80248e9308"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>Health Investment Zone</term> means an area designated under section 2 as a Health Investment Zone.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb248a196e4c410993f27051459d0d3d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Health Investment Zone practitioner</term> means a health care practitioner who—</text><subparagraph id="id6c45c01b8e074484832abb764dbd84e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is licensed or certified in accordance with applicable State law to treat patients in the applicable Health Investment Zone;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id256051bf05244a40aeae0cc5dbfe7f27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides—</text><clause id="id8396e82cd65e40cc8777fd34b05a8707"><enum>(i)</enum><text>primary care, which may include obstetrics, gynecological services, pediatric services, or geriatric services;</text></clause><clause id="id76ac2a04742e42e39fce2d715c5756c5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>behavioral health services, which may include mental health or substance use disorder services; or</text></clause><clause id="id32760a18ad744a9cbd6a2200d90b2a39"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>dental services; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce68b1de4f3e465d8f943fa9c8685234"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a participating provider of services or supplier under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) or a participating provider under a State plan under title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id17282e6e883e4c368333821b5822eebe"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idc09c6e1e3d95437899197b01f6fdc6f1"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this Act, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the last day of the 10-year period that begins on the date on which the first Health Investment Zone is designated.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

