<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY26523-JK7-GS-SKL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4220 IS: Veterans Health Administration Novel Therapeutics Preparedness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4220</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish within the Veterans Health Administration an Office of Novel Therapeutics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Health Administration Novel Therapeutics Preparedness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1a6b2393978546b393398d6f8a527a8c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a29107480c54e3691121793547f00b3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Emerging therapeutic interventions, including certain psychedelic-assisted therapies under evaluation by the Food and Drug Administration as of the date of the enactment of this Act, may significantly alter the treatment landscape for post-traumatic stress disorder, depression, and other mental health conditions affecting veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f5e9cb7f7024bbdb3ecdd6e2fb024de"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The administration of certain emerging therapies may require intensive clinical engagement, interdisciplinary teams, dedicated clinical space, structured preparation, and post-treatment integration that differ substantially from traditional outpatient mental health services.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96867c6fbde8445ebda6ec0284241932"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Veterans Affairs is uniquely positioned to deliver integrated, veteran-centered care that combines medical, mental health, and peer support services within a single system of care.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ec66dfcb7a7476193b22ceca2f4cba5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Absent centralized governance and implementation planning, the Department may face delays, safety risks, or inconsistent access following regulatory approval of such therapies.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4dea0bbcc7249899d0a99bebc967c50"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing a dedicated Office of Novel Therapeutics will ensure that the Department is prepared to responsibly evaluate, research, and implement emerging treatment modalities consistent with patient safety and evidence-based practice.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id6058f629719b4e47843fc3d3b6aec49d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Office of Novel Therapeutics within Veterans Health Administration</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc357210d7a354ce18eec73f512f709c8"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6380526cbca4105860a331be6888839"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">Chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id204af48591be49f9bdf4bd5bf9d6389f"><subchapter id="id759ce1fcfa0241c88805399b8277f5b6" style="OLC"><enum>VI</enum><header>Novel Therapeutics</header><section id="id67dba46059a84dbf9c313d0c9a60e55c"><enum>7391.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id686a43a24e3241efb648b00f14c54593"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Center of excellence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>center of excellence</term> means a medical center of the Department designated under section 7394 of this title as a center of excellence for novel therapeutics to advance research, training, and implementation of emerging therapeutic interventions.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide798cdfe64b64df88717b963c200128f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Emerging therapeutic intervention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>emerging therapeutic intervention</term> means a pharmacological, biological, or other therapeutic modality under evaluation or review by the Food and Drug Administration.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idb998041c6fc745ebb9ea60252ac8d4e2"><enum>7392.</enum><header>Office of Novel Therapeutics</header><subsection id="id0996a4988c134e94a0f5c56e4b6d2814"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Veterans Health Administration, under the Office of the Under Secretary for Health, an Office of Novel Therapeutics (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id0801a7d7cc4d425fb4567777e83e00f2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The head of the Office shall be the Director of the Office of Novel Therapeutics, who shall be appointed by the Under Secretary for Health and who shall—</text><paragraph id="idbbfcd776b0fc48a8889ca26f33e49313"><enum>(1)</enum><text>possess demonstrated expertise in clinical research and implementation science; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc32af82c8294466fab818ce6b8cc3bd6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report directly to the Under Secretary for Health.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6681f0bc77664fa8a3f976e89ce2c40c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordinating authority</header><text>The Office shall serve as the primary coordinating authority within the Veterans Health Administration for matters relating to emerging and novel therapeutic interventions.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida70034caebff45e0a31f6610c6d86e02"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Office shall—</text><paragraph id="iddadba562d245467abfe6aee259ea0619"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and oversee national policy, guidance, and clinical standards for the evaluation, research, and potential implementation by the Veterans Health Administration of emerging and novel therapeutic interventions for mental health conditions affecting veterans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe142aa6f608433fa21a722c52b1c6e0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a national clinical model for the administration of intensive therapeutic interventions, including structured preparation, monitored administration, and post-administration integration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida32409bc73134c8f90d4abdffad4eca8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop guidance regarding patient eligibility and candidacy for emerging therapeutic interventions, ensuring that utilization management or step therapy requirements do not unduly restrict access where clinically appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ef87d03cdbf4815a5b012e1918526ad"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop implementation-readiness plans for therapies that may receive approval from the Food and Drug Administration, including—</text><subparagraph id="id704fad7f21744b2e963253dd2cded3b1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facility infrastructure requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb7a387b8e7754e30be2f341128cb2b7d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interdisciplinary team composition standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc58772b58f19458780e71b2dbfb05db4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allocation of protected clinical time necessary to safely administer intensive therapeutic interventions, including full session and integration requirements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id477ff058c6544c74954940b5a80e9696"><enum>(D)</enum><text>patient safety and adverse event monitoring and response protocols; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd8d5e111aada4d14b3443e3e639e6f96"><enum>(E)</enum><text>integration with suicide prevention, post-traumatic stress disorder, and substance use disorder programs;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id25e7c6d59f4d49c788c5b9dee74002dd"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conduct a workforce-readiness assessment to identify clinicians and peer support specialists with prior training or certification relevant to emerging therapeutic interventions and gaps in training, supervision, and clinical capacity necessary to support safe and effective implementation of such interventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfcb340e3d9a64480a63f0731ecd61ab3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establish national training and credentialing standards for clinicians administering novel therapeutics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97c55f0a9ba94a26942f5ec771f9eae9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>develop a standardized, competency-based training framework for clinicians and peer support specialists participating in emerging therapeutic interventions, including preparation, monitored administration, integration, safety monitoring, interdisciplinary collaboration, and culturally competent care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6d215eee9ff436aa8a71868cc1c0b81"><enum>(8)</enum><text>distinguish between research protocols and clinical implementation standards to ensure that patient care models are not constrained solely by sponsor-driven research design;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1294244d9c214ecbab405393386dee5c"><enum>(9)</enum><text>coordinate with the Office of Research and Development—</text><subparagraph id="id8efd23e14966427bae9824f0a6a0e97f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to align research priorities with implementation-readiness needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf895b79073bf4b50aacc8adf3bf5eeba"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to recommend specialized review pathways for research involving emerging therapeutic interventions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77f02f7d15864ea5a2748cc099a571e6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to develop standards for allocation of protected research time for clinicians participating in research involving emerging therapeutic interventions, including clarification that patients seen under approved research protocols shall be counted toward standard clinical productivity metrics;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6e2e09dac2d7441087163e1ef8713b4b"><enum>(10)</enum><text>develop guidance to ensure continuity of care, including—</text><subparagraph id="idcb94f210716f440281d51c98ef84d15a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>post-administration integration services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ba314542cf540e0ad2fca61c5e1d059"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporation of peer support specialists; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46d814e3d7fb404e9407289c3b9629df"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordination with community-based organizations for aftercare support as appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idab833a03902543de807c7c34fa8aaf54"><enum>(11)</enum><text>identify not fewer than one medical center in each Veterans Integrated Service Network to develop infrastructure and workforce-readiness for emerging therapeutic models; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id587546bc35e04ae0879b0aacf9ea3c17"><enum>(12)</enum><text>establish criteria for the designation of centers of excellence and oversee compliance with national standards.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb10b1309d5ee4d37b72814d38dec8615"><enum>7393.</enum><header>Clinical Implementation Program for Emerging Therapeutics</header><subsection id="id449966f527dc42acae0b59950d772da4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Office of Novel Therapeutics, shall establish a Clinical Implementation Program for Emerging Therapeutics (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to evaluate the effectiveness, feasibility, safety, and scalability of emerging therapeutic interventions within the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5c9373b8f00c48f4aa434ee77c8a3c5f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Program shall—</text><paragraph id="idfdd54233754b42819197337a02866003"><enum>(1)</enum><text>utilize effectiveness-implementation hybrid models to evaluate both clinical outcomes and real-world implementation factors with respect to emerging therapeutic interventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id622efa317c6a4e34bb8a4c87cae00881"><enum>(2)</enum><text>test and refine care delivery models, including patient eligibility criteria, safety protocols, interdisciplinary team models, and post-administration integration services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f494ac46a6b441ca9a3c9a10936d041"><enum>(3)</enum><text>generate real-world evidence to inform potential systemwide adoption; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7295dd2a3f7e49488f47513ad02a89d8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assess workforce, infrastructure, cost, and operational requirements necessary for broader implementation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6510ceadcab742c6b7dfd4f6e520df00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered conditions</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may prioritize one or more brain or mental health conditions affecting veterans, including—</text><paragraph id="id6d81344acea645549ab3edfa6cd157c5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>post-traumatic stress disorder;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd694d79e7d66446b84ff45775e7d2c8b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>treatment-resistant depression;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2bdece1155e942be90f6f70dfa6a909b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>substance use disorders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19ee620ff66d4dc086297ca534000ed9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>suicidality;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id926ccfd6b86a4ac786ac7cd25366a53e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>traumatic brain injury;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a8d209d33fd43f98a0afec170136ffa"><enum>(6)</enum><text>repetitive low-level blast exposure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d1a9a2b94c64324accd4d5612c2c765"><enum>(7)</enum><text>chronic pain;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34c82b4f7dcf4a65a0764d2e4b1c9c6d"><enum>(8)</enum><text>co-occurring conditions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef40446cd6e7445e983dc2a7d7bfbde4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>other clinically appropriate conditions as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id236d041406ac422badc2a8d59e884240"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Site selection</header><text>The Secretary may conduct the Program at—</text><paragraph id="id849a9ab252b545e98bde130397231620"><enum>(1)</enum><text>one or more centers of excellence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc8c265ed2ac4ff6b7d93344d3d5bec1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such other medical centers as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf3a4b35313864b37ad1141398ae4a901"><enum>7394.</enum><header>Centers of excellence for novel therapeutics</header><subsection id="idce19ded4d8ed4ff7bd5ad34ff3930151"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Secretary may designate one or more medical centers of the Department as centers of excellence for novel therapeutics.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida335b043fc3e4ef8946d702c5aee242e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>Each center of excellence designated under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="id1b79ed78d4a74880839828a70be021e9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve as a national leader in research, clinical training, and implementation of emerging therapeutic interventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d760f50557d4078a6c10d46b3e0c511"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and disseminate best practices and clinical standards across the Veterans Health Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6efd04fdfd3a46bba575abbbe0bc82e3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide technical assistance and training to other medical centers of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6dd83be5d874bc288745cd5edfa4458"><enum>(4)</enum><text>integrate interdisciplinary care models, including peer support and post-administration integration services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14f62e88a92445f3ac98d912eeee700f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>incorporate veteran advisory input into program development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7703cc7f0304b099b2291bf5012a220"><enum>(6)</enum><text>coordinate with academic affiliates and external research partners, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id62e7d6e9806f4d61860bf6e599031552"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>Centers of excellence designated under subsection (a) shall operate in coordination with, and under standards established by, the Office of Novel Therapeutics.</text></subsection></section><section id="idf2d134c4ec34407aadaa3b4d8973aade"><enum>7395.</enum><header>Veteran Advisory Committee on Novel Therapeutics</header><subsection id="idc87f7b88c2ad4f1c8b2886663baa9a01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Veteran Advisory Committee on Novel Therapeutics (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>) to advise the Office of Novel Therapeutics.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd42bf728709d4f5d9c4730e6eb0c0a45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Secretary shall select the members of the Committee, which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id84d22227e0bb4b2fab4082b65071683f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Veterans with lived experience of mental health treatment furnished by the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida93666b6d61a49028e77f87ced6b5069"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Veterans who have participated in clinical research involving emerging therapeutic interventions, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd21ae637df844d6e827351efd6c4576c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Family members or caregivers of veterans described in paragraph (1) or (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb943ede0828c47699b7940022374ec32"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Representatives from academic institutions affiliated with the Department with expertise in clinical research, behavioral health, or emerging therapeutic interventions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58e065712d8a4d76be7fe8c3fe577de6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Subject matter experts as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id86b514fab15141e99c30f13ff1c847de"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>With respect to the use of novel therapeutics, the Committee shall provide input on—</text><paragraph id="id49fd11c41117499a86d28c24c1711410"><enum>(1)</enum><text>patient safety considerations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c0182685b654fb98b2a7cfee01c33dd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>informed consent practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idedebbbb217294a059b169cd3d74387a7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implementation and access barriers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7da4e737ab86401faa90ba4dba8b9540"><enum>(4)</enum><text>patient-centered care design.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida08b4d4131184218aeba90bb0a45cbc1"><enum>7396.</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration to support—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd3c39cc542c45c2a27280b8ebfb38a0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulatory readiness;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70e49d100d794403944976051ca5674b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">development of reimbursement and billing pathways;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c98a601e25d4266b112d3b7c004276a"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">scheduling and rescheduling considerations, as appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0961930a61cd401aac249303e40729da"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shared data infrastructure for monitoring safety, quality, and outcomes.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id13382217d62c41958f10499bd9f4798e"><enum>7397.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf25663d00c7f4cc0bb1fc6d20e0d11a1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research activities of the Department relating to emerging therapeutic interventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28dc692d99a74875b967bf8808bbb947"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clinical outcomes and patient-reported outcomes under the Clinical Implementation Program for Emerging Therapeutics under section 7393 of this title;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5241a6152a1477993d4d5c34c4f8a81"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">safety events and adverse outcomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf290d022fd49460cb123af214109dc19"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">workforce readiness and training capacity;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8de6ca3beed47d294d81691cd0476b7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implementation barriers, including staffing, procurement, and infrastructure needs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida78a8ae107ed488a83e55e4dbe5079bd"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for legislative or administrative action relating to novel therapeutics.</text></paragraph></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc1f09746ec94b6a9b0930531f740363"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 73 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id947aef10177a42a8bc9549d641d8cd9a"><toc><toc-entry level="subchapter" idref="id759ce1fcfa0241c88805399b8277f5b6">SUBCHAPTER VI—Novel Therapeutics</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id67dba46059a84dbf9c313d0c9a60e55c">7391. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb998041c6fc745ebb9ea60252ac8d4e2">7392. Office of Novel Therapeutics.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idb10b1309d5ee4d37b72814d38dec8615">7393. Clinical Implementation Program for Emerging Therapeutics.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf3a4b35313864b37ad1141398ae4a901">7394. Centers of excellence for novel therapeutics.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf2d134c4ec34407aadaa3b4d8973aade">7395. Veteran Advisory Committee on Novel Therapeutics.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida08b4d4131184218aeba90bb0a45cbc1">7396. Interagency coordination.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id13382217d62c41958f10499bd9f4798e">7397. Annual report.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id851ada5572db40a89b5de9c496254c1c"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">National preparedness and implementation strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a national preparedness and implementation strategy of the Veterans Health Administration for emerging mental health therapeutics, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fdf09e9c78a4c51b5bfdf12e57515fc"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">workforce capacity assessments;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a9fe179127c4d3c896ab21c9d147835"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facility modification needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida806bda4b52a4d058832bd019920f20e"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">projected timelines for phased implementation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a0524e519544d75a343ac7b3b885b61"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">barriers to implementation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

