<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB5742D84BE9A4AC1B692BB84791E5C64" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8330 IH: Stop Climate Shakedowns Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit liability against those engaged in the mining, extraction, production, refinement, transportation, distribution, marketing, manufacture, or sale of energy for damages or injunctive or other relief from the use of their products, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H83818D3223C24CF5AD0A55A849B0D062" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8FFF9866F3C244CD921AF735CAB34747" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Climate Shakedowns Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H61AF96FA920D4B5C94A88FD750505245"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional declaration; purposes; findings</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA88EFA451DBC4C43A07490B7959A5ED6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Congressional declaration</header><text>Congress declares that the general welfare and the common defense and security require effective action—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84433E24C3004437A70D629E7F452E96"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop, and increase the efficiency of, all energy sources to meet the needs of present and future generations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA37F2EEEFAA84D18B62DCB5460135C71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to increase the productivity of the economy of the United States and strengthen the position of the United States in regard to international trade;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H610E81B1311D4E36B8A45F2A2A7BC7FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to make the United States self-sufficient in energy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02CD96AD841F4ED3BD54BC7C331245C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote and preserve affordable energy for families and businesses in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD80E0BB0BA3D487C8611243024826D23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA97A0BC584B4E6A99175E82D2A6E01E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide for the regulation of interstate commerce; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23E827BE3B2B409F8445B2B7285A64F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote the production and use of affordable, abundant, and reliable energy resources.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD66C43D6E491433A9898BD72899AA430"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H746DA22A59B54D1D80E1248CC9C5F38C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affordable, abundant, and reliable energy resources are a necessary component of the general welfare of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F7054CBCA3E4EB4809C812E40EB966D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the production and use of abundant energy resources promotes—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD15E40DC5C4F47B89C37F2487B58465E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national security of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C62FF8BC334473798C664E64D707D77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the health, safety, and welfare of the citizens of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCDDDE69CFF754C1687A42270DF5C570D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the regulation of interstate, international, and transboundary emissions in the ambient air is within the exclusive jurisdiction of Federal law;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A57892173274A8CB72DF64A5230DC65"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the efforts of States to impose liability on persons engaged in the energy business for interstate and global emissions, whether through State tort law, consumer protection claims, the passage and enforcement of so-called <quote>climate superfund laws</quote>, or other civil actions, invade the exclusive jurisdiction of the Federal Government;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5763FB63FEBC428EB6FF191558122052"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the efforts to attribute local weather patterns and the local harms that result from meteorological events, such as floods, droughts, hurricanes, wildfires, or heat waves, to persons engaged in the energy business lack scientific credibility and are, therefore, arbitrary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDE4AF9EC65746AD8A86F98F5AB5967F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the efforts of States and municipalities to impose retroactive liability on persons engaged in the energy business for otherwise lawful conduct offends elementary considerations of fairness and the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BE1E67524B844AEB395198AF703ABE3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the efforts described in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7BE856DFE854B59AA77F8BAB7E356AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are a strain on the judiciary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0DF5F6E557B47378823663585D99E37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>erode public confidence in the administration of justice;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A81D7E504DD4E33A22D68ADAD5E1C2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>threaten to destabilize entire industries that are lawfully engaging in commerce in the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8EACFB6C01E4FB8A5E9A5510F0977E9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>burden the interstate, Tribal, and foreign commerce of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H386F865BABEF45CCA2D0132F4E9E9388"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>the efforts described in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) undermine the national security of the United States, as affordable, abundant, and reliable energy is critical for the readiness of the Armed Forces of the United States and the ability to deploy those Armed Forces to deter and counter the adversaries of the United States;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EAC3C8E3A714C57B622A39C18FD1079"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the efforts described in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) offend the equal sovereign dignity that each of the States enjoys, invading the autonomy of the other States within their respective spheres;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB70547754030451383FAD371C64E2221"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Commerce Clause of section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States authorizes Congress to regulate all commerce among the several States, with foreign nations, and with Indian Tribes; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0FC39D4B8AD40308FFDEB8F37B4CBE7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>to discharge the constitutional duties of Congress, the Commerce Clause of section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States empowers Congress to craft legislation under such terms and conditions as are necessary and proper.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1143B027864642B6989CAC490C8BB037"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9ECDEA327AE43D9813EDEADB333469E"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Climate suit</header><text>The term <term>climate suit</term> means any suit in law or equity that is brought against any person engaged in the energy business that seeks damages, including punitive damages, injunctive or declaratory relief, or abatement, restitution, or any form of equitable or other relief for alleged past or future harm resulting directly or indirectly from climate change, including because of marketing, alleged misrepresentation, alleged failure to warn, or any other speech.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B0FCF3A8E1F4D129DD81F7E3B6C1B38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy</header><text>The term <term>energy</term> means crude oil, natural gas, lease condensates, natural gas liquids, refined petroleum products, or coal.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3555CC218DBD4AA5ABA944AA7127ADD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Energy penalty law</header><text>The term <term>energy penalty law</term> means any State law, regulation, or ordinance that purports to require compensatory payments from, or otherwise expose to liability, any person engaged in the energy business that the law, regulation, or ordinance deems, either directly or through an administrative process, responsible for alleged costs or harms resulting directly or indirectly from climate change, including because of marketing, alleged misrepresentation, alleged failure to warn, or any other speech.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06963575821B48C6A8B285FC1E2A8EFF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><text>The term <term>greenhouse gas</term> means a gas released into the atmosphere that traps heat, including carbon dioxide, methane, and nitrous oxide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA21E07B9A2674A12B5CE52F254DF979C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means any individual, corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, joint stock company, trade association, or other entity, including any governmental entity, such as a State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2C043E0CB6149DE9813AC71A4E28739"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Person engaged in the energy business</header><text>The term <term>person engaged in the energy business</term> means a person that devotes time, attention, or labor to the mining, extraction, production, refinement, transportation, distribution, manufacture, or sale of energy as a regular course of business in or affecting interstate commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H60A6BEEC9E204B5D9FC9C584D4B14E42"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualified liability action</header><text>The term <term>qualified liability action</term> means a climate suit or any action or proceeding to implement or enforce an energy penalty law that is brought by any person against a person engaged in the energy business.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF746058D86E84F568A744539F3CAC5C1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC70CA34474CB4C49A995454E24FD1B0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0978CC28C234688979F31ABD2BC3751"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other territory or possession of the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F3894A969C745D2BA135A9A43758969"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any political subdivision or instrumentality of an entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA86E2EF1722A41B39C7104460E1EB1D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any State official acting in their official capacity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H848BAB184C6641DC8C9BBDF635B54BC6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Trade association</header><text>The term <term>trade association</term> means any corporation, unincorporated association, federation, business league, or professional or business organization—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7DCD3953B2F4DB8BA054DBF20113C27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is not organized or operated for profit;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA929D60AFB184D9F8F64513B07AB2829"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is an organization described in subsection (c)(6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under subsection (a) of that section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96929A92617C4C7EBA711BFB7163678B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2 or more members of which are people engaged in the energy business.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A9B4E72AA4448EC87068D25C5B02271"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on energy penalty laws and the bringing of qualified liability actions in Federal or State court</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H116203917DDB4DF4AB0A79EAABBC3CB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A qualified liability action may not be filed or maintained in any Federal or State court.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE66716B0E2F4A628B9C2E69309E1C4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dismissal of pending actions</header><text>Any qualified liability action that is pending on the date of enactment of this Act shall be immediately dismissed by the court in which the qualified liability action is brought or is currently pending.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A5FF2E69EE044AD89B6490A0153528F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on State laws</header><text>Each energy penalty law is void and of no effect.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCA7048C8088B41F4B0FCA07D453C8231"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal preemption</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H394C1BA07ABE478FBB255646D2ED286B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulation of greenhouse gas emissions and climate change is and continues to be governed exclusively by Federal law and regulated by Federal agencies with authority delegated to those Federal agencies by Congress.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A90B5FA0457440CBF32D7CB71B2EC35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No private right of action</header><text>No private right of action or claim shall be maintained, implied, or inferred under any State law with respect to climate change-related harms from greenhouse gas emissions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9E8EFBF12FD648F8A288CD2F5C64AFBC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of the provision to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

