<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW25A43-78T-SN-FVW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 560 IS: Recognizing that mercury pollution can cause severe health problems, including permanent brain damage, kidney damage, and birth defects.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 560</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing that mercury pollution can cause severe health problems, including permanent brain damage, kidney damage, and birth defects.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas mercury is a powerful neurotoxin;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mercury occurs naturally in coal, petroleum, and natural gas, and burning those fossil fuels releases mercury into the atmosphere;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mercury emitted into the atmosphere enters the ground, water, and food system;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas consuming fish from mercury-contaminated waterbodies is the most common way people are exposed to dangerous levels of mercury;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas all 50 States maintain web pages to issue fish advisories for mercury-contaminated waterbodies and the Department of Public Health and Environment of the State of Colorado reports that, as of 2025, there were more than 3,700 mercury advisories in effect across the United States;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas fossil fuel-fired power plants are the largest source of mercury emissions in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas an estimated 80,000,000 individuals in the United States live within 3 miles of a fossil fuel-fired power plant, approximately 17,000,000 of whom are children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas exposure to mercury can cause severe health problems, including permanent brain damage, kidney damage, birth defects, and heart disease;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas gestational mercury exposure is particularly dangerous and babies born after mercury exposure in the womb can exhibit severe intellectual impairment, as well as ataxia and cerebral palsy, seizures, vision and hearing loss, delayed developmental milestones, language disorders, and problems with motor function, visual spatial abilities, and memory; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is no known safe level of exposure to mercury: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That—</text><paragraph id="ida313dcea78714aaa919708671a8f38c7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Senate recognizes that mercury pollution can cause severe health problems, including permanent brain damage, kidney damage, and birth defects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e2b1a715e254907b82bc9c9b9a2759a"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is the sense of the Senate that the Environmental Protection Agency should not loosen controls on mercury pollution from power plants.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

