<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB766B24B804D4BB18A5E6E83A438EA43" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8086 IH: To establish a National and Nuclear Risk Reduction Center within the Department of State, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8086</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a National and Nuclear Risk Reduction Center within the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC5934EC4FA314357A902763421CEABB1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDA05791BBE3F43E1B8542059A8EE1101" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishment of National and Nuclear Risk Reduction Center</header> 
<subsection id="HEB3621DFF9CC4B9AAABF30710F6F6C77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Department of State a National and Nuclear Risk Reduction Center (<quote>NNRRC</quote>), who shall report directly to the Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7F834B03D2164BC497E077539AA4AAFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The NNRRC shall carry out the following responsibilities:</text> 
<paragraph id="H47E208324DEA4CA79A1D2DE5C5499BDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Operate a 24-hour basis government-to-government communications center for exchanging notifications with foreign counterparts as required by—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9249C18FCDC41C686349890797672D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bilateral and multilateral arms control agreements or arrangements; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF43E493A8AF34E6EAE8110B209B89D02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>confidence-building agreements between the United States, foreign governments, and international organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65B040D03AB544C39238EE895273D449"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Translate and disseminate incoming and outgoing notifications and messages to and from appropriate Federal Government departments and agencies for purposes of executing, when necessary, operational alerts or time-sensitive notifications requiring immediate attention.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H511C25823DE64100913604CB2395ADBC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Advise Department of State policy and operational offices on communication or technical issues from new arms control and international security agreements. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC119D740FD424E9F88F05098BA32A745"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provide technical assistance to foreign governments on NNRRC-related requirements on the operation of national communication systems for arms control agreements and other confidence-building agreements. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDE0E6EB122B40BA9F4CFE4563AD85B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Ensure the NNRRC maintains not fewer than one linguist on duty at all time who—</text> <subparagraph id="HA4AF3A74728E464E9D0E393D96960C20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>can provide Mandarin Chinese and Russian language translation services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FCBE4F8035642A3A8D27D2315E1B326"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is proficient with technical arms control matters; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35B49BA9547C486686BF8BBD24A2F8D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>can facilitate communications related to notifications and exchanges with foreign governments involving arms control agreements and arrangements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H279DDBD667F445148E3A3EB1909EAA49"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Establish a protocol for coordination between the NNRRC and interagency stakeholders, including liaison roles. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H082C8A653DDF4D7986F6FFEDE743637F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Perform such other duties as the Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security may from time to time designate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

