<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3CEEFE6F389A41CC95CAA9A9EA9DD6BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7441 IH: Bayard Rustin Stamp Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Postmaster General to issue a forever stamp depicting Bayard Rustin, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H23F928D5296549DAB9B2D66F8E81B038" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8AF7C6EA54C346F29C1E36398E9E6E6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bayard Rustin Stamp Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6DDCED5EB47047A19535F7C1C5C3904C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE8AF3FF4FB6B4355836449D8847A9701"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Bayard Rustin was born on March 17, 1912, and was raised by his grandparents in West Chester, Pennsylvania. From a young age, Rustin learned to prioritize the values of nonviolence and peacekeeping from his grandparents’ Quaker faith, and would continue to build these values in his life as a civil rights movement leader.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H670B2DC9600E4D88A73A5C412B9F7650"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Rustin attended City College of New York, where he joined a progressive club that aimed to remedy racial issues during turbulent times. His time with the club was short lived, but it inspired him to join the Fellowship of Reconciliation, an organization that became a champion for labor rights, equality, and world peace.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54116975F0E0454B84ADAC024691F826"><enum>(3)</enum><text>His time with the Fellowship of Reconciliation prompted Rustin to become a leader in the 1947 <quote>Journey to Reconciliation</quote>, an event where White and Black people across the South rode buses together to challenge segregation laws, a precursor to the Freedom Rides.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H46B64B1F1A5146529EB1D372F3FFEE3E"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>Rustin was an advisor in Martin Luther King, Jr.’s inner circle as he advocated pacifism and nonviolence for achieving equal treatment for African-Americans.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA12A5B4BAE546E9AC383F1FB6BE34ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Rustin used his brilliant strategic handling of the use of aggressive, peaceful action in the civil rights movement and throughout his life as an activist.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E1A6F5B08324345B64FA757AE8AFEB8"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>His most important role was as the chief organizer of the March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom in 1963, the largest demonstration ever organized at the time, in which a quarter of a million people turned out to demand civil rights for African-Americans.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB5E07827F694553BAF8DB7F82258CCD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In the years after the civil rights movement, Rustin used his background as a gay man to inspire others to advocate for and to achieve LGBTQ+ rights.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4538F78F70024209815D1471AF5D4108"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Rustin remained a strategist and public speaker for workers’ rights movements, including co-founding the A. Philip Randolph Institute for Black trade union members.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE5984BF0EA624AA3B793057F33B036B9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Rustin committed to promoting social good and advocating for the disenfranchised until his death in 1987.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H263DF88DB5114C878ECFFEA59E7B7645"><enum>3.</enum><header>Bayard Rustin stamp</header> <subsection id="HA5882B7153C5498E85C837AE610B024F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to honor the life and work of Bayard Rustin, a leader in the civil rights movement, the Postmaster General shall provide for the issuance of a forever stamp suitable for that purpose that depicts Bayard Rustin.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4B40206588FD44E6845DC5E0A9AB6D0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of definitive stamp</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, the term <term>forever stamp</term> means a definitive stamp that—</text> <paragraph id="H3226EB6B9A7D4C308D8433494AE58626"><enum>(1)</enum><text>meets the postage required for first-class mail up to one ounce in weight; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00CFE654337A48B29F8B9F4EC708AF15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>retains full validity for that purpose even if the rate of that postage is later increased.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H123154AABA8147109D781D99D168B6FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The stamp described in subsection (a) shall be issued as soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

