<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBFC389E9989B46129EBCC69B5613478F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8805 IH: Increased Compensation for Enforcement and Federal Retention for Officers in Strategic Theaters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8805</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260513">May 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide supplemental payments to Federal personnel performing immigration enforcement operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H62570199F5BF4AFE805A2D9B6309D32F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1AAFE48D8DBA4E4BACEC95701A97677C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increased Compensation for Enforcement and Federal Retention for Officers in Strategic Theaters Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ICE FROST Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE39F338F54464301BB1ED4FD745D5999"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supplemental payments to immigration enforcement personnel</header> <subsection id="HB1A8B657AA254955A8CF1E7A0607C882" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered employee shall be paid a supplemental payment equal to 25 percent of the employee’s annual rate of basic pay.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF642A82B972B4CFD8B0F764B7F95C16E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hazardous duty supplemental payment</header> 
<paragraph id="HB676D1248DEC48EE9012D7CE9513C407" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each covered employee serving in a hazardous duty area, as determined under paragraph (2), shall be paid, in addition to any payment under subsection (a), a supplemental payment equal to 15 percent of the employee’s annual rate of basic pay.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BD2C1E6516945ECB388A538A28CB572"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header> <subparagraph id="H98547FEE54A04D49ABF347E4A355B205"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The following geographic areas shall be designated as hazardous duty areas:</text> 
<clause id="HF569E3B2588E45ADBCB8771E87965F63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Chicago-Naperville Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> <clause id="HD214FA111CC94B049C6C0BA1F5C8A0AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Detroit-Warren-Ann Arbor Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H18725D98086349B7995C422C045DDED4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Los Angeles-Long Beach Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> <clause id="HEDDF727969794EE6BDC96CE7AAA42EF7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Memphis-Forrest City Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H274EDD2610F74D169A68CF3C85643310"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Minneapolis-St. Paul-Bloomington, Minnesota, Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> <clause id="H3B8EE2EBC2CA479D93A723A91939ECF4"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>New York-Newark Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H06C94757DE5F447093A56935CF7212F3"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>San Jose-San Francisco-Oakland Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> <clause id="H52410A938CA4430682B1443D75DC8BB5"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>St. Louis-St. Charles-Farmington Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1764132EC5294060AE7C02D7439AF98F"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Washington-Baltimore-Arlington Consolidated Metropolitan Statistical Area.</text></clause> <clause id="H8CA2F583F7CF473A8559CD6CD1A7E5AD"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other statistical area determined by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, meets criteria for elevated risk to covered employees under subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB0836C642294AE2A18A35A6577D4AC0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other areas</header><text>An area may be designated under paragraph (2)(A)(x) if such area presents an elevated risk to covered employees based on 1 or more of the following factors:</text> <clause id="H4A18C97C6C0A4028843B2AA5DE21214E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Violent crime levels.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7938709631C245F5A96E97EA2DB15DA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Increased presence of transnational criminal organizations.</text></clause> <clause id="H59B8FC989E5645B3B5A5302E1F3376CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Significant concentration of aliens unlawfully present in the United States.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD68F025D8675460295BC5D5D6D43A4B5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Documented incidents of assaults, interference, or threats directed to covered employees.</text></clause> <clause id="H0AD0A8E995EE4D5685751499C01BF5B6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other factor the Director, the Secretary, or the Attorney General determines is an elevated risk to covered employees.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6B1C60762644F168EBD2BA6664E3AA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review and termination</header><text>The Director, in consultation with the Secretary and the Attorney General, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7365752562BA41B4A3C723E47DE5EDE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review each designation under paragraph (2) not less than annually; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4AA5B9F82B84F6E9B92125CADCB463E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>terminate any designation under such paragraph that no longer meets the criteria under subparagraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEAF7A00248C74379BF1DA68B8798FAD4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The supplemental payments under this section shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H55E9871F3137426CBBEFC922C9E2FC23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to any supplemental payment under subsection (a), be paid as a lump-sum on the first day of the first pay period beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE905BDD630AE43FAB6C7922CA999797B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any supplemental payment under subsection (b)(2)(A), be paid as a lump-sum on the first day of the first pay period beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter until the designation is terminated under subsection (b)(3)(B);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06D3FCC4C474432C9D83A06665BEF772"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a supplemental payment for any area designated after the date of the enactment of this Act under subsection (b)(2)(B), be paid as a lump-sum on the first day of the first pay period beginning on or after the date of such designation and annually thereafter until the designation is terminated under subsection (b)(3)(B);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD92553D02D2C4891B1DEB31CD8719F3B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be in addition to a covered employee’s rate of basic pay and any other allowance, differential, bonus, award, or other similar cash payment; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA668081DD0A4E75A9BA8341B13D0FCE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the application of section 5307 of title 5, United States Code, not be counted as part of the aggregate compensation of the covered employee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9927E9CAB9FD411E9389581A7EFA8DCD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H40E06D5B6031456087D3DE9CACAE7133" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>covered employee</term> means a law enforcement officer performing immigration enforcement operations (defined as the identification, apprehension, arrest, detention, or removal of aliens unlawfully present in the United States in violation of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>));</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAB36595132A48C18F67B433A7F31725"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Office of Personnel Management;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22583AA23D844C6C91F75722FD84BCFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5541(3) of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12EAA242AA8442EF94645B634F9635F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46E65FEB40794D59A5D4B2E22193DA46"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>transnational criminal organization</term> means a group of persons that includes 1 or more foreign persons that engages in or facilitates an ongoing pattern of serious criminal activity involving the jurisdictions of at least 2 foreign states, or 1 foreign state and the United States, and that threatens the national security, foreign policy, or economy of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30D840EFE31649F18E8FF319EDD916ED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>violent crime</term> has the meaning given the term <term>crime of violence</term> in section 16 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H736DF39415AD43C88B7F6D7A16E9974B" section-type="section-one"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of surcharge on certain remittance transfers</header> 
<subsection id="H37E8C32E244A49EABEB5008C060E94D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4475">Section 4475(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>equal to 1 percent</quote> and all that follows, and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9CE258610BDA4DD3ADF4BA1CE79AC9C2" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">equal to the sum of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB16932E8480C4DA6BE83750773D1E71B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 percent of the amount of such transfer, plus</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDECC749986A4116B177B788A2743DAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the specified surcharge (if any) with respect to such transfer.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBA596D5B1DC34F4FAA6D9280E6B7F279"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified surcharge defined</header><text>Section 4475(e) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3D0EB897E8B0475D889F0B68223FA46D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H8C88B6C54DD64584AABE8993443842D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Specified surcharge</header> <subparagraph id="H193770B714DF4693A106980894CA7E83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>specified surcharge</quote> means, with respect to any remittance transfer—</text> 
<clause id="HDB3680A4520E44B691A4EF237721C45E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of the designated recipient of such transfer being located in a specified foreign country, an amount equal to $199,</text></clause> <clause id="H2D0143F1CE9944DCA5085A622394AF4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of the designated recipient of such transfer being located in a foreign country with respect to which the visa overstay rate (as defined in section 217(c)(8)(C)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act) exceeds 2 percent, an amount equal to $99, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1A6FA0835F044EA98635CC87A5AB42F0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of both clauses (i) and (ii) applying, the sum of the amounts described in such clauses.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD8515D055E341539B9EA0E2C8371172"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Specified foreign country</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>specified foreign country</quote> means Afghanistan, Burma, Chad, Republic of the Congo, Equatorial Guinea, Eritrea, Haiti, Iran, Libya, Somalia, Sudan, or Yemen.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1BBC3E61AC6F4845BD44B44A3EA66E57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4475(e)(1) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote><quote>designated recipient</quote>,</quote> after <quote>The terms</quote>.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H84881C09850F4BC98F32F0094582C142"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to transfers made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

