<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Reported-in-House" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" dms-id="H11163c62-e350-4162-8969-f5fde25d3399" public-private="public" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 953 RH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 6703) to ensure access to affordable health insurance; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 498) to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to prohibit Federal Medicaid funding for gender transition procedures for minors; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3492) to amend section 116 of title 18, United States Code, with respect to genital and bodily mutilation and chemical castration of minors; and relating to consideration of the bill (H.R. 4776) to amend the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to clarify ambiguous provisions and facilitate a more efficient, effective, and timely environmental review process.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">House Calendar No. 51</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 953</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–411]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</sponsor>, from the Committee on Rules<committee-name committee-id="RU00"></committee-name>, reported the following resolution; which was referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 6703) to ensure access to affordable health insurance; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 498) to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to prohibit Federal Medicaid funding for gender transition procedures for minors; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3492) to amend section 116 of title 18, United States Code, with respect to genital and bodily mutilation and chemical castration of minors; and relating to consideration of the bill (H.R. 4776) to amend the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to clarify ambiguous provisions and facilitate a more efficient, effective, and timely environmental review process.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="Haf37bdb1-ba33-4c65-a982-5ad0982f03f8"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7c9e9cab-fd31-408e-9b16-7cef388934aa"><enum/><text>That upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 6703) to ensure access to affordable health insurance. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided among and controlled by the respective chairs and ranking minority members of the Committees on Education and Workforce, Energy and Commerce, and Ways and Means, or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="H1FD09CD2D75C425ABFFA90E2EEDECE04"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 498) to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to prohibit Federal Medicaid funding for gender transition procedures for minors. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The bill shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill and on any amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Energy and Commerce or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="H9EF3DDB389C944D5BEBAD29A2DAC087F"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 3492) to amend section 116 of title 18, United States Code, with respect to genital and bodily mutilation and chemical castration of minors. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on the Judiciary or their respective designees; (2) the further amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, if offered by the Member designated in the report, which shall be in order without intervention of any point of order, shall be considered as read, shall be separately debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question; and (3) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="HF22E820DDC6944D08A888F5C061E3565"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During consideration of the bill (H.R. 4776) to amend the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to clarify ambiguous provisions and facilitate a more efficient, effective, and timely environmental review process, pursuant to House Resolution 951, the further amendment specified in section 5 of this resolution shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole.</text></section><section id="HF0859940678E4DCB9AC8F89C014BDD7D"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment referred to in section 4 of this resolution is as follows:</text><paragraph id="H4BE208325A2E4D12BDB9199E8407481C"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> “Page 29, after line 6, insert the following:</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE26B1495328E43AF9ACBF6D6FAC66A4C"><enum/><text>SEC. 4. PRESERVATION OF ONGOING ADMINISTRATIVE CORRECTIONS.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12110D9BC8D24E2B84377CD5B3E8B362"><enum/><text>This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall not apply to any agency action with respect to which a Federal agency has, during the period beginning on January 20, 2025, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act—</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B03B5C007EF47198C8834A3D68F8028"><enum>(1)</enum><text>filed a motion to voluntarily remand; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3310CE6A7AA43C5809F158B289728D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">otherwise reopened, reconsidered, or initiated corrective action under the statutory authority of the Federal agency, regardless of whether the Federal agency has completed such corrective action as of the date of enactment of this Act.”.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body><endorsement><action-date>December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the House Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

