<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H925CBB40364840EABAFE9979F199D35E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9669 IH: Forensic Assertive Community Treatment Pilot Program Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9669</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, to establish a 5-year pilot program under which the Secretary will award grants to eligible entities for purposes of expanding forensic assertive community treatment team programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C2A4CD6779B432BB6FEB4C50BFE2E33" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE1E6BA61BC6E45C6AC2CEB90767E4C21" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Forensic Assertive Community Treatment Pilot Program Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FACT Pilot Program Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H828D2BB7129844BCB35AB6693C39C026"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to support State and local forensic assertive community treatment programs</header> 
<subsection id="H65D99D8E284E4A6A99517321B93CBCE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="H8848F1CFA79B4BB3BE56430E0CACFD5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall establish a 5-year pilot program under which the Secretary will award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to, directly, or through a subgrant to a nonprofit organization, licensed mental health treatment agency, a local management care entity/managed care organization, or any other entity the Secretary considers appropriate, expand the forensic assertive community treatment team programs carried out in the respective jurisdiction of the eligible entity to enable such entity to serve more community members.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE504A75A47BE4C6ABEAE9A234877D3C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H94F228C82FC241609AA69136DC84C8B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State or a local government that, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, is carrying out, or is partnering with, a forensic assertive community treatment team program within the respective State or locality or localities served by the local government.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED3A1B4AF378417790B19C1E6BF60206"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>forensic assertive community treatment team program</term> means a program—</text> 
<clause id="H2F917747009F42A5A22868AA5E965628"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a small client-to-team ratio under which around the clock, time-unlimited care and intensive, field-based services, including mental health care, addiction treatment, vocational training, and housing assistance, are provided to individuals with serious mental illness, who may have co-occurring substance use and physical health disorders, and who are involved with the criminal justice system;</text></clause> <clause id="HD6D3556D2DE249F5B75C7EE77BF8A1AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that maintains fidelity with the Assertive Community Treatment model, while incorporating adaptions that address the criminogenic risk and needs of the individuals described in clause (i); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6BCC02A5B0F4C83A3BF97F85759D584"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in which such services are provided by a multidisciplinary team of providers that includes—</text> <subclause id="HC071F4338D1246659BF4676CAB617751"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from the field of psychiatry (including psychiatric nursing);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H56950930857F444BA31F93E2A6F54205"><enum>(II)</enum><text>specialists in employment and substance use services;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H57149B0073E14585B25D51A01004FDD7"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a criminal justice partner (such as a member of local law enforcement, a provider of pretrial services, or a probation or parole officer); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA5FFE229A76440DB967DC381E4C9F0B1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one or more forensic peer specialists living with serious mental illness or a co-occurring disorder who have personal experience with criminal justice system involvement.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C91705A23114CFABC2D44E5C03A88FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>involved with the criminal justice system</term> means to have had contact with law enforcement, the courts, or correctional systems. Such term includes involvement at any stage, including arrest, pre-trial services, incarcerated in jail or prison, incarcerated in jail or prison and pending imminent release, recently released from incarceration or a forensic hospital setting, probation, parole, or other forms of community supervision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD511244A6D5B4C50A9609CEF83A2BD87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HABBE63016DA944A987C2A81A8C72969F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report</header> <paragraph id="H3106B864249845D9889E30238D79A29A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall seek to enter into an agreement under which the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, shall conduct a study which shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1289A313D95F4EF892AE012A6350B4AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommend defined and measurable metrics of effectiveness that the Secretary and other Federal agencies may use in evaluating programs, including metrics measuring—</text> <clause id="H5DB6E0A6D4A9430BB2DA72A9807C36F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reduction in recidivism, psychiatric hospitalizations, emergency department utilization, and reoccurring hospitalization and the associated costs;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE28BFD636574A1D9293A952C5D874EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reduction in time it takes for an at-risk individual to access stable housing;</text></clause> <clause id="H4E059C3E243E435C9D0EEC76F040AB15"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the reduction in the time it takes for an at-risk individual to access mental health services;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5C28F67178AD4F54AC26C978BE7D471F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the improvement in mental health outcomes;</text></clause> <clause id="H4C397F21D1CF482AA7D3F51216E31775"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any increase in community connection and reintegration; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC7A4ED6E63D2452E8CE5CF3608B0C46C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>improvement in overall public safety;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF90016AB5D4A42DF94CA05401275C657"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify key mechanisms of model fidelity that can be recognized despite the variation between local and State programs and justice systems and identify model fidelity metrics for use in future evaluations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3A772C137D3F4CB8AAD8612C651D82D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop policy proposals that can be made at the Federal and State level to scale up existing programs and infrastructure, with attention to implementation considerations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D6C6EFEEE794FA8B9F78EF8832F1BAD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide an implementation framework for States and localities interested in starting new forensic assertive community treatment team programs, with attention to the unique needs for adaptation in rural communities;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1442F1D55C5E42A3BBFAD7061FC2FCC2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide a cost estimate for the development and implementation of such policy proposals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2B99A543DE641539D4F2EC5F13EF4F9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide a cost-savings and benefits analysis of the program model, including the impact on health care and justice systems; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2413A58136D94A699BE45D0B42BD9A19"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Secretary for the improvement and implementation of such model.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD0F20A919834112B096F64DE2ECAF3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission to Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agreement entered into under paragraph (1) shall require the National Academies, not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, to submit to the Secretary and to Congress a report containing the findings of the study conducted under such agreement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7381F9CE813242718A82767F81ECB9A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the submission of the report under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H4BDCBC0119904CDBB201CB7D004126EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish such report on the public website of the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1BC9A7E7E3845BFA7DDF7CEF016AEB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>distribute such report to State and local governments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EFF107FBD2A4F59BB77F1615AFBCFFC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $1,500,000, to remain available until expended.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

