<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AA5025313734A6CA9594A69771C57B8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9276 IH: Federal Cryptocurrency Theft Enforcement and Coordination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9276</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Federal Cryptocurrency Theft Task Force, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H446EE40B0E684153B38F46ECB3333C0A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE6ACB4CE979D459398720E8A08C5B4E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Cryptocurrency Theft Enforcement and Coordination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA80CE05DC9F54DFE93CEE7DD13D04D8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H34FF602023124C49B9B73342982F6C96"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cryptocurrency theft and related digital asset crimes have increased in frequency, scale, and sophistication, resulting in significant financial harm to individuals, businesses, and communities across the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4648D6095BE44F7EB46BA1A5FFB46C05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Cryptocurrency theft has created a criminal justice and law enforcement challenge involving fraud, hacking, theft, conspiracy, and other violations of Federal criminal law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6420A6199F340F0BB62A985B4B7D2AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Victims of cryptocurrency theft frequently encounter fragmented and inconsistent responses from Federal, State, and local authorities due to the absence of a centralized Federal coordination mechanism.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03A59062BDA342FC9D37BA94AC066309"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State and local law enforcement agencies often lack clear guidance, training, and Federal points of contact for responding to cryptocurrency theft incidents.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDE4D990D9E994303ADFFE1776E70825A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Federal cryptocurrency theft task force</header> 
<subsection id="HF81D4CCDC6DA4A72ACC858AC4F02BA9B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Department of Justice a task force to be known as the Federal Cryptocurrency Theft Task Force (in this Act, referred to as <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA4E6D439DB614F7D9EB235600E1F10E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Task Force shall be chaired by the Attorney General, or the Attorney General’s designee.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97737394855547E186643782E878F3D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Task Force shall include senior representatives from—</text> <paragraph id="H776DF832498247298CBFE3126A711F99"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Justice;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87AD9678FFB7484D82BE29FC97449E19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53960441DA4644EDBA13A5703F5DA2FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security, including Homeland Security Investigations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8AA126AC6044F98B722CF7DF0E6C59D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury, including the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21D6D1B4D62F41EA95806AD0AB26351F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other Federal law enforcement agency the Attorney General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2059D19A6BBF4A01BD230CD181A0E49A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criminal law focus</header><text>The Task Force shall operate consistent with the Attorney General’s authorities under title 18, United States Code, and other applicable Federal criminal statutes.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HBAD20A3529F94561B4D1FF46D67612D3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the task force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Task Force shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2A6F395A04E543B98073B18917AF5E00"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as the primary Federal coordinating body for the prevention, investigation, and prosecution of cryptocurrency theft and criminal activity directly related to such theft;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H154ED116CBF641548C7A3DBD78BF7682"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve coordination among Federal law enforcement agencies involved in cryptocurrency theft investigations and prosecutions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86462C528856476A881B9C2A996E0CE5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and disseminate best practices for Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies related to evidence collection, analysis of seized digital evidence for cryptocurrency artifacts, investigative techniques, asset tracing, and victim engagement in cryptocurrency theft cases;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0BF914CEAAF486398419B589465A0D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide technical assistance, training, and guidance to State and local law enforcement agencies, including prosecutors, regarding cryptocurrency theft investigations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E55DCB23E7842ABA7C017ACD1200A86"><enum>(5)</enum><text>facilitate information sharing among Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FEBF880AE9F46DF8D33E0579365FB3C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate, any challenges and gaps in existing criminal enforcement authorities and measures related to cryptocurrency theft along with suggestions for reforms to address such challenges; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE36ABA08C4634BD9801CC7B809A4C9A6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>coordinate, as appropriate, with international law enforcement partners on cross-border cryptocurrency theft investigations.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9ED5A70740AD4F01909DF8F86D45B5FE"><enum>5.</enum><header>State and local law enforcement coordination</header> <subsection id="H120618062C19476BB84CD52E88696AC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall conduct regular outreach to relevant State and local law enforcement agencies to collect information to improve investigative coordination and referral processes related to cryptocurrency theft.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAA82121093DC4ED19F5A4AD065496456"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Voluntary participation</header><text>Participation by State, local, Tribal, or territorial governments in activities under this Act shall be voluntary.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HACA7F983779846EE96DBD069501DD4EA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Cryptocurrency theft described</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>cryptocurrency theft</quote>—</text> 
<paragraph id="H83556B798943401AAB6B424A9FF47B9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means the intentional unauthorized or unlawful use or transfer of a person’s cryptocurrency that constitutes an offense under title 18, United States Code; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF3E2690EB194BDCB619EE14E603B883"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes gaining access by fraudulent means, including hacking, phishing, tricking, or scamming.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFEE51B53F68E4272BA8D96ACE9AFF0FA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HE120123E705240B6BCED92074160D39C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the activities of the Task Force;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D03D3E8B1304B6E9CF1C5E767D43BB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trends and emerging threats related to cryptocurrency theft and criminal activity directly related to such theft;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E88781D63F242018C0ABACE91D01FC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of coordination with State and local law enforcement agencies; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A58CA2F25C54E1F89732F8454A983E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or administrative actions to strengthen the investigation and prosecution of cryptocurrency theft.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HAD460834917842659B9EE93B19043CD9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB3D989283CE64F9AABB608843378281E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorize the regulation of cryptocurrency, digital asset markets, financial institutions, or financial products;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE732A07ADFD44D6FB241AF076DBB949F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expand or limit the regulatory authority of any Federal agency;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9EB23756D944292BADA7357F4AC4824"><enum>(3)</enum><text>create any new criminal offenses; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F29D2AD667041A4B516DA4C69A0F7D7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>create any private right of action.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

