<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26972-DDG-VD-K03"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4839 IS: Bank-Fintech Partnership Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4839</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation to study how partnerships between financial technology companies and banking organizations can support new banking organization formation and community bank health, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1ADBD2BBA15345CC9D82A280C656C597"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9A23D63881D84AC2A5AF4CABB58F13A2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bank-Fintech Partnership Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27c3e9f18d09481fbbf6ceb683ac9527"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9397fe6a74af43ed959dd6d56daa404f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Banking organization</header><text>The term <term>banking organization</term> means a depository institution holding company or an insured depository institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e1e1ed04d774bcb932c71694a4662f3"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Depository institution holding company; insured depository institution</header><text>The terms <term>depository institution holding company</term> and <term>insured depository institution</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2A99AD8806BB4F1AB125456EA2BDEF87"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on bank-fintech partnerships</header><subsection id="H32662A9913D94CBFA24865D013A730F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall carry out a study of—</text><paragraph id="HFE9BDEDA4D504937B4AC0409B69B7800"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of partnerships between banking organizations and financial technology companies on the banking sector, competition, innovation, consumer protection, and the availability of financial products and services, including the extent to which the partnerships support the formation of new banking organizations, reduce time to market for products and services, lower compliance burdens, boost customer acquisition, improve technological capabilities, and provide access to more diverse funding sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H412D5F256B17430C86DF0DE8064C06B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">what changes to Federal laws governing banking organizations, or to rules or guidance adopted by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, or the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, may help promote effective partnerships between banking organizations and financial technology companies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4493E5716A2E4CAC9AE025D23583EA54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall submit to Congress a report containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="idfdb2951bea3d47fbada3e4e5b34ae91d"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study on credit union-fintech partnerships</header><subsection id="idb3411e853e5941d2956c149197a0d105"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The National Credit Union Administration shall carry out a study of—</text><paragraph id="id78d2ddd8800f48b28920cd1ac02690e0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the impact of partnerships between credit unions and financial technology companies on the credit union sector, competition, innovation, consumer protection, and the availability of financial products and services, including the extent to which the partnerships support the formation of new credit unions, reduce time to market for products and services, lower compliance burdens, boost customer acquisition, improve technological capabilities, and provide access to more diverse funding sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id96949c915a3f4b7fb428ab459af54db9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>what changes to Federal laws governing credit unions, or to rules or guidance adopted by the National Credit Union Administration, may help promote effective partnerships between credit unions and financial technology companies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id246cadd0f50b4ff1b234dceef52adcfb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the National Credit Union Administration shall submit to Congress a report to Congress containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

