<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF22F2B42FBD349D0BBB2F535EB60E2B9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6085 IH: Stop Ballroom Bribery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6085</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent corruption by appropriately limiting donations for any public property, building, or fixture at the White House, the Naval Observatory, or certain other public property, for events on such property, or for monuments to living current or former Presidents, current or former Vice Presidents, or current or former employees or officers appointed by the President.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9A7B88C912E2451E8476870F378ACA65" style="OLC"><section id="H5BCB26DAF1064F3A921021E857CBBFD1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Ballroom Bribery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H36F9DADC06C643408D41A4CD1D23DF55"><enum>2.</enum><header>Donation restrictions for certain public property linked to President or Vice President</header><subsection id="H175A9B780D034C44B218280775AC66BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6172618F7D694957884D32A96D381B9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered project</header><text>The term <term>covered project</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4FC8C211344D43928C65C0304F95627B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the maintenance, acquisition, enhancement, improvement, alteration, demolition, or construction of any public property (including real property), building, or fixture located on or immediately adjacent to the grounds of the White House, the grounds of Number One Observatory Circle, or other public property intended for or dedicated to the use of the sitting President, the sitting Vice President, or a spouse or child of the sitting President or the sitting Vice President;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H562503E6D73541FC99B62E04A81187D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the maintenance, acquisition, enhancement, improvement, alteration, demolition, or construction of a Federal monument or other structure on public property that names or honors a living current or former President, Vice President, or employee or officer appointed by the President; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H887C3171D4B143C6B6B5B69CA6777AEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an event hosted on the grounds of the White House, the grounds of Number One Observatory Circle, or on any other public property intended for or dedicated to the use of the sitting President, the sitting Vice President, or a spouse or child of the sitting President or the sitting Vice President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H462FB608F8C24F30BC81E011B9D96828"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Donation</header><text>The term <term>donation</term> means a gift, donation, bequest, or devise of anything of value, including services, whether made directly to the Federal Government or indirectly via another entity or person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FAFF76F3547492C8E673A831BEC0298"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign government</header><text>The term <term>foreign government</term> has the meaning given that term in section 7342 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D31C52C700F4AE3A9960E8BBCF0AB28"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Lobbying activities</header><text>The term <term>lobbying activities</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD46D1A32F66E4AA4899288EB096D0991"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization that is described in paragraph (3) or (4) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA80B8F0F0EF5464F879C6F022C38BFC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restrictions on accepting donations</header><paragraph id="H0781905FB2E6410F83D743F6443FE0F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>NPS and OGE approval before acceptance or use of a donation for a covered project</header><text>A donation for a covered project may be accepted or used by the Federal Government only—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E603596E15F4581B23B2201590364B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with an authority to accept gifts or reimbursements under existing law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H917D7A208CD54196BDE2FD9A86F33605"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the individual who is serving in the position of Director of the National Park Service, and who has been appointed to such position by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2EDD33B4BF44630BB501288C10781B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes a written determination, with the concurrence of the individual who is serving in the position of Director of the Office of Government Ethics, and who has been appointed to such position by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, that the donation complies with the restrictions under paragraph (2);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58D11802C98446959F5B5E65EC92C280"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submits to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform of the House of Representatives the determination described in clause (i); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H862F959DCC8747C183FB3350E0E3207F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publishes the determination described in clause (i) in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97D3D54AF2FB4EBEA130EA9930F864EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictions; requirements for donors</header><subparagraph id="HD0188CBD92D44094992219E74573B9AF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibited donations</header><text>A donation for a covered project may not be accepted or used by an officer or employee of the United States, including the President and Vice President, or a non-Governmental agent operating on behalf of such an officer or employee, if the ultimate source of the donation, in part or in whole, is a person who—</text><clause id="HD07BD41B89754AD983CB677DE6A5239F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the time the donation is made is, or at any time on or after the date on which the sitting President assumed the office of President was, involved in litigation with the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="H1D9EF80AAD294E91A3451A9EF11F7FE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at the time the donation is made is, or at any time on or after the date on which the sitting President assumed the office of President was, the subject or target of an administrative investigation or other enforcement action by the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="HEBB2E19D54A1460E84966502032F07E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at the time the donation is made is seeking or has in effect a contract or other business relationship with the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="HC185BB86D5434560A84EE952C1B904B3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>at the time the donation is made is seeking a grant from the Federal Government or has received such grant for which the funds have not been fully expended, revoked, or depleted;</text></clause><clause id="H53E920337ADE4E2F8EF3AE7F5CEF484A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>at the time the donation is made is, or at any time on or after the date on which the sitting President assumed the office of President was, involved in lobbying activities targeting any part of the executive branch;</text></clause><clause id="HDE394F1A58D04047BC98877BFE6BBE6A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>at the time the donation is made is seeking or requesting, or at any time on or after the date on which the sitting President assumed the office of President sought, requested, or received, a pardon from the President; or</text></clause><clause id="HA9F7FEEAC5EF4386A6AA7B808F32E65D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>at the time the donation is made is seeking, or at any time on or after the date on which the sitting President assumed the office of President sought, to be appointed to a position in the Federal Government by the President.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06897217F31549E79E948FE017854C92"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Integrity of donation</header><text>A donation for a covered project may not be accepted or used if the donation—</text><clause id="HF7D8058C88A3406EA0B4146DDE870D19"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes as an actual or implied condition of receipt of the donation any benefit derived from the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="H57E9D5D85F8145EA82894FE3EE90F133"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has been coerced through the use of the authority or position of any officer or employee of the United States, including the President or the Vice President; or</text></clause><clause id="HD337C568523149ADB02D34C4AF795EAA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>would influence or appear to influence the performance of the responsibilities by any officer or employee of the executive branch of the Federal Government, including the President or Vice President, or would otherwise compromise the integrity or appearance of integrity of any part of the executive branch of the Federal Government.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD764B42691144ABA1C8F06E646AD699"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prohibited solicitation</header><text>An officer or employee of the Executive Office of the President, including the President and Vice President, or the spouse or child of the President or Vice President, may not solicit a donation for a covered project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA47D176B2DC4606A801AB34F3869010"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Approval of foreign gifts and emoluments</header><text>A donation for a covered project made by a foreign government may not be accepted unless Congress has approved the accepting of the donation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE6E80F7F341145CFAEFB0F02CC1383FB"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Post-Donation restrictions</header> <paragraph id="HDFC1D96BB4504747AF5F3FFBA6772673"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Donor recognition limitations</header> <text>A donor name, donor logo, or other indication of the identity of a donor may not be displayed at any location described in subsection (a)(1) as recognition of the donation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HC1C0EC0CA7924F7290340E39BCC2FD96">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Cooling-off period</header>
 <text>A person making a donation for a covered project may not engage in any lobbying activities directed at any officer or employee of the United States in a position in the executive branch, including the President or the Vice President, during the 2-year period beginning on the date of the donation.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD59506992755424B903F4F2C06E0A3E3">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Conversion of donation to personal use</header>
 <text>No person may convert a donation to a covered project to the private use of the person or to the personal use of any other person.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H8AEFF8A05A2043F7B3E5BF6CF4C48EB7">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Disposition of leftover donations</header>
 <text>In addition to any other restriction on the disposition of unused funds by a nonprofit organization or other entity or person, the remaining balances of a donation for a covered project may not be expended for anything that directly and predictably benefits the President, the Vice President, a spouse or child of the President or the Vice President, an employee of the Executive Office of the President, or any officer appointed by the President.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection><subsection id="HBCBA0534D2D742FCB8ECA2218F711B47">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Transparency To ensure donations are disclosed and prohibit straw donations</header>
        <paragraph id="HE37F812C83524348B8536B4939290B7C">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>Disclosing donor meetings</header>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="H7E66EA7A95324B238BC1889927A057FD">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header>
 <text>In accordance with subparagraph (B), a person making a donation to or for the benefit of a covered project, directly or indirectly through another person, shall disclose to the Director of the National Park Service any meeting or other communication with the President, the Vice President, a spouse or child of the President or the Vice President, any other officer or employee of the United States, or any agent working on any of their behalf that occurs during the period beginning on the date that is 1 year before the date of the donation and ending on the date that is 1 year after the date of the donation, and the disclosure shall, for each such meeting, include the topics discussed and the date of the meeting.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="H1EFCD6487301489DB39FB37816F42699">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Timing of disclosure</header>
 <text>A person required to disclose a meeting or other communication under subparagraph (A) shall—</text>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="HF33FDE837FDD4761BF4C80A51A6FCA51">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a meeting or other communication occurring before the date of the applicable donation, make the disclosure required under subparagraph (A) not later than 7 days after the date of the donation; or</text>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="H6E551C0A1FD84B33B3C7A3DB1292EBA4">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a meeting or other communication occurring on or after the date of the applicable donation, make the disclosure required under subparagraph (A) not later than 7 days after the meeting or other communication.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB014E330CA494F0BBC41F668D194AC5C">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Quarterly publication</header>
 <text>The Director of the National Park Service, in coordination with the heads of any other relevant agencies and entities, shall publish a quarterly report in the Federal Register listing each donation contributed to or for the benefit of a covered project, which shall include, for each donation—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H8C8B6B8D437E4C2D8C94CEADB247FA45">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a brief description of the donation and the circumstances justifying acceptance;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H3BD4C7EC8D3742748BF5666A8D03BB37">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the date of acceptance;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H138E9E05226D4D61B93DE5B3297E296E"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the identity of each person who—</text>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="H2ABFBB909C0E41D881B318B73051C4F7">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contributed to the donation; and</text> </clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4C549C802204DDB8841322F3AD206F7"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contributed an aggregate amount of more than $200 as a part of donations made during the applicable calendar quarter; and</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="HEDE542B916F940EC8B3D41BEEFFBE9DE">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>information regarding any meeting or other communication described in paragraph (1).</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H936CB2977B2540B781793756022F60E7">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition on straw donations</header>
 <text>With respect to any donation to a covered project, whether made directly or indirectly, it shall be unlawful for a person to knowingly—</text>
          <subparagraph id="H6D45E19EB35843FDB81FC3D94BF79F11">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>make the donation in the name of another person;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCDCA8952B1424F52AFDA8FEC5811C890"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>permit the name of that person to be used to effect the donation by another person;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H103E1FF80BF844AA9881D40E965831E1">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>accept such a donation that is made by one person in the name of another person; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H651C2540278C4D89AAA19A1177DF2DB9">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>direct, help, or assist any person in making such a donation in the name of another person.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HB6B1B4A737554CED9A791FA1CADEB6F5">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
          <header>Prohibition on anonymous donations</header>
 <text>No donation for a covered project may be accepted if it is made on the condition that it be anonymous.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H96AF007A06404164B93051C28BEA5D12">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
          <header>Attestation by certain donors</header>
 <text>A donor employed by or closely affiliated with a person barred from making a donation under subsection (b)(2)(A) shall attest that the donor is not explicitly or implicitly making the donation on behalf of the person.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="H3F2D3EDA37B8476E88F7D893E3A4B13B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="HF8C9E98D139A4DD1A1AE568FD8A5975E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>OGE regulations and disgorgement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Government Ethics shall publish regulations implementing the procedures under this section, which shall permit the Director to direct the return of any donation that violates any provision of this section at any point in time.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72802F3F618141A99EE85F67E79047E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judicial review of OGE determinations</header><text>Any determination by the Director of the Office of Government Ethics under this section shall be subject to judicial review and the attorney general of a State or the Attorney General may bring an action in accordance with this subsection seeking judicial review of such a determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H349DB08DB956450AA5962B99B4C05315"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement by State attorneys general</header><text>The attorney general of a State may bring a civil action to redress a violation of this section in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or in any district court of the United States with jurisdiction over any part of the United States served by that attorney general.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H539CAD2898A246168BE2FC4647597BF4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enforcement by the United States</header><text>The Attorney General of the United States may bring a civil action or criminal prosecution to redress a violation of this section in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF29E1903DB684B199B49E09D8595BFAE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Civil and criminal penalties</header><subparagraph id="H21053C51B58845519092105E75561ACA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Civil</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5F0D10F9E074FC8A7CCDEFAEA851EFE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), any person who violates this section shall be subject to—</text><subclause id="H77E0ED56C2E54FAEBB19CCDB758C3F5C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a civil penalty that does not exceed the greater of $20,000 or an amount equal to the aggregate value of the donations involved in such violation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEC4656B7A6864BD5A3FBE44E2E77C219"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an order requiring the person to disgorge any benefit derived from any donation involved in the violation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1FC5476CE4FC4E5CA7CC418154887E22"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Larger violations</header><text>If the aggregate value of all donations involved in a violation of this section by a person during a calendar year exceeds $50,000, the person shall be subject to—</text><subclause id="H0422651A9947498CA0BF995BACD00EEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a civil penalty that does not exceed the greater of $100,000 or the amount equal to the aggregate value of the donations involved in such violation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6B9B7A5CEA8C4E34A27465E0ED5E0A99"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an order requiring the person to disgorge any benefit derived from any donation involved in the violation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8103E987A76439198E510F4F4696A11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criminal</header><clause id="H767901DB889A44139763B6563C4BFC0D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), any person who knowingly and willfully violates this section shall be—</text><subclause id="H50CF10F867CB4433A105CF5ABBF7BC62"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEC21DD11F6B24D70929AF1E752BC4FC7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subject to an order requiring the person to disgorge any benefit derived from any donation involved in the violation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4CB29C299B884216B4A489E5D3B88B54"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Larger violations</header><text>If the aggregate value of all donations involved in a violation of this section by a person during a calendar year exceeds $50,000, the person shall be—</text><subclause id="HC5D0DFA7DFCC4E9ABD31D6EEE4636CFD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fined under title 18, United States Code, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA853B34C0B404D1D9DE51A208EBD19AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subject to an order requiring the person to disgorge any benefit derived from any donation involved in the violation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE7A0DF8BE6243BA9453929147B81C6D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Other relief</header><text>In addition to the civil and criminal penalties described in paragraph (5), in an action brought under this subsection a court may grant a permanent or temporary injunction, restraining order, or other order, upon a showing that the person involved has likely committed a violation of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AA713A4CE9548AC8A2E998DE4BAEE6F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Period of limitations</header><subparagraph id="HB0DFC4356A1749E5AA1B7B6ABBFE471B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Civil</header><text>A civil action under this subsection may not be commenced later than 10 years after the cause of action accrues.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A5D6A4543A040049E73CCBEF981A305"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criminal</header><text>No person shall be prosecuted, tried, or punished for any offense under this subsection, unless the indictment is found or the information is instituted within 10 years after such offense shall have been committed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A2EB20B86294A18A21E55003EB6418F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The imposition of a civil or criminal penalty under this subsection does not preclude any other criminal or civil statutory, common law, or administrative remedy, which is available by law to the United States or any other person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H264339AA5EB4490F8B586E9D4D04F991"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this section, or the application of a provision of this section to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this section, and the application of the provision to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

