<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT26583-86M-2T-8KK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4991 IS: Homestake AI Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4991</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish an extremophile whole genome sequencing initiative, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homestake AI Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id92b723d618124aecbed2c5eca7fcb333"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extremophile whole genome sequencing initiative</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1a9ac5b3f90437a9d69e90e8665604b"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2ccbcfac18c4f2397adab4d9bd9f819"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means the long-term storage facility planned for under subsection (c)(1)(E).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37f2df9ae7594dc1bf9c0860f9f5229e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initiative</header><text>The term <term>initiative</term> means the extremophile whole genome sequencing initiative established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2cac88f68b24a49aa98836008895f45"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Undersecretary of Science.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd80506e156554a30b942c2c41a9adb67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an initiative, to be known as the <quote>extremophile whole genome sequencing initiative</quote>, that shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34d0e1ab38c047bdb28e60e230842b6f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be consistent with the goals of the Genesis Mission announced in Executive Order 14363 (90 Fed. Reg. 55035; relating to launching the Genesis Mission); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a22d22ead264776b46266e31d8580b9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the collection of new genomic data that will contribute to advances in scientific discovery and may support the development of new healthcare treatments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ddaa50447c9438bb00f4192d4770779"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initiative</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4298b0dc1c9a48d189f3041c91b70c89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the initiative, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="idfd5f610ab19744f7af066f3986c3035d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect, catalogue, and sequence the whole genomes and metabolites of samples from animals, plants, fungi, and microbes found in locations selected under paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf96200eba6b840a195abdb894e733b70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a database for the data collected under subparagraph (A), or use an existing database, such as the database of the National Center for Biotechnology Information, including sequence data, genome assemblies, peptides, metabolite data, annotations, and associated metadata, including genome and transcriptome data, metabolome data, and proteome data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb9ede7c40f24e3f839e8fb5797a696f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collaborate with industry, academia, and other government agencies to collate existing relevant data for inclusion in the database established or used under subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e828eb9d01940c68122b59bc3b40a25"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make that database accessible to persons in the United States, subject to the condition that the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, prevent the sharing of such information with adversary nations or foreign persons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id830c2bfab5974990be2f7e3700f9fa0f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, develop a plan for the construction of a new long-term storage facility—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb794d1c4596a4edba1087ca635670e6b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for, at a minimum, the samples collected under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida62f6f5ebacf44e181074032575ed7c6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in such a manner that the facility may continue to operate in the case of a catastrophic incident (as defined in section 602 of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/701">6 U.S.C. 701</external-xref>)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idefd9c428c1be4af8adb04571110c2852"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Third party collection</header><text>The Secretary may enter into contracts with third party entities, including institutions of higher education or private sector entities, to collect samples under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac21698f6e954202b9d27ab7e6ff8e76"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Locations for collection</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc20fc72bccb74edfa179fa41215d3240"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall select not fewer than 5 locations from which to collect samples under paragraph (1)(A), at least 1 of which shall be a mine or former mine that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4b3eb5166c84b9ba7ef745a4f27d058"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is deeper than 4,500 feet; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce49cf04844c4624ac471c726b04956c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>houses an underground science facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id86f87e04c4e4409187d0e2587d8056a7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddfa86f1b0acf45539b02be23dd127412"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select locations under subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95cc3fc55b9b4e41b6a605d59550f57e"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that are unique or are exposed to unique properties, such as extreme heat or pressure;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6eac0dea2f1442c8ae58b6b4639d50ab"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that are under risk of destruction before 2050 from natural or unnatural forces;</text></subclause><subclause id="iddc46ad0964c040829cd0ebe0eebe4c4c"><enum>(III)</enum><text>based on the potential for finding useful organisms that will contribute to advances in scientific research and discovery; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7750816bdfb4a8785094a1f46a78685"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that may support the development of new healthcare treatments relating to cancer, including cancers affecting children and individuals with high mortality rates, diabetes, and dementia, including Alzheimer’s disease.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida99b45c2044b4afa92d0dbe506a01ebd"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In selecting locations under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may give preference to a location on land owned or controlled by the Department of Energy (including National Laboratories).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3643b85e09c449829073db4e4b36a763"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Range of extreme conditions</header><text>In selecting locations under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that the locations reflect a broad range of extreme conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id187f05c391fc4a2bb9b5ffcc17028c7b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Long-term storage facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting a location for the covered facility under the plan developed under paragraph (1)(E), the Secretary shall consider, among other factors determined relevant by the Secretary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id772dd9efd1454196b28f23b90e619305"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">colocation in a Department of Energy facility or a facility that receives significant funding from the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb789e4765a404b3fade9613a2259aeff"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the benefits of storing the applicable materials underground in a remote area; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5cd2ef60592744fd9781cf1bca97913e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ability of the location to withstand natural disasters, such as earthquakes, wildfires, or meteor strikes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b05ef53bb2845fcbe0edc73695a5f30"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Data standards</header><text>In carrying out the initiative, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="id5f227d7b22364cfb93956f257ec9bf00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>leverage existing and emerging data standards to ensure—</text><clause id="ide528041eea874882b617eced75107c89"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high-quality data are obtained under the initiative; and</text></clause><clause id="id1a6105d6b1a7424e84cfa9237a2943bf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data collected under the initiative are considered usable and interoperable, with appropriate metadata to be included;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e2da5c1a8a842b882e2bbc090017626"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that data outputs under the initiative—</text><clause id="idaab563abd1aa4aaa90735fd1f7298f1b"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9536a56ebaa6455798a8fba00c10cf81"><enum>(I)</enum><text>meet applicable Federal data standards for biological data; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id74af036ab38f4874b47b4570167d2a28" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if there are no applicable Federal data standards described in subclause (I), meet data standards for the initiative established by the Secretary, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology and other relevant agencies, based on findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability data principles and using industry best practices; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id81ecf64b7a864c76921753d224a697b3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are updated to comply with any applicable United States Geological Survey standards for biological data; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93b9d2ef92cb4fd69a5171fc6c6c5123"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that appropriate cybersecurity and access safeguards are implemented to protect the data generated or stored under the initiative, including by ensuring that data outputs under the initiative are updated as necessary to meet applicable Federal cybersecurity standards for genomic data, including controls consistent with the National Institute of Standards and Technology special publications 800–53 (relating to Security and Privacy Controls for Information Systems and Organizations) and 800–111 (relating to Guide to Storage Encryption Technologies for End User Devices) or any successor framework.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0ee515376c840a08c2f45b48edd1daa"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Long-term storage requirements</header><text>The Secretary may consult with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution with respect to storage capabilities for the management and long-term storage of samples collected under the initiative, subject to the following:</text><subparagraph id="id7935ecc6c7714560b39840abb0083f41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Access to samples collected under the initiative may be managed by the respective institutional collection managers, with—</text><clause id="idb43e92d9264e4d60808cedd354ef519d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the natural history collections managed by the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution; and</text></clause><clause id="idd3ce01e286da4e05966b4580605fae93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the germplasm repository and the covered facility managed by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda157e640ec94daaa89cce949677cd3e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Before any samples are stored at the covered facility, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="idb1ab18801bda4e48b021980818df19f0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluate the species to be sampled to identify which species need to be collected for long-term storage; and</text></clause><clause id="id5690b1f4675744bbae2fcbb0323d38a1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>from among the species identified under clause (i), identify which species should be considered to be high-priority species.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id582eb6629edc4b70bc3982bb40c707c0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any samples identified for long-term storage under subparagraph (B)(i)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34864a6cbc244a7c85866bb3679c620f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be collected and stored at the covered facility after the covered facility is operational; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe57f3a9d1704d738b3c5b1aa2b55744"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be stored in an alternative location until that date.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id69e3a763c221492eb785ea18510c714c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any high-priority species identified under subparagraph (B)(ii) shall be collected for storage in each of—</text><clause id="idfef6b6cee6be49ccb84a2966a20adce4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the natural history collections to be managed by the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution;</text></clause><clause id="ide5f3e78d691c48e39ce969d33ab69646"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the germplasm repository to be managed by the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb15d638f2ff342b99616b1d328de9a14"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8430cda4f2e4be894e6a1fdbf48451d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any physical samples collected under the initiative shall not be transferred, exported, or loaned outside the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62db49e5728140f2aa0c2efaa7989fe1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any physical storage, curation, and laboratory processing of samples collected under the initiative shall occur within facilities located in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id42acafa5eb7b40c59b2a78de106ef83c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Secretary may accept donated samples for storage from third parties or other countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbe2cb7e07a742cd936343f552b8c945"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sequencing and data processing</header><text>In carrying out the initiative, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="idf99136355f8e49b0850851325a5964b0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collaborate with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution, and the heads of other applicable Federal agencies to sequence genomic information from samples collected under the initiative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b28664e786c4346b46f313fe539ecfc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop and use standardized sequencing protocols to ensure consistency and comparability of data; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idafd1a5041ccd46d7a819f06c006e444c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incorporate automated data processing and quality checks to ensure the reliability of the data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c3d7cd7ca3c4ac0b683bd707ebac2c9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Termination of collection</header><text>No collection of samples under paragraph (1)(A) may occur by the Secretary or a third party pursuant to a contract entered into under paragraph (2) after the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd381408b68414608af81c49c6a6b4a69"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with other entities</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3fe471f027f4d3293ae79474989a0c9"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>In carrying out the initiative, the Secretary may coordinate with—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b840657a5664dc186cca0bac65b4c4b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other offices within the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8575f6a6d96d4343be2f270b2bc90b08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id415aca889f4742d0bae0d6e67f40779e"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other relevant agency that may benefit from utilizing the covered facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a0d6ef1edde441d8c9f4ea34799971f"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Smithsonian Institution, including the National Museum of Natural History;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25b1b850416e45dba9c527e03ca22c77"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Institutes of Health, including the Childhood Cancer Data Initiative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf40053410f334d73a7c4543adf3a323a"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">academia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2036d60efb8f455a927916454d1ed3cf"><enum>(G)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations, including organizations focused on the collection of data for the discovery of treatments for cancer, diabetes, and dementia, including Alzheimer’s disease;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f19fdd731c94f4fbf08d90cb6b3b27d"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nonprofit organizations that support biodiversity conservation, including nonprofit organizations in allied countries described in subsection (e)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id17f9b4afc44445a7b3b4508c5e2567ed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>private sector entities, including entities in the pharmaceutical, biotechnology, and artificial intelligence industries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idb56ecc25024548f68b6497ae67dc3b01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private sector contributions</header><text>There shall be established a foundation, which shall be an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that Code, to receive in-kind contributions from biotechnology and other private sector companies to assist in carrying out the initiative and supporting the operation of the covered facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id48709a5c7128480bae4e26e0d333a3fa"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other agency resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use the services, personnel, and facilities of another agency if agreed to by that agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id123cc4f527c046b086d18be6c5d66efe"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Working group</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb51598fa96cd4991b4295e09a59b6756"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a working group to coordinate with private and public sector initiatives in the United States and allied countries described in paragraph (2) collecting relevant genomic data to create alignment between scientific groups—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d71682169b446888f83ab94f4f61716"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maximize beneficial research output; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida266bed4816b4495b30f0f8bd2ccf8b7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to minimize duplicative spending of the initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b99733dd2c4401d82b5beb46beb9364"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allied countries described</header><text>The allied countries referred to in paragraph (1) are—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1cd5d12343d44bdab52102974b964d26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Australia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e0bca5a15314f6cae6f0bc9472eb71d"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">member countries of the European Union;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0af6954d914e499ead8447e3bd4087f2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Japan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd484f799931e486e8822ab477e5c98c7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>South Korea;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id758fd22015f94d7cb29dfca4f4c12412"><enum>(E)</enum><text>New Zealand; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f2bec38af1944a484f90db2f8592a87"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>the United Kingdom.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6ff928421e0544f387ea30c31bcd382a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

