<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26300-MGS-MR-WF1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3962 IS: Housing and Economic Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3962</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve interagency coordination between the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Economic Development Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing and Economic Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16366d66fd7c4360a39e44855583d0f7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development shall establish a memorandum of understanding, or other appropriate interagency agreement, to—</text><paragraph id="id2f16be6bdc464b9a87ce97fff2cb2c2f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase collaboration related to projects approved by and funded by amounts from both the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Economic Development Administration to construct housing and implement economic development projects, which, where practicable, may include—</text><subparagraph id="id89c3b6754b444995b2e7eb3e2b2bf0b3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinating timelines for application review and award decisions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59acfc1f7413492db5ea580530f803e2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>standardizing terminology and definitions used in notices of funding opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32d19a81120242afbf3818a3069b4e76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>issuing joint guidance to reduce any duplicative reporting and administrative burden for applicants and grantees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1950819a3a0646b494b25239ac773426"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing clear points of contact at each agency to resolve questions for applicants and grantees regarding jointly funded projects;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa221592e7ab499aac35ddf5dc1cf061"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify barriers preventing the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Economic Development Administration from further coordination and identify future opportunities to promote jointly funded projects that advance shared goals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1afa4ee4c64743c4bddf585bc7bc7970"><enum>(3)</enum><text>share relevant housing-related research and market data that facilitate evidence-based policymaking.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id2290eab195f24e8188f233ca1dc0e89d"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interagency report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development shall jointly submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that includes recommendations for legislative, regulatory, or administrative actions to improve the efficiency of, and reduce barriers to future collaboration on, construction projects jointly funded by amounts from the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Economic Development Administration.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

