<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H507B3C1B8A934BE383BF60901FAEBCA7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7170 IH: Language Access to Gun Violence Prevention Strategies Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7170</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To remove linguistic barriers to participation in Gun Violence Prevention Strategies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H40913DA6D42C4F8781E2BF6402A86538" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD59DEF006FCB4C8A8197A5694FDBB3B3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Language Access to Gun Violence Prevention Strategies Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD803D6DFF3664927B21F0C031BA02438"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H8B0462D5B23645ECAC12BAC5C559D501"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community-based organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community-based organization</term> means a neighborhood or community-based organization, as that term is defined in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE872BCF29DA04A64B7705BD56C33AC29"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extreme risk protection order</header><text>The term <term>extreme risk protection order</term> means a written order or warrant, issued by a State or Tribal court or signed by a magistrate (or other comparable judicial officer), the primary purpose of which is to reduce the risk of firearm-related death or injury by doing 1 or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H432170621BCE46639C61EBD5D3EC82E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Temporarily prohibiting a named individual from owning, purchasing, possessing, receiving, or having under the custody or control of the individual, a firearm.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A412276AABC4F5FA08B9549032B418C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Having a firearm temporarily removed or requiring the temporary surrender of a firearm from a named individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C67ECC6618845458B288C30A71F5CF2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text>The term <term>firearm</term> has the meaning given the term in section 921 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0735A66F6F404C549BF2B317295540CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gun violence</header><text>The term <term>gun violence</term> includes mass shooting incidents, other firearm homicides or assaults, firearm suicides or self-harm, unintentional firearm deaths and injuries, and firearm-related crime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F77332D098542118FEB08FDDB84E514"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Gun violence prevention strategy</header><text>The term <term>Gun Violence Prevention Strategy</term> means programs, policies, or practices that have the potential to reduce firearm-related violence, injuries, death, or crime within populations or settings experiencing elevated risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CE81240697445B0B10B1235C3198EF0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Individual with limited English proficiency</header><text>The term <term>individual with limited English proficiency</term> means an individual who does not speak English as the individual's primary language and has a limited ability to read, write, speak, or understand English.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4625D5D308D4784B3A37F2294CFF65B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Language access</header><text>The term <term>language access</term> means the provision of culturally competent and effective language services to an individual with limited English proficiency designed to enhance that individual’s access to, understanding of, or benefit from the services, activities, programs, or benefits provided by a Federal agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96DF15AC5FC546F7A5697ED273B2FBD7"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Limited English proficient population</header><text>The term <term>limited English proficient population</term> means the sum of all individuals with limited English proficiency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AF0486E29ED4C11A714D59373897C5C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Priority languages</header><text>The term <term>priority languages</term> means, at a minimum, the 10 most commonly spoken languages in the United States other than English, which shall include Mandarin, Cantonese, Japanese, and Korean.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4E160FBE74D487BB1634CBE5BC6E6C5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0313A03C8154EB8BECBCA983EF01037"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Significant resource</header><text>The term <term>significant resource</term> means, in the case of a Federal agency, any material, digital or otherwise, prepared by the Federal agency that contains information critical for education, awareness, and participation in public education campaigns, such as informational and outreach materials.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB1AEA293D68F41C0905B3EE6C62D1ADD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Translation of Federal agency materials</header><subsection id="H51236CB727BD428A902063A225F15E34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General and the Secretary shall ensure that all significant resources for services, activities, benefits, and programs of the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services, respectively, that are prepared for the general public relating to gun violence prevention and firearm safety are competently translated and provided in accessible formats in priority languages.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4AC79F215B5344A19267863B05F48835"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specific resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The significant resources described in subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7DDEBDC157B147B9BA1AF11DDE804FDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">extreme risk protection orders and safe gun storage materials; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46AF572A1DDF4F8E9BF1FAAABC8FA9FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">significant resources prepared using amounts appropriated under division B of the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/159">Public Law 117–159</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 1338) for Federal grant programs and other activities carried out by the Attorney General and the Secretary that were in effect as of the date of enactment of that Act to support mental health services, crisis response, school-based mental health, and suicide prevention.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68254250AC6141D7AB530A4DF6C3F30A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Community review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF37FFAEF4FA4E798AF3FB4124091C6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of ensuring that significant resources described in subsection (a) are culturally competent and accessible by the intended audience, the Attorney General and the Secretary shall ensure all translated materials are reviewed by community-based organizations with demonstrated relationships with speakers of a given language prior to publishing.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H963E09B99BEB49BD99454162541D8910"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General and the Secretary shall provide amounts appropriated to carry out this Act to community-based organizations to carry out paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA4E1233C8A6A413E8A939C179613B7BF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Priority grant applications</header><subsection id="HBAF6AD7D76D64D44BBF74DBD207FEDAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall ensure that applications for grants for the creation and implementation of extreme risk protection orders, State crisis intervention court proceedings, and other gun violence reduction efforts incorporate meaningful engagement with limited English proficient populations by giving priority to applications that demonstrate a targeted outreach plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6B11FDC14C6642AC89093000DCF838BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public outreach and education efforts</header><text>Section 501 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10152">34 U.S.C. 10152</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC7BA0059F86A4BBF9C87C8329006338B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(I)(iv)—</text><subparagraph id="HBB13EBF1C32546479755979403156BDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB8C86A2C0984DED8842AEAA7E56B8A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA1C5CC4E816430D82C418CCAA11BC1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0E90232216048C7B949C246E05179E3"><subclause id="HF650ED9413B141DC8F1B8DD4822504C1"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public outreach and education efforts, which shall include—</text><item id="H1EF75DC2F4E5437284AC2AA1E2A17454"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>meaningful engagement with community-based organizations directly serving limited English proficient populations (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Language Access to Gun Violence Prevention Strategies Act of 2026</short-title>); and</text></item><item id="H06C81DC487D44C1C8914C88635CD24E8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>translation of public facing documents into any language other than English spoken by a limited English proficient population that constitutes not less than 3 percent or 500 individuals, whichever is less, of the population served or encountered.</text></item></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC94E38B14F4812930397C898C3F6F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text><subparagraph id="HD23CE95353A04A8BA2353899E7C6877F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB027A8520924E03A924113031EE83D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAF71CED5CB14277B45A337CD4DB0AA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H632C53F0C87A4474964D138E25FF1C90"><paragraph id="H89BB7A0B548E492D84939AE6D1FF675F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures that have been taken by each grant recipient to comply with subsection (a)(1)(I)(iv)(V).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BFF709085D74140837E545B4C1839CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall issue guidance related to the requirements set forth in subsections (a)(1)(I)(iv)(V) and (h)(5) of section 501 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10152">34 U.S.C. 10152</external-xref>), as added by subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="HC5190D83CF254381BA9D4BFFD0000B33"><enum>5.</enum><header>Department of Justice gun violence prevention public awareness campaign</header><subsection id="H1935792F19DD40E98120AFFBCC987936"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of increasing language access to community-based gun violence prevention strategies, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Justice Programs, and in coordination with the Community-Based Violence Intervention and Prevention Initiative of the Office of Justice Programs, shall develop and implement a national public awareness campaign to increase awareness of federally supported gun violence prevention strategies, such as extreme risk protection orders, with a focus on outreach and engagement with limited English proficient populations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCCAFADDF741643729BF9F2E1FAC7B2E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The public awareness campaign under this section shall include—</text><paragraph id="H9ADAF3D445B644AE95B07F671C954541"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the provision of in-language and culturally appropriate messaging to disseminate scientific and evidence-based information; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75B68B4858974D6F8D0942994326A67B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the dissemination of information on subgrants to community-based organizations educating professionals and community stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7128644F0F043989648E9EC849B6583"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The public awareness campaign under this section shall be complementary to, and coordinated with, any other Federal, State, Tribal, and local efforts, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H96A61E827E194F6C8A4281B6C9BA29E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall submit a report to Congress detailing how funds appropriated to carry out this section were used.</text></subsection></section><section id="H619F650A564840E0B48A3D3F16BCD08A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Department of Heath and Human Services gun violence prevention public awareness campaign</header><subsection id="H25B3C663BB574947AFD5984179E5CE32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose of increasing language access to gun violence prevention strategies, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in coordination with the Director of the National Center for Injury Prevention and Control, shall develop and implement a national public education campaign to increase awareness of gun violence prevention strategies and firearm safety programs supported by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, such as safe gun storage practices, with a focus on outreach and engagement with limited English proficient populations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8E07C01F782F4F1387394B464EBB1628"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The public awareness campaign under this section shall include—</text><paragraph id="HFFD9E784CE7E4BF7A5E452304828BD7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provision of in-language and culturally appropriate messaging to disseminate scientific and evidence-based information related to gun violence prevention and firearm safety; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2CE9A227189456C8D379EF070758680"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the dissemination of information on subgrants to community-based organizations educating professionals and community stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H237C2F7DBC7843AFB14213ED82E5DE4F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The public awareness campaign under this section shall be complementary to, and coordinated with, any other Federal, State, Tribal, and local efforts, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDEB0E5F8107B49708EDF0666FE554242"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report to Congress detailing how funds appropriated to carry out this section were used.</text></subsection></section><section id="H138438B239644534854DDF970534C589"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

