<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5BECEA6E03C64A349F9A79C8AA41FEF7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6405 IH: Arms Sale Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6405</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify the expedited procedures in the House of Representatives under section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act with respect to consideration of joint resolutions prohibiting proposed sales of defense articles or services, prohibiting proposed licenses for exports of defense articles or services, and prohibiting approval of United States commercial technical assistance or manufacturing licensing agreements.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE3F06B3BA3654FF5AC5EEBD1554D42ED" style="OLC"><section id="HBF46B3F7FD5048BEAC1A75567A9B4F3D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arms Sale Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H43C580E114B24595A1EB5937A34D2EE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of expedited procedures in the House of Representatives under section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act</header><subsection id="HD0C9D6C47FB24EC8AB329EF88AD3551D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text><paragraph id="H29A6A71AD4454118B7EB6674E33A3C13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In subsection (b), by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4A6CEA246C9A414FB7A613A1A3DF6920" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HEFBC5C5B38194C4FA0D0B9A8453C316B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any such joint resolution shall be considered in the House of Representatives in accordance with the following:</text><subparagraph id="H69F57527619B441F968CA4F9D1EAE916"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4AF9B21B3E7848648777D22DBC0FAB1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>If the committee to which a joint resolution with respect to a proposed sale has been referred has not reported it at the end of 10 calendar days after its referral, it shall be in order to move either to discharge the committee from further consideration of such resolution or to discharge the committee from further consideration of any other resolution with respect to such proposed sale which has been referred to the committee.</text></clause><clause id="H1622C3489DE1483FBE180B078A91F311" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A motion to discharge may be made only by an individual favoring the resolution, shall be highly privileged (except that it may not be made after the committee has reported a resolution with respect to the same proposed sale), and debate thereon shall be limited to not more than one hour, to be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the resolution. An amendment to the motion shall not be in order, and it shall not be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion was agreed to or disagreed to.</text></clause><clause id="H0FB69CECB73447BDB53C7A273C5E94B8" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the motion to discharge is agreed to or disagreed to, the motion may not be renewed, nor may another motion to discharge the committee be made with respect to any other resolution with respect to the same proposed sale.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8569704792314416984AA00930C8D5C5"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD8AFCA66CB3E4841BFF8DE1E896102F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>When the committee has reported, or has been discharged from further consideration of, a resolution, it shall be at any time thereafter in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution. The motion shall be highly privileged and shall not be debatable. An amendment to the motion shall not be in order, and it shall not be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which the motion was agreed to or disagreed to.</text></clause><clause id="H39AE3E38D73F405A928221426BD3D50B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Debate on the resolution referred to in clause (i) of this subparagraph shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing such resolution. A motion further to limit debate shall not be debatable. An amendment to, or motion to recommit, the resolution shall not be in order, and it shall not be in order to move to reconsider the vote by which such resolution was agreed to or disagreed to.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2D6517C4F0C468F96E8F765C31A410A"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA7F054A484014707A5A8DAA6A699A6F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Motions to postpone, made with respect to the discharge from committee, or the consideration of a resolution and motions to proceed to the consideration of other business, shall be decided without debate.</text></clause><clause id="HDDB088ECE8994AFD8E0C1B7E2C422385" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Appeals from the decision of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the House of Representatives to the procedure relating to a resolution shall be decided without debate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21CBDF838368418D99C3B9A0B2D3BB5E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, if the House of Representatives has approved a resolution with respect to a proposed sale, then it shall not be in order to consider in the House of Representatives any other resolution with respect to the same such sale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6B924315B7433EAE2626BFB07E8A0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In each of subsections (c)(3)(B) and (d)(5)(B) by striking <quote>For the purpose</quote> and all that follows through <quote>House of Representatives</quote> and inserting <quote>Any such joint resolution shall be considered in the House of Representatives in accordance with the provisions of subsection (b)(3) of this section.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4B250DCE3D147DCA11DA2924AA7DA3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to any joint resolution described in subsection (b)(3), (c)(3)(B), or (d)(5)(B) of section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act that is introduced in the House of Representatives or the Senate, as the case may be, on or after such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

