<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26E50-NKX-TC-R1P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4929 IS: Epidemic Barrier and Outbreak Leadership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4929</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require continued participation by the United States in the World Health Organization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Epidemic Barrier and Outbreak Leadership Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EBOLA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id4767a279390e46e4991a8ac5485c9bdf"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ccc77e67bf04dcd83b68cca5ab714ad"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Infectious disease outbreaks and pandemics pose significant threats to the national security, public health, and economic well-being of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ea37f5c97f84a7caee419175e8a584a"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 2026 Ebola Disease outbreak in Central and Eastern Africa has rapidly spread across international borders and resulted in more than 1,000 cases of the disease.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7de7845a4bdf4062ba29d378ffbb325b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention’s model scenarios, without a strong public health intervention, the current outbreak could become larger than the outbreak in West Africa from 2014 to 2016 in which more than 11,000 people died.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9c371135c0a4668a4987b2ea05d35d6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite the need for continued reforms, the World Health Organization serves as the principal international body for disease surveillance, outbreak response coordination, and public health information sharing.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9d90973daac4b8da619ce17b0c27be6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Participation in the World Health Organization enhances the ability of the United States to monitor emerging infectious diseases, coordinate with international partners, and protect the health of the American people.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd891b715531841e698977962c2cbea5e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On January 20, 2025, President Trump initiated the withdrawal of the United States from the World Health Organization through Executive Order 14155 (90 Fed. Reg. 8361), which was completed on January 22, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03f2c0fd139e4acf90f26603b4db5e9f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In previous public health emergencies of international concern, the United States has consistently communicated with representatives of the World Health Organization, other multilateral health agencies, and the governments of other countries to ensure United States global health funding was targeted, coordinated, and efficient.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96a975414a9c43769ecd62a3c8b59b26"><enum>3.</enum><header>Participation in the World Health Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3c1aba7dc99f4990b2a444a2c30582b5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take all necessary steps for the United States to rejoin the World Health Organization not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6426b1cfa4ab49b18b2b5572b8a83cce"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately collaborate with the World Health Organization to respond to the Ebola Disease outbreak in Central and Eastern Africa.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idbf1932bf1e3c477b8d067974ea805599"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act, including—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd886dc956cb64df29a7b9e2829054b21"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paying assessed contributions and any other financial obligations to restore United States membership in the World Health Organization; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3263879b01d46f4b66105df1cc8bb00"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting the response effort of the World Health Organization and other United Nations entities to the Ebola Disease epidemic in Central and Eastern Africa, including through voluntary contributions and programmatic support, in order to prevent global transmission of the virus, including transmission to the people and territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

