<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MUR25913-DFY-SL-NGL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3298 IS: Medicaid Primary Care Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3298</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To facilitate direct primary care arrangements under Medicaid.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="not-changed" id="HE7C721B0CEE04A5DA365D793E301AF23"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9B6E2C4274964617B4C6771E4BC97DDC" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Primary Care Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5485A5A68C634E8E8F59CEB702457D7E" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clarifying that certain payment arrangements are allowable under the Medicaid program</header><subsection id="H92674210C4A542D79DF5172755C8BFD3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be construed as prohibiting a State, under its State plan (or waiver of such plan) under such title (including through a medicaid managed care organization), from providing medical assistance consisting of primary care services through a direct primary care arrangement with a health care provider, including as part of a value-based care arrangement established by the State.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id1cdd9091889143ea87754f36bc9bcc4f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id2b880c76f7f940008421530b9d41991b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Direct primary care arrangement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>direct primary care arrangement</term> means, with respect to any individual, an arrangement under which such individual is provided medical assistance consisting solely of primary care services provided by primary care practitioners, if the sole compensation for such care is a fixed periodic fee.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="id222efc96d6484e7b9dcbd8b8fed64381"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medicaid managed care organization</header><text>The term <term>medicaid managed care organization</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1903(m)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(m)(1)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed" id="idd2c336d298574699abfa28c56aee7fb7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA578068799D4DE88E194BED1D879B88" changed="not-changed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HBBCE34711D6C452E86FF02ACC5BD930F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convene at least 1 virtual open door meeting to seek input from stakeholders, including primary care providers who practice under the direct primary care model, State Medicaid agencies, and medicaid managed care organizations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7AB8B3E58234641BE60372725B73CF2" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>taking into account such input, issue guidance to States on how a State may implement direct primary care arrangements under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29EC07DE0CAF47AB8F4CA9063C32C576" changed="not-changed"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text><paragraph id="H263C9684A5E34D75AACBA03AEF5DDD7C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the extent to which States are contracting with independent physicians, independent physician practices, and primary care practices for purposes of furnishing medical assistance under State plans (or waivers of such plans) under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) through direct primary care arrangements; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29CDC2B1F3CE4EB38622DFD4F6E5D270" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of quality of care and cost of care furnished to individuals enrolled under such title where such care is paid for under a direct primary care arrangement through a medicaid managed care organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE804EE93765247D88013C090C23C4247" changed="not-changed"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter statutory requirements applicable to State plans (or waivers of such plans) under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), including requirements relating to cost-sharing and requirements relating to the amount, duration, and scope of medical assistance that is required to be made available to individuals who are eligible for such assistance under such a plan or waiver.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

