<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE810728829074A558E523B3805F3ABA8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6423 IH: Help Ensure Lower Patient Copays Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6423</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to apply financial assistance towards the cost-sharing requirements of health insurance plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3454EE4D4F24425FA326E79755E00B8A" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H68DBDBC4B80D4545AF6CB9815E9CECA9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Help Ensure Lower Patient Copays Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HELP Copays Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H59063A362BED45B5B60FD6BDC5E1754F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Application of financial assistance toward cost-sharing requirements</header><subsection id="H82D5E7A34FFC40B5A964C1B8372BDEC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application toward cost-Sharing requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2715(g)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-15">42 U.S.C. 300gg–15(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In developing the standards for defining the terms <term>deductible</term>, <term>coinsurance</term>, <term>copayment</term>, and <term>out-of-pocket limit</term> (as described in paragraph (2)), such standards shall provide that such terms include amounts paid by, or on behalf of, an individual enrolled in a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage, including financial assistance offered by non-profit organizations and prescription drug manufacturers, and that such amounts shall be counted toward such deductible, coinsurance, copayment, or limit, respectively.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H59502DFE91F942968FD14EB23DB6C7A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HE4A4B4270B81482A9BC0F2D873D25595"><enum>(1)</enum><header>PPACA</header><text>Section 1302(c)(3) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F3ADBAA5D924EFEA0E94705A7EDC316"><subparagraph id="H3AF018AC7489443AB85D70AFB2690913"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application of terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the terms <term>deductible</term>, <term>coinsurance</term>, <term>copayment</term>, or <term>similar charge</term> and any other expenditure described in clause (ii) of such subparagraph shall include amounts paid by, or on behalf of, an individual enrolled in a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage, including financial assistance offered by non-profit organizations and prescription drug manufacturers, and such amounts shall be counted toward such deductible, co-insurance, co-payment, charge, or other expenditure, respectively.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F281E76F1FA437AB149AF55E9DD042D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>PHSA</header><text>Section 2707(b) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-6">42 U.S.C. 300gg–6(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For purposes of the previous sentence, such limitation shall be applied to prescription drugs as if the reference to <quote>essential health benefits</quote> in section 1302(c)(3) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act were a reference to <quote>any item or service covered under the plan included within the prescription drug category of essential health benefits as described in (b)(1)(F) of such section</quote>.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D39D32BE3554C55A3172AFDA9892C82"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Internal Revenue Code of 1986 safe harbor for certain amounts applied to deductibles</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223(c)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FD898BB4BC54253BC5E2BF7AF9BF595"><subparagraph id="H3A856F783CB44FDCA2B5FE49597DADE0"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Safe harbor for certain amounts applied to deductibles</header><text>In the case of plan years beginning after December 31, 2025, a plan shall not fail to be treated as a high deductible health plan by reason of counting amounts paid by, or on behalf of, an individual, including financial assistance offered by non-profit organizations and prescription drug manufacturers for outpatient prescription drugs, when determining whether the minimum deductible under subparagraph (A) has been satisfied.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6124F891A4F14274BA0441C8C734E5D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall—</text><paragraph id="H166E85A60C7C42D5A26FF7F1A969F374"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply to standards relating to deductibles, coinsurance, copayments, or limits with respect to prescription drugs that are specialty drugs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93DF480936174D09BB8060996C8F2BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply to standards relating to deductibles, coinsurance, copayments, or limits with respect to drugs that are subject to utilization management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0A5FFB5515D40C7957B1A2F37D635A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not impact the use of utilization management tools, including prior authorization and step therapy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FA99AEB56B5400493E35E6AD6E1E498"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply to group health plans and health insurance issuers for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2026.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

