<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H3E56B8A5CBE84C8DBC39706F28E7EC45" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><form><distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4429</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise the definition of a qualifying investment, for purposes of the exemption from registration for venture capital fund advisers under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940, to include an equity security issued by a qualifying portfolio company and to include an investment in another venture capital fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0337A126AAC24D8699B919A95E591D12" style="OLC"><section id="H003B89B140FD49FD814B9A3FBE751CC3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing and Empowering our Aspiring Leaders Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCCB42ADB099D4B9E8B447E698271D881"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Securities and Exchange Commission shall—</text><paragraph id="H6FB7B26481704C71B05951D2C699C5A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise the definition of a qualifying investment under paragraph (c) of section 275.203(l)–1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations—</text><subparagraph id="HECCB67D1C627432F9DAC7027B7DC4590"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to include an equity security issued by a qualifying portfolio company, whether acquired directly from the company or in a secondary acquisition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDD2FADB58BC4709ADEDD1ECC9F88C80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to specify that an investment in another venture capital fund (as defined in paragraph (a) section 275.203(l)–1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations) is a qualifying investment under such definition; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72D4702A72884F399288D6AA330E3D00"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise paragraph (a) of such section to require, as a condition of a private fund qualifying as a venture capital fund under such paragraph, that, immediately after the acquisition of any asset, such fund holds no more than 49 percent of the amount of the fund’s aggregate capital contributions and uncalled committed capital (excluding short-term holdings) in—</text><subparagraph id="HD3EB759B7334465884860E1E381D3260"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one or more venture capital funds; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E380B2E7DA4E2882CB34BF29E197C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>qualifying investments acquired in a secondary acquisition, valued at cost or fair value, consistently applied by the fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20251201" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 1, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill>
