<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72983E7301DF499BA28AF3B769FD2FA6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9344 IH: Establishing and Developing University Cannabis Agriculture Techniques and Excellence Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9344</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977, to provide for marijuana agricultural research program at 1890 institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2B99EE6CB87B4B07B7E69EA9E02DE989" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC3F2AF539AEB458A96A44BEFCB8BC9D1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Establishing and Developing University Cannabis Agriculture Techniques and Excellence Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EDUCATE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HDE975893BB7B466B888A8D0D3160D1E3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Marijuana research at 1890 Institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3101">7 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H75F038DE1A8B4CB59968C013DA03AF0E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subtitle id="HAF2B49C24035485997DF7C40BEE24BAB"><enum>P</enum><header>Marijuana research at 1890 Institutions</header> <section id="H0A555D6F3D0D4B3CA614529883A3029B"><enum>1492.</enum><header>Marijuana agricultural research program at <enum-in-header>1890</enum-in-header> institutions</header> <subsection id="H38B066E47B614D398450CB9DEB0B769A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture (in this subtitle referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall establish a program under which the Secretary will award, on a competitive basis grants to authorized institutions to conduct research on the cultivation (including agronomic best practices) and processing of marijuana. Such research may include research on the following topics:</text> 
<paragraph id="H53719C9627BE4B0DBE337A5248F7B021"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The optimization of cultivation and harvesting practices for marijuana crops.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2AC8AA2BE7E443529B3081AE04B0163B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The examination of soil health, water conservation, pest management, and sustainability impacts of marijuana agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1299C3528BAD4D5C96AD1B37A08AAFD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The evaluation of economic development opportunities for minority and disadvantaged farmers in emerging marijuana markets.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H457380FDD1D14D6B8D95F1CB74D9E275"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Workforce development, training, and extension activities related to marijuana agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6D14CF80ECA42DE9C7B6D07FC4E15B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An authorized institution seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including documentation of the registration of the institution as described in section 1492D(2).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF6FA10CD82EA4F1B84305C6B69F458A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of grantees</header><text>In selecting authorized institutions to receive a grant under this section, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD7CDAA5D4C74405AABDC27208F8B6701"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give priority to institutions that have partnerships with minority and small-scale farmers or community-based agricultural organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5BD852CE0C94977B1B8042D42BF0E3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure an equitable distribution of grant funds among such institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H76316F57F05A44FDB66BB940180B037A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Condition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An authorized institution receiving a grant under this section shall agree, as a condition on receipt of such grant, to coordinate with the Secretary and other Federal agencies to ensure compliance with applicable Federal laws relating to the possession, handling, study, or other research activity involving marijuana.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H40755130EE8F49D8923338AC98342801"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="H067E86030CDC4D748418D74D6BF2885B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H301F090EB70940A2BB28A9289EC79220"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation of funds</header><text>Of the funds made available under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve not less than 25 percent to award grants to authorized institutions that are Hispanic-serving institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE22FAE53EBE84F1295E2308DE11C909D"><enum>1492A.</enum><header>Marijuana agriculture studies scholarship program</header> <subsection id="HD17D2093BB2F444FA09ADF2861654FE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program (to be known as the Marijuana Agriculture Studies Scholarship Program) under which the Secretary will award grants to authorized institutions for purposes of awarding scholarships to individuals who—</text> 
<paragraph id="H30FE6534D44845078710463617B93E11"><enum>(1)</enum> 
<subparagraph id="H18C3A844A9544BB887182D62ECED70AE" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been accepted for admission at such institution and will be enrolled full-time at such institution in an undergraduate or graduate program in the food and agricultural sciences not later than one year after the date of such acceptance; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H213366D8884948CE828199A778A9C48F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are enrolled full-time at such institution in such an undergraduate or graduate program; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B80953531124C24AB418B6F30B25F86"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intend to pursue, or are pursuing a career in marijuana or hemp agriculture, marijuana cultivation, plant science, agricultural technology, agricultural science, or agricultural policy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA84B1424211B45B8A5F9000734D47852"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An authorized institution seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including documentation of the registration of the institution as described in section 1492D(2).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0F4AF4C5F414EDFA0C7934AB02B1C62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maximum amounts</header> 
<paragraph id="H9582B5D89AA24A2F8799E7893B9E173D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scholarship amount</header><text>The amount of a scholarship awarded pursuant to this section shall not exceed $10,000 per student, per academic year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8991F811DF7C4A26B89DB4F647E3DFE9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>Of the funds made available under subsection (c), the Secretary may use not more than $100,000 to award grants under this subsection for the academic year beginning on July 1, 2027, and each succeeding academic year for which such funds remain available.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5D863A46D54842EDB04F7E0333447611"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3A73FECF52AA4D3BB03DDBC74F573E97"><enum>1492B.</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subtitle, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDB7EDFCCA8524E2A82B7EA63885A259E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>grants awarded under the program established under section 1492;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66AE64FB9EAA4DF0A0718E1E5227EBC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the outcomes and findings of research conducted pursuant to such section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF12CA73D61DB4575B6E399C104621664"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the participation in the scholarship program under section 1492A and outcomes of such program.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA87C9A419EA44DD6AC634DF4498C974E"><enum>1492C.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination; safe harbor; rule of construction</header> <subsection id="H2BBC08091B3D4A1AB94845E179155A55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No denial of Federal benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an institution of higher education, faculty member, researcher, employee, or student that receives funding under, conducts research pursuant to, or participates in a program or activity authorized by, this Act shall not be denied any Federal benefit, grant, or contract, solely because of the cultivation, possession, handling, study, or other research activity involving marijuana conducted in accordance with this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E349D265DED4F1A807FB5E2CBAD9620"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No Federal prosecution or civil penalties for allowed conduct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual or entity who receives funding under, conducts research pursuant to, or participates in a program or activity authorized by this Act shall not be subject to criminal prosecution or civil or administrative penalties under Federal law relating to that receipt of funding, research, or participation so long as the individual or entity, in receiving such funds, conducting such research, or participating in such a program or activity is acting within the scope of the applicable registration under section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) and such other requirements as may be imposed by the Secretary under this Act.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H44E7E82F3BA54CB9A07B7B7CC0D1B700"><enum>1492D.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5BB5CC3C375B4B8E81BAB41A99A0EA55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>1890 Institution</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7601">7 U.S.C. 7601</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EBDA10330744777A16C8A23255C592D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>authorized institution</term> means a covered institution that, as of the date on which the institution submits an application under section 1492 or 1492A (as applicable), has a registration in effect under section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) to conduct research with marijuana.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3D667E116FA4C80A6029AB656031C8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>marijuana</term> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA3D81004A664307B6A06FA9116AB461"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>covered institution</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC37F25E6DF7142D0A5B1D34B3841176D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an 1890 Institution;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6317BB95942349A7A7948CB2BFCEF004"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Hispanic-serving institution (as defined in section 502 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB4C7C4B0D2AE4F6FA731284DE3F037A5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a part B institution (as defined in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>)) that—</text> <clause id="H5336D15EE6AB40578E53CAEBF5FA56A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not an 1890 Institution; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0053B1A0B80A4156B83A2AE41D7ECE34"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has an accredited program offering education in the food and agricultural sciences.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

