<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H835BDDDFC11446CD87A726CFD95E349C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1338 IH: Supporting the designation of June as Family Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1338</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of June as Family Month.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the traditional nuclear family is the foundation of a healthy society;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas mothers and fathers play a crucial and irreplaceable role in the upbringing of their children;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the best environment for children to thrive is a home with a married mother and father;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas roughly half of all marriages in the United States end in divorce;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas many young people are opting to delay or forgo marriage and starting a family;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many tax and welfare policies encourage cohabitation and penalize couples for getting married;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the birth rate in the United States has fallen below the replacement level needed to replenish the population and sustain the economy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the month of June was first declared as Pride Month by President Bill Clinton in 1999 and has been done so by Presidents Barack Obama and Joe Biden, rejecting the importance of marriage and family;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Americans are inundated with perverse Pride Month displays and events throughout the month of June that denigrate the nuclear family;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Americans who hold to a traditional view of marriage and family are often disparaged;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the decline of marriage and family has corresponded to a rise in crime, drug abuse, and other social ill;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas our Founding Father John Adams said, <quote>Our Constitution was made only for a moral and religious people. It is wholly inadequate to the government of any other.</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas our survival as a country and civilization depends on the continuation of traditional marriage and family; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas it is fitting to observe a month of rededicating our Nation to the importance of the traditional nuclear family: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HCD381CFE219A4394ADBF1F47773FA60B"> 
<section id="H6B58CA7017274316B52B611905A2910B" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H0919CDF36842472C920BFC16B26C45AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the benefit of marriage and family to men, women, children, and society;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9AEED68F5534F90BC2005F940CCACE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no longer recognizes Pride Month; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F1396639FFC43D79536B5A574CAE563"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the designation of Family Month for the purpose of rededicating our Nation to the importance of this essential unit.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

