<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE6252532AFFE4A96B1A3457D0F646368" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6240 IH: Rural Hospital Closure Relief Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to restore State authority to waive for certain facilities the 35-mile rule for designating critical access hospitals under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E771B8034684C11A7493DD60A19B8B8" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HFA43228865A0426F8C66DE2AFE674DE1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Hospital Closure Relief Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H508FBF43EDF64C6BBCB71A48C7DCEA9A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restoring State authority to waive the 35–mile rule for certain Medicare critical access hospital designations</header><subsection id="H1C736352779C4519A3B0837DEF3BAE07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1820 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-4">42 U.S.C. 1395i–4</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB78C1868054445168EFF371B3050046F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H11449714AFC64A929FB11130F581C36F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)—</text><clause id="HA1E8A941B66B4480812030C9676BBEDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="HF42E22F6117E4952BFA1B161EBD6BEEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end; and</text></clause><clause id="H55D4BC3630F34610A749D66E0B244231"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52FBD2D0D36942F8A57CB66DA33FA311"><subclause id="H3C1E806420294B829641BBFA11C10E8E"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (G), is a hospital described in subparagraph (F) and is certified, on or after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Rural Hospital Closure Relief Act of 2025</short-title>, and before the date that is 9 years after the date of enactment of this subclause, by the State as being a necessary provider of health care services to residents in the area;</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0370497547104368B143BBB0FC3C7412"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2F7A62D816C4F049F93DDED85A11F5B"><subparagraph id="HAC5A994D84E44CA5811AA710857E7897"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Hospital described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (B)(i)(III), a hospital described in this subparagraph is a hospital that—</text><clause id="HDE02541E5B344442BF22AE91F34E553C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a sole community hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(5)(D)(iii)), a medicare dependent, small rural hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(5)(G)(iv)), a low-volume hospital that in 2021 receives a payment adjustment under section 1886(d)(12), or a subsection (d) hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(1)(B)); </text></clause><clause id="HF63A8959416F47CB92D0AD9142AD4C86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is located in a rural area, as defined in section 1886(d)(2)(D), or a rural census tract of a metropolitan statistical area (as determined under the most recent modification of the Goldsmith Modification, originally published in the Federal Register on February 27, 1992 (57 Fed. Reg. 6725));</text></clause><clause id="H24BC7E472A3D4DED881230C9298D0676"><enum>(iii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1BAF699A86CB492BB6228C2CCF496CF1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is located—</text><item id="HDE1AE870DA0443E99A42A3B8D8D682A3" indent="up1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in a county that has a percentage of individuals with income at or below the Federal poverty level in 2023 or 2024 that is higher than the national or statewide average in that year; or</text></item><item indent="up1" id="H682686E9168B467BAB6A0131E5A656FE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in a health professional shortage area (as defined in section 332(a)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act); or</text></item></subclause><subclause indent="up1" id="HFE5814F798894C22B82D26D2F956F472"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has a percentage of inpatient days of individuals entitled to benefits under part A of this title in 2023 or 2024 that is higher than the national or statewide average in that year;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6C094DDEE7584A9CAE13B6C1B713A17C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has attested to the Secretary that the hospital—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD51586DBB2B74569AE1CB578D8DA8BBF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was operating as of the date of enactment of this subparagraph; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6508CE36D00F4E05AD950DF603F36A5F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">had 2 consecutive years of negative operating margins preceding the date of certification described in subparagraph (B)(i)(III), as defined by the Secretary in the regulations or program instruction issued pursuant to section 2(b) of the <short-title>Rural Hospital Closure Relief Act of 2025</short-title>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2C24FF39DBD94135A8F269EB98FD8B27"><enum>(v)</enum><text>submits to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, an application for certification of the facility as a critical access hospital, including an attestation outlining—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC10401A8A8F54545A998127C59A93B01"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the good governance qualifications and strategic plan for multi-year financial solvency of the hospital; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB083F1CEFCB438684902B606188883E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the hospital’s commitment to open and maintain, for the duration of the hospital’s designation as a critical access hospital under this section, a new service line or expanded service capacity for a service that is in high demand or limited supply in the hospital’s service area (determined based on the hospital’s most recent community health needs assessment under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(r)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (or other comparable assessment)), such as obstetrics or behavioral health care services.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2215D43DAB24DA7A6623CA6F24F9B2F"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Limitation on certain designations</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H998F58C1572D4DF28EDBE018542D34AF"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Subject to clauses (ii) and (iii), the Secretary may not under subsection (e) certify pursuant to a certification by a State under subparagraph (B)(i)(III)—</text><subclause id="HDAAFEF5FE7E14686B8B134427D34BE0F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>more than a total of 120 facilities as critical access hospitals; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2DC803012EC9485CA99957C1A7B4F66A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within any one State, more than 5 facilities as critical access hospitals.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF32041DF2EA4407840D88897F4A86DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The Secretary shall follow the following process in carrying out clause (i) with respect to each year in which the Secretary determines that the limitation under clause (i)(I) has not been reached:</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC537355993D24A5E8A666962ED4E7A0F"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initial assessment</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct an initial assessment of the total number of hospitals described in paragraph (2)(F).</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AFB4DE3C3A64D12ACF1D6597726782B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Initial allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the total number of designations available under clause (i), the Secretary shall allocate 1 for a hospital in each State that the Secretary determines (based on the initial assessment under subclause (I)) has one or more hospitals described in paragraph (2)(F).</text></subclause><subclause id="HF34C966F16DE4870BB309C319EFF2F9E"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Remaining allocation</header><text>Of the total number of designations available under clause (i), after application of subclause (II), the Secretary shall allocate the remaining number on a proportional basis based on the total number of hospitals described in paragraph (2)(F) in each State that are eligible (as determined based on the initial assessment under subclause (I)).</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79E75DE258C3478691E45912EA67955F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Effective beginning on the date that is 9 years after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Secretary may not certify a hospital as a critical access hospital pursuant to a certification by a State under subparagraph (B)(i)(III).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DE74774985349D3AC1857B2A319BA07"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Information submission requirements for hospitals certified pursuant to Rural Hospital Closure Relief Act</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E9B62A10FAA49E987378EF5D4F94E6A"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A critical access hospital that is certified under subsection (e) pursuant to a certification by a State under subparagraph (B)(i)(III) shall submit to the Secretary the following at a time, and in a manner, specified by the Secretary:</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6AF763CA4614AEBB4926E028E85D084"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports containing such information as the Secretary may specify with respect to items and services furnished as part of the new service line or expanded service capacity for a service as described in the attestation submitted by the critical access hospital under subparagraph (F)(v)(II). To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall align such reporting with other reporting requirements applicable to critical access hospitals under this subsection.</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFEE00A7B1E6446FA7F69078D46A9D24"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the critical access hospital materially changes the new service line or expanded capacity for a service as so described, notice of such changes along with a plan to satisfactorily maintain access to care (as determined by the Secretary).</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC210856A0D67430A9DC7E55FC0BC70B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Revocation of certification for noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines that a critical access hospital described in clause (i) has failed to submit an annual report required under subclause (I) of such clause or a notice required under subclause (II) of such clause, the Secretary may, as the Secretary determines appropriate, revoke the certification of the critical access hospital under subsection (e).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1517DA6FB64799AA48059E4157395C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by inserting <quote>, subject to subsection (c)(2)(G),</quote> after <quote>The Secretary shall</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7952CAF5B5974C6EA56C825438AF8044"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue final regulations or program instruction to carry out subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H87EC00FBD700458887F73B267E597832"><enum/><header>I Clarification regarding facilities that meet distance or other criteria and application of other criteria</header><text>Nothing in this section shall affect—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H00A577A627654C57AE215C4613F11917"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application of criteria for designation as a critical access hospital described in subclause (I) or (II) of section 1820(c)(2)(B)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-4">42 U.S.C. 1395i–4(c)(2)(B)(i)</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECF58CFFD204478D97E67A06509AB001"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the application of criteria for designation as a critical access hospital described in clauses (ii) through (v) of section 1820(c)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-4">42 U.S.C. 1395i–4(c)(2)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H132CF953560441D1B8E98CF9D1657E70"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F5297DE6CBD4F568BD13FA98EC745DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States (in this section referred to as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study on the implementation of the amendments made by subsection (a). To the extent such data are available and reliable, such study shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H0F0EAF9750C944019CC9371B61D205C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B844DDE109E4218A43F52F5791A2814"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the characteristics of facilities designated as critical access hospitals pursuant to section 1820(c)(2)(B)(i)(III) of the Social Security Act, as added by subsection (a);</text></clause><clause id="H53E7D6A45B0C44B2A5F17B1E2973EB38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an analysis of the financial status and outlook for such facilities based on their designation as a critical access hospital pursuant to such section; and</text></clause><clause id="HABD24F00B8C44470A1C5FBC4E0D636C7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an analysis of any increase in expenditures under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) as a result of such designation, relative to the expected baseline expenditures under the Medicare program if such facilities had not received such designation; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF591C346E66D4D99AE7AF3AA1064974A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the authority to designate facilities as critical access hospitals pursuant to such section 1820(c)(2)(B)(i)(III) promotes access to care in rural areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H910590BC62A44E3CB614FE0E674BBCBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC43AE2C86F5A427DB2957B40AB22EA13"><enum>3.</enum><header>MedPAC study and report on payment systems for rural hospitals</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H49142646FFB94F49AC9419390AE29268"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall conduct a study, using data from 2018 through 2028, on payment systems for rural hospitals under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>). Such study shall include an analysis of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF31E129EB4A14DFEADD76D0A309C16EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilities designated as critical access hospitals pursuant to section 1820(c)(2)(B)(i)(III) of the Social Security Act, as added by section 2(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8DFD439757F495C9995167D11BAAD75"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">features of payment systems for rural hospitals, including value-based payment systems, that would—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23509DC74EFA414396429304C257CA14"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure financial sustainability for the Medicare program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C46C0836B394F1F8DD5E00FB6DE972E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserve access to care for Medicare beneficiaries; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12EDF090536D4D39827A6A2A2ADF6004"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Commission recommends any new payment system for rural hospitals under the Medicare program, to the extent feasible, the impacts of transition from existing payment systems to such new payment system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F9F198F11594693BF621F0C78E2AA54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 8 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under subsection (a), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BADAA98139E41D5BAD1AE19758F8253"><enum/><header> I Definition of rural hospital</header><text>In this section, the term <term>rural hospital</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5612D75C7D094C86A0E9572900C98930"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(mm)(1)</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC238FB8C9AA84F23BAFC6E1939F00AA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a subsection (d) hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(1)(B)</external-xref>)) that is located in a rural census tract of a metropolitan statistical area (as determined under the most recent modification of the Goldsmith Modification, originally published in the Federal Register on February 27, 1992 (57 Fed. Reg. 6725));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48C98FD8C7364FD9A83EEFDEF966D7C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a sole community hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(5)(D)(iii)) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(D)(iii)</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16F67D6686D34C008BF6BED0E97CE04A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a medicare dependent, small rural hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(5)(G)(iv) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(5)(G)(iv)</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAB32FDE966448598B14CEB2941F5590"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a low-volume hospital (as defined in section 1886(d)(12)(C)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(12)(C)(i)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD08CB127E06A4CC4A5B8B46D1D84DE3A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Adjusting Medicare critcal access hospital requirements for Guam, American Samoa, the northern mariana islands, and the virgin islands</header><subsection id="iddbda06ce8cbb4f01b2cd2daa284bc55d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Section 1820(c)(2)(B)(iii) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.S. 1395i–4I(2)(B)(iii)) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81702F66137D4E628E867F228B389B73"><clause id="id284abdd3ac394910aa907a5032c60740"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides—</text><subclause id="id653008ac9bcf408b8ca58d8a4978ed98"><enum>(I)</enum><text> in the case of a facility located in 1 of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, or Puerto Rico, not more than 25 acute care inpatient beds (meeting such standards as the Secretary may establish) for providing inpatient care for a period that does not exceed, as determined on an annual, average basis, 96 hours per patient; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idf4bcd13dd6e34a9583c280fb769c1c7c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a facility located in Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, or the United States Virgin Islands, acute care inpatient beds in a number determined appropriate by the Secretary (meeting, such standards as the Secretary may establish) for providing inpatient car for a period that does not exceed, as determined on an annual, average basis, 96 hours per patient.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idf95eb9b3040e45c3b256b159297f295c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply beginning October 1, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="id232d558fd4234b8bb93599cd8b6b0997"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 9 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a mechanism and provide guidance and technical assistance under which any facility that was designated as a critical access hospital pursuant to a certification by a State under section 1820(c)(2)(B)(i)(III) of the Social Security Act, as added by section 2(a), may transition within 1 year to one of the following payment models:</text><paragraph id="ide04910749ed048baa416e363b2187ebf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Such new model or models recommended by the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission in the report submitted under section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c83219bfcd14ccf9201fb00b98fd0cc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The prospective payment model (or models) under which the facility received payment under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) prior to being designated pursuant to such certifcation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef2d5aaa9e074492b7fb7e9403d51d55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Payment as a rural emergency hospital under section 1834(x) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(x)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

