<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26041-9DH-TK-782"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4818 IS: National Strategy for Social Connection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4818</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260617">June 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Office of Social Connection Policy, to establish a national strategy on social connection, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H3CD661EEA0344EDFB0B89006AE45B30F"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Strategy for Social Connection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6e9e74f76e0a42449f98d9d64cea9dd1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id26ea62899edc4fea8b3c3e7d0e943945"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The health of the Nation is rightly measured not only by its aggregate wealth or global power, but more centrally by its shared vision and the bonds of connection that knit its people into a community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d732875a48b49d9a61c3d4cf53a0061"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The fraying of the social fabric is directly implicated in the growth of loneliness, decline of civic and religious participation, the disintegration of communities, rising economic inequality and precarity, falling economic mobility, rising rates of depression, anxiety and addiction, diminishing health and life expectancy and rising levels of polarization and radicalization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide75c6f663080492bbebebaa5d24727e3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These changes affect all people of the United States, but fall with particular force on the poor and marginalized, on children and adolescents, on individuals residing in economically disadvantaged regions, on veterans and on the elderly, and individuals without a college degree.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb14d50c67d4419fb61ffc7eca2bb769"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Surgeon General declared an epidemic of loneliness and isolation on May 2, 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c0fd827e0c34a73aaec8c41781e3887"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to the Surgeon General, social isolation and loneliness pose a significant risk to individual health and longevity, including a 29 percent increased risk of heart disease, a 32 percent increased risk of stroke, and for older adults, a 50 percent increased risk of developing dementia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2fc4a29ebebd4973a37058107468041a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Loneliness and social isolation increase the risk for premature death by 26 percent and 29 percent, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida35ae06b5e754b3b8a1c1c6126538362"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The general flourishing, economic health and stability of the United States, and the effective functioning of government and society require renewed attention to social connection at every level of society, from individual and family, to local community and Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a924799807f4c44aca37bc9838ae1d3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The causal connections between these changes are complex, and thus the various cultural, technological, demographic, economic, political and institutional drivers of social connection require attention from a dedicated expert body that may develop and share knowledge to incorporate into the national decision-making process and align relevant agency actions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9eabf2436904471682c893d73c795918"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Federal funding for research and policy around social connection represents an investment in the future that is indispensable to sustained national progress and human flourishing, and there should be continuing national investment in identifying and expanding proven local strategies, assessing how agencies are or are not contributing to social connection, and funding incentives to drive improvement commensurate with addressing contemporary problems.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id6d2fbb68b5c54d52b67620210f3ab7c5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Social Connection Policy; National Strategy on Social Connection</header><subsection id="idd566de617bce486592197da62de0ee42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide67c35cc71cf4cdca7b8a03db92c464d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory Council</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Council</term> means the advisory council established under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee1bc56fccd04077a512ca9c70fbb8b6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb38dd4767c28403f8dffacd8390d2d87"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inadequate</header><text>The term <term>inadequate</term>, with respect to loneliness, means the discrepancy or unmet need between an individual’s or community’s preferred and actual experience.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id236fbd5d3558498cac80ac5abe6c5be5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Loneliness</header><text>The term <term>loneliness</term>, with respect to an individual, means a subjective distressing experience of an individual that results from perceived isolation or inadequate meaningful connection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8181d07c9094400a24cf49c5176cf10"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Social Connection Policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe267c6f7c3b412ab28b17fcd9b32ac1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Social connectedness</header><text>The term <term>social connectedness</term> means the degree to which an individual or community achieves and maintains social connection needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e0e43d7054e40cfabd806758ef05cb8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Social connection</header><text>The term <term>social connection</term> means a continuum of the size and diversity of an individual’s social network and roles, the functions such relationships and roles serve, and the positive or negative qualities of such relationships and roles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21842d5430be44efa06ff3a51427b695"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Social disconnection</header><text>The term <term>social disconnection</term> means objective or subjective deficits in social connection, including deficits in social relationships and roles, the functions such relationships and roles serve, and the positive or negative qualities of such relationships and roles.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idbf0de1fc3a414343bbe0ff2dd7025960"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Social infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>social infrastructure</term> means the programs (such as volunteer organizations, sports groups, religious groups, and member associations), policies (such as public transportation, housing, and education), and physical elements (such as libraries, parks, green spaces, and playgrounds) of a community that support the development of social connection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id21ffa89c22154457b49bd7deecf62dc7"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Social isolation</header><text>The term <term>social isolation</term>, with respect to an individual, means that the individual objectively has few social relationships, social roles, or group memberships and has infrequent social interaction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b39b393c6f74133b7e5f31aa0f5e6bc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Social Connection Policy</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3df509bc6b54e4d93304c3a1414a711"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>There is established within the Executive Office of the President an office, to be known as the <quote>Office of Social Connection Policy</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida756a204cd72467bb9dc937912d40fc4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Office shall be to provide to the President independent, expert judgment and assistance on policy matters that require accurate assessments of social connection.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6a61f621c4d64032a498c5c581a4d1e7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9336455be2f64f47940c8ce394ba123e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Office shall be the Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ae969c6ed2e4bfdb787ad9f69d3168b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall be compensated at the rate provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41bfc172a5cb48f7bc3e366491cff02a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Associate directors</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc65ff196c388440da865cd0f75f24ab8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, not more than 4 Associate Directors of the Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20fd91c87c1348049e1b063bd5e671c2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Associate Director appointed under subparagraph (A) shall be compensated at the rate provided for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd4c9e6f3f72d4f9ba8c982ffc68acaac"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duties</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id29767283cb664a16910cee30741e5c3f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbef2802c95b34d589dd47fb1bd43eb2d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advise the President on timely and authoritative research regarding public health, technological, and social infrastructure aspects of social connection and loneliness that require attention at the highest levels of the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="id22a4c930ca9749d5836d52a19e0c4093"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advise the President on social connection and loneliness considerations with respect to issues of national concern, including the economy, public health, national security, the environment, and civic and community engagement;</text></clause><clause id="id46aa2b9cf3da4042a8d7827cadeec539"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to research and development relating to social connection and loneliness—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4e79f4e90174b02b617dbe6cf89263c"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist the Director of the Office of Management and Budget with an annual review and analysis of funding proposed for such research and development for all Federal agencies; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6f5ff08cae0470ea7513f778789e211"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and the heads of the Federal agencies throughout the budget development process;</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1c59112748041fba19bf47d5d3c4f13"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assist the President in providing general leadership and coordination of Federal research and development programs relating to social connection and loneliness;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf3d24ebb214545698f222d5395eb24cb"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide prompt, effective, reliable, and systematic information to the public on the impact of policies and programs conducted by the Federal Government on social connection and maintenance and development of social infrastructure;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f9cdfbf87354b5585cfe95e15e3258c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish, maintain, and update the national strategy in accordance with subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida392238cddb54a35a22c9719c9565d52"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out such other activities as the President may determine.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1f9cd2dc72f48f4bb42ff7ef4d8ba15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National strategy</header><clause id="id7f5d0994a66046c88cc79be40af188bf"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office shall establish, maintain, and periodically update an integrated national strategy to improve social connection, ameliorate loneliness, and slow or stop the progression of social disconnection.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebfb7e495604430d8837317ab0b09479"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The national strategy under clause (i) shall be an inclusive, Federal Government-wide approach that leverages existing Federal resources and authorities to achieve enhanced social connection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb03d8c2382e34581925d7ead00a7e5c9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advisory Council</header><paragraph id="id1588b491ffea4130bedf8e87c221cfa0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish an intergovernmental advisory council the purpose of which shall be to address loneliness, social disconnection, and social connection experienced by individuals in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida72d35fa84474e128a9fbf22eda325c6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Advisory Council shall—</text><subparagraph id="idac67a378691f4b2795ceb052ab4d95c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out an annual assessment on social connection in accordance with paragraph (5);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id620c6b4edab04025931be12e05763c53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide information on, and coordinate, social connection research and services across all Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66d9eb7c466545fcbed4f50c4641a450"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encourage the development of effective strategies and approaches to prevent social disconnection and improve social infrastructure, quality of life, and community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddedace151f914e8287398d30ede4bf97"><enum>(D)</enum><text>review the impact of social disconnection and loneliness on physical, mental, and social health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6e68733c94c40deafdb3de77657f030"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate with international bodies to integrate and inform the global mission to improve social connection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53c2ebb0ac0c4102a722b9587b3582ab"><enum>(F)</enum><text>advise the Director;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2074c511f3e4945846aaa917c8a8584"><enum>(G)</enum><text>issue national guidelines on social connection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id492a70a9a3cf455b931d304e2378271a"><enum>(H)</enum><text>carry out such other activities as the Director determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf5e2b11b220443a98798303bcb35541"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph id="id472556a8a80c4b5f8b18220af3ddea10"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Council shall be composed of—</text><clause id="id70201b724a8f46ae9e2220ba68d3d03e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Director (or the Director's designee), who shall serve as the Chair of the Advisory Council;</text></clause><clause id="id2e1460ae202b45048cfb0b55d33d618e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Federal members under subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="id0d0a89843a884deb8df50e1fc09255c2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the non-Federal members under subparagraph (C).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfeffc99f130d44b7a9b102a9158c05e9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal members</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2480d1648d2e49869cac103e0e200487"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the Director (or the Director's designee), the Federal members of the Advisory Council shall consist of 1 representative from each of—</text><subclause id="idbf9cf27d4fac44b4b6e64ef4a9d99fa5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text></subclause><subclause id="id528425013b82482884e486199c0e39b2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1f8550d360644e1d8e93bba15b5cd8d9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Department of Education;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1f41a64b27ec418695adb5dfc184af8d"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services, including—</text><item id="iddfab57e265cd4d718e12f92ca69ac10a"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Administration on Community Living;</text></item><item id="idc0e698b8c2a24f7494308f201e257ddb"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbccdb7a95788479e9b39af9662d49d9d"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of the National Institutes of Health;</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddfbb2985d7fe49ae8a99435b3563d4ad"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subclause><subclause id="id18c89b0413604c859ccf127b7ca82668"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development, including the Office of Community Planning and Development;</text></subclause><subclause id="id5f909356f3124fe8848034540b86fc8a"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subclause><subclause id="id0ba1919ca6b543b1aed66f46bf8f0ee3"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the Department of Labor;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide65caa9f100f4adaac490e9e023ae00e"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury;</text></subclause><subclause id="idfdc8337b580d4b299dec8573a1ce5e81"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7723a7f3d838458babbee8f2eca112ec"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subclause><subclause id="id886a1f47f79f40d4ae75ae2ad532dec5"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>the Corporation for National and Community Service; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idfbb909caa6614dd8ac1f2a355c63b79f"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>other relevant Federal agencies, as determined by the Director.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19c7ed9355f842c1af0e67f8fe09ba49"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal members under clause (i) shall be appointed—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5b1091670b34b94a97af092998bea2a"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the head of the respective agency or office; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id05d5edc691634616aad5f16cf5549c88"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">so as to ensure that the membership of the Advisory Council is diverse and inclusive.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fd909cb14364a3cbcbdf645af646fee"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Non-Federal members</header><text>The non-Federal members of the Advisory Council shall be appointed by the Director, and shall consist of experts in their respective fields, including—</text><clause id="id26ab1bdcd1ad452bb5290ef10f31149e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 or more caregivers;</text></clause><clause id="iddd20800f319444b4bdd8f99131aa6af7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 or more health care providers;</text></clause><clause id="idc191cc6f4b1d4a0db5efdc162b7b7999"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of nonprofit organizations that advocate for policies that reduce loneliness and social isolation;</text></clause><clause id="id03c8cb45e2d2463a80448070057793fe"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of State, territorial, local, and Tribal governments;</text></clause><clause id="ida0f530c158c643ae980674d3fd9580e6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>1 or more researchers from research institutions;</text></clause><clause id="idf056de2016d24e04a43cfb8a67e7200c"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of State education agencies;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf5754429a8c14683ada1fcdbcd727d64"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of Veterans Service Organizations;</text></clause><clause id="id75af510c7a5b45389c13690b4b10828b"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>1 or more employers;</text></clause><clause id="ida03b7e3b72cb4873af13f2cd2387ef1d"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>1 or more workplace representatives;</text></clause><clause id="id0f354101a2c04e9a847af97f7c690b32"><enum>(x)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of volunteer organizations;</text></clause><clause id="id6cafe7c057bd4ef08cb346ef78d2a476"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of nonprofit organizations that advocate for youth and have youth serving on their boards or in leadership positions;</text></clause><clause id="id1f51b52eda9744a78624dbef7c2c64d1"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of community action agencies;</text></clause><clause id="id78ffd5513db842f280c5896f738b3eb3"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of disability rights organizations; and</text></clause><clause id="idb041a727abe548e9a1d7e4dff8c20a64"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>1 or more representatives of LGBTQIA+ advocacy organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb63ca6d2456459a84e4d7fbbdb40066"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="idd7e8acb6fcb543e99d5811f6c8e459f5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Quarterly meetings</header><text>The Advisory Council shall meet not less frequently than quarterly, and at the call of the Director.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2b76af1a0a747b0a7087afe992a13a1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Open meetings</header><text>The meetings of the Advisory Council shall be open to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id265552bfa8394f83a9155949db3614a8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual assessment</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Advisory Council shall carry out an assessment of the progress of the United States in improving social connection, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idd762e256e804452faa3b2c107d976ea9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of steps that have been, or should be, taken—</text><clause id="id22840a0b247344cfbe9a9673cb3e15dc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to increase the use of the national strategy described in subsection (b)(5)(B) in Federal policy development and implementation;</text></clause><clause id="id737b2c5e46a842df8ee3fa0b95da140d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to establish a framework to improve and connect social services;</text></clause><clause id="id6024098f82874f66b6aa841554174713"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to promote continuous community-led planning and design to improve social connection through reimagined community spaces, transportation, housing, and technologies;</text></clause><clause id="id03e6c3d3a69240c283db7f5030f8e899"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to establish and scale community connection programs;</text></clause><clause id="idb531938c1c75445594ad73ce10c59648"><enum>(v)</enum><text>to coordinate public health campaigns that raise awareness and reduce the stigma surrounding loneliness;</text></clause><clause id="id94737b117bdb4ccd8f50e9d36377022e"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to strengthen measurement practices to increase collection of data measuring loneliness and social connection;</text></clause><clause id="idddb0fe66c683443580e541268dada3a0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>to provide assistance to State, local, and Tribal governments seeking to improve social connection among residents; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd48810f4327c409db329c7c87e8ba3ae"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>to support youth participation in strategies to improve social connection and community connection; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5609adc63064a7b92412b327d30b82e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of other issues the Director determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id65aae58eb0b54623adf4da80b9b69ad6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Advisory Council shall submit to the Director and Congress a report that describes—</text><subparagraph id="id4f1e64e430ca45e3932393441ce71e0f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of all Federal efforts to address loneliness and improve social connection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id694add5c52f34d6a90267805fe5037fa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative changes needed to implement goals described in clauses (i) through (viii) of paragraph (5)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id44725a0fdaea45b1879da630a89eee6c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of the implementation, including outcomes, of the national strategy described in subsection (b)(5)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1b5203b0156943a882e40213de6d89df"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data sharing</header><text>Each Federal agency that has data relating to loneliness and social connection shall share such data with the Director and make such data publicly available, subject to applicable Federal law relating to disclosure of such data, to enable the Advisory Council to complete the reports described in subsection (c)(6).</text></subsection><subsection id="id15ebfa015feb4dcc89a80bce74eb0bba"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031 to conduct or support research on loneliness and social connection.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

