<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A75D11B2895478292C39EDA5B34080A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9737 IH: Consumer Health Claim Assistance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9737</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employment Retirement Income Security Act to establish a Benefits Assistance Program to improve access to benefits under employee welfare benefit plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9EACCFD13F346D8BD4D36A8072CFF59" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H19DB027946A04EAE91E13EF63F5D9759" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Health Claim Assistance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1E2A3797199A47FB86B4ED3201C16A3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Benefits assistance program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part 5 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1131">29 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD523FC766AAA4D3799A2112646DACEE7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H322685C8E366485AB86C09B8E17D1C6A"><enum>524.</enum><header>Benefits assistance program</header> 
<subsection id="HDF6FE7969133422AAE61963CB6A09DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall establish, within the Employee Benefits Security Administration of the Department of Labor, a Benefits Assistance Program (in this section, referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to improve access to benefits under employee welfare benefit plans.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8A643E2521DB4071A0BFAFE16010C00B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Program shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD84DA244A1144BDBB1E8E821B18C7FE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a process for the receipt of inquiries or complaints from participants and beneficiaries, and health care providers (on behalf of participants and beneficiaries), relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D2FD7EB505046A9B0AA62DDFA38DE7B"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adverse benefit determinations (as defined under section 2560.503–1(m)(4) of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer Health Claim Assistance Act</short-title>); and</text>
                            </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FFC30311BCF4500A43F9EDC7C6544FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>alleged violations of—</text> <clause id="HFF5C268C08FB4E24A90937CBF9C04821"><enum>(i)</enum><text>plan terms; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="H3350E8DE6AE645589039A95C86EC623F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any provision of this title;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85CAB739E0D94E638B79D78FF41F9F8C"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist participants and beneficiaries in understanding their rights to benefits under their plan and the availability of internal appeals and external review (as such terms are defined under sections 2590.715–2719(a)(2) of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Consumer Health Claim Assistance Act</short-title>);</text>
                        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAC09C742F014F3294728456A51C6C0C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>directly assist participants and beneficiaries in filing appeals for denied benefits and navigating such appeals or reviews;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA125AC206D84D6987516AAD43A5365E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>make referrals to appropriate entities regarding any inquiries or complaints relating to adverse benefit determinations by a plan that may violate this title or any other law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H103A03A93C624DD6ACD08C31C89EF980"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide additional training, technical assistance, and support to Department staff, including benefits advisors, to address adverse benefit determinations or any violations of this title; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52C6F914879D490DA32899349CC1325C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the inquiry or complaint was received as a result of a referral from a State office of health insurance consumer assistance, health insurance ombudsman, or other program that carries out the duties described in section 2793(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-93">42 U.S.C. 300gg–93(c)</external-xref>), inform such office or program of the result of such inquiry or complaint.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H32E74753A1BB447ABC23A2C27EAC9A41">
                        <enum>(c)</enum>
                        <header>Annual report</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Labor shall, on an annual basis, submit to the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report, with respect to the Program, on the following:</text>
                        <paragraph id="H9D1D0811EE1D45D08C4FCAD1ABE8BA05">
                            <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The number of inquiries and complaints received (disaggregated by type of plan, size of plan, and type of assistance provided).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HD592EC1F3522453E8196E61E692F1B26">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The number of participants and beneficiaries who received assistance (disaggregated by type of plan, size of plan, and type of service provided).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HE682452F4D86481797D9BA4C413629A7">
                            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The dollar amounts of claims for benefits for which assistance was provided (disaggregated by type of plan, size of plan, and type of service provided).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HBF4A7FCE21A6405095BB55B9BD74ECC4">
                            <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>The total dollar amount expended to operate the Program and the number of full-time equivalents assigned by the Secretary to operate the Program.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="H64ED51F0AB634615AB8FE93E54F3FFAB">
                            <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>The number of referrals to appropriate entities and, when available, the disposition of such enforcement actions.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HBF9EF186DD4F41EA92BEB2B843979C46">
                            <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>The number and type of any non-monetary recoveries by participants and beneficiaries who received assistance.</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HC679DC44F201455BBD7C2FC9033D41FC">
                            <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>The average amount of time it takes to provide assistance.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H99F9731F5B82424FB16C95B9A4AF7B14"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations regarding any additional authority or resources needed to improve the Program, including recommendations on necessary increases in filing fees under section 104(d).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph id="HED40BCF028274F70831C8D959D52F86A">
                            <enum>(9)</enum>
 <text>Any other data determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H962C89EA62224D04B9C695585661ABB0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Plan filing fees</header> <subsection id="H00F2409B4A6D46A7ADDC0E5307802CBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fees on filings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1024">29 U.S.C. 1024</external-xref>) is amended by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively, and by inserting after subsection (c) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6A0BE903B08B4DFC8F0103218E2ABBF8" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H22DA48B40B884A008284687E04CC6A82"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fees on filings with Secretary of Labor</header> 
<paragraph id="HF7DC23D925254538B2A4AD8AAF41F3D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The administrator of any employee welfare benefit plan which is a single-employer plan shall pay to the Secretary a filing fee in the amount determined under paragraph (2) at the time of filing an annual report or a notice under subsection (a)(1)(A).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AB75BD2B943441AACDBED14856FD4AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of fee</header> <subparagraph id="H177865E4B2A64E76AF1D9BA802F2B198"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the amount of the fee under paragraph (1) with respect to each report or notice shall be—</text> 
<clause id="H3B7682B678EE4E6C80FBDB0B26058802"><enum>(i)</enum><text> $250 if the plan had fewer than 100 participants as of the close of the plan year preceding the plan year in which such report or notice is filed;</text></clause> <clause id="HC6F030BB2110478AADBDE8FB991FCBC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$500 if the plan had 100 or more but fewer than 500 participants as of the close of such plan year; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H910223BE879E4E76ACE8AFAF1768A716"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not less than $1,000 in the case of any other plan.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4DA78C299014B8D85CF983AA740E416" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulatory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may by regulation require a fee that is higher than is otherwise required under this paragraph. If the Secretary requires a higher fee, the Secretary shall establish a fee scale that increases the fee charged to a plan as the number of participants in a plan increases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF936AA8026D946C0999382E195A147D0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of plan assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payment of a filing fee under this subsection may not be made using any funds that are assets of the plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C89B1C139D14A4E9E56EE8C4307D9C5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use and availability of funds</header> <subparagraph id="H34A257CDE4FF4822A8782A6686075AEF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall expend the amounts received under this subsection for each fiscal year for enforcement of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and to support operations of the Benefits Assistance Program described in section 524. Such funds shall be available without fiscal year limitation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7FBCDEE83F142D0A283E15EFB1BE342"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>At least 50 percent of the amounts described in subparagraph (A) shall be used to support operations of the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAF45859925A24E958AB6F5C75D24FC22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104(d) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, as added by this section, shall apply to reports, descriptions, notices, and attestations filed after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2D76B09611964472A8BCD3048C48002F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Minimum notice</header> 
<subsection id="HBE32A056A4014A0C8CDA975293CE24D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 104(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1024">29 U.S.C. 1024(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF9A4EBE36BE54B0EA3BDB7F97A63C0DD"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>in paragraph (1), by inserting after <quote>plan year</quote> the following: <quote>(or, if applicable, file with the Secretary a notice as described in paragraph (3)(B) for a plan year)</quote>; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEC22A46FD2A4884A398728BD9F97C9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> <subparagraph id="H5516DB135B84420FA8B151BFC9F63519"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(A)</enum-in-header></header-in-text> Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F3D1CBB099C416EA6AACE49F296D895"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC5CD37A645CF4890AECB6CB2516F1722" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H8FE181600AB846D9AA1369A7C419444C" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any employee welfare benefit plan which is a single-employer plan that is not required to file an annual report for any year, the administrator of the plan shall file with the Secretary a notice containing the following information in relation to such plan for such year:</text> 
<clause id="HAA711B3F803646E1BFDB323F280CB294"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The name of the employer maintaining such plan.</text></clause> <clause id="H4974FB6BD0FF4A968ECC293DA297922F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of employees covered by such plan.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H108104F66AE84564A93670809089B4CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The aggregate amount of benefits provided by such plan.</text></clause> <clause id="HF0F5106EC2644E3284C7C679C0E0B851"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The method of funding of such plan (whether such plan is unfunded, insured, or a combination) and, if applicable, the name of any issuers contracted to provide health insurance coverage in connection with such plan.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H97C8C83AD4A648CAB26D2DDA04E2214A"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The name of any service providers that rendered services to the plan and received $5,000 or more in compensation, directly or indirectly, from the plan.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3419145549164EB6A796A691D697878B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective dates</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to plan years ending after January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

