<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFDD50A83C83640D48D871E30863FB93C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7555 IH: Audit the Pentagon Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7555</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that the Department of Defense achieves a clean audit opinion on its financial statements, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7A16A2D5E92F420783FFF3BBF5539B37" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7B7BED6BEE874F9E9FF635608283D6A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Audit the Pentagon Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB1365B1CE3C4486CA6EFCDE9C9BC1FE2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <paragraph id="HC607D8C02AC14FB19F6F954FC0593AD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Pentagon failed its 8th consecutive audit in December 2025.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5400E30E3D49400D9CEF35394AFCACA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In November 2023, upon failure of its 6th consecutive audit, the Pentagon was unable to account for hundreds of billions of dollars, accounting for 63 percent of its nearly $4 trillion in assets.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6087CD00F1924A69939174A5AC86DD85"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8AF76F9FCF0F4ACB9AE3B70BA52506A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as the overall defense budget is cut, the congressional defense committees and the Department of Defense should not endanger the Armed Forces by reducing wounded warrior accounts or vital protection (such as body armor) for members of the Armed Forces serving in harm’s way;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47CC9B65E27A4063A6EA50B093ADD4CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the valuation of legacy assets by the Department of Defense should be simplified without compromising essential controls or generally accepted government auditing standards; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H649CBB5BB0F6476AB0AFA1E4FC8594B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nothing in this Act should be construed to require or permit the declassification of accounting details about classified defense programs, and, as required by law, the Department of Defense should ensure financial accountability in such programs using proven practices, including using auditors with security clearances.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HCBF68326457F4FFC8883428D03E21DA7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Department of Defense spending reductions in the absence of an unqualified audit opinion</header> <subsection id="H5AB599FC1B66401A841885042E900D05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H7E6FA878D6614CF49DC019FF75B6A0DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reductions</header><text>If, during any fiscal year after fiscal year 2025, the Comptroller of the Department of Defense fails to certify to Congress that a department, agency, or other element of the Department of Defense has achieved an unqualified opinion on its full financial statements, the amount available for such department, agency, or element shall be reduced—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA7DA54D4233A4704A075295D7D9C6D62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the fiscal year during which such determination is made, by an amount equal to 0.5 percent; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA177425E3784B51B18F0F442EB0A857"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for any subsequent fiscal year during which such determination is made, by an amount equal to 1.0 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81B4A1575AD44B919C9741BD228BFCAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of reductions</header><text>For any fiscal year for which a reduction is made pursuant to paragraph (1) for a department, agency, or element, the amount of the reduction shall be applied on a pro rata basis against each program, project, and activity of such department, agency, or element for that fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10A76C13CF7E4D1899112B906105F600"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of reduced amounts</header><text>The amount of any reduction made under paragraph (1) shall be deposited in the General Fund of the Treasury and shall be available for purposes of deficit reduction.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H55DD6AF5B3FB4273A47A0B41AA773D2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accounts excluded</header><text>The following accounts are excluded from any reductions under subsection (a):</text> <paragraph id="HAF082674B7104461A1D80C16A1DF2495"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Military personnel, reserve personnel, and National Guard personnel accounts of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB07FD81A06FA40CB8A1A3C1BBC45E9A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Defense Health Program account of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9366DCAF6E1E4749818378921073B757"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive subsection (a) with respect to an account if the President—</text> 
<paragraph id="H23F8EE04A474479C826519C0674D4926"><enum>(1)</enum><text>certifies that the application of such subsection to that account would—</text> <subparagraph id="H6A9808B23A224872BB08426248B1E470"><enum>(A)</enum><text>negatively affect the national security of the United States or members of the Armed Forces who are deployed in combat zones; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F5F531D36EE4CF3B7FECDA9202FF034"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affect the Defense Health Program account; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H318F2F1282174A70A02DFD45E60D1BDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on the Budget of the Senate a report on such waiver that includes a description of the specific activities that would be affected and why such activities are essential to the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34DBC2AFF91545EA84EA0B2F022F4C11"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after a reduction takes effect under subsection (a), the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall submit to Congress a report specifying each department, agency, or other element of the Department of Defense subject to reduction and the amount of the reduction.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H173391B13E7E48B1A86EBC1BBAB7258E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF73BF4E705F24A2982C44E370B6A458E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The terms <term>financial statement</term> and <term>external independent auditor</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3521(e) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57E852D1B318469AA4082CFCF14B8BBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>unqualified</term>, with respect to the audit status of a financial statement, includes the characterizations clean and unmodified.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

