<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H44257DCDED554A24A0AD1381B0111DC9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7545 IH: Defending the Human Rights of Palestinian Children and Families Living Under Israeli Military Occupation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7545</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit funds made available for assistance to the Government of Israel to be used to support certain violations of international law, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE381793A00474B3D9CC9CF417772D666" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE775004EBA3F4F00925804A70F3BFA51" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending the Human Rights of Palestinian Children and Families Living Under Israeli Military Occupation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9058B3470E3946A5A6511EB00BE0CC7F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCE2FFC89348A41148893BA807A420FED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the West Bank, Israeli military law is applied to Palestinians while Israeli civilian law is applied to Israeli settlers, resulting in different legal protections, including for minors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4907BCB5B1B54458A66DA38E3DDDA4EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each year, Israeli authorities detain and prosecute hundreds of Palestinian minors within a military court system that does not consistently provide timely access to legal counsel, parental presence during interrogation, or other basic due process guarantees as required under international human rights and humanitarian law, including the Convention on the Rights of the Child, which Israel ratified in 1991.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE28A893ED7F746B88892B9F9E2C2B7FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Reports by Israeli, Palestinian, and international human rights organizations have documented the use of nighttime arrests, coercive or prolonged interrogations, and prolonged administrative detention of Palestinian minors without charge or trial, practices inconsistent with international standards for the treatment of children in detention.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB868AAFA997C4F859A7C1B76EB02870C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Israel’s ongoing imposition of a restrictive planning and permitting regime in Area C of the West Bank and East Jerusalem results in the routine demolition or confiscation of Palestinian homes and structures.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE7AECDA80B843C88B1057CCC09331EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These demolitions in Area C and East Jerusalem contribute to the displacement of Palestinian families, heighten tensions on the ground, and impede efforts to create conditions conducive to long-term stability and peace for Israelis and Palestinians alike.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H754CF9BAB38C4E1E87FF03C3192EA9D6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The expansion of Israeli settlements and any steps toward unilateral annexation of parts of the West Bank contravene international law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9925605BC89945E590ABC4E264A188F3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Israel receives significant United States security assistance, including Foreign Military Financing and funds designated for <quote>offshore procurement</quote>, which constitutes an exception to standard United States arms transfer and assistance practices, under which a portion of United States assistance may be used to procure defense articles produced in Israel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3861CFDD3192458894214A3642DEA426"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Congress has an interest in ensuring that all United States-origin defense articles and funds are used in a manner consistent with United States laws, regulations, and policy objectives.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HADC2D6C238854B71B4E3626265979C7D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H99CB0D62AD78449CB532FD8A69D6D5F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actions by the Government of Israel in the occupied West Bank, including the detention and prosecution of Palestinian children in the Israeli military court system, the seizure, appropriation, and destruction of Palestinian property and forcible transfer of civilians, and further annexation of Palestinian land in violation of international law and internationally recognized standards of human rights—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37D816060F1343CDB83595F8064BFC22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are contrary to the values of the American people and the efforts of the United States to support self-determination, human rights, and dignity for both Palestinians and Israelis; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E0F4CDC18844927A3AB715653F63395"><enum>(B)</enum><text>undermine efforts by the United States to achieve a just and lasting peace between Israelis and the Palestinians;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52F64A028AAD4F77AD075039A8735DB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promoting human rights, human dignity, and democratic rights for all Palestinians and Israelis are foreign policy priorities of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE774F8E712E4373AEB2DC379334D168"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States rejects any undemocratic system or act of aggression in which Israel unilaterally exercises permanent rule over a Palestinian people denied self-determination and human rights.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H88AA2F77FE7E4B80A3EFEF1E077CC7BF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States not to support actions by the Government of Israel involving—</text> <paragraph id="HF1694354443A4CD2B000139659A478DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the military detention of Palestinian children in violation of international law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H712958EDD993458F9007DCBAC18DA05D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the seizure, appropriation, and destruction of Palestinian property or the forcible transfer of civilians in the occupied West Bank in violation of international law; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94D6642D25CD418AA74FB63CB31829C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>further annexation of Palestinian land and property in violation of international law.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5D38B2BA62C1444291FB70AF883C33F6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on assistance</header> 
<subsection id="H536B7268AA4E4A4A9A5EEF715AC3379E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for assistance to the Government of the State of Israel may be obligated or expended for any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H75F263246C80495EA6AD34F459A97591"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Supporting the military detention, interrogation, abuse, or ill treatment of Palestinian children in violation of international humanitarian law or to support the use against Palestinian children of any of the following practices:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6E832893060F4BF69FABE90420E19273"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Torture or cruel, inhumane, or degrading treatment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5769FC63DF9C42C1B7A7B964503C7D9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Physical violence, including restraint in stress positions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H407D062D2863433C96BC5556AD0476E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Hooding, sensory deprivation, death threats, or other forms of psychological abuse.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA1B0CA433EC4C878C53733D0B43E374"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Incommunicado detention or solitary confinement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAFC6BD7CDB52497CBF80338589A6A61C" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Administrative detention, or imprisonment without charge or trial.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61C1A19B0B484299977F69062D28ED4E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Arbitrary detention.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1D9B4E4321943719B63EE732566B58D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Denial of access to parents or legal counsel during interrogations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C65515E230F422997A05BC0EC23A80D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Confessions obtained by force or coercion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AF25489FB9146A0911BA9D9AEF8A819"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Supporting the seizure, appropriation, or destruction of Palestinian property or forcible transfer of civilians in the Israeli-controlled and occupied West Bank in violation of international humanitarian law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H762F2A2658544D24A71D55060A084C0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Deploying, or supporting the deployment of, personnel, training, services, lethal materials, equipment, facilities, logistics, transportation, or any other activity to territory in the occupied West Bank to facilitate or support further unilateral annexation by Israel of such territory in violation of international humanitarian law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF417D361044E42EFB965C979503FDC6B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2027, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, with respect to the fiscal year ending on such date—</text> <paragraph id="H17F11AB187964FA48B790ABC24A36633" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a certification that none of the funds obligated or expended for assistance to the Government of Israel have been used by such Government to support personnel, training, lethal materials, equipment, facilities, logistics, transportation, or any other activity that supports or is associated with any of the activities described in paragraphs (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC56FE3D5FB3E4AFBBB593E981DD84BF1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a certification that funds obligated or expended have supported or been associated with one or more activities described in paragraphs (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a), along with a report describing in detail the amount of such funds used by the Government of Israel in violation of such subsection and each activity supported by such funds.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5C70B6FB88DF42C7AEB1AA201FFB806F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Oversight and additional reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 116 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151n">22 U.S.C. 2151n</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H30ABAB7BABC04E98A1289E1B339C3E93" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H143167BF195E4597B4C554E29283AB60"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Activities by the Government of Israel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (d) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HF1A2874A38204640BDD0ABF6377C6108"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the nature and extent of detention, interrogation, abuse, or ill treatment of Palestinian children by Israeli military forces or police in violation of international humanitarian law;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H275AF826FAA24A179CBAC09F4ABD85BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the nature and extent of the seizure, appropriation, or destruction of Palestinian property in the Israeli-controlled and occupied West Bank by Israeli authorities in violation of international humanitarian law; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H466B641C41974E19A6C1E52B41399D18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the nature and extent of Israeli settlement activities, including an assessment of the compliance of the Government of Israel with United Nations Security Council Resolution 2334 (2016).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H213EB82D2892402196918CA121024209" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>GAO report on Israel’s expenditures for offshore procurement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2027, and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="H8C33347B362C4711A59091920E02BA4B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies the specific programs and items for which funds for offshore procurement in Israel have been allocated by the United States, including specific branches, units, and contractors of the Armed Forces;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2F4B777CAB64642893548BF4721C556" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses executive branch compliance with legislative requirements governing offshore procurements in Israel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD72CDBC4CAA844459E8B88B972473141" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies, in detail, all end-use monitoring the Government of Israel is subject to with respect to United States-origin defense articles; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B7CED5910864BD4908F948E0BE1FBF4" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analyzes the effects of offshore procurements on Israel’s military budget and domestic economy since 1991, including an assessment of the manner and extent to which funds provided for offshore procurement have directly or indirectly supported illegal Israeli settlement activity in the occupied West Bank.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

