<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC33FB71C35C14F1285D7708F894B8BAB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7642 IH: Generating Utility through International Disaster Expertise Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7642</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260223">February 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the recruitment and retention of specialized disaster assistance professionals by the Department of State.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B4ABE7B94A64711B544D22126C3DE76" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE9E805CE1EFA4042AC762B3BD9DAF3C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Generating Utility through International Disaster Expertise Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GUIDE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB22234CA95CD40A9A93BD71A35391B79"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization to recruit specialized disaster assistance professionals</header> <subsection id="HA1311D013A4F480CB204FD8367FAF6CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, acting through the Under Secretary for Foreign Assistance, is authorized to establish a program to recruit, train, and retain specialized disaster assistance professionals for the Bureau of Disaster and Humanitarian Response, to ensure that the Bureau has sufficient personnel with the skills and expertise necessary to plan, implement, and manage complex international disaster assistance operations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H851C19D4F36247F299545E082A48AC2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A specialized disaster assistance professional recruited, trained, or retained through the program established pursuant to subsection (a) shall have expertise in relevant matters including procurement, logistics, public health, nutrition, protection, engineering, and finance.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

