<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE42957BA9E2C494E981922DE234A056F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 967 IH: Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that European laws and regulations unfairly and unreasonably burden American speech and innovation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 967</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that European laws and regulations unfairly and unreasonably burden American speech and innovation.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the right to express oneself freely under the First Amendment to the Constitution is at the very core of democracy in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas labels like <quote>misinformation</quote> and <quote>hate speech</quote> are inevitably used by the powerful to censor critics and silence dissent;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas oversight by the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives has shown that the Biden administration coerced and colluded with social media companies to censor First Amendment-protected discourse related to elections and the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas both Meta and Alphabet informed the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives that the Biden administration successfully pressured them to censor First Amendment-protected content on their platforms;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the American people resoundingly rejected this censorship and reinforced fundamental free speech principles in the 2024 election;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the European Union, its member states, and the United Kingdom have enacted comprehensive digital regulations that violate due process, punish American companies, and censor legitimate political discourse;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas European digital censorship laws set de facto international standards for content moderation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas European and British officials have explicitly used these laws to target First Amendment-protected political discourse by and among United States citizens;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas European digital regulations impose significant costs on American companies, harming American workers and consumers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas European digital regulations violate the due process rights of American companies to administer fines and penalties that amount to targeted trade barriers against Americans;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas European digital regulations are designed specifically to target United States companies while leaving European competitors free from burdensome requirements; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas European regulations function as a tax on American innovators, distorting the free market and free exchange of ideas to fund Europe’s bloated welfare state: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H8D8335AC96034A3E9DD63B5B1072455D"> 
<section id="H32A886DE3BDD4C9BB3632B9E77388DB5" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HCDCFE21D79024B0DA1AFCAA76049A94D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses disapproval of the European Union’s Digital Services Act and Digital Markets Act, the United Kingdom’s Online Safety Act and Digital Markets, Competition and Consumers Act, and similar foreign laws;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9969C058434E4481A2956B7B6019069C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the Trump administration to use diplomatic and economic tools to protect the free expression rights of United States citizens and prevent foreign governments from undermining the freedoms enshrined in the First Amendment to the Constitution;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41CF2C53CC574C08836BEBFAFF73DBA4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the Trump administration to use diplomatic and economic tools to protect American innovation and prevent foreign antitrust authorities from harming United States consumers and companies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A2C316195F54AB4B12D474C04BEB380"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission to reject the antitrust principles underlying the European Union’s Digital Markets Act and the United Kingdom’s Digital Markets, Competition and Consumers Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11CFEFB1A2D54809BFC58B63D2733EA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>calls on the Department of Justice and the Federal Trade Commission not to cooperate with European governments in the enforcement of these or any other similar foreign antitrust laws.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

