<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26752-K09-T8-J25"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4629 IS: Government Bailout Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4629</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to State and local governments and school districts for payment of obligations, to prohibit the Federal Reserve banks, the Department of the Treasury, and other Federal agencies from financially assisting State and local governments and school districts that have defaulted on their obligations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idE1E8D2520D984B9788319F062100C692"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Government Bailout Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idD908DC6788EF43A7AA75652D00A0A41A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>State</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idAAED219EA647472092B3F455D8C2F5BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any of the several States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id92DC2F992BFE4822ADF9FACB62B6FBD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the District of Columbia; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id699C6E2E7321423CBA629DA015EB3808"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id9582748C11F04B68B8EB2DFC28B3F9FB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of Federal funds to pay or guarantee State and local obligations</header><subsection id="id2B3E640504E04CC595F7231A57BEA922"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be used to purchase or guarantee obligations of, issue lines of credit to, or provide direct or indirect grants-and-aid to, any State government, municipal government, local government, county government, or school district which, on or after January 1, 2026, has filed for bankruptcy, has defaulted on its obligations, is at risk of defaulting, or is likely to default, absent such assistance from the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="ID296be60133d94a539ec59e83736218f0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limit on Use of Borrowed Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall not, directly or indirectly, use general fund revenues or funds borrowed pursuant to title 31, United States Code, to purchase or guarantee any asset or obligation of any State government, municipal government, local government, county government, or school district or otherwise to assist such government entity, if, on or after January 1, 2026, that State government, municipal government, local government, county government, or school district has defaulted on its obligations, has filed for bankruptcy, is at risk of defaulting, or is likely to default, absent such assistance from the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="idCC0D84C4A8CC418AB19149C9192CAA6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal Reserve assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal Reserve bank may provide or extend to, or authorize with respect to, any State government, municipal government, local government, county government, school district, or other entity that has taxing authority or bonding authority, any funds, loan guarantees, credits, or any other financial instrument, including the purchasing of the bonds of such State, municipality, locality, county, school district, or other bonding authority, or to otherwise assist such government entity under any authority of any Federal Reserve Bank.</text></subsection><subsection id="IDcbc55ddddba9455986ede940c2d6dacb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Subsections (a) through (c) shall not apply to Federal assistance provided in response to a declared disaster.</text></subsection></section><section id="id9C85F99EC11C42BF80354A1582A33292"><enum>4.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The prohibition under section 3—</text><paragraph id="id33F28CBEBADF4A6B9DE447FB4587683F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes debt restructuring or any other related activity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0E9BE86778064E378AAF069251A5F87B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include—</text><subparagraph id="id11E481F930B34D0E8DFC8D3EE01058C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any discretionary appropriations or direct spending, as those terms are defined in section 250(c) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/900">2 U.S.C. 900(c)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id740D79FBF68A435FA8C23A5DE9E1A93C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any grant awarded by the United States to the State government, municipal government, local government, county government, or school district.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

