<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26236-PXY-FK-2KW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3944 IS: Women’s Heart Health Expansion Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3944</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260226">February 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize the WISEWOMAN program.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HDBBB2FDBBDB6448CB7189B47D975CB35"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC4B12D44D5464CF88991BE62BEF3A5D3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women’s Heart Health Expansion Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBD9471F18AD74FB5BBD165EA71D5908B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of WISEWOMAN program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1509 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300n-4a">42 U.S.C. 300n–4a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE74F89FFF83C407DB955CE326EFECF72"><section id="H5F3EF7CBB751494290E841192E7824E4"><enum>1509.</enum><header>Supplemental grants for additional preventive health services</header><subsection id="HF61DD76170814F59B979FC9B07EFED42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Screening and referral projects</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award supplemental grants to recipients of grants under section 1501 to carry out projects for the purposes of—</text><paragraph id="H48FE7152E122426D9C7D7617005AE62B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing preventive health services in addition to the services authorized in such section, including—</text><subparagraph id="H0157FFCF038F451BA0C6508F2B6E64F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>screenings regarding blood pressure, cholesterol, obesity, and other relevant risk factors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H805CB7E2762D46128A2D067A6B11EF08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evidence-based health education offered by a qualified provider to improve a measurable health outcome, such as blood pressure, cholesterol, diabetes, or obesity;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD3656B78195434CBE0F52D47B8A6050"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing appropriate referrals for medical treatment of women receiving services pursuant to paragraph (1) and ensuring, to the extent practicable, the provision of appropriate follow-up services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAA779A41376466093BD6221A1663B7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluating activities conducted under paragraphs (1) and (2) through appropriate surveillance or program-monitoring activities and reporting to the Secretary on such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB4392B0F209499C9E06F18B57BEB025"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility for services</header><text>Women eligible for services pursuant to a grant under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H32426C6BD473449789D97CD76E6107A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>women eligible for services pursuant to a grant made under section 1501; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4F1454134C54B91A3E59361D68FA821"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other women who are high-risk and meet such eligibility criteria as the Secretary may specify.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9A5AD4DDD4546B3883A0B38BFFA0A56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized providers</header><text>Health services provided pursuant to a grant under subsection (a) shall be provided by—</text><paragraph id="H2938AE3A27934E7DB6EE7910CF70CE8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an entity screening women for breast and cervical cancer pursuant to a grant under section 1501; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8344D5BC81241D18227AE9D3DF6CAD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other health care entities, as the Secretary determines.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFBF26E89D64741398AA40E8AF4626745"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $250,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id78010acdd5d24cfab62ec942b6cb83bf"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2027, the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives on the work of the Well-Integrated Screening and Evaluation for Women Across the Nation Program, including—</text><paragraph id="id695deeafb05648c6b0b1eff415f4e252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an estimate of the number of individuals eligible for services provided under such program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c10c9a542584f4480cf5d47b81811f0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of trends in the number of individuals served through such program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida325e98f827b4903b92393c558e5cbc4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of any factors that may be driving the trends identified under paragraph (2), including any barriers to accessing cardiovascular health screenings provided by such program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3296ce2096234374bb91bf0ce10a1ce2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of the cost-effectiveness of such program with respect to patient outcomes, such as blood pressure, cholesterol, diabetes, or obesity.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

