<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26359-4WL-MG-4CF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4243 IS: No Nuclear Weapons for Saudi Arabia Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a joint resolution of approval for the entry into effect of a civilian nuclear cooperation agreement with Saudi Arabia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H4D14F19BFD0D4B068E1DE51E5C0020D1"><section section-type="section-one" id="H94F3788E0A2248F59558534BA977CE68"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Nuclear Weapons for Saudi Arabia Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB83721CA62094B2EBAB0BA3EF4BD6277"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States should not approve a civilian nuclear cooperation agreement with Saudi Arabia until the Government of Saudi Arabia has renounced uranium enrichment and reprocessing on its territory, as well as agreed to an Additional Protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency.</text></section><section id="H477CFBFC9A034CC9ADD782AF9FF2263E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HFEE6A6D7669447BAA231E5B66B6EF494"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to oppose, through the Nuclear Suppliers Group, the sale of nuclear technology to Saudi Arabia, until the Government of Saudi Arabia has renounced uranium enrichment and reprocessing on its territory as part of a civilian nuclear cooperation agreement with the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0435B7A42A2456F93E4E745A03CAEED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to seek modification of the guidelines of the Nuclear Suppliers Group relating to the transfer of nuclear technology as applied with respect to Saudi Arabia, until Saudi Arabia has renounced enrichment and reprocessing on its territory.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H618F478399064E7BA5A7E637D3B5E708"><enum>4.</enum><header>Congressional approval required for civilian nuclear cooperation agreement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other requirements under section 123 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2153">42 U.S.C. 2153</external-xref>), a civilian nuclear cooperation agreement with Saudi Arabia may only enter into effect on or after the date on which each of the following has occurred:</text><paragraph id="H3105E5BA529B4131AE43589754A495F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The President has submitted a proposed agreement with Saudi Arabia in accordance with the requirements of such section 123.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5629D2F3CC2340C69D5EF8A70931DAB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In conjunction with such submission, the President has submitted to Congress a report that describes each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD7C179134AE54AE68BD2CBD901F6DE6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which Saudi Arabia has renounced uranium enrichment and reprocessing on its territory or will commit to renouncing such enrichment and reprocessing as part of the proposed agreement with the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA41C0262E32D461FA145C10641E61EFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether Saudi Arabia has agreed to sign an Additional Protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B3A40559AFC45929E322176FCDD82EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On or after the date of the submission of the proposed agreement and report required by paragraphs (1) and (2), Congress has adopted, and there is enacted, a joint resolution stating that Congress does favor such agreement.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

