<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD089A3F48CE14060AD09D60D3C7B099B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9210 IH: Block Lawless Agreements and Nullify Corrupt Handouts and Emoluments Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9210</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to establish certain requirements for compromise settlements between the President and the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4E0D73CC9760441FA4FA43AD99CFA812" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H85EC226A277746AAAD654EA95CAF3BCF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Block Lawless Agreements and Nullify Corrupt Handouts and Emoluments Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BLANCHE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H94B52046C83F485490E0D20F9757C819"><enum>2.</enum><header>Compromise settlements</header> 
<subsection id="HE1B85D5CA688427CA6FC1BF535060813"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/161">Chapter 161</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/2414">section 2414</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H181100B44FED4CE3AE44082179939921" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HD13E57686CCC47EC80695B8193CE61F8"><enum>2414a.</enum><header>Compromise settlements between the President and the United States</header> <subsection id="H68B9C0743D524285A3FDF2B439C66B66" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any administrative claim, civil action, or other claim against the United States filed by the President (including a claim or civil action filed by an individual who assumed the Office of the President while such claim is pending), a covered agreement resolving such claim or action may not be entered into, and no action pursuant to such covered agreement may be taken, if, pursuant to such covered agreement—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD7B65FDA1DBE4726A56FAD56637A0D27" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President (including after the President leaves office), or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5927FBBF7CB4449EAE90F30B9D564B85" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any third party, at the direction of the President,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">would receive any payment by the United States, in cash or in kind, including for damages, reimbursement, or attorneys' fees.</continuation-text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H787A171A6FA344E686933C26C1D5DB7F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Invalidity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any administrative claim, civil action, or other claim against the United States filed by the President (including a claim or civil action filed by an individual who assumed the Office of the President while such claim is pending), any covered agreement to resolve such claim or action is void ab initio unless such covered agreement is the subject of a court order giving it effect. A court of the United States may not issue such an order unless—</text> <paragraph id="H45B39DB7CE4348179793BD28B2F2AF9C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President, if no such civil action has been filed, files a civil action before the court and files the proposed terms of the covered agreement with the court; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H065A9D4852CD4581A61B2B360F3E4B33" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the court conducts a hearing on the proposed terms of the covered agreement, with presentation of evidence by the parties, and thereafter enters the order giving effect to the terms of the covered agreement, that includes explicit findings of the court that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0BA84EFE4DC4406BDB3AF9E01416602" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the parties to the action are adverse;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAE0AD0F34984764BDBE05BD3A6D2991" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the action was not brought to force a covered agreement with the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37070821BA45411EB5ED47528E2EAEB0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States made a good faith effort to explore available defenses to the claims at issue and has a reasonable legal basis for its decision to enter into the covered agreement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1ABF46338CE74C20B196BA0334691D56" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered agreement is not—</text> <clause id="HFB4241B55AA94348A72EAA1A647A82A9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collusive; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H18B98E037FEB4D8C8A2104F13B9FCF32" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the perpetration of a fraud on the court; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF35340F1D62D4388972C8AEBCFF99883" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered agreement is in the interest of justice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H492466D89AA44EDD926C9CB907A675C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered agreement defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered agreement</term> means any settlement agreement, consent decree, compromise settlement, or other agreement to resolve an administrative claim, civil action, or other claim against the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67E929A5A4EE47BEBC274E6DA54BE312" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply to any covered agreement between the President and the United States concluded before, on, or after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7877D6CD9BBC42218D06C42086780C94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/161">chapter 161</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item related to section 2414 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HFC45DD9091AE488882ECD10D3052FC97" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">2414a. Compromise settlements between the President and the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

