<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25C71-591-16-P1M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 572 ATS: A resolution honoring the service and sacrifice of United States Army Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard and United States Army Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar, who were killed in action in Palmyra, Syria, in a targeted assault against United States service members on December 13, 2025.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 572</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution honoring the service and sacrifice of United States Army Sergeant William Nathaniel Howard and United States Army Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar, who were killed in action in Palmyra, Syria, in a targeted assault against United States service members on December 13, 2025.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on the morning of December 13, 2025, members of the Iowa Army National Guard were conducting a counter-terrorism engagement near Palmyra, Syria, as part of ongoing multinational efforts to degrade Islamic State remnants;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during this engagement, a lone gunman believed to be affiliated with the Islamic State opened fire on United States and partner forces in a deliberate assault;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as a result of this attack, United States Army Sergeant William Nathaniel <quote>Nate</quote> Howard, age 29, of Marshalltown, Iowa, and United States Army Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar, age 25, of Des Moines, Iowa, both assigned to the 1st Squadron, 113th Cavalry Regiment, 2nd Brigade Combat Team, 34th Infantry Division of the Iowa Army National Guard, were killed in action;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a United States civilian interpreter also lost their life in this attack, and 3 other Iowa National Guard soldiers sustained injuries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Sergeant Howard and Sergeant Torres-Tovar were dedicated soldiers who served with distinction in defense of the United States and in the global campaign against terrorism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Sergeant Howard served over 11 years in the Iowa Army National Guard and had a deep commitment to his fellow soldiers and his mission, representing the very best of Iowa and the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Sergeant Torres-Tovar was beloved by his community and fellow National Guardsmen for his selflessness, professionalism, and commitment to service, and he joined the Iowa Army National Guard before his high school graduation ceremony in 2019; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the families, friends, and communities of Sergeant Howard and Sergeant Torres-Tovar have endured an immeasurable loss and continue to honor the memory of their loved ones: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id945430f9ed2049298fcf407049914630"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the memory, service, and sacrifice of United States Army Sergeant William Nathaniel <quote>Nate</quote> Howard for his dedicated service to his State and to his country as a member of the Iowa Army National Guard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id03a38068082f44f9be561a738e9bf88c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the memory, service, and sacrifice of United States Army Sergeant Edgar Brian Torres-Tovar for his dedicated service to his State and to his country as a member of the Iowa Army National Guard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0916e1ee717e4a5c97a1deb95f657cd3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>extends its sympathies, gratitude, and support to the families of Sergeant Howard and Sergeant Torres-Tovar, and to all others affected by this attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idce39431de5624436b6b6068a5715426e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the bravery and professionalism of the National Guard members and partner forces who responded under fire and cared for the wounded;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idae8d9fac23c246b688a3aed325b63277"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expresses profound gratitude for the swift actions of the United States and allied personnel on the scene who engaged the attacker and prevented further loss of life;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc82e68be83004d31ab9c11d48945addf"><enum>(6)</enum><text>condemns in the strongest terms the horrific terrorist assault targeting United States service members and civilians; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id021e336d10c94c82861cd709f511adf8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recognizes that the members of the National Guard and all volunteers who serve in harm’s way on behalf of the United States embody the highest ideals of duty, courage, and selfless service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94442bf97ed74e72a21789d23a78b58e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Secretary of the Senate transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa62c64a7ba747c79c7fd97645da6613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the family of Sergeant Howard; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84de1579fc9044729a0e983c71a191c9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the family of Sergeant Torres-Tovar.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

