<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A2015CBA3284FEEA645D71DC5DDD1CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7323 IH: Defense Technology Hubs Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7323</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260203">February 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to establish a network of regional hubs to foster innovation, collaboration, and rapid development of defense-related technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7EBB2331C2E04FA7B35401B22C68AE91" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDABEC392F2CC484C8F3D9F887997FC72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Technology Hubs Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4264727A60F642CB967B7C2B7CA3E556"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to enhance national security and technological superiority by requiring the Secretary of Defense to establish a network of regional defense technology hubs to foster innovation, collaboration, and rapid development of defense-related technologies to attract talent from across the United States.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF63FA52137B541FAAA58B8607F8A5478"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H23F7753684F947CDA70D3359936F503E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Anchor Federal defense institution</header><text>The term <term>anchor Federal defense institution</term> means a defense manufacturing facility, an institution of higher education that engages the Department on research, development, testing, and evaluation, or a military installation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBC71436F2C745A6B7C785A5077275AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defense technology hub</header><text>The term <term>defense technology hub</term> means a regional hub designated and supported under the Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3046AE03EF14C1BAC8861F2D7586E00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible consortium</header><text>The term <term>eligible consortium</term> means a consortium composed of universities, defense contractors, small businesses, nonprofit organizations, independent research entities, and State or local governments.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H926390B6844848FFAC6C5D336434B4A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Emerging technologies</header><text>The term <term>emerging technologies</term> means scientific and engineering advancements with potential military applications as identified by the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0177BACF4AFD463EA092DDB05C9430C6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Defense Technology Hubs Program established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H92A7D19ECA954828AF38608D8ADFA4FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Defense Technology Hubs Program</header> 
<subsection id="H3EB523EC89CD489E83E6D7E3E80BA1D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program required</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC85556586B0441D6A43E254627E111C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program to designate and support regional hubs focused on advancing defense technologies critical to national security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B0043A40562470394EB2CCA5CA11A0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The program established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be known as the <quote>Defense Technology Hubs Program</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF62C3C069AA940B3BF3F72D40131E904"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of defense technology hubs</header> 
<paragraph id="H7B9B7990C32B4F888D8793B8A7054CCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Solicitation of applications</header><text>Under the Program, the Secretary shall solicit applications from eligible consortia to be designated as defense technology hubs under the Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD964010A1ABD456BA8961B27715514C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submittal of applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A consortium seeking designation and support as a regional hub under subsection (a)(1) shall submit to the Secretary an application therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEB3695D88A04670B0A064D6EBF6338F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall select eligible consortia for designation and support under subsection (a)(1) from among those submitting applications pursuant to paragraph (2) of this subsection using the following criteria:</text> <subparagraph id="HFCFB7B0331974CA098D6A4DDCFA3B7DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Demonstrated capability in defense-relevant technology areas.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DDA6809DD4C447A880C3B49E16B9690"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Evidence of regional collaboration and stakeholder commitment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4E01C231769444B836150560364D282"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Presence of anchor Federal defense institutions or mission-critical installations of the Department that support or are early adopters of emerging defense technologies, such as geospatial intelligence, data fusion, artificial intelligence, autonomy, edge networking and computing, human-machine teaming, and quantum.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7321C25752074ACD97F06F555800AD7B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Existence of regional innovation ecosystems with demonstrated success in leveraging Federal, State, and private sector collaboration, such as technology innovation consortia, academic research clusters, and specialized defense accelerators.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3B9CD4DDC0D4B059A31E8126A8832C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Demonstrated success in developing partnerships and collaborative arrangements with local Federal defense institutions and mission-critical installations for the purposes of advancing research, development, prototyping, and transition of emerging defense technologies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3FACA53F57894D5EB39EAEC041D8A70F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Demonstrated success in developing partnership and collaborative arrangements with Federal defense institutions and mission-critical installations in workforce development and training programs to build a skilled pipeline for defense innovation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8EF8BF9CD0B34371BF5A872222854A98"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Potential to address Department-identified strategic priorities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7603995950FF4112B208EE08FB6343F9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Economic and workforce development impact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D5CCE5744284CACAD018E88F27DB0BB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header> <subparagraph id="HC4BEF1051B8047B880A3D3FF30639951"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting eligible consortia for designation and support under the Program, the Secretary shall ensure that defense technology hubs are distributed—</text> 
<clause id="H9E58CFCE02A94C309B38E0D696FF17E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>across diverse geographic regions of the United States, with a goal of designating at least 10 defense technology hubs before the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCDC2933E73B242498A51F8F572F98F4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to regions in which eligible consortia are co-located with, or readily accessible to, multiple facilities of the Department, including mission-critical installations, to maximize collaboration between eligible consortia and the Department of Defense.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8FD4570A02F74EE4ABCECD5AF11387B1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In considering geographic distribution, the Secretary may give preference to regions with demonstrated strategic relevance to national security missions, including those with newly constructed or expanded Department facilities and intelligence community investments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE66D8186F2941F2BD4400B88A683D17"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Objectives of defense technology hubs</header><text>The objectives of a defense technology hub under the Program are as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H94CB265246A0493E8621DFC7F06547C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To accelerate the research, development, prototyping, and transition to operational use of emerging technologies intended for military applications, such as artificial intelligence, edge networking and computing, quantum technologies, human-machine teaming, hypersonics, biotechnology, and advanced manufacturing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H220295A3B3BC405A9319082F4938C581"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To foster partnerships among components of the Department of Defense, private industry, academic institutions, and State and local governments.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC2E1618EB6649F395D4E530BFDE53F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To address regional defense technology needs while leveraging local expertise, infrastructure, and economic strengths, including proximity to Federal mission partners such as combat support agencies and participation in existing innovation consortia or university-industry alliances.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85681ACAC7BF49AB85FED71E46BAE7EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To promote workforce development and training programs to build a skilled pipeline for defense innovation including partnerships with research universities, community colleges, and vocational programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HACA388FD243E4D43A28E13BE0B7E728E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To enhance the resilience and security of the defense industrial base.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H194E6D793A1F4DD198A21D16C71E82B6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19FAC639725842A2B1EA1B724E9696A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, the Secretary may award grants to defense technology hubs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CC86230FD7F4DEFBB22009D92508EB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A defense technology hub receiving a grant under paragraph (1) shall use the amounts of the grant for the following purposes:</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA8E0512A5F245DFBA407B309D4BD75E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>As seed funding for establishment of the defense technology hub.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99F5E6C9463541BDB38DBD03B82CA8C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For research, prototyping, and technology transition projects consistent with the objectives set forth in subsection (c).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H549F29EB28444D59A3F0D23C73E6E1C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Administrative and evaluation expenses of the defense technology hub relating activities under the Program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4402235FA63B46089842F0574BEC9065"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Establishing and maintaining required security and compliance systems and functions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9090D093E97D4A1E88B67EF199FD1EC0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Security and compliance requirements</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2B401D6D853442F8DF48CD00AD47BA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, each defense technology hub shall do the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB7B0B4565BD547229514D7A055F2E9B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Implement cybersecurity measures consistent with Department cybersecurity standards.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5678F091E7064C2AA577229C6C3CC2E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ensure all research and technology transfers comply with the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (ITAR) and the Export Administration Regulations (EAR).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6429B3BDA72E45B692F9B3D3AEC62E64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Prevent participation by foreign entities of concern, as identified by the Secretary in coordination with the heads of the elements of the intelligence community (as defined in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>)) or identified in the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and set forth in Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, and consistent with existing Federal designations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B46A0C29F3F4F4C82E96E257E680B13"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Establish mechanisms to prevent unauthorized access to sensitive defense-related research and technology.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CA98D4AB2CC44EB80772C7569A74B74"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Establish necessary programs, infrastructure, and processes to sponsor, obtain, and hold security clearances for the purposes of enabling classified research, development, and prototyping of emerging defense technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76D435E28C3C4A8CB5BB4AE3E0851758"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monitoring and enforcement</header><text>The Secretary shall, in coordination with the Director of the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency, establish procedures to monitor and enforce compliance with the requirements set forth in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H99F2EA1CE4A74E6B999F4E043240F935"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Intellectual property management</header> 
<paragraph id="HBD9E4A24171741ECBFAF68E43D9BCBAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidelines required</header><text>The Secretary shall develop guidelines under the Program for intellectual property ownership and licensing within the defense technology hubs, balancing national security needs with commercial incentives for private sector participation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13AC8567C84842AC864045DAE74C2483"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retention of rights</header><text>The guidelines developed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include provisions for the Department to retain necessary rights for defense applications while allowing members of consortia that are defense technology hubs to pursue commercial opportunities as may be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF55CBE758A934EA6B7CB9E9C263AE5E4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header> 
<paragraph id="H343C505763DD4344906CC69965BA459F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense to carry out the Program $375,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4D9B1DE64AB4F418890A37214625033"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization in paragraph (1), $75,000,000 shall be available to the Secretary to award grants under subsection (d).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC056D2205074D9299EE0737C35E1EE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of support provided to a defense technology hub under the Program in a fiscal year may not exceed 50 percent of the total cost of the operations and activities of the defense technology hub under the Program in that fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H32324238D66140C29A949D7BBD336A03"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration</header> <paragraph id="H632C5ABAF41A47C0B7B7574713C7082F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall administer the Program through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Critical Technologies and in coordination with the Director of the Defense Innovation Unit and the heads of such other elements of the Department as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04B9A68F6BC6470BAF08B140E90DDB62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver of acquisition regulations</header><text>For any project of a defense technology hub under the Program that the Secretary determines has a total cost of less than $10,000,000, the Secretary may waive applicable acquisition regulations to expedite development and prototyping, consistent with similar authorities of the Secretary that were in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A40E62654F6482ABF74E6C5C998B48B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual progress reports</header><text>Each defense technology hub shall, not less frequently than once each year, submit to the Secretary an annual progress report detailing technological advancements, partnerships, and economic outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF097F1BEC4140F3A18212A0D5CEE0DF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Coordination with existing program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure the Program complements, and does not duplicate, existing efforts such as efforts of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), the Manufacturing USA Institutes, the Regional Technology and Innovation Hubs of the Economic Development Administration (EDA), the Defense Innovation Unit (DIU), and the Regional Innovation Engines of the National Science Foundation. The Secretary shall, as the Secretary determines appropriate, align defense technology hub activities with existing defense and intelligence infrastructure to maximize the use of established mission platforms and reduce redundant investments, particularly in areas where new Federal campuses are designed to serve as long-term anchors for defense innovation ecosystems.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H937BD663353F4EE6BE28137E4E1E7DEF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Evaluation and reporting</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE3553DFAB8174E19B1B676F7A8403DF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent evaluations</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into a contract with an independent entity to evaluate the effectiveness of the Program annually for the first 5 years of the Program, and biennially thereafter, assessing technology outputs, national security impacts, and return on investment.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F549D1A31CE4EE68796C6062D6C17A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives an annual report detailing Program activities, defense technology hub performance, and recommendations for improvement to the Program.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9763A7A543A64A1EB0B54AE2DEC60114" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

