<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBB21E976E6BD45D2B2C5277E186AA67E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7124 IH: Realigning Mobile Phone Biometrics for American Privacy Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7124</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of facial recognition mobile phone applications outside ports of entry, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0237DE0E176E4196B1AAB75BAAB73B29" style="OLC"><section id="HCCC6EBF69CEE4422B563AC653F24EBE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Realigning Mobile Phone Biometrics for American Privacy Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H07ACAB54E2B546F19EF7AA43C76C1071"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of facial recognition mobile phone applications outside ports of entry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop standards and guidelines for the Department of Homeland Security and its components—</text><paragraph id="HC964B4D348DA410E8ECC53F6DD4B5EF3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibiting the use of the Mobile Fortify Mobile Application, Mobile Identify Mobile Application, or successor applications, except for identification purposes at ports of entry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4271D3BCE903448AA81252B8F7377AF0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibiting the Department and its components from sharing the Mobile Fortify Mobile Application, Mobile Identify Mobile Application, or successor applications with any other Federal agency or any State, local, Tribal, or territorial agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D57059CCA8F4A419DBF96292216FB9E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requiring—</text><subparagraph id="HD21B4D51160D40418261ED643677AB08" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the removal of the Mobile Fortify Mobile Application, Mobile Identify Mobile Application, or any successor applications from Department and component information technology, except as necessary for identification purposes at ports of entry, in accordance with paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H400A4204E42B4E8BBA7600083D3A3E9A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department to remotely render inoperable any such applications downloaded on non-Department information technology;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0C5D21ADF74B438C288DF1853E7A82" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in paragraph (5), requiring the immediate destruction of any image, photograph, or fingerprint of any United States citizen captured through the use of the Mobile Fortify Mobile Application, Mobile Identify Mobile Application, any successor applications before such standards and guidelines are implemented, wherever such image, photograph, or fingerprint may be stored; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H063A4D6D42244C3EA611E02A15A39BB5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requiring the destruction of any image, photograph, or fingerprint of a United States citizen captured through the use of the Mobile Fortify Mobile Application, Mobile Identify Mobile Application, or successor applications for identification purposes at ports of entry pursuant to paragraph (1) not later than 12 hours after such image, photograph, or fingerprint is captured.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

