<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H220C7D967A7343F695CD3142C14A3BDF" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1123 IH: Recognizing the victims of the Happy Land Social Club fire in the Bronx, New York City, New York, on March 25, 1990, and designating March 25, 2026, as the day of remembrance of the Happy Land Social Club fire.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the victims of the Happy Land Social Club fire in the Bronx, New York City, New York, on March 25, 1990, and designating March 25, 2026, as the day of remembrance of the Happy Land Social Club fire.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Happy Land Social Club fire was an act of arson that took the lives of 87 people on March 25, 1990, in the Bronx, in New York City;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the fire was the deadliest in New York City since the Triangle Shirtwaist Factory in 1911 and the most horrific mass murder New York City had ever known until 9/11;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the 87 victims were trapped in the unlicensed Happy Land Social Club, located at 1959 Southern Boulevard in the West Farms section of the Bronx;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas most of the victims were young Hondurans, the majority of them part of the Garifuna-American community, as well as Puerto Ricans, Dominicans, African Americans, Americans, and other Latin Americans;</text>
    </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the tragedy exposed longstanding issues regarding building safety, fire code enforcement, and the need for stronger oversight of social establishments, prompting reforms that continue to protect lives today;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this human catastrophe exposed the need to strengthen fire safety regulations and building codes, including the requirement for automatic sprinkler systems and smoke alarms in nightclubs and other public assembly buildings;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it also prompted New York City to launch a comprehensive inspection and enforcement program to ensure that all existing and new places of assembly comply with the new safety regulations;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Happy Land fire left an indelible mark on the Bronx, shaping its collective memory and reminding Americans of the profound human cost when public safety regulations are ignored;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas countless first responders, community members, faith leaders, and families came together in the aftermath of the fire to offer support, comfort, and solidarity to those grieving unimaginable loss;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, decades later, the Bronx continues to honor the memory of the 87 victims, ensuring that their names and stories are never forgotten and that future generations remain vigilant in advocating for safety, dignity, and justice for all communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas from the ashes of this horrific event emerged the modern celebration of the Central American Parade and Festival, and the celebration of Garifuna Heritage Month; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas local events, including the annual Memorial Mass organized by Bronx Community Board 6, will be held to remember the victims of the Happy Land Social Club fire, and to educate citizens about the important role this tragic event played in the history of New York: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB3A708F5E247469AB466CCEC49AF87EB"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7E54F01D7C3645AF80AEFC381314829B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HAFE8D6DE008A44C5B62D8681BCF7B08E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of a day to remember the victims of the Happy Land Social Club fire;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15C7C308B85847C38E0DC8AB79BD4687"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solemnly commemorates the victims of the Happy Land Social Club fire, honors their memory, and expresses enduring solidarity with the families, survivors, and all those affected by this tragedy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17D7F22376D74AF5BF948AED964F1F5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms its commitment to strong fire safety enforcement, community protection, and the prevention of tragedies of this kind, so that the lives lost at Happy Land may forever inspire action that safeguards the well-being of all people.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

