<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC80EAF4F32C041C8BABDE17DCB3B35F2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1012 IH: Recognizing and honoring Cristina M. Rodríguez for her historic appointment as dean of Yale Law School.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1012</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and honoring Cristina M. Rodríguez for her historic appointment as dean of Yale Law School.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Cristina M. Rodríguez, the Leighton Homer Surbeck Professor of Law at Yale Law School, was selected to serve as the dean of Yale Law School by a search committee of distinguished law school faculty members in December 2025;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas she will assume the deanship on February 1, 2026, as the Sol and Lillian Goldman Dean and Professor of Law at Yale Law School, marking a historic transition in the leadership of one of the Nation’s most prestigious legal institutions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Cristina M. Rodríguez was born in San Antonio, Texas, earned her bachelor of arts from Yale College, received her master of letters from the University of Oxford as a Rhodes Scholar, and earned her juris doctor from Yale Law School;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Cristina M. Rodríguez was the first tenured Hispanic law professor at Yale Law School, trailblazing a path for future generations of Hispanic legal scholars;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Christina M. Rodríguez will be the first Latina and second woman to hold the position of dean at Yale Law School since its founding;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Cristina M. Rodríguez is a distinguished scholar who has authored more than 70 academic articles and essays on constitutional law, administrative governance, and immigration law, establishing herself as a preeminent thought leader in the legal community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Cristina M. Rodríguez is a principled leader and venerated educator who serves as a devoted mentor to her students;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Cristina M. Rodríguez’s distinguished career in public service includes serving as Deputy Assistant Attorney General in the Office of Legal Counsel at the United States Department of Justice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, Dean Rodríguez was appointed to cochair the bipartisan Presidential Commission on the Supreme Court of the United States, providing vital leadership on matters of national judicial importance; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the presence of experienced, highly credentialed legal professionals in leadership roles at academic institutions is essential to the integrity of legal education: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HDA7AC29CD7DD48FFBF40C05789060547"><section id="H0E2E0C1EE10E468EB8674036A2946FF3" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H8700773C08364CAEA5A417572064B5AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors Cristina M. Rodríguez for her landmark appointment as dean of Yale Law School;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49BF73B22601474F84BCE3594884F669"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the significance of Cristina M. Rodríguez becoming the first Latina to lead Yale Law School and the inspiration her leadership provides to the legal profession;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8659D5296594DEC8A4072DA68BE661B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges the importance of having leaders in academia who possess a deep mastery of the law and a commitment to public service; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6083198BC9E4D2DAD61822BAB379906"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages all law professors, following the example of Dean Rodríguez, to—</text><subparagraph id="H488381C0B3D24278935C53FED6818835"><enum>(A)</enum><text>invest in the success and mentorship of every student; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B8115EC89404A01B305EF7F8647DE91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>honestly and diligently teach the rule of law and the United States Constitution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

