<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5CFDD180E8694D4C8429B8691DD7923D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7797 IH: Toll Evasion Prevention and Plate Visibility Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7797</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide certain requirements and guidance relating to license plate readability, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H478E4216D0A245C89D1C63767192AF87" style="OLC"><section id="H4F4837D78128469F83DBA84D40BF99B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Toll Evasion Prevention and Plate Visibility Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8003118AA94748FF8D8CCC977A014142"><enum>2.</enum><header>License plate readability</header><subsection id="H65D09D40950B4885B7CEC609A4B25701" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on sale of products that impair readability of license plates</header><paragraph id="H835A2C77372E472383974FEA3B3398A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No person may sell, offer for sale, or facilitate the sale of—</text><subparagraph id="H5DA339A1ED07421A9A8310D53C4F1DC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a good that is designed or marketed to impair the readability of a license plate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD93D8947372D4D6AA02D760C4CA33611"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fraudulent, counterfeit, or altered license plate, including any plate that—</text><clause id="H45760A043B4E4EA3BF0C6F5CD26ADAB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>falsely displays registration information;</text></clause><clause id="HCEC18E9B6FC94CDE9BA5E5A67B3882C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>mimics or replicates a valid license plate issued by a State without proper authorization; or</text></clause><clause id="HAAD71EBA8F8D42B293D318B55739C221"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has been materially altered from its originally issued form to misrepresent vehicle registration information;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEA00936AFF3479385AA83C27EC933CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a year of manufacture license plate without authorization from the State in which such plate is intended to be used; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H555B506C2A1F44E58C133F1F6B01F222"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a legitimate license plate originally issued by a State without authorization from such State to engage in the sale of such plate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE433D573EC84156AD3EED37EC0DDB04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, a person who receives, holds, or otherwise transports a good or license plate described in paragraph (1) shall not be deemed to be a person facilitating the sale of such good or license plate solely by reason of receiving, holding, or transporting such good or license plate in the ordinary course of business.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H577B2911917B45148FB6EEDC78E0E734"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header><subparagraph id="HCA5A407ABB224F749169FEB26C8CE115" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this subsection or a regulation promulgated under this subsection shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94B5E4C94D8E40218BADC6CEE5C4CAD0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this subsection and the regulations promulgated under this subsection in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this subsection. Any person who violates this subsection or a regulation promulgated under this subsection shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FE4DE087C8048148875999F8882D874" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This subsection shall apply to a sale or offer for sale made on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12BC7C5B49034D608F79C6CFB94F8085" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission may promulgate, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, regulations to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H261ED942317F48FBA61EF2CFC1E1F95D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to preempt, limit, or otherwise affect the authority of any State or local government to enforce laws, regulations, or ordinances with respect to prohibiting or regulating the use, installation, or operation of a device that impairs the readability of a license plate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2697538E7334F0ABAA99B0DC0041D89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance on license plate readability</header><paragraph id="H9103D54A809942AEBF009EF660201D43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration shall work with industry associations, State motor vehicle agencies, tolling authorities, law enforcement, and other relevant organizations to publish advisory guidance relating to the readability of license plates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57973412BB434BDABB312CBE63307FC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In publishing the guidance under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H99F380A8630A42B69AA77A0E38392DF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>best practices with respect to the appearance of license plates that facilitates the use and increases the reliability of digital imaging technology in capturing plate information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H368A3FB808E2416C82BB88FB09804242"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information regarding license plate frames and covers that reduce the readability of such plate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8931D5FD3E8B46A7AC07DCE44F5EF4F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No interference with State programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidance published under this subsection shall be advisory only and shall not be construed to require States to modify existing license plate designs, specifications, or programs, or to adopt particular design standards or technical specifications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H639F5E97DA6045E5872EF7A17AFC7825"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant program</header><paragraph id="H0E441FEE33FA4A74A82A95E85792A232"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration shall establish a grant program to facilitate the use of information technology systems to identify vehicles that regularly evade tolls.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACE7ACED6B0D46E7B0354F4FB7EB464E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program established under paragraph (1), the Administrator may make a grant to—</text><subparagraph id="H87773177DC504C559101576E53066AFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A1CA3BD1CC946F6BAE6E3C522A50771"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unit of local government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDE812CB3E624AA39608D216DE8EAA95"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement agency of a State or unit of local government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46960AD9C24D47BB99B924E6A905391A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a multi-jurisdictional law enforcement task force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7831B3B18F354D669139FC95233257F1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a multi-jurisdictional organization representing State licensing agencies and law enforcement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8311AC48C4A47BD9F42E69B7123900B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an owner of a toll facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE20DEAA271C74933878C33B31A8216A8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the program established under paragraph (1), an entity described in paragraph (2) shall submit to the Administrator an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0485D78D844046939C76693DBACD8A08"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program established under paragraph (1), the Administrator may make a grant for—</text><subparagraph id="HD71C3E48729F431A8414383C326CDB6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development and implementation of information technology systems to identify vehicles that regularly evade tolls;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB22397DDB9094B0391B7041B10CA99E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training programs for law enforcement personnel on the detection and enforcement of license plate obstruction violations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FA034D14D0F4166BCAE4121692B0BF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data sharing systems that facilitate coordination between law enforcement agencies, State agencies, and owners of toll facilities in identifying repeat violators; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99E07453C90148D488E06F14059DE6D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other activities that the Administrator determines will enhance enforcement of laws relating to license plate readability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB56014B798C244378E4B7D8A0319F5F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

