<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC613E086A6D4761858AC7BFF80C7FC6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 828 IH: Supporting the designation of October 26, 2025, as the “Day of the Deployed”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 828</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251024">October 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of October 26, 2025, as the <quote>Day of the Deployed</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas more than 2,000,000 individuals serve as members of the Armed Forces of the United States, including the reserve components of the Armed Forces;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas several hundred thousand members of the Armed Forces are currently serving overseas in every region of the world;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas more than 2,000,000 members of the Armed Forces have deployed to the area of operations of the United States Central Command since the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, in the decades following the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks, members of the Armed Forces deployed in 2 major conflicts and countless operations throughout the world, and their service and bravery helped protect the United States from further terrorist attacks;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas the United States is kept strong and free by the loyal military personnel from the total force of the Armed Forces, which includes the active duty components and the reserve components, who protect the precious heritage of the United States through their declarations and actions;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas members of the Armed Forces have deployed to the Middle East to defend United States security interests, deter aggression, prevent the proliferation of nuclear weapons, and promote stability in the region;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas members of the Armed Forces serving at home and abroad have courageously answered the call of duty to defend the ideals of the United States and to preserve peace and freedom around the world;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas members of the Armed Forces are called upon to respond to an increasingly complex and wide-ranging set of global threats to the United States;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas the courage, professionalism, and sacrifice of these deployed forces represent the highest traditions of the United States military;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas the United States remains committed to easing the transition from deployment abroad to service at home for members of the Armed Forces and their families;</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas members of the Armed Forces personify the virtues of patriotism, dedication, courage, and steadfast service;</text> </whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas the families of members of the Armed Forces make important and significant sacrifices for the United States; and</text> </whereas> 
<whereas> <text>Whereas the Senate has designated October 26 as the <quote>Day of the Deployed</quote> since 2011: Now, therefore, be it</text> </whereas> </preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2D70FC3766C24C0387B2780487D17BF7"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0FB948A74CCD40F18506F8866E84B125"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4561116D34DB43A38CFF8F13063C2290"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for a <quote>Day of the Deployed</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F34E15A73A445B7B21447AF6181C218"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the deployed members of the Armed Forces of the United States and their families;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6938E98208ED4E458A922DEFEB3E28EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to reflect on the service of those members of the Armed Forces, wherever the members serve, past, present, and future; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EC8F0937A784B9C8515B0160996E84E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe the <quote>Day of the Deployed</quote> with appropriate ceremonies and activities.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

