<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA26377-NK3-3T-S7K"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4281 IS: Multilateral Alignment of Technology Controls on Hardware (MATCH) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4281</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260413">April 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for export restrictions on certain semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components therefor, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Multilateral Alignment of Technology Controls on Hardware (MATCH) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id096fde89eb5c403fb51ee4cbd57efde1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="id0125f55aecec4d0f8f1ebc8cad012e2a"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>export controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components represent one of the United States most effective defenses of this foundational technology;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idbb6322d3c9a149d18c1b749d72c1f34e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advanced computing applications like artificial intelligence are transforming military affairs and the balance of power;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1528608485104f6897b3cb36d484ddeb"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States and its allies have an advantage in the foundational technologies that underpin advanced computing applications, including advanced-node integrated circuits and the equipment and software required to design and produce advanced-node integrated circuits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idac210d03f86f41199a9e16afb3d8e322"><enum>(4)</enum><text>robust controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components have been a bipartisan priority across multiple administrations, reflecting a shared recognition that protecting America’s semiconductor advantage is essential to national security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbcd637242940445a9b04ce506a31023c"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the adversaries of the United States are exploiting gaps in the current export control regime;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5bfcebe88cb146aab0e67c2e813ba1e1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>certain entities, including ChangXin Memory Technologies, Hua Hong Semiconductor Limited, Huawei Technologies Company, Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation, and Yangtze Memory Technologies Corporation are engaged in efforts to produce advanced-node integrated circuits that are especially crucial for the Military-Civil Fusion efforts of the People’s Republic of China and warrant comprehensive export controls to prevent those companies from accessing items made with United States technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9ad69461a2b04b35a48696dfd052209c"><enum>(7)</enum><text>companies located in adversary countries that produce semiconductor manufacturing equipment are critical to adversaries’ efforts to overcome exports controls to develop advanced-node integrated circuit production capabilities, and such companies should not be permitted to utilize or benefit from United States or allied technology or components;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f318663571b444bb60439da48cd3c3d"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the United States Government should work closely with allies and partners of the United States to align export controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and components to prevent gaps in controls, reduce the risk of circumvention, and ensure a level global playing field; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf130256031d64bf6b622111d7b196ee1" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>securing a diplomatic agreement, including through the use of positive incentives to encourage adoption of these controls, is the best and most sustainable path to alignment.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id629276a7d75b433fa7404b558e402ef0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report and application of controls</header><subsection id="idc62fec6e268d4655b6b7de23a2307172"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identifying chokepoints</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the covered agency heads shall—</text><paragraph id="id06a94b4a2b924aaa9f3009323a6aad1c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>jointly conduct a review to identify all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment and all covered facilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7b922639d8a4ca29fdd358a10307aa4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall—</text><subparagraph id="idbaf8035d5ffa4be790dfe4fa9007c88c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of all such equipment and facilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca7f8e43b98f43808dd4dad503231836"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the public in the Federal Register when this submission has occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide62c2d13db744210b0b1936c3bbb0853"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Diplomatic engagement</header><paragraph id="idc13b758161994055935fdf7c946e10ab"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The covered agency heads shall prioritize and, upon the date of the enactment of this Act, immediately engage in diplomatic efforts to encourage the governments of allied supplier countries to adopt—</text><subparagraph id="id8bae600059714e6ba2a39b9e127eda78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>countrywide controls, or other policies that have the same practical effect as countrywide controls, on covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment that are subject to the jurisdiction of such allied supplier country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3f8f1e45f9f04ea2ae8329e9d018b423"><enum>(B)</enum><text>license requirements for the export of all applicable items to any covered facility and the servicing of all applicable items at any covered facility, with a policy of denying such license.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id50aa79334731427aacc7854e2ccf0b71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing on diplomatic efforts</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the covered agency heads shall provide a briefing to members of the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><subparagraph id="id108cba63880d42d794885f78cc514f3d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the status of diplomatic efforts to secure the adoption by allied supplier countries of the controls described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaf1dc2aeec0d4d4c8ec747ebb9b07761"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outlines and assesses positive incentives to encourage adoption of these controls; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbdfc213b8b5a4188adefe82531626a8f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifies—</text><clause id="id20a6404e20374dbd9b8b64d51d6de023"><enum>(i)</enum><text>countries that have not adopted the controls described in paragraph (1)(A);</text></clause><clause id="idb17f32c7843348eaa1cf7b4d3507804f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>countries that have not adopted the controls described in paragraph (1)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="id3b97156203e1469ea1b8bfd5c8841d04"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>measures that the United States has taken to implement the controls described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id246bf8d8fb584ed5986ae76cbe6c792e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application of controls and exhaustion of diplomatic recourse</header><paragraph id="id063177000ce04019a4b97bccc630c12b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of controls</header><text>Not later than 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall issue regulations that—</text><subparagraph id="id30357305371940789f1177fe889a139a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>apply countrywide controls to covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment produced in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2ac793b83f84184ac6147210a0ce395"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply comprehensive end-user or end-use restrictions to all covered facilities located in countries of concern.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idab5c0468bff04f1dab45068b8140711c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exhaustion of diplomatic recourse</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (4), for each allied supplier country, the covered agency heads shall jointly certify, not later than 150 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, to the appropriate congressional committees that either—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id694562ce56794b20b35749b3c6006995"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country has implemented—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9aa0c14da6f34327b34923188708df95"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">countrywide controls, or policies that have the same practical effect, on all semiconductor manufacturing equipment that is subject to the jurisdiction of the allied supplier country; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id483b1cee203849abafd2cae025ad66df"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">licensing requirements, with a policy of denying the license, for the export of all applicable items to any covered facility, or other policies with the same practical effect; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd156f54ae5c84222a043f657be7cdc1f"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idf7cf2abfc52140458c7c2f8823355417"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the country has not adopted the controls described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (b)(1);</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9370fe8e6cb4d1c96610fadeb9f1cbd" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered agency heads have prioritized and exhausted available diplomatic channels;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id57e66d86ac6246c6ad2ac51a4ac5683f" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such channels have failed to secure export controls from the allied supplier country that have the same practical effect as those described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (b)(1); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id354663869bd446d7af4b7c66e7b9b19f"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continued delay would materially undermine the national security of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf76ff936649042faba7f17cf302af279"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extension of controls</header><text>For each allied supplier country for which the covered agency heads submitted a certification described in paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall issue regulations that—</text><subparagraph id="id58ffcce48b444da086d1affb8dbe0f6e"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>establish jurisdiction over and apply countrywide controls, by directly controlling the equipment, indirectly restricting the end-use of essential components of such equipment, or both, to covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment exported from the allied supplier country;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe86097b7f134baebafa2687a4cf981b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require a license for the servicing of any applicable item that is also subject to the jurisdiction of the allied supplier country in any covered facility located in a country of concern and implement a policy of denying the license for such servicing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78e00fa8bf7840eaa13b6b037d4f880c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish jurisdiction over applicable items from the allied supplier country and apply end-user or end-use controls prohibiting the export of such items to any covered facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id77775444ed9e4357ac79a41ac52e2b90"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text>The covered agency heads may jointly grant a one-time waiver to extend the 150-day deadline for certification under paragraph (2) by not more than 90 days, if the covered agency heads, with concurrence from the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, jointly—</text><subparagraph id="id86f87865f77542aca614ec8e892eaf79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees describing—</text><clause id="id7a0dc89aed5b40548748550bbf841d74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>justification for why the deadline could not be met; and</text></clause><clause id="idc051f923f83348f9bd240044e13bdf0c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the interim steps the covered agency heads have taken to prevent stockpiling; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0bc4e9615bdb4f4e89d6c1cd32bbe1c8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determine and certify to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><clause id="ide8f1f3b85ffd4d39a0293ab08d275afb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extension is in the national security interest of the United States, despite the risk that countries of concern may take advantage of the delay to further stockpile covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment; and</text></clause><clause id="id9513250035c14da5b9c4ff7f05b55f53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the government of the allied supplier country is taking concrete, verifiable steps, pursuant to their domestic laws and regulations and as expeditiously as possible, to adopt and implement controls that have the same practical effect as, or are more stringent than, the controls that would otherwise be imposed under paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7239de917484475aa1950f8871b8e5ec"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the covered agency heads shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="idedbbc4cf866941e08921542b0186228d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of all covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda6e28aa81864e568fe7f738d6295337"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all entities that own or operate a covered facility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a6ca0597db2424f828e999593b721a5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the scope of the countrywide controls imposed by the United States and allied supplier countries on each covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment identified pursuant to paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59598c4884cd4417b17bfeef114080d6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a summary of diplomatic engagements and unilateral actions undertaken by the covered agency heads in the 12-months period prior to the submission of the report to close any gap among allied supplier countries in the countrywide controls imposed by such countries for covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd89055f09c7f4cac84791f443ff6f479"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a certification that the export of any covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment to a country of concern and the export of any applicable items to any covered facility, or servicing of any such item located in a country of concern, requires a license issued by the United States or an allied supplier country, with a policy of denying such license.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd7d5291fc597417c83a6d63fdfa59bea"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination and reimposition of controls upon allied action</header><paragraph id="idbfa6051bef514d96ba526fe59c28c275"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination or modification</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may terminate or modify any control imposed under subsection (c)(3) for items exported from an allied supplier country, if the country has established controls, including licensing policies, that have the same practical effect as those described in subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44a35b488ebd45fba7fb3fb10aa8ab52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimposition</header><text>If, after terminating or modifying a control under paragraph (1), the covered agency heads determine that the allied supplier country has materially weakened, suspended, or revoked the control that justified the termination or modification under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Commerce shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State and not later than 60 days after making such determination—</text><subparagraph id="id8cd02c51283d476dbfd2bce187d05dbf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of such determination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a115608f7fd49ae984d3136fb00d8c1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reimpose the control under subsection (c)(3) that was terminated or modified under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id55c8310d3c3a46a9a18c08b590d013c4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed as diminishing or superseding the authority of the Secretary of Commerce to control the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of items under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id5b755c045f704aeca8d47c8d5f128623"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id711b20e358bb418cad7ded8e07dd1c53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced-node integrated circuits</header><text>The term <term>advanced-node integrated circuits</term> has the meaning given that term in section 772.1 of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60eafbff4c4349279a4ac793f47b2f89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allied supplier country</header><text>The term <term>allied supplier country</term> means any country that—</text><subparagraph id="id994bf6e52458408fbbfe1c6b8d93961a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not a country of concern; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1e6436b15644c52befac96b8f2e2f94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is engaged in the production of covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida49142ec3bff4ee4b45a59154dec3c56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable item</header><text>The term <term>applicable item</term> means any item that is or can be made subject to the Export Administration Regulations, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40d14ee968f04809ad610e9125bd0f3c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States-origin item;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id494e21ac9ba542928409fc6ed0a95d72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a foreign-produced item that is the direct product of, or produced by plants or major components that are the direct product of, United States-origin software or technology subject to the Export Administration Regulations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id38709730f74a4d599828b254398af78f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a foreign-produced item with more than zero percent de minimis United States-origin content; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id49c17a20b35f4e22b1e4362818231955"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a foreign-produced item that contain United States-origin or foreign-produced integrated circuits that are presumptively designed or produced, directly or indirectly, with technology, software, or equipment that is subject to the Export Administration Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b19628c2b13438cae3a0a50ea94d307"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id01ced74edba14b938f8bd2d80a622617"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id48cf5b17797046c59fb61c702dcbaf4b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c1fba62c2d84c8d94a635142f1ba0cf"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Capabilities comparable to those of the product sold by the global market leader</header><text>The term <term>capabilities comparable to those of the product sold by the global market leader</term> means, considering cost, throughput, reliability, precision, and any other relevant factors, advanced-node integrated circuit makers headquartered outside of countries of concern, when selecting a tool for use in high-volume manufacturing, would be indifferent about using, or would prefer to use, the tool produced by the country of concern, rather than a tool sold by the company with the greatest share of the global market for tools used to accomplish the same function.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id70600f1fe253491196b5a49b662a772b"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58ea9ff27de04cc183fad7c18850f511"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Countrywide controls</header><text>The term <term>countrywide controls</term> means licensing requirements, with a policy of denying any such license, for the export, reexport, in-country transfer, or servicing of specified items to any destination within a country of concern, excluding exports where the destination is a fabrication facility that existed as of the date of the enactment of this Act and remains owned and operated by a company headquartered, and the ultimate parent company of which is headquartered, outside of any country of concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf48e551f477b490d93729169ba537473"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Covered agency heads</header><text>The term <term>covered agency heads</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, and the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4211a44e9a68406c83390c58ac0cf22a"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Covered facility</header><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id8af3f4eed5ab401aa2b5e8484ad2c205"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a facility engaged in the production of advanced-node integrated circuits which is owned or operated by an entity headquartered in, or whose ultimate parent company is headquartered in, a country of concern; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b750741b53b45d9a993824746b1ae6c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any facility owned or operated by, or in common ownership or control with—</text><clause id="idbb633d3ffd4c4c28801cafdc57e36db8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any entity referenced in subparagraphs (A) or (B) of section 5949(j)(3) of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/4713">41 U.S.C. 4713</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause id="id016a590fd6cd41a581626c3d7f25767f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Hua Hong Semiconductor Limited;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6e656b1fa674237ac66bf6721502055"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Huawei Technologies Company;</text></clause><clause id="id275d6d34dda948db9432d63d37504814"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any producer, manufacturer, or developer of semiconductor manufacturing equipment that is headquartered in, or the ultimate parent company of which is headquartered in, a country of concern; or</text></clause><clause id="id97da0a96991141cda4d532946e530db5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any entity that is a subsidiary, affiliate, or successor to, or has a joint venture, teaming agreement, joint development or research agreement, technology transfer or collaboration agreement, or other similar type of arrangement with an entity described in any of clauses (i) through (iv).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1729e9ca633544c3b057881275911f99"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment</header><text>The term <term>covered semiconductor manufacturing equipment</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id65b14637495f4c5699075bfcea610668"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means semiconductor manufacturing equipment or a component therefor that—</text><clause id="id514149d5a07243168ac3eaf0b56872ab"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an applicable item; and</text></clause><clause id="id430ecc9b4df74b85934598f0c8f7004f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the covered agency heads determine no country of concern produces in sufficient volumes and with capabilities comparable to those of the product sold by the global market leader, as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3371e10629a4397a1eeef83abff4a33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes, at a minimum—</text><clause id="id1b31c5c0ab7e4ae0bedf7e94e6686ecd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all semiconductor manufacturing equipment, materials, and software that, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, require a license for the export, reexport, or in-country transfer to any destination in a country of concern;</text></clause><clause id="id1fa0f4856a664f33aec021129999b11f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all deep ultraviolet immersion photolithography machines, through silicon via deposition and etch tools, cryogenic etch equipment, and cobalt deposition equipment; and</text></clause><clause id="id5bc9bc71738d4707ae46230cffba05a9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>all semiconductor manufacturing equipment or components specified in Export Control Classification Number 3B993 (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act) except any item the covered agency heads determine do not meet the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e2cb70964014dbbbf2736817f102e71"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Export; in-country transfer; reexport; export administration regulation</header><text>The terms <term>export</term>, <term>in-country transfer</term>, <term>reexport</term>, and <term>Export Administration Regulations</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 1742 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4efe6f2995864f98b2eca88f0b51e351"><enum>(12)</enum><header>In sufficient volumes</header><text>The term <term>in sufficient volumes</term> means in volumes sufficient to meet 75 percent of current demand from all countries of concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf1e84227c5514d9d81bf6477aa1aa99d"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Servicing</header><text>The term <term>servicing</term> means any servicing of equipment or components, whether in-person or remote, including installation, calibration, repair, overhauling, refurbishing, testing, diagnosing, updating software or firmware, training, field services, application support engineering, customization, technical assistance, process adjustments, troubleshooting, and transfer of industry best practices for maintenance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

