<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA947635A50594C40A1FB604801D8D2BE" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1124 IH: Supporting the designation of March 21, 2026, as “National Women in Agriculture Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1124</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of March 21, 2026, as <quote>National Women in Agriculture Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the United States proudly recognizes agriculture as one of the most impactful industries of the United States and acknowledges the countless women who help agriculture prosper both in the United States and abroad;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are more than 1,200,000 female agricultural producers in the United States, making up more than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the agricultural producers in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2022, farms operated by women in the United States sold $222,000,000,000 in agricultural products, accounting for 41 percent of the total agriculture sales in the United States for that year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to leading farming operations, women working in agriculture make a difference across the United States in various commodity and industry fields, including research and development, manufacturing, sales and distribution, agricultural education, agribusiness, and advocacy, which extend benefits to individuals across the globe through the international trade of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States recognizes that women are vital in fostering the next generation of the agricultural workforce by promoting science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and agricultural education and entrepreneurial and community initiatives by serving as mentors for the 4–H Program, the National FFA Organization, the Cooperative Extension System, and numerous postsecondary agricultural science educator programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2026 is the International Year of the Woman Farmer, highlighting and celebrating the vital role of women throughout agriculture globally;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas March is National Women’s History Month; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas female professionals, instructors, and leaders in the agricultural field should be celebrated for their efforts during National Ag Week, which takes place between March 15 and March 21, 2026: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0DCA36F2CE81484E99F05887B25DACAB"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE8E569AEAB5E459F8032FC95C1E74EF7"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HAA116A7C3B4A44C9A6FF5CC32A0EACAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Women in Agriculture Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05C62E4D4D8C4A04879BFAC949604738"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the important role of women in agriculture as producers, educators, leaders, mentors, and more; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC01E54C4DCA54077928FA1EAADA7E891"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages all citizens to—</text><subparagraph id="H20C7A752D9CD459196A7FB0C8011BA17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognize women working in agriculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD52C31EFB3A48BAA282C101FE1B2552"><enum>(B)</enum><text>praise the significant positive impact those women have on the food resources and the agricultural workforce of the United States by encouraging and empowering women to—</text><clause id="HADC8825EC71F4DB1B7692E02071E0F8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enter the agricultural field, which is a high-demand field of work;</text></clause><clause id="HB97ADC86CC3846338F176722DDB14A4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cultivate opportunities to lead; and</text></clause><clause id="H4280B2CA0B8A4E35B9C4C1ABA10C3778"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>feed a hungry world.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

