<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25B23-LVL-CG-F2R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 502 ATS: Recognizing November 2025 as “National Family Caregivers Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 502</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date>November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing November 2025 as <quote>National Family Caregivers Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, there were 63,000,000 family caregivers in the United States who provide essential care to millions of people each year, providing unpaid care worth an estimated $600,000,000,000 annually;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas family caregivers play a vital role in the healthcare system of the United States, supporting loved ones who have chronic illnesses, disabilities, and are aging;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas family caregivers, who are disproportionately women, often face significant challenges including financial strain, physical and emotional exhaustion, and social isolation; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas <quote>National Family Caregivers Month</quote> is an opportunity to recognize and appreciate the contributions of family caregivers of all ages and to advocate for policies that support family caregivers: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id16D5768BCA624BBDAC7208EF255B01C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes November 2025 as <quote>National Family Caregivers Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA10D592476AD4B20B4BB97248E53730B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the 63,000,000 family caregivers in the United States who provide essential care to their loved ones and chosen family each day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5BDE3D56F68249E6BF95BAE8C7CF47E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of the 2022 National Strategy to Support Family Caregivers as a roadmap to better support caregivers in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1393EE9B21824996AF017714D70022A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages all people of the United States to learn more about family caregiving and to support their loved ones and neighbors who are providing care. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

