<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H947C40DCC7FF410E92FE086FD4BA6DC9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6498 RH: Student Financial Clarity Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 395</calendar>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6498</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–461]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on December 9, 2025</action-instruction>
</action>
<action>
<action-desc><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to increase transparency in college tuition for consumers, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H45CD164DA5AE41C590D9B5D908184817"> 
<section id="H91E1E35B09904D82A7F3E2D76039AB17" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Financial Clarity Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2EB523D93A174AE28C184C4B6B0589B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transparency in college tuition for consumers</header> <subsection id="H5DAAA8AF75404F03B0A1918E374CA825"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 132 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015a">20 U.S.C. 1015a</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (a) through (j) and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block id="HC5D2919F5C0441D08B9C42EE4E30E6D3" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H50C1D1396F94452BB58A61F4B6EBC6D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC48899C9060B466FB4F9D30B9BFAFDFE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>College scorecard website</header><text>The term <term>College Scorecard website</term> means the College Scorecard website required under subsection (b) and includes any successor website.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F73F32325424F4E979CBE4423923162"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost of attendance</header><text>The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given such term in section 472(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16DC73070801437E896A915FD74EA1A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required costs</header><text>The term <term>required costs</term> means the sum of all the items listed in section 472(a) that are required by an institution of higher education for a program of study for the program length of a program of study, for the time to credential for a student, or for an award year of a program of study, as applicable, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2381C190362145888E124BD60BC8EC1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the tuition and fees normally assessed a student enrolled in such program of study carrying the same academic workload, as determined by the institution; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0B2B4983100481987854C909580800F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which the institution requires a student to reside in institutionally owned or operated housing or to use institutionally owned or operated food services, the applicable standard allowance for such housing or food services determined by the institution in accordance with section 472(a)(5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5635611DA8C54A58B3E0C484360A57D0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Amount of grant and scholarship aid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>amount of grant and scholarship aid</term> means the sum of all of the grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for the program length of a program of study, for the time to credential for a student, or for an award year of a program of study, as applicable, that a student does not have to repay, including need-based, merit-based, or athletic-based, or another type of grant and scholarship aid, that is—</text> <subparagraph id="HEAA28F90E486408A913C0A845BDEC970" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offered under title IV;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB03A78F763B643BE8E993204BB098175" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offered through other Federal programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6900559138834795A903FCDE243E33C1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offered by the institution;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H997004A96176466D8004A20237C01A8F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>offered by a State; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A6AFBF516DB49158C88504F5EE13A60" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>offered by any other source.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7609E80AD3FA4E11BD77E8EF458A1F3F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Net price required for completion</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1BC85ADA1C9E493C8BBD41DF954EC51A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Total net price required for completion</header><text>The term <term>total net price required for completion</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study—</text> <clause id="HF425767645184EE0A6E24B748D0E0155" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the required costs charged to such student for the program of study for the time to credential; minus </text></clause> 
<clause id="HC392F7DB9D384B179CD91D8F2273DFE1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for such program for the time to credential.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF870E04FF3D842EA97E29AB84A7D4C42"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual net price required for completion</header><text>The term <term>annual net price required for completion</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study—</text> 
<clause id="HEC886D86864D46F68B2255CDEF00B949" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the required costs charged to such student for the program of study for an award year; minus </text></clause> <clause id="H4D3F93D45B3C45098682371E3A35174A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid that is available to the student for such program for such award year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EB485488D474D078F30CB5528F288EF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Net price of attendance</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE8A966CF86F9453394D95F9418DB9541"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Total net price of attendance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>total net price of attendance</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study, the sum of—</text> <clause id="H1D93B125191A49B6B9C6DCFFE22C240D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total net price required for completion; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB72EAE162572488B8772BB905435AB2D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sum, for the time to credential, of all the costs listed in section 472(a) that are not required costs.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19B8DEF2B1E04313ABEA3C10E5F047E6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual net price of attendance</header><text>The term <term>annual net price of attendance</term> means, with respect to a student in a program of study, the net price of attendance for a specific year of the program of study, determined by disaggregating the total net price of attendance for the student by each year of the student’s time to credential.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01F2EF01E1584D19BE23B7AA964C3498"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program length</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program length</term> means the minimum amount of time in weeks, months, or years that is specified in the catalog, marketing materials, or other official publications of an institution of higher education for a full-time student to complete the requirements to obtain the degree or credential awarded for a specific program of study.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE31C25CF05C46C2912947245284AB6F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Time to credential</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>time to credential</term> means, with respect to a student, the actual amount of time in weeks, months, or years it takes the student to complete the requirements to obtain the degree or credential awarded for a specific program of study.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6148F60F3E414C169B75706EC05ED0DF" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consumer information</header> 
<paragraph id="H721DB8606EF244648C0A4ED792D73638" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of information for title iv institutions and programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the effective date of this subsection, the Secretary shall make publicly available on the College Scorecard website the following information with respect to students of the institution who have received Federal financial assistance described in paragraph (2)(I), for the most recent award year for which such information is available:</text> <subparagraph id="H0B939AD291FE4043AD6C63AAA101B470"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each institution of higher education that participates in a program under title IV, the following:</text> 
<clause id="H16A8EFD0081C4A599B2FAA849CAE61F4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A link to the website of the institution.</text></clause> <clause id="H4613B4990D024943864A2989267D3A90" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A link to the Universal Net Price calculator described in subsection (c) and, if applicable, a link to any net price calculator developed by the institution in accordance with paragraph (7) of such subsection.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6DC381CD09C74C23B2522DEEA722DE33"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the type of institution, including predominant and highest credential awarded, research intensity, and programs of study offered.</text></clause> <clause id="H5BA8BB5609E542D38B9743862A9A9AB9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution that requires scores for a college entrance examination (such as the SAT or ACT) to be submitted, data on such submitted scores.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7B184423AF204279A4604F720CEF0C45"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The acceptance rate, determined by calculating the percentage of individuals who submitted a completed application to the institution who were accepted for enrollment.</text></clause> <clause id="H9C1EE091DC96498B8291BA6B0386592A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution’s cohort default rate, as defined under section 435(m).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H798FD876313F4824A10EA0465C519FF5" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A link to the website of the institution containing the information on campus safety required to be collected under section 485(i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E4801E18AA548149052FEFE1B9C8480"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Institutions and programs of study</header><text>With respect to each such institution and to each program of study at each such institution, the following:</text> 
<clause id="H6818BE8E03394D9E85947A912CEAECE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The geographic location.</text></clause> <clause id="HB72352F9912C4C1B8A88353FD6B131CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Information on student enrollment, including the number and percentage of students enrolled full-time, less than full-time, and enrolled in distance education.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE86272BB12F4EDE99D1CB4467A04A12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the number of degree- or certificate-seeking undergraduate students who have transferred from another institution.</text></clause> <clause id="HA3A5531D64794472A88188CA1295C768"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Information on student progression and completion, including time to credential and rates of withdrawal, retention, transfer, or completion.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H020CB0DC85474CA4A2E9455E5F7F735A" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Information on college costs and financial aid, including—</text> <subclause id="HDAEE3F71D3E541F0BA21BF5C3D7E85F0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average, median, minimum, and maximum values of—</text> 
<item id="HC1CC643B22234DC9AED1D6EB8BFC273E" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the required costs for such award year (determined for an institution based on the required costs for all programs of study);</text></item> <item id="H43498F5EC0074D2BA589A738BB4FE4F8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of attendance for such award year (determined for an institution based on the cost of attendance for all programs of study);</text></item> 
<item id="HFAA0313B4BD548898EB541F33EC85938" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid received by students for such award year (determined for an institution based on the amount of grant and scholarship aid received by students for all programs of study);</text></item> <item id="H7676B38B1A914D8C89274B62A28ABE69" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information described in item (cc) and subclause (II)(cc), disaggregated—</text> 
<subitem id="H56D5681CED784BC380F0FD8A57893DF9" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>by the type of source described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of subsection (a)(4); and</text></subitem> <subitem id="H92D4416170E542A7957FCC6CDD36AEE8" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>by whether such aid is need-based, merit-based, or athletic-based, or is another type of aid; </text></subitem></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H55AF542D3C484A4F88DE55B552CAB424" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to students who completed a credential during the most recent award year, the average, median, minimum, and maximum values of—</text> <item id="H9FDDFD3321AC4637925A1E06EBD65D48" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the program length (determined for an institution based on the program length for all programs of study);</text></item> 
<item id="H68E4ED57974D447DB2EBF02D81FC3DE5" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the time to credential (determined for an institution based on the time to credential for all programs of study);</text></item> <item id="HC4A75E62279A401CB2520775CC98B35A" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of grant and scholarship aid received for the time to credential (determined for an institution based on the amount of grant and scholarship aid received by students for all programs of study);</text></item> 
<item id="HC4C09E4DEEAB4BE68FD69573B1F1A678" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the total net price required for completion (determined for an institution based on the total net price required for completion for all programs of study); and</text></item> <item id="H359D8D35B0CC4559992344742BCC618E" commented="no"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the total net price required for attendance (determined for an institution based on the total net price required for attendance for all programs of study);</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAC1B41DCA2364C96B2686CD7D1FD01BB"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of students receiving any amount of grant and scholarship aid for such award year, and with respect to students who completed a credential during the most recent award year, the number and percentage of such students receiving any amount of grant and scholarship aid for the time to credential;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4A37B1FBF8BA47A6ADC65A7EA87407F6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average annual percentage change and average annual dollar change in the required costs for each of the three most recent academic years for which data are available; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2D9039ED29554A31B2C9727B57FA7B59"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average annual percentage change and average annual dollar change in the total and annual net price required for completion for each of the three most recent academic years for which data are available.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H46518CD87368407EA9A3594ECDD739FE" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Information on student debt and repayment, including—</text> 
<subclause id="HD8F469944E6A45928D3D5604305CAE60" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average, median, minimum, and maximum amounts borrowed by students under title IV; </text></subclause> <subclause id="H5740148AD1854EEDA89DA9FDFD140D1F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information with respect to repayment of loans made under title IV, including borrower-based repayment rates, dollar-based repayment rates, and time spent in repayment; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H78F150AFB2864178A014FBC8DA155418"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the number and percentage of students who—</text> <item id="H26691F0E70BA4562B16017EF53EA558D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>are borrowers of a loan made under title IV;</text></item> 
<item id="HFF1B577864934A65B64CFEAADCB62386"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>are not borrowers of a loan made under title IV, but have at least one parent who is a borrower of a loan made under title IV on behalf of the student; and</text></item> <item id="HF5039E4E8C374A81801E69CB33B121AF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are borrowers of a loan made under title IV, and have at least one parent who is a borrower of a loan made under title IV on behalf of the student.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H01C30ED596FD4B748A064371482FF01B" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Information on the earnings of students, including the average, median, minimum, and maximum values of— </text> <subclause id="H041233DF9AE44F92A29450BBF9D6AFB5" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to students who complete a program of study in the most recent award year for which data are available—</text> 
<item id="H2E5CA1EA3B4E415DB2604ED6E4509267" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the annual earnings of such students; and</text></item> <item id="H493900D6FDC7468ABAA38FD1A432FB48" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the value-added earnings (as defined in section 481(b)(3)(A)(iv)) of such students; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H55BB8586055B4648AAC67CE6FA705B35" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the annual earnings of students who were enrolled in a program of study at the institution during the most recent award year for which data are available, and who at the time the information is reported—</text> <item id="H03418AC73FE64186A50EB3350FEC16A9" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>have not completed such program of study; and </text></item> 
<item id="H7B2D4A3944D94ECBA6E64D7A62FEEC1A" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not enrolled at the institution in any program of study.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88EAEE7097D245CF896CE402BBA45D9A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Programs of study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each program of study at each such institution, the credential awarded for completion of the program of study.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9553D4EC666C467E9B11736B168EEB61" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disaggregated information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure the information described in paragraph (1) is disaggregated, as applicable, by the following student characteristics: </text> <subparagraph id="H0C1974C1AA0244ED8AEC08A3A594387E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Financial circumstances including—</text> 
<clause id="HF8BABF5863D446F58334B207BD811025" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>household income categories, as determined by students’ and families’ adjusted gross income; and</text></clause> <clause id="H08C9CF3FCF41401C952552E14D121D77" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>student aid index categories, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74D61F34368D448DBD4D917FE931BCF9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Sex.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H38D07D1DDB1B41699A0ECA756D366618" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Race and ethnicity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H915EC2C498EC4C38B23C7AE69D993320" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Classification as a student with a disability.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H960F30B482844AB9B28A438C6033BC59" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Enrollment status, including part-time or full-time enrollment, and status as a distance education student.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5FBBC85D86FB4A06BDBEBC16518FD2F7"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Status as a first year, second year, third year, or subsequent year student, based on the number of years a student has been enrolled at the institution or in the program of study, as applicable.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EA3D88407A441DF9F4A0CF4A2DB9EA9" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Status as an in-district, in-State, or out-of-State student.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F675471D24448AEA4A69590C67A8A26" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Status as an international student.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF884E07A3834E3D9FA4E2F52807EB95" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The type of Federal financial assistance received, including—</text> 
<clause id="H2E371ACA318F4AB9A7BDEB761554CCA1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Pell Grant;</text></clause> <clause id="H2186606633E24E3FBCFD0CD5D5E3DDB7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a loan made under title IV; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDF99245BC0E941E08D5106AC676214E3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assistance described in section 131(f)(4) administered, sponsored, or supported by the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACC2E69FD2414390BE16AE2D559E42E6" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Status as a participant in a program described in section 116(b)(3)(A)(ii) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(3)(A)(ii)</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H812EDF52FA7B459C91BD99B5CF12FB1E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Comparisons; access; privacy</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the College Scorecard website—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D5A5E3CBFD6436F9AA88175B33813CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes a method for users to easily compare institutions and programs, including in a manner that allows for such comparison based on—</text> 
<clause id="H2EF8213DA9A74F41A20E40A616F47DFE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the institutional and program information described in paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="H85639F36625344829C0FE95DEBAD95DD" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the student characteristics described in paragraph (2); </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48250DBBE4B5460888783206652E971E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides access to information in an electronic and downloadable format; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA41F2B3A883F416FB575E33BFC359989" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>complies with applicable Federal privacy statutes and uses appropriate statistical disclosure limitation techniques necessary to ensure that the data released to the public cannot be used to identify specific individuals, including with respect to disaggregated information under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2197E122A60B4C5B978995E84C3D4164"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual updates; adjustments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1DB3563DB439406B8EAA14189B0834B3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual data</header><text>The Secretary shall annually update the data on the College Scorecard website required under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF11A937603C418CBF3B8D14E05D8772"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustments</header><text>The Secretary may adjust the data required under subclauses (IV) and (V) of paragraph (1)(B)(v) using the Consumer Price Index if the Secretary determines such adjustment is necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE30578BC8A0A4D1BA5AD9551CD93B184"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner for Education Statistics shall continue to update and improve the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System (referred to in this section as <quote>IPEDS</quote>), including the reporting of information by institutions and the timeliness of the data collected. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAC9AE9FD5B6147768245E5AF78ACEB87" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Universal net price calculator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text> 
<paragraph id="HFE2DD0B0C5A3402BB3ED080E3E759BC5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the effective date of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish, on a dedicated website of the Department, a Universal Net Price Calculator that—</text> <subparagraph id="H3649EB5322E241E2A43B3A4956AACC41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allows an individual to select one or more institutions of higher education and one or more programs of study offered by each selected institution for which estimates shall be calculated;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H241C17A1D76946D3A58D7273240C1370"><enum>(B)</enum><text>makes available to the individual, with respect to each selected institution and each selected program of study, the individual’s—</text> <clause id="H78F57BE76520404BBBE355468360787E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>annual estimated net price required for completion for each year of expected enrollment based on the program length of a program of study, based on the average annual net price required for completion for similarly situated students (based on the individual’s information described in subparagraph (C)(iv)) for such institution or program for the most recent award year, adjusted in accordance with clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (C);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H552269B8FFB84CD8920E7E347EAD80F3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>total estimated net price required for completion equal to the sum of the annual estimated net price required for completion for each year described in clause (i);</text></clause> <clause id="H92557C24B3254469B6405A8F45E497EA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annual estimated net price of attendance for each year of expected enrollment based on the program length of a program of study, based on the average annual net price of attendance for similarly situated students (based on the individual’s information described in subparagraph (C)(iv)) for such institution or program for the most recent award year, adjusted in accordance with clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (C); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA20D5784FE87435CABE0BED9AA3A456E" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">total estimated net price of attendance equal to the sum of the annual estimated net price of attendance for each year described in clause (iii); </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92A57C54BEAB48B4AAB099210201396C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to calculating net price estimates as required by <internal-xref idref="H241C17A1D76946D3A58D7273240C1370" legis-path="(c)(1)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>—</text> 
<clause id="HDFDFC6FF23FA48B0B2C282B6A38408BE" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determines an estimated annual percentage change for each year for which a net price calculation is made, based on the annual percentage change in an institution’s or program’s required costs and other costs under section 472(a), as applicable, for the most recent three-year period for which such data are reported;</text></clause> <clause id="H632D82518B8F473CB30EF92051AA816B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides the individual with the option to replace the estimated annual percentage change described in <internal-xref idref="HDFDFC6FF23FA48B0B2C282B6A38408BE" legis-path="(c)(1)(C)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> with an alternative annual percentage change specified by the individual;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC887A80AB6DB46A5B85FAB0D7B21D35C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an institution that offers a multi-year tuition or net price guarantee program, allow the individual to have net price estimates calculated based on the provisions of such guarantee program; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8019CE455F544DADA4B66148952DE0D5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses the individual’s information, based on—</text> 
<subclause id="H9A229649614749089868B0730BCABE64" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the single set of questions developed by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2); </text></subclause> <subclause id="H297207B02698499E9FBB6B86EBD228B1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the student-level data elements reported by institutions in accordance with section 668.408 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations); </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD57188D67DC343B1B87A7349D1BDF6AE" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of an individual who submits a Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483, the contents of such application; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC73C6DD707254CD2B545AA8235AE7E06" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional information provided by the individual with respect to the individual’s grant and scholarship aid;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE9DE954022894F48B472512C33DFC493"><enum>(D)</enum><text>includes a method for users to easily compare institutions and programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9789742B9A6B44AEA3C3A110AEA72042"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides access to information in an electronic and downloadable format.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A9BE0E4A0E74BF6AD1785EBBF32C3D6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of input questions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop a single set of questions for purposes of capturing the information specified in subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H090D2581AA874096B3B4972EF17F3488" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates</header> <subparagraph id="H5ED9664A7BBE40D5959156947D7038B0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Data</header><text>The Secretary shall update the data on the Universal Net Price Calculator Website, as required under this subsection, not less than annually.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BC1AB65FB6F4FB2A572F95541044985" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Technology and format</header><text>The Secretary shall regularly assess the format and technology of the Universal Net Price Calculator website and make any changes or updates that the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAA6A8468F0C40EAB7A0700A9F9EACE0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Integration with other Federal financial aid resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with subsection (d)(5) of section 483, the Secretary shall ensure that a website link or other means of accessing the Universal Net Price Calculator is included on the FAFSA website (or similar successor website).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93CC7239079041B98137FFF3C15BF860" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with each appropriate head of a department or agency of the Federal Government, shall ensure, to the greatest extent practicable, that any information related to higher education that is published by such department or agency is consistent with the information published on the Universal Net Price Calculator website.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE8C2FEF353E4F2483B5FAD2374B6F26" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consumer testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing and maintaining the College Scorecard website and the Universal Net Price Calculator website, the Secretary, in consultation with each appropriate head of each appropriate department and agency of the Federal Government shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB15211FA68014A25A6956E64E0BF3CB0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 6 months after the date of the effective date of this subsection, and not less than once every 4 years thereafter, conduct consumer testing with appropriate persons, including current and prospective college students, family members of such students, institutions of higher education, and experts, to—</text> <clause id="HCBBF39825EA54613B9EC7568637743B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve the usefulness and relevance of the College Scorecard website, with respect to the presentation of the consumer information collected pursuant to subsection (b); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC78038240A4F4542ADA6ED9989B4754B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that the Universal Net Price Calculator website is usable and easily understandable and provides useful and relevant information to students and families; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A778536A9E74307A406128B9D58525F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>display prominently on such websites in simple, understandable, and unbiased terms for the most recent academic year for which satisfactory data is available, the categories of information described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) and paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection that were determined to be useful and relevant to students and families based on the consumer testing described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BCEFC4260904D4986D8F0830DA6AC63" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Use of net price calculator by institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date on which the Secretary makes the calculator developed under <internal-xref idref="HFE2DD0B0C5A3402BB3ED080E3E759BC5" legis-path="(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> available to institutions of higher education, each institution of higher education that receives Federal funds under title IV shall make publicly available on the institution’s website a net price calculator to provide to current and prospective students, families, and other consumers a student’s individual net price estimates at such institution of higher education. Such calculator may be a net price calculator developed—</text> <subparagraph id="H0EF56130C20649D8B371BAFC4F5F98F1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by the Department pursuant to <internal-xref idref="HFE2DD0B0C5A3402BB3ED080E3E759BC5" legis-path="(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0180D72BB6BD4505B2F89C00C2D3ED86" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by the institution of higher education, if the institution’s calculator includes, at a minimum, the same data elements included in the calculator developed under <internal-xref idref="HFE2DD0B0C5A3402BB3ED080E3E759BC5" legis-path="(c)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8FD814784C45437C8B4E5F50B338DCB0" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>A net price estimate calculated for an individual using the Universal Net Price Calculator under this subsection shall be accompanied by a clear and conspicuous notice—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HADAEAB31081542388520003F8B8E4FDF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stating that the estimate—</text> <clause id="H529BEB91B75F41ADBA6AEBD0033848B5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not represent a final determination, or actual award, of financial assistance; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HCF3D4DD92C1E474B898028BEE3BFFD97" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be binding on the Secretary, an institution of higher education, or a State; and </text></clause> <clause id="H6FAF7A789BFE4F579072F87362FCB119" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may change;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H614EAB93BDA342F881385454FD2AF5D7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stating that an individual must complete the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483 in order to be eligible for, and receive, an actual financial aid award that includes Federal grant, loan, or work-study assistance under title IV; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BC2806331B24EB396684DC63917524A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>including a link to the website of the Department that allows individuals to access the Free Application for Federal Student Aid described in section 483; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEEDB6C1E269641B396D28A4959145331"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">explaining that the net price estimate calculated for an individual using the Universal Net Price Calculator under this subsection may differ from the net price calculated for such individual using an institution’s net price calculator due to differences in data or methodology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4277F92C093441A3B77CDFA18921746D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 132 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015a">20 U.S.C. 1015a</external-xref>) is further amended by redesignating subsections (k) and (l) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7F61E9D2C6844280830DBEE3B37169CD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Other amendments</header> 
<subsection id="H640291CB81BE48198955F7C9AD35AECC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cost of attendance of a program of study</header> 
<paragraph id="H5F1F3959D6B24064983EC64AB60E0A9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of cost of attendance of a program of study</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDF520E3894E24472BAFD863635A62F44"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 472(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <clause id="H4C1DA67521AB4238AC1FA425256C9B1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>carrying the same academic workload</quote> and inserting <quote>enrolled in the same program of study and carrying the same academic workload</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H43D090867D724562876363C18CFEB700"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>same course of study</quote> and inserting <quote>same program of study</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2A1E429C5E8842AF855E98548258421B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking <quote>program</quote> and inserting <quote>program of study</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C9F887B0DD04B72B954346A1C814C00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Section 472(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H19B78532E0414DD0961A0ED5B48D15E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>of each program of study at the institution</quote> after <quote>cost of attendance</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9874023A0AD346F1816005E77B028BE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of the institution</quote> and inserting <quote>of such programs of study at the institution</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H66FB9575407B4C51961C6BF10D5C333F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program of study defined</header><text>Section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H494CE112956D4D678CA683F9D36F382F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (15) through (24) as paragraphs (16) through (25), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H307B86B4CDE34D4B9662C99050383E30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (14) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H76F548CFBD5F48EE868E7538B21A8277" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H66D820AD290248948E9CAC1441641D33"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Program of study defined</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFEBD5A3EE4B94DA4B41A9CFCE17DEE47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>program of study</term>—</text> <clause id="HAD58430ADF694F808C347A76D32E8ACA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means an eligible program at an institution of higher education that is classified by a combination of—</text> 
<subclause id="H0B97D89A3335497C9E664D435F565FC9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>one or more CIP codes; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF3CD72D3FABF4F8C99884F190CA6A66B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>one credential level, determined by the credential awarded upon completion of the program; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H39C5F8200A0D49F6BA481F33EFC905B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include a program of study abroad.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35DB8B300B6146FCB2F74034A5B22620"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cip code</header><text>The term <term>CIP code</term> means the six-digit taxonomic identification code assigned by an institution of higher education to a specific program of study at the institution, determined by the institution of higher education in accordance with the Classification of Instructional Programs published by the National Center for Education Statistics.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H504A7B48DA9A4E8D93A670211FB505A3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Credential level</header> 
<clause id="HB48DF6F9186B4A578D7B4FA6AA93323A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>credential level</term> means the level of the degree or other credential awarded by an institution of higher education to students who complete a program of study of the institution. Each degree or other credential awarded by an institution shall be categorized by the institution as either undergraduate credential level or graduate credential level.</text></clause> <clause id="H8195E2269CED4A288D4AA0E35A197F34"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Undergraduate credential</header><text>When used with respect to a credential or credential level, the term <term>undergraduate credential</term> includes credentials such as an undergraduate certificate, an associate degree, a bachelor’s degree, and a post-baccalaureate certificate (including the coursework specified in paragraphs (3)(B) and (4)(B) of section 484(b)).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7A6EA7E143F945D3A284A93620917A7C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Graduate credential</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When used with respect to a credential or credential level, the term <term>graduate credential</term> includes credentials such as a master’s degree, a doctoral degree, a professional degree (as defined under section 668.2 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations), and a postgraduate certificate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H94EF8D4028E1420BA7E79BAFAD455BB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elimination of early estimator tool</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (4) of section 485E(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092f">20 U.S.C. 1092f(b)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54D5FD5237D240C1B5785395E4345BD0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H7B21BDE2F0D94131A09170B30B0173DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Higher Education Act of 1965</header><text>The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, is further amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H09078B1910F2415F87F95805204A4A5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>College Navigator</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>College Scorecard</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H595314A37F62460BB8A6DEB35B09A783"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the header of section 487(d)(3), by striking <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">“college navigator”</header-in-text> and inserting <header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">“college scorecard”</header-in-text>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8091FF11677A4CCE88DC81C36E8D9CE4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other references</header><text>Any reference in any law (other than the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>)), regulation, document, record, or other paper of the United States to the College Navigator website shall be considered to be a reference to the College Scorecard website.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H16452021048A45378A83C220195E2A2A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on July 1, 2027, and shall apply with respect to award year 2027–2028 and each subsequent award year, as determined under the Higher Education Act of 1965. </text></section> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date> <action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

