<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C53620CAC604DA98935C116D6E2BBB9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6121 IH: Promoting Physical Activity for Americans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6121</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the publication by the Secretary of Health and Human Services of physical activity recommendations for Americans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H107443E953A84460B9BE7A632E7FB641" style="OLC"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H7EED5700CE2A4A5385DC4AEA0DF164B1"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Physical Activity for Americans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H551FC697D20E456F83970AD53C2AFEBB"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Physical activity recommendations for Americans</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1665740D76FC4F2B825A06A343D1CFFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A1377A3084D494D993D2F40AFBE82CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2029, and at least every 10 years thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall publish a report that provides physical activity recommendations for the people of the United States. Each such report shall contain physical activity information and recommendations for consideration and use by the general public, and shall be considered, as applicable and appropriate, by relevant Federal agencies in carrying out relevant Federal health programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7130B930A0E47B9B95229ADDA7047F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Basis of recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information contained in each report required under paragraph (1) shall be based on the most current evidence-based scientific and medical knowledge at the time the report is prepared, and shall include additional recommendations for population subgroups, such as children or individuals with disabilities, including information regarding engagement in appropriate physical activity and avoiding inactivity.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EE2AC9C45674421AE952C9B2B05391D"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Update reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the publication of the first report under paragraph (1), and at least every 10 years thereafter, the Secretary shall publish an updated report detailing evidence-based practices and highlighting continuing issues with respect to physical activity. The contents of reports under this paragraph may focus on a particular group, subsection, or other division of the general public or on a particular issue relating to physical activity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACD0F61EE70D4F2E97AF89E471170C58"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Interaction with other recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal agencies proposing to issue physical activity recommendations that differ from the recommendations in the most recent report published under subsection (a)(1) shall, as applicable and appropriate, take into consideration the recommendations provided through reports issued under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9115B2CDE050471CA9DBA4BBB2BEB235"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Existing authority not affected</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section is not intended to limit the support of biomedical research by any Federal agency or to limit the presentation or communication of scientific or medical findings or review of such findings by any Federal agency.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC75B0E051F36495E8BB2A1579B47C413"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, no physical fitness standard established under this Act shall be binding on any individual as a matter of Federal law or regulation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

