<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72C06CC6F7764360B438610A7090D2A8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5995 IH: Have You Served Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5995</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of carrying out Ask the Question Campaigns, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3D702311CFE481C917FC2C65C16E84B" style="OLC"><section id="HE1A04BC46DA04395BDD282335433E1C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Have You Served Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4A525C459C8648E2A54E74459CEE4A63"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for Ask the Question Campaigns</header><subsection id="H3B3D50134FDF486591C24E31A3B93A41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of carrying out campaigns, to be known as <quote>Ask the Question Campaigns</quote>, to encourage human services professionals, State and local governments, and community providers to ask consumers whether they or a loved one have served in the Armed Forces.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB25BE9E96FBA460181C44D1AEA9549AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall use the grant—</text><paragraph id="HD187A23E957A4E99AB119513E2CA14AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop or expand an Ask the Question Campaign, under which the entity shall provide training to human services professionals, State and local governments, and community providers about—</text><subparagraph id="H2DA35466F84C4065952E4CBD62B40ED5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how to appropriately ask consumers whether they or a loved one have served in the Armed Forces; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA9684FBD9FF4DB99B8D37374066E3D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resources available for members of the Armed Forces and veterans in their community through the Department of Veterans Affairs and other service providers to encourage the recipients of such training to refer consumers to the Department and other service providers, as appropriate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31AF60DB724F4DD49F78AD13670F7576"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for associated program costs, including staffing, technology, marketing and outreach materials, and convenings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE35CC25E15144275866E8D55CEA8C719"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, an eligible entity is a State or an American Indian or Alaska Native tribe—</text><paragraph id="HE4BD6DE6B0DD48BEBADA3D0944081461"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that—</text><subparagraph id="HCC945843A74D486492526674D3EED99F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a State, develops a veteran suicide prevention plan, known as a <quote>Governors Challenge Action Plan</quote>; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72FB00CB5DE24D6C96ED67EE2A016CFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an American Indian or Alaska Native tribe, develops a veteran suicide prevention plan; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E0C632B91364F9193935318420740FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that submits to the Secretary a proposal for the implementation of such plan that contains such information and assurances as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80773ADD36FF44E79B66E92A3C041183"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to eligible entities that receive grants under this section to support the development and implementation of Ask the Question Campaigns. Such assistance shall include—</text><paragraph id="H248AFB6A34A449129035E77D808623C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the provision of best practices acquired from the experiences of other eligible entities carrying out Ask the Question Campaigns;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD80AFCAE4CA0453D88A37338242D0A76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the provision of information on veterans resources in the State where the eligible entity is located;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FD24FBF99C84E28B7CB09B26B8FEDB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the provision of information about screening protocols used by the Department for assessing suicide risk and social determinants of health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B987FFC25EA4A59BC49879FA15477F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing key performance indicators for the training provided under the Campaigns.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24CF343448354CE4B1C3363C8FA21179"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amount of grant</header><text>The Secretary may make up to 25 grants under this section for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030. Each such grant shall be in an amount that does not exceed <quote>$200,000</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H94760539B9774F5BBF6AD9C6B5C0491F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H25F6C49BF81B4D16B3FFAD09082734F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree to submit, by not later than the last day of each fiscal year during which the entity receives a grant, to the Secretary a report on the key performance indicators for the training provided using the grant funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AFC766A514B4B38A6F6123D994AA710"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB76E0B92434C4A00801E41A4061166F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the last day of a fiscal year for which the Secretary makes a grant under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the key performance indicators for the training provided under such grants.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4B038D478144BEBB3AB94B5A337154D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Ask the Question Campaigns for Federal Agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall develop a plan to work with each Federal department and agency to implement Ask the Question Campaigns, where appropriate, through any social service or health care programs of the department or agency through which employees of the department or agency interact with individuals receiving services and benefits.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E3F9BE272834233975DFACF6D851DCA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out this section $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4420982CC3714B09866AA53A7657A4DA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>State defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, Territories, and possessions of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

