<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN26344-XXC-2H-KLR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 767 IS: Celebrating the historic significance of the 2026 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) World Cup and welcoming the international community to North America for the first tournament hosted by 3 nations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 767</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating the historic significance of the 2026 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) World Cup and welcoming the international community to North America for the first tournament hosted by 3 nations.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas soccer is the most popular sport in the world, with an estimated fan base of 3,500,000,000 people across every continent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas soccer remains the most accessible sport on the planet, requiring only a ball and a field of play, which allows it to serve as a universal language for people of all ages and backgrounds;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 1994 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (referred to in this preamble as <quote>FIFA</quote>) World Cup, which was hosted by the United States, remains the most attended tournament in history, with 3,600,000 spectators;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the legacy of the 1994 FIFA World Cup fundamentally changed the trajectory of soccer in the United States, leading directly to the 1996 launch of Major League Soccer and the creation of new professional pathways for players from the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 2026 FIFA World Cup will be a milestone in sporting history as the first edition to feature an expanded field of 48 national teams and a record 104 matches;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for the first time in the history of the competition, the FIFA World Cup will be jointly hosted by 3 nations, the United States, Canada, and Mexico; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the <quote>United Bid</quote> of our 3 nations exemplifies the spirit of continental unity and cooperation among our great neighbors, with matches scheduled across 16 iconic host cities, including 11 in the United States, 3 in Mexico, and 2 in Canada: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="ide5e6de3348a542c09c65e12666a5f1e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>welcomes the world’s fans and players to the United States, Canada, and Mexico for the 2026 Fédération Internationale de Football Association World Cup;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide71e6e192cbb4be1b8aae557c771e170"><enum>(2)</enum><text>thanks our neighbors and partners, Canada and Mexico, for their historic collaboration in bringing the world’s most popular tournament back to North America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbad4b1fadb9349608bb447dcffb0208a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the decades of peace and prosperity grounded in mutual respect that have characterized the relations between our 3 nations, making possible our joint hosting of the tournament;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b754419d21c46ef9defe0a5cf126d77"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the 16 host cities for their dedication to providing a <quote>home team</quote> atmosphere for fans and players from all 48 participating nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec0e680f504f43c997fe0018e7a2d27f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>commits to upholding equal access to the tournament for teams, media, and fans of all nations and equal protection under the laws of the United States, acknowledging the heritage of the United States of freedom and justice on our 250th anniversary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60b1db143148461ca69de7e545174783"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports the continued use of sports as a banner of peace, friendship, and fair competition to unite a diverse global public.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

