<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDFB672F435B04948A87C4F08F06355B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6666 IH: Helping Improve Recruitment and Retention Efforts for Prosecutors Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6666</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to establish a single grant program to make grants to hire prosecutors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC32B873E965B4755A8B311A4EB72A53E" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HA21BEDA8BDB44CACAA3FF5A48B9DB308"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Improve Recruitment and Retention Efforts for Prosecutors Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>HIRRE Prosecutors Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6A91DB1F7C3041199B55406FDAC87191"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to make grants for prosecutors</header> <subsection id="H0797FC3762874684A64A164B51FD0E06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish a program (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to assist a State, territory, unit of local government, or tribal government in hiring prosecutors.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA74117A3397849DAAF41BAB811AEE6E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Attorney General may award a grant on a competitive basis in accordance with this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6792B87B260840F7A02D62C042342E02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may award a grant under the Program each year to a prosecutor's office of a State, territory, unit of local government, or tribal government that submits an application pursuant to subsection (d).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9230CBA50712400EA0C962D0008E584A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an eligible recipient shall submit to the Attorney General an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Attorney General determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6CFF508061DA4D70A19B1A05F1B54DB1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>Grant funds awarded under the Program may only be used to hire, retain, and train prosecutors or support staff for a prosecutor's office of a State, territory, unit of local government, or tribal government.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43D70438E965405185FEF8F9AF830DE3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of components</header><text>The Attorney General may use any component of the Department of Justice in carrying out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H780C5B599949481995EBDD5DBA3A1A27"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preferential consideration of applications for certain grants</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Attorney General may give preferential consideration to an application—</text> 
<paragraph id="H72446525877A45C7842FF62200A596A9">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>to hire and train new prosecutors or support staff for a prosecutor's office of a State, territory, unit of local government, or tribal government;</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H252F887C9E0E4598A0DDF8A34DBF704F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to rehire prosecutors who have been laid off as a result of State, territory, unit of local government, or tribal government budget reductions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B914044EB084BE9A4DA9E0AC860C9B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>from a jurisdiction representing a tribal, remote, or rural area, as defined in section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H259BE11AA5324C56B9B2EE7DD199305F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal share</header> 
<paragraph id="HF637AE1CF54A4E17AE3DD11E5C88B4AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project assisted with a grant under the Program shall not exceed 75 percent.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7E14A1E63894A3996455C9EC06778F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Attorney General may waive the 25 percent matching requirement under paragraph (1) upon making a determination that a waiver is equitable in view of the financial circumstances affecting the ability of the eligible recipient to meet that requirement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF16F7CA086974A7DA9F7B1493AC32D35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonsupplanting requirement</header><text>Funds made available under the Program shall not be used to supplant State or local funds, or, in the case of Indian tribal governments, funds awarded by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, but shall be used to increase the amount of funds that would, in the absence of Federal funds received under the Program, be made available from State or local sources, or in the case of Indian tribal governments, from funds supplied by the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D70383FC13C47EBA0881B34A808BBE8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Non-Federal costs</header> <subparagraph id="HAD2B4BB5CE5347BEBB0809C009805CFC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or unit of local or tribal government may use assets received through the assets forfeiture equitable sharing program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B421EDE767A47158194601D9BA39173"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Indian tribal governments</header><text>Funds appropriated by Congress for the activities of any agency of an Indian tribal government or the Bureau of Indian Affairs performing prosecutorial functions on any Indian lands may be used to provide the non-Federal share of the cost of programs or projects funded under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF19E054C99E647C48C782BC9D31F3C46"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Performance evaluation</header> <paragraph id="H6EFC5318860847EC9EE393DF94BE8F02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Monitoring components</header><text>Each project funded by a grant under the Program shall contain a monitoring component, including the systematic identification and collection of data about activities, accomplishments, and programs undertaken pursuant to the Program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HCE56A5F63D8E4B9B83684A4E32A4493D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation components</header><text>The Attorney General shall evaluate each project funded by a grant under the Program, individually or as part of a national evaluation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1BE8CCA341864BAD9AB5713EC0B7903D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Periodic review and reports</header><text>The Attorney General may require a project funded under the Program to submit to the Attorney General the results of the monitoring component and evaluation under paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, as well as any other information as the Attorney General deems necessary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HC7174559E755455E8C2175EC17B67692"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Revocation or suspension of funding</header><text>If the Attorney General determines, as a result of evaluation under this subsection, or otherwise, that a grant under the Program is not in substantial compliance with the terms and requirements of the Program, the Attorney General may revoke or suspend funding of that grant, in whole or in part.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA91D53E59E014B8089CD9CC95FE54498"><enum>(j)</enum><header>General regulatory authority</header><text>The Attorney General may promulgate regulations and guidelines to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF5ECD9BCFD9461CB166CD8C237B71FF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the Program $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

