<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WAL25728-2M8-X3-XXD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3285 IS: Adoption Deserves Oversight, Protection, and Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3285</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 18, United States Code, to criminalize unlawful adoption practices.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Adoption Deserves Oversight, Protection, and Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ADOPT Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id77be0938547c4f23bb433b294c637983"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to—</text><paragraph id="id0e7bc2031748451491456d4aa58e453e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protect individuals and families impacted by private domestic interstate adoption from exploitation by unlicensed adoption intermediaries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0938f4eb4ddc408184cc529bc40e0f37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that individuals seeking assistance with private domestic interstate adoption have ready access to licensed and regulated adoption providers in their communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfb240f687a8e4548816eebf77897225e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prevent the commodification of children who are the subjects of private domestic interstate adoptions.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id3a7e57d25ff34cd3a263919a422e763b"><enum>3.</enum><header>Adoption offense</header><subsection id="id8c5d1fe04b394ab1a8e9ba43b7d67caa"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/11A">Chapter 11A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4accb79de733471aa7d33899486fbea6"><section id="idde6bc11a568a47329558be5852bbce4c"><enum>228A.</enum><header>Unlawful adoption practices</header><subsection id="id84acf36aa6c94c009dd2d34d12785e35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="iddde958d78b2646e18f2356b10c0f5f08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adoption advertising</header><text>The term <term>adoption advertising</term> means a paid advertisement, article, notice, or other paid communication published in any newspaper, magazine, or on the internet, on a billboard, over radio or television, or any public media that—</text><subparagraph id="idc42313492cd2481eb53edde65c1c5727"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicits prospective adoptive parents for the purpose of acting as a link between a placing parent and a prospective adoptive parent, or the representative, attorney, or agency of a prospective adoptive parent or placing parent, for the placement of a child for adoption;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f55c638969f41f793295bf03b5be141"><enum>(B)</enum><text>solicits placing parents for the purpose of acting as a link between a placing parent and a prospective adoptive parent, or the representative, attorney, or agency of a prospective adoptive parent or placing parent, for the placement of a child for adoption; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ce7dae998ad4d6287fe4c826902173e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offers to disburse any thing of value, including living expenses, medical or hospital care, or any other expenses of a placing parent in connection with the birth or adoption of a child.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a446da665164416b73e41b253b97fb2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adoption intermediary services</header><text>The term <term>adoption intermediary services</term> means the provision of any of the following services, in exchange for direct or indirect compensation:</text><subparagraph id="id8ba733eaf4884d7a994f315133d36498"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Soliciting placing parents, whether through adoption advertising or other means, for the purposes of acting as a link between a placing parent and a prospective adoptive parent, or the representative, attorney, or agency of a prospective adoptive parent or placing parent, for the placement of a child for adoption.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32ca19a6ed484608802879fedc5509a0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Soliciting prospective adoptive parents, whether through adoption advertising or other means, for the purpose of acting as a link between a placing parent and a prospective adoptive parent, or the representative, attorney, or agency of a prospective adoptive parent or placing parent, for the placement of a child for adoption.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66c53e736d894e6f8fc912455d0037b9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Acting as a link between placing parents of a child and prospective adoptive parents, whether directly or through the representative, attorney, or agency of a prospective adoptive parent or placing parent, for the placement of a child for adoption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8d9cc447bf04d83854b01d9eff694eb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Placing parent</header><text>The term <term>placing parent</term> means a parent with legal authority to place the child for adoption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id19b426ed6f394207abddd9af2524839e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public child-placing agency</header><text>The term <term>public child-placing agency</term> means any government child welfare agency or child protection agency that has the legal authority to place children for adoption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide112374f3e5945259401469bb06100c3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Private licensed child-placing agency</header><text>The term <term>private licensed child-placing agency</term> means a licensed or State approved agency that has the legal authority to place children for adoption.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93a8dd50fc4243549f5ca945ca3ca788"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adoption intermediary services</header><paragraph id="id5a7cd9acc9dd4e97800b9000116062f2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>Whoever, in any circumstance described in subsection (e), knowingly provides adoption intermediary services shall be punished as provided in accordance with subsection (f).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id796e34f05967483eb462a58bd4d1ac1a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text><subparagraph id="idffcab17dc84c4aaebeec223d4d768125"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public child-placing agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07e37c117c0e42c7b8b84d0b9c3cdb03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Act that is acting under contract by a public child-placing agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3941f140e29d4e24a35bef1fe5ec3845"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a private licensed child-placing agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida7005f97c2e4401a98165ee237f1d5dd"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an attorney licensed in the State in which the intermediary services are provided; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida912ddbf48ff464aa2a80c6384f01d4d"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an adoption service provider accredited or approved in accordance with title II of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14921">42 U.S.C. 14921 et seq.</external-xref>) advertising provision of services through an intercountry adoption program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id07fb9fc905cf47a0a00af9514bd43984"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adoption advertising</header><paragraph id="id0e5756d5d6f9463184d18fa0a6b1af8e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>Whoever, in any circumstance described in subsection (e), knowingly places an adoption advertisement shall be punished in accordance with subsection (f).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idce6589f7a2cb454fbd386cde310fe519"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text><subparagraph id="idb2204368059e4eec873424292f6bd5e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public child-placing agency or private licensed child-placing agency licensed to provide services in the State in which the advertisement appears;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04D4EB3A92564736A6956E2BF82F0CA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Act that is acting under contract by a public child-placing agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd431d27d6b6844bc861c8b96ef60bf95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an attorney licensed in the State in which the advertisement appears; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4f3a62cb069b4dc887aff63d5e86f859"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an adoption service provider accredited or approved in accordance with title II of the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14921">42 U.S.C. 14921 et seq.</external-xref>) advertising an intercountry adoption program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id20a05f1681d0412cb90c993c974342da"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unauthorized payments to or on behalf of a placing parent</header><paragraph id="id221fd0e7869e4ab8b88c3a9ee36a1c41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>Whoever, in any circumstance described in subsection (e), knowingly provides any thing of value, including money, property, or services (including medical or hospital care), whether payment is made directly or indirectly for the benefit of the placing parent in connection with the birth of a child and in furtherance of an adoption in an amount exceeding $2,500, before the consultation of a placing parent with a private licensed child-placing agency or attorney licensed in the State where the placing parent resides or is located, shall be punished in accordance with subsection (f).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida350b589806047bb93e9bb1ed4eaa6ce"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to any payment made by or in cooperation with—</text><subparagraph id="idfea57323181d4b7bb3e3a464ca25f4ce"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a private child-placing agency licensed in the State in which the placing parent resides or is located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43ec68ac85c04872914c6261998af4b7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an attorney licensed in the State in which the placing parent resides or is located; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb2012e431ed48deb1a789120cd36641"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a public agency or entity pursuant to any law or regulation, including any entitlement benefit, public assistance, or similar government support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfb4f89aff2aa4cb082bf232ab710c456"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>For the purposes of subsections (b), (c), and (d), the circumstances under which those subsections apply are—</text><paragraph id="id7d0bfe2ad21e4058a2d7b04f3c370390"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the defendant, placing parent, or prospective adoptive parent traveled in interstate or foreign commerce or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (b), (c), or (d);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idb8d9b13b854e4b4db484e5d9f1488640"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the defendant knowingly used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (b), (c), or (d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2597df09c654a799fcf8f6693131e80"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the defendant knowingly made a payment, directly or indirectly, using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (b), (c), or (d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbbad287fdc204d9398dcae91b76433fa"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the defendant knowingly transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication using any means, channel, or facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, including wire or computer, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (b), (c), or (d);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a355de79ed74934b673199222a366e5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (b), (c), or (d) occurred within the territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fa65db1b2684197a0168926c51ddb3b"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (b) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc303125b64824258aa29f5350d7b3777"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Whoever violates subsection (b), (c), or (d)—</text><paragraph id="idcbe43c273b3f4817a0b52b0cf0e26636"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an individual, shall be fined $50,000, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both per violation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8e334fb00c94d08aa08ca1fbf80ad4a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an organization, shall be fined $100,000 per violation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id804af7c4a8f54422b46ade22c1ec519e"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5819d98a8274dd396e1d91d0333004a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affect the application of the Indian Child Welfare Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1901">25 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5938fe3453574dfc9323b186e109bbaf"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit the provision of intercountry adoption programs and services authorized under the Intercountry Adoption Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/14901">42 U.S.C. 14901 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03a6f53924a24691aadad87e5e46308e"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit a State or local government from enacting or enforcing requirements that are more stringent than the requirements established under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id26d5318b5871407196b9836abf8270e4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><paragraph id="H8506244E4B1447C496E3E65E162AA6F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Table of chapters</header><text>The table of chapters for part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7A41F38370334D558BECF62C37531B48"><toc><multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>11A.</toc-enum><level-header level="section">Child support and unlawful adoption practices</level-header><target>228</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c94110d2a6a480aa4d530488d366357"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chapter heading</header><text>The chapter heading for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/11A">chapter 11A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="OLC">AND UNLAWFUL ADOPTION PRACTICES</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="chapter" style="OLC">CHILD SUPPORT</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb32d3c4c7cc8479abdf284cb69a9f1de"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/11A">chapter 11A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 228, the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83B042679B7A4F77950DB2548E0CEA89"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">228A. Unlawful adoption practices.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8a310c03e8de46148df8b01fe5a262cd"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

