<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9EA349D38434158B8F55DF1ABC49BDB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6428 IH: To require the Secretary of State to submit a report on participation in educational and cultural exchange programs.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6428</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to submit a report on participation in educational and cultural exchange programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC917887015FB4ADAAAFE5D564AB85F2E" style="OLC"><section id="H9BD2CFEF11FB408988800FAA3D0F04F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Promoting United States educational and cultural exchange programs</header><subsection id="H1A81CC265A3B4CD18D2FD112AD2E7B13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H568B68ECF9144192A5C6BDDA6A721F86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress recognizes the critical role of international exchange and study abroad programs in advancing United States national security interests, strengthening diplomatic ties, and fostering global leadership skills among emerging leaders, particularly in regions vital to United States strategic interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4419C7082A914A27B3843F4BC694811D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>educational and cultural exchange programs are critical soft power tools for building influence with the next generation of leaders in partner nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3BE85FB02D24F89A9BCB9EC8D203149"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China is actively deploying such programs to expand its influence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB33B9A17003C47DB9BC7B727626D6F15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States must expand and strengthen its own exchange programs to maintain and advance United States strategic interests globally.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EC8705EFAF349EFA00AC31D9FF0DFA5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="H750C75C2AA50402E856191A71C21292B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H8F14E8E3FF8F499FA8249B53901CF485" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list, disaggregated by country, of the number of individuals who participated in educational or cultural exchange programs sponsored or funded by the People’s Republic of China in the previous year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DBCDE12F5D047DE984F2EA59A3BF9D2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list, disaggregated by country, of the number of individuals who participated in a program described in paragraph (2) in the previous year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H033ABEC4B5DD457081F6DFAFE0709431" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in coordination with the Monitoring, Evaluation, Learning, and Innovation Unit, for each program described in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H14BA5416632743BE98D95AF9FAB98835" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of funds provided by the United States for the program;</text></clause><clause id="H3189C5F1B53B4577B6D9847C295FD6AE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of participants in the program;</text></clause><clause id="H95FBC893C20040E5BCE56E6BD7246B7A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of cohorts in the program;</text></clause><clause id="HFBA582C6E2234756BA1C3ACFB616C41C" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the countries of origin of the participants in the program;</text></clause><clause id="H7E4F2DDB33A04F99A6D4D5446946C475" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ages of the participants in the program;</text></clause><clause id="H5B7E03AC763845AFBF4602F9D512F136" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the percent of participants in the program who reported a more favorable opinion of the United States Government following participation in the program;</text></clause><clause id="H837C3EBE7B684344B76290CAFFE4D521" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the percent of foreign participants who traveled to the United States for the first time during the program;</text></clause><clause id="H4659EF7AA5BD4A4C981E7E880CBA6307" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percent of foreign participants who reported that they are more likely to recommend the United States as a good place to study following participation in the program;</text></clause><clause id="HCB09B9583139406593D1558714548B11" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percent of foreign participants who reported a more favorable opinion of United States citizens following participation in the program;</text></clause><clause id="HAB6566EFC89A4FBE8F99615826802E86" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the percent of foreign participants who reported an increased understanding of United States culture and values as a result of participation in the program;</text></clause><clause id="HECF656A2630D4705B340A9570D869FCA" commented="no"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percent of participants who agreed with statements in support of democratic values following participation in the program;</text></clause><clause id="H73B3B0C8F9324C08A63D053FE739F0E7" commented="no"><enum>(xii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percent of foreign participants who reported an increased network of United States citizens as a result of participation in the program; and</text></clause><clause id="HC4822BCB6BD144A2BAE0407B3B1A7627" commented="no"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>the percent of participants who reported that they understand that the program they participated in is a Department of State program;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE933A3D268FA4AFCB1A53A2047118921"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of trends of participation in the programs described in subparagraph (A) and paragraph (2) and an analysis of the implications of such trends for United States diplomatic and strategic interests; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BC452A2531649AB97429E671D90E835" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an analysis of the impact of such programs on the diplomatic standing and strategic influence of the United States and the People’s Republic of China in each respective country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6F917624A44BD0BD867E6960FEBF68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Programs described</header><text>The programs described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8FD75589C41743D6B1DADC35E1C3BB01" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Fulbright Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B7C9727EC614A3194A5FEE315C2D3EE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Young African Leaders Initiative, including the Mandela Washington Fellowship.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB016AABF1CE8462AA02FA0966B02DABE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Young Southeast Asian Leaders Initiative.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D3B898FBB1C4314989B47E578F10AD3" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Kennedy-Lugar Youth Exchange and Study Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BF237264EA54F99B4C0AE130CC3689A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Future Leaders Exchange Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75C1547476A84AB0A3FFDC209AEF4B2B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any educational or cultural exchange program sponsored or funded by the United States that was previously included in a report required by paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E2E7D4BE727488493AA79266551FCDA"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any report required by paragraph (1) submitted after the first such report, not fewer than 10 educational or cultural exchange programs sponsored or funded by the United States that have not been included in a previous such report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3CFBE996BCC47B7B5EBB9D666A58536"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The reports required in this subsection shall be submitted in an unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E964BF1E3054086827FEF8952B141EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H90D05C4C277E400EB171263D3FF63CCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8818347E12274BD1AAE6BE5E88C288E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

