<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7BE68ABBA0A4D12A70B2BB488197AE5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6471 IH: Justice in Sentencing for Survivors Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6471</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the court to impose a sentence that is below the minimum statutory sentence in the case of a victim offender.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H589508F1855E4BA6885A0570EADF3DD1" style="OLC"><section id="H09157FCA8A314F8DAD57856CBE6932A6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice in Sentencing for Survivors Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H25736B1E6FC847E89E10F98E839AADCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HFDB78A9A05B04738B30A2FCB4BA462B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Although the United States has less than 5 percent of the world’s population, the United States has one of the highest rates of incarceration in the world, with over 1,900,000 people incarcerated in state and Federal prisons, local jails, juvenile correctional facilities, immigration detention facilities, and jails operated by Tribal authorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11B855488142449C98655DAF89B1DC65"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Between 1980 and 2024, the number of incarcerated women increased by more than 625 percent, rising from a total of 26,326 in 1980 to 190,600 in 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF175B7262FE147B0B118884334946546"><enum>(3)</enum><text>More than 77 million people in the United States have a criminal record, creating barriers to housing, jobs, healthcare, and food assistance, among many other collateral consequences.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41CBC3368175466FAF9DE5B38F177265"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Survivors of abuse and sex trafficking are often punished by the United States legal system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3830751C634440BFBA065117BEFCC7F5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>One study found, of incarcerated women—</text><subparagraph id="H8CEC3E4D8E81441693225581BAF6D3A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>86 percent report having experienced sexual violence in their lifetime;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AA94080EDFF41AAB43E5F816FDDA885"><enum>(B)</enum><text>77 percent report partner violence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD526CC3EF78E43939C2EAF3D5B8E3039"><enum>(C)</enum><text>60 percent report caregiver violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18B51FBDEB2D4B0A953F6FA688DE8520"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Rates of childhood and adult trauma are notably elevated among incarcerated men.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA344D2EC55B4421E93E718B1179F9B24"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sentencing offenders who are survivors of abuse</header><subsection id="H07686D6A0A0A407CA9ACB3C631A01678" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sentencing victim offenders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of a victim offender, the court shall have the authority to impose a sentence that is below the minimum sentence established by statute in consideration of any sexual assault, stalking, dating violence, domestic violence, or severe forms of trafficking in persons experienced by the victim offender.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB6805EE492DC4151BB9732F46D6BEA87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposing alternative sentence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the court shall have the authority to impose a sentence of probation, community confinement or a combination thereof, in consideration of any sexual assault, stalking, dating violence, domestic violence, or severe forms of trafficking in persons experienced by the victim offender.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED25305360E94A89BC671241F464E388" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A victim offender may be eligible for the imposition of a sentence pursuant to subsection (a) or an alternative sentence pursuant to subsection (b) even if—</text><paragraph id="HF15CB954BC6C43CA9CF8A26272D5EF2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any sexual assault, stalking, dating violence, domestic violence, or severe forms of trafficking in persons experienced by victim offender—</text><subparagraph id="H0908F3E54A99431EB57F8E64C56D08CB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>did not result in physical injury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41D7B4244457453382E920389ABDC862" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was not experienced for a long period of time; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD98E779B338D46978F448FFA6C2DCD27" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>did not occur contemporaneously with the commission of the offense; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2C8C3C6E8FE47AC9A1B310310D1A597"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the offense was committed against someone other than the perpetrator of the sexual assault, stalking, dating violence, domestic violence, or severe forms of trafficking in persons experienced by the victim offender.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H732C2943D2514181BCAB8CA1412ABEE0" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration of certain evidence</header><paragraph id="HE6EEAE8B7D8345EAA8F7D8B920AC3186"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The victim offender’s ability or failure to offer evidence to the court prior to sentencing with respect to any sexual assault, stalking, dating violence, domestic violence, or severe forms of trafficking in persons experienced by the victim offender shall not determine their eligibility for the imposition of a sentence pursuant to subsection (a) or an alternative sentence pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8850E3AFB9A846FBA703B57D141E3477"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affidavit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether relief is appropriate under subsection (a) or (b), the court may consider an affidavit that demonstrates, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the victim offender has experienced physical, emotional, sexual, or psychological abuse, trauma, or neglect.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC39565B595A4FA7B1BEFD96E9D57F1E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="H906ED41FF6B145FCA32F75949CEA2EA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pending cases</header><text>This Act shall apply to any sentence imposed on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76EEB420B3F943B89AFAF8DD59C9AC70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Past cases</header><text>In the case of a victim offender who, before the date of enactment of this Act, was convicted or sentenced for a Federal offense, the sentencing court may, on motion of the victim offender, the Bureau of Prisons, the attorney for the Government, or on its own motion, impose a sentence in accordance with subsections (a) or (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC135EF385DF0419E92665232FEACB31A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Directive to United States Sentencing Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to its authority under section 994(p) of title 28, United States Code, the United States Sentencing Commission shall review and amend the Federal sentencing guidelines and the policy statements of the Commission, as appropriate, to include as a factor to be considered in imposing a sentence any sexual assault, stalking, dating violence, domestic violence, or severe forms of trafficking in persons experienced by a victim offender.</text></subsection><subsection id="H484EC5F68E0C4DE1A95B4714461CB370"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H86A997D0BBE14C279CB0CB3361897063"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dating violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>dating violence</term> means violence committed by a person—</text><subparagraph id="HA99A6B09B3624DF7A07C598BC4F33A6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is or has been in a social relationship of a romantic or intimate nature with the victim; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B78442D6A4445AAAE5229D0A412F97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>where the existence of such a relationship shall be determined based on a consideration of the following factors:</text><clause id="HC9B49AC0CB2449E5B54FF70E9EAC1971"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The length of the relationship.</text></clause><clause id="HF54FDBEA5F514A6B947D8EBFEA1C84AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The type of relationship.</text></clause><clause id="H8D0389A057AE4D18A598590BA6311365"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The frequency of interaction between the persons involved in the relationship.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D0F4562766042CF99B1E42ACF41F757"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Domestic violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>domestic violence</term> includes felony or misdemeanor crimes committed by a current or former spouse or intimate partner of the victim under the family or domestic violence laws of the jurisdiction receiving grant funding and, in the case of victim services, includes the use or attempted use of physical abuse or sexual abuse, or a pattern of any other coercive behavior committed, enabled, or solicited to gain or maintain power and control over a victim, including verbal, psychological, economic, or technological abuse that may or may not constitute criminal behavior, by a person who—</text><subparagraph id="HA0D991C7163C4578AE57163274213278"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a current or former spouse or intimate partner of the victim, or person similarly situated to a spouse of the victim;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC412038424CC417CBF3220495C096C83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is cohabitating, or has cohabitated, with the victim as a spouse or intimate partner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77AD3C94B22040F9AEE1A22E572E3095"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shares a child in common with the victim; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C21765A51444B2E9AAF572C422B25B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>commits acts against a youth or adult victim who is protected from those acts under the family or domestic violence laws of the jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74E9F08B978543D592509E23033ED880"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sex offense</header><text>The term <term>sex offense</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 111 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20911">34 U.S.C. 20911</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA7BC2816176444EA64460B80BAF7B6C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sexual assault</term> means any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, tribal, or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82309B45B0D74D64B71D9EF7F48AB6F8" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Severe forms of trafficking in persons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>severe forms of trafficking in persons</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H066CC1F154D3406D8C15492169C44A27"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Stalking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>stalking</term> means engaging in a course of conduct directed at a specific person that would cause a reasonable person to—</text><subparagraph id="HB0177709964E4FDE98AD6527DC06EBFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fear for his or her safety or the safety of others; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B146509F8D44D2F9D94427D9465263F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suffer substantial emotional distress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE263D41C8864E9AB0260869BD3BA4CE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Victim offender</header><text>The term <term>victim offender</term> includes an individual—</text><subparagraph id="H9DA2B4D422AC458581C3EFCB7CE2FF6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who has experienced sexual assault, stalking, dating violence, domestic violence, or severe forms of trafficking in persons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF276C1FA8B8347119CAEDFB58B1C8D4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for whom such abuse was a significant contributing factor in the offender’s criminal behavior; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AFD546330F848A28B0FBD64A75BBF05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who has not been convicted of a sex offense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

