<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-WIL26304-RRV-CP-KJ4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4742 IS: Artificial Intelligence Data Authorization and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4742</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize certain labor market data collection activities and to improve Federal measurement of the workforce impacts of artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence Data Authorization and Transparency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AI DATA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id2cc30496f54f46018a1e9dc4e4999b1f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="id8000dce1cf264275bc893c7d24869f48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f1312e3f9334f5eab9d012cd71037c0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business trends and outlook survey</header><text>The term <term>Business Trends and Outlook Survey</term> means the recurring survey conducted by the Bureau of the Census to measure business conditions and expectations across industries in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb30c14ff789746c5b44562d7bc5086ae"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8e27fb765e74a5b9e886f4e3bea0e78"><enum>3.</enum><header>Labor market flow data collection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(a) of the Wagner-Peyser Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/49l-2">29 U.S.C. 49l–2</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa16194260cb4e24b4b70456e03fd5ae"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1d2ed2577d44331b68057466e0de277"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Labor market flow data</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72544353ed594ce581dd2061e4dca89f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In collecting the data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall conduct a monthly recurring establishment survey regarding job openings, hiring, separations (including due to workers quitting or being laid off), and other measures of labor market turnover determined relevant by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id640f964c5a3b48bfbfd4bb3cb12ba1ce"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data and information requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data and information collected for purposes for the survey under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7e21a893c61c4b3b8a843e0fc5175aef"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be grouped based on industry, occupation, and geographic area; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id040d670f4d2a429490f5e983060197d0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be collected to an extent that would be sufficient to assess changes in labor demand associated with technological change, including artificial intelligence and automation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51bea1834d9c4d43bbea64a0a1008dc8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication of survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data and information collected for purposes of the survey under subparagraph (A) shall be disseminated monthly through the nationwide workforce and labor market information system in accordance with paragraph (1)(G).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id1124a23298a842f6b816059903ffcf5f"><enum>4.</enum><header>Time-use and labor force participation data collection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(a) of the Wagner-Peyser Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/49l-2">29 U.S.C. 49l–2</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc5502ef23bc4d3f8085cb849cf450ba"><paragraph id="id38d931626ec64978bc8855f8cf6f0af1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Time-use and labor force participation data</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ebd6c60c27f418284a58f1c5f28bed6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In collecting the data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall conduct a recurring household survey to measure how individuals allocate time across work, caregiving, household production, education, and other activities determined relevant by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80924d34d3294529b471ca67d2e3018f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data and information requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The survey under subparagraph (A) shall include measures sufficient to evaluate the use of digital tools and emerging technologies in the workplace.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbe6d2f9ba954cc78d87ae486bde7a13"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication of survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using the data and information collected for purposes of the survey under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall annually disseminate, through the nationwide workforce and labor market information system in accordance with paragraph (1)(G), data necessary to evaluate how technological change, including artificial intelligence, affects work patterns and labor force participation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76b73cff3b6c4ba3a9da423071005d3d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Longitudinal labor market data collection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(a) of the Wagner-Peyser Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/49l-2">29 U.S.C. 49l–2</external-xref>), as amended by section 4, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85e48eb102384c408123fef06a5f750a"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id58ca8a02550d44dea55622bdfa1ea248"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Longitudinal labor market data</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b4295a6e8774da8b736b3d389069946"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In collecting the data and information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall conduct longitudinal surveys that follow individuals over extended periods to assess employment, earnings, occupational mobility, education, training, and related outcomes determined relevant by the Secretary and publicly report on such surveys annually.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id20137efe39ae4bffb0dca8dbbb0aad4d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Frequency of cohorts</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall initiate new survey cohorts every 10 years to maintain representative and contemporary data.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91af5ca0e71c4e6bbf6217320844c8e4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Data and information requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The surveys under subparagraph (A) shall include measures sufficient to evaluate the long-term effects of technological change, including artificial intelligence, on earnings, job stability, retraining, and economic mobility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id8f66767b952e40baa0a928ee8ef41414"><enum>6.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence workforce reporting through the business trends and outlook survey</header><subsection id="iddd9ff933ba2c4c4f88ed614e2a0b8d91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Census (in this section referred to as the <term>Director</term>), in coordination with the Secretary and the Commissioner of Labor Statistics, shall incorporate into the Business Trends and Outlook Survey questions and analysis necessary to assess the adoption of artificial intelligence and related technologies, and the impact on the workforce of such adoption.</text></subsection><subsection id="id820ebcc47a804a5d88c11495f4a27ca0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Director shall collect data regarding—</text><paragraph id="idddb2b79d01f5428eb3ec4f6ff1452af7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the adoption and use of artificial intelligence and related technologies across industries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f7db58706e54e589123ce4243025520"><enum>(2)</enum><text>changes in hiring, separations, job openings, occupational demand, and business operations associated with such technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9d4c991944d34a25926cc51ae55d793a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Director shall publish the data collected under subsection (a) on a quarterly basis.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8fe1e0b569db4aa98b2f39ce009246d0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id7c61259e2434419196d689bf64577b4c"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on the impact of artificial intelligence on the workforce</header><subsection id="idc7af66d3934b4b29b518467788d8cb78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Commerce shall publish an annual report assessing the impact of artificial intelligence and related technologies on the workforce of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id821bdd80d5a746d1b7f3a618224b6d9d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data integration</header><text>In producing the report required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Commerce shall, to the extent practicable, overlay—</text><paragraph id="id1cb20b23f2114a159b08628657283d8e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>industry-level data collected through the Business Trends and Outlook Survey collected by the Director of the Census;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86c3cecf1cae4c518973e84b39515161"><enum>(2)</enum><text>labor market flow, time-use, longitudinal, and projection data and any other relevant data collected by the Bureau of Labor Statistics; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida08760c1c60d48b0ba498c0055faeb1b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other relevant Federal data necessary to evaluate workforce impacts by industry and occupation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id377210b5811a48faa2ba4572213010ee"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include analysis of—</text><paragraph id="idd57c7080977b43ea90e2a309058ef015"><enum>(1)</enum><text>changes in hiring, separations, job openings, and occupational demand associated with artificial intelligence and related technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id355b5663f6654141807e8f2303e48763"><enum>(2)</enum><text>industry-level impacts on employment and skill needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ae6d5387a834ec6982cd5e8c73226d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>broader workforce effects, including impacts on earnings, job mobility, and training patterns; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c5ae2c2c1d14f6591a781dfd09ef7db"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other analysis the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Commerce determines necessary to understand the scope and impact of artificial intelligence and related technologies on the labor market.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4a973d27548d4994bbc53837c4459bbe"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9a073a88e6f42898941ad428dd88259"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

