<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB37475930DF7483BBEFBDA83BDDB57F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6429 IH: Expanding Cybersecurity Workforce Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6429</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security a program to promote the cybersecurity field to disadvantaged communities, including older individuals, racial and ethnic minorities, people with disabilities, geographically diverse communities, socioeconomically diverse communities, women, individuals from nontraditional educational paths, individuals who are veterans, and individuals who were formerly incarcerated, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B070AA160D540F597F5DE204A8B3767" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HEC084F7D7DF34D228D1234A82014B317" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Cybersecurity Workforce Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H20E22FA70C7E458E895738240FDF9DD3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of CISA’s Cybersecurity Education and Training Assistance Program</header> <subsection id="H740866B18CDC4359A3E7BAAE131FA770"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security shall establish within the Cybersecurity Education and Training Assistance Program of the Agency a program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to promote the cybersecurity field to disadvantaged communities, including older individuals, racial and ethnic minorities, people with disabilities, geographically diverse communities, socioeconomically diverse communities, women, individuals from nontraditional educational paths, individuals who are veterans, and individuals who were formerly incarcerated.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H21CFDDA280EB4650906D749B7B580727"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out subsection (a) and promote awareness of the Program, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security shall conduct outreach to different institutions to raise awareness of and promote the cybersecurity workforce, including to educators, unions, chambers of commerce, State and local workforce development offices, private sector entities, community colleges, parents of K-12 students, and other institutions as the Director determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDA7C441A25104228867A6D8E4959F46B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security shall tailor the Program to the unique needs of each region and sector across the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1241F1AA851C49ED9730165DD45CFB2B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the efficacy of the Program, including how the Program is impacting the general characteristics of the cyber workforce throughout the United States, and suggestions for Congress regarding how to improve the Program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9838BFA01A6B4675B90D08DBC6BB8722"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter through 2031.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2D5745DAD9E04848B1B3268FB1F6D2DD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFA843AABD76E432D88C42C1799669FD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The term <quote>disability</quote> means an intellectual or developmental disability.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF4823EA15124A1183C81B070BBA8B46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Geographically diverse</header><text>The term <quote>geographically diverse</quote> means that the participants should be represented as close as possible to an equal spread of high-density urban areas, suburban areas, and rural areas of the United States or over-represent low-income communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1473430F26745C2B72FCD933AE49D05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nontraditional educational path</header><text>The term <quote>nontraditional educational path</quote> means a graduate of any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB3575F26759747F59C2C287F5B61F8AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A two year degree program, trade school, or community college.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H11C42FBFC0C34774890DFFB7DF458F25"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A historically Black college or university.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37B8261F0E214E54811D9CD568F3780A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A Hispanic-serving institution (as such term is defined in section 502(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF473FA4D95B448EF92BD737CFE4E7757"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A Tribal College or University (as such term is defined in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B785D269033447788066835FEE0BBAE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An Alaska Native-serving institution (as such term is defined in section 317(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39B8BCDCFF4E485EA879578F7AE3920B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A Native Hawaiian-serving institution (as such term is defined in section 317(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD52D693279794162B654A230783BDED8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A Predominantly Black Institution (as such term is defined in section 318(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059e">20 U.S.C. 1059e(b)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEC45624F9DD4A54AD97938CEB484F38"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A Native American-serving, nontribal institution (as such term is defined in section 319(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059f">20 U.S.C. 1059f(b)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H68335659414B4002BD5A653342961988"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An Asian-American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution (as such term is defined in section 320(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059g">20 U.S.C. 1059g(b)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3D49864247B4C8F9B2B7BA9793507AD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Older</header><text>The term <quote>older</quote> means an individual who has attained the age of 40 or older as of the date on which such individual is scheduled to begin participation in the Program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBB06A3A716A45A883BEA2CF388FF035"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Racial and ethnic minority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>racial and ethnic minority</quote> means Black or African American, Hispanic or Latino, Asian American, or Native American.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08F7A7983D164764A15360BE8A7B0E63"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Socioeconomically diverse</header><text>The term <quote>socioeconomically diverse</quote> means a spread of income levels, including low-income individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

