<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC8870774C634422E8091A6A304229AB2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9057 IH: Country Of Origin Labeling Online Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9057</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require origin and location disclosure for new products of Foreign origin offered for sale on the internet.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4327B5767ED343768BC7C3D13E623550" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0366C2E5A55448879BED021440C40DE4" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Country Of Origin Labeling Online Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COOL Online Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4D45B51761BA455E8F6089822454B6F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Mandatory origin and location disclosure for new products of Foreign origin offered for sale on the internet</header> <subsection id="H93EAF2129E3D43D4ACA93DCFDAF47B1F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory disclosure</header> <paragraph changed="not-changed" id="HAFDBD00ACB444EFDBAAB17E9BB4BC744"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H179079BA3FED40A4BC8E598C882DE993"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), it shall be unlawful for a product that is marked or required to be marked under section 304 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1304">19 U.S.C. 1304</external-xref>) to be introduced, sold, advertised, or offered for sale in commerce on an internet website unless the internet website description of the product indicates in a conspicuous place—</text>
<clause id="HE23DD1AAF9F4415FA74BE9D648CD1D8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the country of origin of the product (or, in the case of a multi-sourced product, the countries of origin), in a manner consistent with the regulations prescribed under such section 304; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD0B86F8656C740019791F955EFF9F5B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the country in which the seller of the product has its principal place of business.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph changed="not-changed" commented="no" id="HED774878E2324265B279A79CCA2E63CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header>
<clause id="H167F1529CAC042EF98F6465768A5B4C1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Agricultural products</header><text>The disclosure requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall not apply to—</text> <subclause id="H1EEFDD43488A4A1A9248014A75E92E57"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a covered commodity (as defined in section 281 of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1638">7 U.S.C. 1638</external-xref>));</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HAEE0806132B1430D8444546D0314B5B5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a meat or meat food product subject to inspection under the Federal Meat Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/601">21 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4432DEE5147047BA96C41E11E295BCFE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a poultry or poultry product subject to inspection under the Poultry Products Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/451">21 U.S.C. 451 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H09688BBF91AA4355AD766D7D5CF4216F" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an egg product subject to regulation under the Egg Products Inspection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1031">21 U.S.C. 1031 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause> <clause changed="not-changed" commented="no" id="H21D2569C61444124A85E2715956672FB"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <header>Food and drugs</header> <text>The disclosure requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall not apply to a food or drug (as those terms are defined in paragraphs (f) and (g), respectively, of section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>)) that is subject to the jurisdiction of the Food and Drug Administration.</text>
                        </clause>
<clause id="HB2263E09693B4EA7A1224B2D53E28797">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
              <header>Used or previously-owned articles</header>
 <text>The disclosure requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any used or previously-owned article sold by an internet website marketplace or a seller on an internet website marketplace. For the purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <term>used or previously-owned article</term> means an article that was previously sold or offered for sale at retail.</text>
            </clause>
<clause id="H0B8A9DD2FCA3472AB0C179F21897FE09"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Small seller</header><text>The disclosure requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (A) shall not apply to goods listed by a small seller. For the purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <term>small seller</term> means a seller with annual sales of less than $20,000 and fewer than 200 discrete sales.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEE31E78609846F38FADD3CC16A22026"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Multi-sourced products</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), a product shall be considered to be a <quote>multi-sourced product</quote> if a seller offers for sale a finished product, identical versions of which are produced in multiple countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph changed="not-changed" id="H7E61E5965C96490F909E18D61EC71166"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain drug products</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a drug that is not subject to section 503(b)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/353">21 U.S.C. 353(b)(1)</external-xref>) and that is required to be marked under section 304 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1304">19 U.S.C. 1304</external-xref>) to be offered for sale in commerce to consumers on an internet website unless the internet website description of the drug indicates in a conspicuous place the name and place of business of the manufacturer, packer, or distributor that is required to appear on the label of the drug in accordance with section 502(b) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/352">21 U.S.C. 352(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB0BE00AAF46477E80B0482523538AFF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Obligation to provide</header><text>A manufacturer, importer, distributor, seller, supplier, or private labeler seeking to have a product introduced, sold, advertised, or offered for sale in commerce shall provide the information identified clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (2), as applicable, to the relevant retailer.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H62E69AB7BD2846CDB599AC40F6E61A13"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text>A retailer or a seller on an internet website marketplace satisfies the disclosure requirements under clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (2), as applicable, if the disclosure includes the country of origin and seller information provided by a third-party manufacturer, importer, distributor, seller, supplier, or private labeler of the product.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H58B08FB8A8BA4B8096622A5A98E3CB9A" changed="not-changed"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Commission</header> <paragraph id="HC7B9BA6AAA7D4351A6CDFB3A21195006" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6E545C1BDB3D4B12AB877321F5C7EBD9" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header>
<subparagraph id="HBFDBD12A2DE04BD3BEAA9BC6E7448C9F" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8CBA52B24EE46CBBB988359C1226943" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person that violates subsection (a) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) as though all applicable terms and provisions of that Act were incorporated and made part of this section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5C71CB3ADB54E78A22C920F1026F7E5" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29EBF8AFC31645CBAB2B30EBAD2A5942" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interagency agreement</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Commission, the U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the Department of Agriculture shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H351A91F024974F47A02E86F2BCE19C98" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enter into a Memorandum of Understanding or other appropriate agreement for the purpose of providing consistent implementation of this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35C112E47D6E43928B7C56FCE0CC8F3D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish such agreement to provide public guidance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAB871E9D1A0450C83F15F9A25C10926" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAEDDFDCD61704220BCECE16D4BA84B29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text>A retailer or seller is not in violation of subsection (a) if—</text>
<paragraph id="HF59FAB6502D5409391AE1DCCA478CF6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a third-party manufacturer, distributor, seller, supplier, or private labeler provided the retailer or seller with a false or deceptive representation as to the country of origin of a product or its parts or processing; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24FF00E915F7416DBEFD29585A1C2DEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the retailer or seller—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9A1550DE15B2465DADF1525334F68767"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relied in good faith on that representation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H10EE21EBA4DB45E592E4EE545D215425"><enum>(B)</enum><text>took immediate action to remove any such false or deceptive representations upon notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1556E1FEE4B245C3B958007B7ADB728C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Department of Agriculture, the Food and Drug Administration, or U.S. Customs and Border Protection under any other provision of law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H05BF38FAE052411092E40ACCA8A2783B" changed="not-changed" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect 12 months after the date of the publication of the Memorandum of Understanding or agreement under subsection (b)(3).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

