<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26090-JH8-1J-K98"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 610 ATS: Congratulating the Seattle Seahawks for winning Super Bowl LX.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 610</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the Seattle Seahawks for winning Super Bowl LX.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on February 8, 2026, the Seattle Seahawks defeated the New England Patriots by a score of 29 to 13 to win Super Bowl LX in Santa Clara, California;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the game marked the second Super Bowl victory and fourth Super Bowl appearance for the Seahawks;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Seahawks finished 14–3 in the regular season, coming first in the National Football Conference (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NFC</quote>) Western Division, on their way to victories over the San Francisco 49ers in the NFC Divisional Round and the Los Angeles Rams in the NFC Championship Game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Seahawks opened up a lead in the first quarter of Super Bowl LX, which the Seahawks never relinquished throughout the game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas running back Kenneth Walker III dominated the defense of the Patriots, running 94 yards over 14 plays in the first half alone and becoming the first running back to win the honor of being named the Super Bowl Most Valuable Player in almost 30 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the unmatched <quote>Dark Side</quote> defense by the Seahawks held the Patriots scoreless through the first half of the game and forced punts on 8 of the first 9 possessions of the Patriots;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas kicker Jason Myers scored 5 field goals, setting a new record for the most field goals in a Super Bowl and becoming the first player at any position to score more than 200 points over an entire season in the history of the National Football League (referred to in this preamble as <quote>NFL</quote>), establishing a new record of 206 points, as part of a strong special teams performance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas quarterback Sam Darnold capped a strong first season with the Seahawks with a 16-yard pass to AJ Barner to score the first touchdown of the game;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas cornerback Devon Witherspoon hit the quarterback of the Patriots, Drake Maye, in the fourth quarter and forced an interception by linebacker Uchenna Nwosu, who carried the ball 45 yards to a touchdown;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the remarkable season of wide receiver Jaxon Smith-Njigba made him a unanimous All-Pro selection and the second Seahawk ever to win AP NFL Offensive Player of the Year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the second-year head coach of the Seahawks, Mike Macdonald, led his team to victory, becoming the first head coach to win a Super Bowl as the primary defensive play caller and the third-youngest head coach to win a Super Bowl;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the general manager of the Seahawks, John Schneider, who was named the NFL Executive of the Year for 2025, constructed a second Super Bowl-winning roster for the Seahawks, with entirely new players and a new head coach, becoming the first NFL executive to do so with the same organization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the chair of the Seahawks, Jody Allen, played an important role in maintaining the winning culture established by previous owners while pushing the organization to develop innovative strategies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Seahawks became the first team in NFL history to win the Super Bowl and commit 0 turnovers over the course of their full postseason;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every member of the Seahawks roster contributed to their decisive victory in Super Bowl XL; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the victory of the Seahawks would not have been possible without the support of the <quote>12s</quote>, the greatest fans in the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id22e522db76b347449621c4fff1762e00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Seattle Seahawks, their staff, and <quote>12s</quote> everywhere for the victory of the Seahawks in Super Bowl LX; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d5aa48c494b44289d96862eef4407d1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>respectfully directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text><subparagraph id="id82ee493b02444bf4832709d3a29484b5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the chair of the Seattle Seahawks, Jody Allen;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc36aa143696949238951f72d776b193f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the president of the Seattle Seahawks, Chuck Arnold, and the general manager of the Seattle Seahawks, John Schneider; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd7171e6318e4bb4a1eb45f1bca28880"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the head coach of the Seattle Seahawks, Mike Macdonald.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

