<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26027-VKM-5L-3SN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3677 IS: Dietary Supplement Listing Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3677</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To improve transparency and the availability of information regarding dietary supplements by amending the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require manufacturers of dietary supplements to list dietary supplements with the Food and Drug Administration.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dietary Supplement Listing Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida7f2ffa4159b4ed79abf4831a3473c6f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulation of dietary supplements</header><subsection id="idb0a0f43f2f38447682da25b8751cf4d4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter IV of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/341">21 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding after section 403C of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343-3">21 U.S.C. 343–3</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id156e4f1fa69d49c2b10f62b044e8466e"><section id="id33eb8d58c2d14cbc92e34bc8e7bc6bdf"><enum>403D.</enum><header>Dietary supplement listing requirement</header><subsection id="id9dbee5ccf3044309b70fc7247e9af5c2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date specified in subsection (b)(4), each dietary supplement marketed in the United States shall be listed with the Secretary in accordance with this section. Each such listing shall include, with respect to the dietary supplement, the information specified in subsection (b)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="id6baa6e90c89542dfb48f6f7afc805771"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="idcb29d200158e4dbb8b468d1016a9e137"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The manufacturer, packer, or distributor of a dietary supplement whose name (pursuant to section 403(e)(1)) appears on the label of a dietary supplement marketed in the United States (referred to in this section as the <quote>responsible person</quote>), or if the responsible person is a foreign entity, the United States agent of such person, shall submit to the Secretary in accordance with this section the following information for a dietary supplement that is marketed in the United States:</text><subparagraph id="id83261d06958640b1a5240a74c34264ca"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any name of the dietary supplement and the statement of identity, including brand name and specified flavors, if applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc760093cb4894dcc88aee52a1c1b0672"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The name and address of the responsible person and the name and email address of the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the responsible person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70d5c012cea24cc18e46fb8bedef1052"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name, domestic address, and email address for the United States agent, if the responsible person is a foreign entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6a0e6578cf34e1ea6a0ce958864a764"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The business name and place of business the responsible person provided on the label pursuant to section 403(e)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id675d263f27a1403e933eb6ea9ec56dea"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An electronic copy of the label for the dietary supplement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id98c93e64db7c4ed18af134411f8ce898"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A list of all ingredients in each such dietary supplement required under sections 101.4 and 101.36, title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), to appear on the label of a dietary supplement, including—</text><clause id="idb7dfee773ee748269635dc38ce40d4d2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>where applicable, ingredients in a proprietary blend as described in section 101.36(c) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations);</text></clause><clause id="id96e1ffe84d374ad3b9505e9a1ef81df5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount per serving of each listed dietary ingredient;</text></clause><clause id="ida902aa6d14a5476fb255b356b3de1200"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if required by section 101.36 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), the percent of the daily value of each listed dietary ingredient; and</text></clause><clause id="idc3876b2fb3eb4fd794342ee32ee990c8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the amount per serving of dietary ingredients within a proprietary blend (which shall remain confidential and not subject to public disclosure).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id71d75ec11c0a4aa1abfc769c67d1f392"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The number of servings per container for each container size.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2952ea6dab844b74bb1ce26db5c475c4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The directions for use.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86cb741c801246df9c39c3ed11011a0c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Warnings, notice, and safe handling statements, as required by section 101.17 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4dca02d3030e4601b7a128744df472a4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Allergen statements for major food allergens (pursuant to sections 403(w) and 403(x)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb4115690a4a14f30863efa7e3ff8c7c3"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The form of the dietary supplement (such as tablets, capsules, powders, liquids, softgels, and gummies).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc34fab0da76a4c98818192879b365d2e"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Any claim that appears on the label or package insert that—</text><clause id="id0b99b700181542eb9819a6924e380fa9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>characterizes the relationship of any ingredient to a disease or a health-related condition and is described in section 403(r)(1)(B); or</text></clause><clause id="idbb62602e6a654fd8a9d1035d31cc23df"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is subject to notification under section 403(r)(6), provided that no additional listing or change to listing information is required under this paragraph for any minor variation or modification to a claim for which notification under section 403(r)(6) is not required.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id893cb3c2c0104c15898b4f2774fb8fc4"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The dietary supplement product listing number for the dietary supplement provided by the Secretary in accordance with subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2202012b946e42929e876dfe7e88db4a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Format; notification of receipt</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85d5db1159c546828da36bcb64d42a38"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Format</header><text>The Secretary may require that a listing submitted under paragraph (1) be submitted in an electronic format.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida77fef6aef9640db818bd37e75e3a94a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification of receipt</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id090c4ddee60641b7b61ce7883c293904"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of a listing under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall promptly notify the responsible person of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc58618b2de14d33b4dde13ac66a63b1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the receipt of a complete listing; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84956189ae76476f80c7af7d847be5c1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the receipt of a listing that is not complete, together with a statement describing the reasons why the listing is not complete.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65ef5c86e9ca4970aadb68ad8ede29cb"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Complete receipts described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A listing under paragraph (1) is deemed complete once all fields of required information have been completed by the responsible person who represents that the product will be marketed in the United States as a dietary supplement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e2edab754624566b9fbbc00c1b2e327"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Listing content</header><text>A single listing submission for a dietary supplement under paragraph (1) may include multiple dietary supplements with identical formulations and forms, or formulations of the same form, that differ only with respect to color, excipients, or flavorings, whether offered in a single package size or in multiple package sizes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8265ce19b8b74231a4c0e4f82b9d8b32"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph id="idc292b68a1a794b6a94d8730ad901da6a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause id="id540213478d3643438179ca1b82b62094"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Dietary supplements on the market</header><text>In the case of a dietary supplement that is being offered in interstate commerce on or before January 1, 2027, a listing for each such dietary supplement introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce shall be submitted by the responsible person to the Secretary under this subsection not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Dietary Supplement Listing Act of 2026</short-title>.</text></clause><clause id="idd9d71c34bcf74105a059d3b798c94696"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>New dietary supplements</header><text>In the case of a dietary supplement that is not being offered in interstate commerce on or before January 1, 2027, a listing for each such dietary supplement introduced or delivered for introduction into interstate commerce that has not been included in any listing previously submitted by the responsible person to the Secretary under this subsection shall be submitted to the Secretary at the time of introduction into interstate commerce.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id048785e58657401ca2fac4f007cba6a4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Discontinued dietary supplements</header><text>The responsible person shall notify the Secretary not later than 1 year after the date the responsible person discontinues the introduction into interstate commerce of a dietary supplement required to be listed with the Secretary under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92c371cdfa8143c389b76348a6e2ea44"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Changes to existing listings</header><text>The responsible person shall submit to the Secretary any change or modification to listing information submitted under paragraph (1) included on the label of a dietary supplement not later than 30 days after the dietary supplement with the change or modification is first introduced into interstate commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id915af4d2e3bb40409ec975eb97dd6d77"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>The responsible person shall provide, upon request from the Secretary, not later than 10 calendar days after such request—</text><subparagraph id="id1b9d9af8838a4d4a863796ec7c262fa2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the full business name and physical and mailing address of all locations at which the responsible person manufactures, packages, labels, or holds the dietary supplement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4e648c87737744b28ed0436958d6a0aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the full business name and physical and mailing address from which the responsible person receives a dietary ingredient or combination of dietary ingredients that the responsible person uses in the manufacture of the dietary supplement or, if applicable, from which the responsible person receives the dietary supplement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5ae5df7fd70041b383c23fc1fdc96a2f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Product listing number and dietary supplement electronic database</header><paragraph id="iddb9fb6c697514c0883111b6a91c49f36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dietary supplement product listing number</header><text>The Secretary shall provide each dietary supplement listed in accordance with subsection (b)(1) a dietary supplement product listing number, which may apply to multiple dietary supplements with identical formulations, or formulations that differ only with respect to color, excipients, or flavorings, including dietary supplements offered in a single package size or in multiple package sizes. The Secretary shall provide a process for a responsible person to reserve dietary supplement listing numbers in advance of listing under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0d153770338642e0936ae197672703c9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Electronic database</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Dietary Supplement Listing Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish and maintain an electronic database that is publicly available and contains information submitted under subsection (b)(1) (except for the information submitted under subparagraph (B), (C), and (F)(iv) of such subsection). The Secretary shall make such information maintained in the electronic database publicly searchable, including by dietary supplement product listing number, and by any field of information or combination of fields of information provided under subsection (b)(1) (except for the information submitted under subparagraph (B), (C), and (F)(iv) of such subsection).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60bb1cf60f814692a6745a4a62d5a470"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidential information</header><text>In response to a request under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, information described in subparagraph (B), (C), and (F)(iv) of subsection (b)(1) that is derived from a listing under this section, and information described in subparagraph (b)(5), shall be withheld under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2fe79eceb13b48c883679f2aa3b85cd0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="id5c2bfd57f33347e4a43b7f2ffd305ce6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit the authority of the Secretary to inspect or copy records or to require the establishment and maintenance of records under any other provision of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0938e9a0457e4645959f9107f5183c2b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to authorize the disclosure of information that is prohibited from disclosure under section 301(j) of this Act or section 1905 of title 18, United States Code, or that is subject to withholding under section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb0e742af18e4a0787c5cebad2ebad7b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to authorize or permit the release in the public database, or to make subject to disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, information that discloses the identity or location of a specific registered person or facility not identified on the label, or the quantity of any individual ingredients in a proprietary blend; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id852d3236fedc44a485663a717162a6ae"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to grant the Secretary authority to require the approval of a dietary supplement prior to marketing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd92f48bcac2e4af5ab75b479b285ea9f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $7,872,984 for fiscal year 2026, and $6,615,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030, for purposes of conducting the activities under this section and hiring personnel required to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id53b59b5028184fed8dbb52ebaaece819"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Misbranding</header><text>Section 403 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/343">21 U.S.C. 343</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a976afd77014f349101f7a281d520ed"><subsection id="id12b59a771c364401a09f50d5a66dfd8b"><enum>(z)</enum><text>If it is a dietary supplement for which a responsible person or the United States agent of such a person is required under section 403D to file a listing, file a change to an existing listing, or provide additional information to the Secretary, and such person or agent has failed to comply with any such requirements under section 403D with respect to such dietary supplement.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id040377f152d74376b71b818c80425523"><enum>(c)</enum><header>New prohibited act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide723f3e75f8547a68764cabedb905cc4"><subsection id="id6a6c182c62c04843b311af802709107f"><enum>(jjj)</enum><text>The introduction or delivery for introduction into interstate commerce of a dietary supplement that has been prepared, packed, or held using the assistance of, or at the direction of, a person debarred under section 306.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

