<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3DF9964607694D4A9752883857A82BE6" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 905 IH: Supporting the designation of November 2025 as “National Homeless Children and Youth Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 905</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of November 2025 as <quote>National Homeless Children and Youth Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, public schools identified nearly 1,400,000 enrolled homeless children and youth during the 2022 to 2023 school year, a 14-percent increase from the previous school year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, every year, an estimated 1,200,000 children younger than 6 years of age, and approximately 4,200,000 youth and young adults, experience homelessness, with many of those children, youth, and young adults staying on couches, in motels, in shelters, or outside;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Housing and Urban Development reported a 39-percent increase in families staying in homeless shelters or visibly on the streets in 2024, which was the highest of any population and the second consecutive year of increase;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas infants experiencing homelessness are at a higher risk for certain illnesses and health conditions;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas families experiencing homelessness are more likely to experience involvement in the child welfare system and difficulty with school attendance;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more than 48 percent of students that experienced homelessness during the 2022 to 2023 school year were chronically absent, a rate 22 percent higher than other students;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, high school students experiencing homelessness were nearly twice as likely to have seriously considered suicide or made a suicide plan and more than 3 times as likely to have made a suicide attempt within the past year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas individuals without a high school degree or general educational development certificate are over 4.5 times more likely to report homelessness than their peers who completed high school, making lack of education the leading risk factor for homelessness;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2022, the high school graduation rate for students experiencing homelessness was 68 percent, compared to 80 percent for low-income students and 85.5 percent for all students;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the rate of youth homelessness is the same in rural, suburban, and urban areas;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas 29 percent of unaccompanied homeless youth between 13 and 25 years of age have spent time in foster care, compared to approximately 6 percent of all children;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas homelessness among children and youth is a complex issue that often occurs with deep poverty, low education and employment levels, substance misuse and use disorders, mental health disorders, lack of affordable housing, and family conflict; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas awareness of child and youth homelessness must be heightened to encourage greater support for effective programs to help children and youth overcome homelessness: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5095586EBBB14A68873F33AB896A9E50"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF5A5D23E857F49FBBA6D54E505FD3D6E"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H80B040471CF44C398278D1EFDF14C786"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the efforts of businesses, governments, organizations, educators, and volunteers dedicated to meeting the needs of homeless children and youth;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BA44A85A40942F4B2107C937C344D89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>applauds the initiatives of businesses, governments, organizations, educators, and volunteers that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H642BAAB4081B41D588CDF607D793C8D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use time and resources to raise awareness of child and youth homelessness, the causes of child and youth homelessness, and potential solutions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99D9A7E88C2B4E51B71AC1B8680A9557"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work to prevent homelessness among children and youth;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44B70C9D61404AF980A2B695B88DB072"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the designation a <quote>National Homeless Children and Youth Awareness Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36218BBE1AF94050B2E864E2C8F0D0A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages businesses, governments, organizations, educators, and volunteers to continue to intensify their efforts to address homelessness among children and youth during National Homeless Children and Youth Awareness Month.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

