<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7CBD2C7E2F334148B549CACE23D4C050" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7752 IH: Kelsey Smith Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7752</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, to require emergency disclosure of location information to law enforcement or public safety answering point.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H648DDEE36AA049729374DE34E0EB633E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF394A57CBC7D41E39D00E3ECDF721564" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kelsey Smith Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HDF8DFB8BCC4341FB820F75C046EAD23D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Required emergency disclosure of location information to law enforcement or public safety answering point</header> 
<subsection id="H2020F5601ACC4C0FB9A9BBA07D824880"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2510 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB27C751D2E0F4D89829BEB0A5D224C78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (20), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E308421158E406D820A5C8EBBB5B06D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (21), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H063306B84C074292802574EC810786F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HE305C93AD4BD4C4F8E9D1883AC1299D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HB5F6BA26FE4146A6AA0E5253BF12A89D"><enum>(22)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> the term <quote>location information</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="HCDE773742C854BEE83179D966CBB2BDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any data or information concerning the current or most recently known location of a telecommunications device that, in whole or in part, is generated, derived from, or obtained by the operation of the device; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8BD22F79F2742DF8335F05478556770"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the contents of any wire or electronic communication;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBB9BAFCE8484506AA1F14C6B22E7592"> <enum>(23)</enum> <text>the term <quote>telecommunications device</quote> means any customer premises equipment (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/153">47 U.S.C. 153</external-xref>)); and</text>
                        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3461B797066C4162AECF451FD37654EA"><enum>(24)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>public safety answering point</quote> shall have the meaning given such term in section 7 of the Wireless Communications and Public Safety Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/615b">47 U.S.C. 615b</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCAC04318A2E1433CB0DA6D415112E8E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required emergency disclosure of location information to law enforcement or public safety answering point</header><text>Section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HADEE591FF45E4AFEA1CDCB556FE3291E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HA95C0618320D4388B022845605E720E8"><enum>(i)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H19F6245AD15347B5A01319EE0E20D4E3" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Location information requests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the request of an investigative or law enforcement officer, or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point acting on behalf of such an officer, who is acting in the course of the official duties of such officer, a provider of electronic communication service shall provide to such officer the available location information of a telecommunications device without delay if the officer asserts—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D967630B0E14BD3A0670CCDDA38C2ED" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause id="HB7BDBF3F4F20450CA1684EFDF9BEC2E3" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the telecommunications device was used to contact a public safety answering point requesting emergency assistance during the preceding 48-hour period; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H038B0A5C90FA43F4AC2312B453290D09" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the officer has reasonable suspicion that the telecommunications device is in the possession or presence of an individual who is involved in an emergency situation that involves the risk of death or serious physical harm; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BA88FCEAEAE41318A8F73AD1601256A" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="H0EC541554B5C41589A1C534CE1D116C4" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the subscriber or customer of such electronic telecommunication service has consented to such request or, if such subscriber or customer is not reasonably available, then the next of kin of such subscriber or customer has consented; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H131504EC5677407C817CA04E52143D4F"><enum>(ii)</enum> 
<subclause id="H6EA4CD834824469F8D50BCE2AA4E40D1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reasonable efforts have been made to obtain such consent or the consent of next of kin of such subscriber or customer;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H88B156DBF0F349AB9CBC21031DBF44AA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such consent was neither obtained nor refused; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H316E2E6B91D64BD09C93029D803A1655"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such officer reasonably believes delay in providing the available location information may increase the risk of death or serious physical harm.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H419EF31151A04533924F559EB8781DD7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Records of disclosed records</header><text>If an investigative or law enforcement officer, or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point acting on behalf of such an officer, submits a request for location information to a provider of an electronic communication service under paragraph (1) the investigative or law enforcement agency employing the officer shall maintain a record of the request that includes each of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1025A99ECCB2481794D1C5FC13CEDB53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of the officer or agent making the request (and, in the case of a request made by an agent, the name of the officer on whose behalf the agent is acting).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7600A0EA547E48ADB7CB9F2F0460A232"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A declaration that disclosure of location information is needed based on the conditions described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (1)(A) and that the requirements of clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (1)(B) have been satisfied.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA580BEF9557C45728D7B18977B417C28"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description—</text> <clause id="H91F3A08A63364EB1A718908551882DA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the request that explains the need for disclosure of location information; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE44ADFC0AC6429E8DD4B709A6B01C2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>of the manner and the name of the person by whom the consent required by clause (i) of subparagraph (1)(B) was given or of the reasonable efforts required by clause (ii) of subparagraph (1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5108C43281624E85A4800BA7C719947C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header> <subparagraph id="H03C1D50C5CA749AB9628342BCC34BFA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall exempt a telecommunications carrier or a provider of electronic communication service from complying with any applicable State law that requires the carrier or provider to provide location information of a telecommunications device to an investigative or law enforcement officer or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point acting on behalf of such an officer in response to a request by such officer or agent.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6E42492D45A54712AF114701DFE02A7D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>A circumstance described in this subparagraph is a circumstance in which the officer or agent—</text> <clause id="H136BBBB04E594567A51AD22C35C04FA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>makes the request while acting in the course of the official duties of the officer or agent; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6902581F7FCF420C8099CE688E15A9C1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>asserts that the request is made for the purpose of responding to—</text> <subclause id="H02072EE463794EAD98CF74E3C4684AE2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a call for emergency services; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H85A0FD6AE6DA48AFA4CE31DA6D27F5C9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an emergency situation that involves the risk of death or serious physical harm.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00EAFBC3059040E69CBE5370C9A078C2" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Next of kin determination</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, a next of kin determination shall be made in the following priority order:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H62D4D5EAD68442778659E222494691BE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Legal spouse.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78547193082D465AB710115917831344" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Child (whether by current or prior marriage) age 18 years or older in descending precedence by age.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03E63B7BDF134E8C86856BB3A5F1A4A8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Father or mother, unless by court order custody has been vested in another (adoptive parent takes precedence over natural parent).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A403AB4AB9C4472949B73F7FDDDAF0C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Sibling (whole or half) age 18 years or older in descending precedence by age.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8363FFB1C0844D08A9FB9BD5C8B55AA6" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Grandfather or grandmother.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF5310CB268D49F9950E71531DA884A5" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other relative (precedence to be determined in accordance with the civil law of descent in the State in which the investigative or law enforcement officer is employed).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

