<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL26736-FJP-4X-YPR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4591 RS: Nurture Originals, Foster Art, and Keep Entertainment Safe Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 446</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To protect intellectual property rights in the voice and visual likeness of individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSJU00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nurture Originals, Foster Art, and Keep Entertainment Safe Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NO FAKES Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida73d99b8be4f44b5b4186ebb6dd6dbc2" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSJU00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Voice and visual likeness rights</header><subsection id="iddc918feb49de4113bfae728eae11c52b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id063ac77e72fc4b1b8a99f90cc15a55ef"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital fingerprint</header><text>The term <term>digital fingerprint</term> means an electronic label or identifier created by a cryptographic hash function (or similar function), or any other digital process, tool, or technique selected by the provider of an online service, that is unique to a specific piece of material such that it is effectively certain that such piece of material will not be misidentified as a match for a different piece of material.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7985b6b0b55f48c397a83a40eb8ba481"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital replica</header><text>The term <term>digital replica</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3843dfaf808a454982904154817cd03c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a newly created, computer-generated, highly realistic electronic representation that is readily identifiable as the voice or visual likeness of an individual that—</text><clause id="id3db434c0546e46069de3f164bbe4d62d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is embodied in a sound recording, image, audiovisual work, including an audiovisual work that does not have any accompanying sounds, or transmission—</text><subclause id="idd8f1ee761b5b4b5c889ed71fb1e5a7a2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in which the actual individual did not actually perform or appear; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id1f896e9de67f4f26b8dd5c5e3695c431"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that is a version of a sound recording, image, or audiovisual work in which the actual individual did perform or appear, in which the fundamental character of the performance or appearance has been materially altered; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06ac544fc9cf4089a3aa2e78f61e369d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the electronic reproduction, use of a sample of one sound recording or audiovisual work into another, remixing, mastering, or digital remastering of a sound recording or audiovisual work authorized by the copyright holder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ideee8f3e82b0143fcb4542defbd0f9717"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individual</header><text>The term <term>individual</term> means a human being, living or dead.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3bf6697252e74dcc8138f6a792faa042"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interactive computer service</header><text>The term <term>interactive computer service</term> means any information service, system, or access software provider that provides or enables computer access by multiple users to a computer server, including specifically—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8b5cd0d9ee15437596e9dcb73998d524"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a service or system that provides access to the internet; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id252a840156e74c37a5a949658907ac4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such systems operated, or services offered, by libraries or educational institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb585eac78842426886ce5c3116acc1fd"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Online service</header><text>The term <term>online service</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18a19e5291b049e3ae547ea75a425899"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means—</text><clause id="id40741d47e4564319946937cd2a100ec3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any website, online application, mobile application, or virtual reality environment that predominantly provides public access to user uploaded material;</text></clause><clause id="ide4b683cab00b40ac82922158fa705e6e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any digital music provider to which section 115 of title 17, United States Code, applies, to the extent that the digital music provider provides public access to a significant amount of sound recordings that are predominantly the fixation of sounds of a performance of a musical composition and are user uploaded material, if that digital music provider is not covered under clause (i); and</text></clause><clause id="id14f970f68412417d93acad3c6559e284"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any online application, mobile application, virtual reality environment, application store, search engine (including any feature that provides web search results), advertising service or network, online shopping service or platform, electronic commerce provider, mapping service, cloud storage service, aggregator of visual and audiovisual works for licensing, or website hosting service or any other interactive computer service that is not covered under clause (i), and is not a digital music provider to which section 115 of title 17, United States Code, applies, but only if the provider of that interactive computer service has registered a designated agent with the Copyright Office under subsection (d)(2); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id786a24715b3b451dade5857982237845"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any website, online application, mobile application, virtual reality environment, application store, cloud storage service, or search engine, if the primary function of that website, online application, mobile application, virtual reality environment, application store, cloud storage service, or search engine is to distribute, import, transmit, or otherwise make available to the public a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b3f6504a1d74a1b98c63220634477ae"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Right holder</header><text>The term <term>right holder</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9f8a167614945bfaba3689b7f957b67"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual, the voice or visual likeness of whom is at issue with respect to a digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33edbc89208f4f558cc86e06f50bc5df"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other individual or entity that has acquired, through a license, inheritance, or otherwise, the right to authorize the use of the voice or visual likeness described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1fad82d7d8e947d494b7fb7fb6a60630"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sound recording artist</header><text>The term <term>sound recording artist</term> means an individual who creates or performs in sound recordings for economic gain or for the livelihood of the individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e333a6f72f740d49b9c536ca074e902"><enum>(8)</enum><header>User uploaded material</header><text>The term <term>user uploaded material</term> means material, such as a video, image, game, audio file, or other similar material, that is placed on a service directly by, or at the direction of, a consumer end user of a service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id45920e64fcfa42138538e28a21d19686"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Digital replication right</header><paragraph id="idb9709ffe6edd42b795f0523a1b80368a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the other provisions of this section, each individual or right holder shall have the right to authorize the use of the voice or visual likeness of the individual—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1dc95276998647c682dfb7cf7a29d9a9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a digital replica; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46cba0a0d31f460ebadc770a88fd1a7e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in connection with a product or service for which authorization of the individual or right holder is required to avoid liability with respect to an activity described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6f9c6754d1841d39a920ea5a30f82cd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nature of right</header><subparagraph id="idaf5f75b850b84ba69f1af7b50d9a6023"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The right described in paragraph (1) shall have the following characteristics:</text><clause id="idcaea58c04dff44f28639c3446670e073"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The right is—</text><subclause id="id7ce15985a908448487e077efe0c68405"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a property right;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd28af568476f426f931a219326b7e7af"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not assignable during the life of the individual; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb5e704e3c73e4953aa4c15772a4fcf73"><enum>(III)</enum><text>licensable, in whole or in part, exclusively or non-exclusively, by the right holder.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id39c13f69b9da468189eb5bd7f0b3d768"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The right shall not expire upon the death of the individual, without regard to whether the right is commercially exploited by the individual during the lifetime of the individual.</text></clause><clause id="iddbdc32fed718491e834bfb28ec845391"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Upon the death of the individual—</text><subclause id="id962067db9352415f907d56776c6b45ca"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the right is transferable and licensable, in whole or in part, by the executors, heirs, assignees, licensees, or devisees of the individual; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ida93dc6b047114eeeab746e87b242e245"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ownership of the right may be—</text><item id="iddbad347aab3c4ebabd439af9c1cfc211"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>transferred, in whole or in part, by any means of conveyance or by operation of law; and</text></item><item id="id358d23f3896e49d79521d2cf6322ba01"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>bequeathed by will or pass as personal property by the applicable laws of intestate succession.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id341e14fef29a4dbdb52a9033a4330408"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The right shall be exclusive to—</text><subclause id="id41b1907fa8ea47fe96da9995919ca37a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the individual, subject to the licensing of the right during the lifetime of that individual under subparagraph (B); and</text></subclause><subclause id="id4986915ddbac40a0856cbdd024b21696"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the right holder—</text><item id="id6726b88198dc46d1b9ed32f29fbcce67"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for a period of 10 years after the death of the individual; and</text></item><item id="idbf1a53dda92448aeb551eaf4fb5f7f1c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if the right holder demonstrates active and authorized public use of the voice or visual likeness of the individual in interstate or foreign commerce during the 2-year period preceding the expiration of the 10-year period described in item (aa), for an additional 5-year period, subject to renewal for additional 5-year periods, provided the right holder can demonstrate authorized public use of the voice or visual likeness of the individual in interstate or foreign commerce during the 2-year period preceding the expiration of each additional 5-year period.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idd4fb9f0896b143a8ac4726ade444821e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The right shall terminate on the date that is the earlier of—</text><subclause id="idca0d9a722ada4e83963c03b2b1c38eb9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date on which the 10-year period or 5-year period described in clause (iv)(II) terminates without renewal; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id863996ad8aa0478cbf06c3a5188d97d3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date that is 70 years after the death of the individual.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id038cf87ebe9b423bb0160c2b5d382210"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for license</header><clause id="id72ec9c1019504700987075d600acc420"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A license described in subparagraph (A)(i)(III)—</text><subclause id="idb00b16cd24fd431fb0af9a9fe78e99ab"><enum>(I)</enum><text>while the individual is living, is valid only to the extent that the license duration does not exceed 10 years; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide80f10d6341d4e87b67f4c0540b8d968"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be valid only if the license agreement—</text><item id="id4ac21fcba4e5483babecdd6927e97dfc"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is in writing and signed by the individual or an authorized representative of the individual; and</text></item><item id="id63cd52e109534d09a0a5286ed65064f2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>includes a reasonably specific description of the intended uses of the applicable digital replica.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idd64460164ef542749fbebe8b5ef43e9e"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Licenses involving a minor</header><text>A license described in subparagraph (A)(i)(III) involving a living individual who is younger than 18 years of age—</text><subclause id="id17cc715f109b42c38546e619d42d2b26"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is valid only to the extent that the license duration does not exceed 5 years, but in any case terminates when the individual reaches 18 years of age; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id699d0f179e5948968d2a910f05a7788b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be valid only if the license agreement—</text><item id="id579592c567f54e66b74676a377373627"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is in writing and signed by the individual or an authorized representative of the individual;</text></item><item id="id3416eaca830a4f02966ae711a6796510"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>includes a reasonably specific description of the intended uses of the digital replica; and</text></item><item id="idd7187ce956854fceb2d69ffcdc9ba6d5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>is approved by a court in accordance with applicable State law.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id83d95fea84f74ac0b1282aa02c653283"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Collective bargaining agreements</header><text>The provisions of clauses (i) and (ii) shall not apply with respect to a license if the license is governed by a collective bargaining agreement that addresses digital replicas.</text></clause><clause id="idd97bb6e564b446949e3ea2568c96e5be"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The provisions of clauses (i) and (ii) shall not affect terms and conditions of a license or related contract other than those described in this subparagraph, and the expiration of that license shall not affect the remainder of the license or related contract.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0573540d1c394c9aa6350449da700e7c"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements for post-mortem transfer</header><text>A post-mortem transfer or license described in subparagraph (A)(iii)(I) shall be valid only if the transfer agreement or license agreement is in writing and signed by the right holder or an authorized representative of the right holder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id83f79d3266244f4a83176bd4546c9c92"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Registration for post-mortem renewal</header><clause id="ide68707a546a14516a36c68105940322e"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The renewal of a post-mortem right under subparagraph (A)(iv)(II)(bb) shall be effective if, during the applicable 2-year renewal period described in that subparagraph, the right holder files a notice with the Register of Copyrights that complies with such requirements regarding form and filing procedures as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation, which shall include—</text><subclause id="idc6e15764d90e4b70b8c335ff04d473e9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the name of the deceased individual;</text></subclause><subclause id="idc452053df9a446f09f0e76fb06dbde8a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a statement, under penalty of perjury, that the right holder has engaged in active and authorized public use of the voice or visual likeness in interstate or foreign commerce during the applicable 2-year period;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7941075d3b304065be9ed63566283d76"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the identity of and contact information for the right holder; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idbdb3227b6d8046efa073654fcabc7f92"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>such other information as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id60c2596a53614135abd95fcb7b95dc76"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Directory</header><text>The Register of Copyrights—</text><subclause id="id6ee6dbb0d59841409e1eb498407df3bf"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall—</text><item id="idb27d90f49c4f4f358cc42e247457a77c"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>maintain a current directory of post-mortem digital replication rights registered under this subparagraph; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10fc6ec814704390b3ce76c78f421d75"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the directory described in item (aa) available to the public for inspection online; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="ida4fd49f1d669451f8f8853d75e01dacf"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may require payment of a reasonable filing fee by the right holder filing notice under clause (i), which may take into consideration the costs of maintaining the directory described in subclause (I) of this clause.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id45cc0469e78c44a8992f45b6046a9814"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Voluntary initial registration</header><subclause id="id1b0226fc22094f11adc5bb1906a21237"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A right holder may voluntarily register the post-mortem right under subparagraph (A)(iv)(II)(aa) by filing a notice with the Register of Copyrights that complies with such requirements regarding form, content, and filing procedures as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation.</text></subclause><subclause id="ide9c75fbbed20452b8f9a6546e5ae0d1a"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authority of Register of Copyrights</header><text>The Register of Copyrights may—</text><item id="id3366679674fe48bba5fa5f7a16a79ede"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>include a voluntary registration of the post-mortem right under subparagraph (A)(iv)(II)(aa) in the directory maintained under clause (ii)(I)(aa) of this subparagraph; and</text></item><item id="id5b2b790887d24dfb9c35ba407000b114"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>require payment of a reasonable filing fee by a right holder registering a right under this clause, which may take into consideration the costs of maintaining the directory.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idb3104dadaa054c6689c9411fd3f3973f"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Authority of Register of Copyrights</header><text>The Register of Copyrights may make such interpretations and resolve such ambiguities as may be appropriate to carry out this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a14feac8d01402abf4de2e039619b89"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Post-expiration or termination utilization of authorized uses</header><text>A digital replica that is embodied in a sound recording, image, audiovisual work, including an audiovisual work that does not have any accompanying sounds, or transmission, and the use of which is authorized pursuant to the terms of a license, may continue to be utilized in a manner consistent with the terms of that license after the expiration or termination of the license.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddc3e4cdb03fb4aef876945d44e4aa99d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Liability</header><paragraph id="id07ce1f02b55c4de7a7a9dd77fdfc9b04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual or entity that, in a manner affecting interstate or foreign commerce (or using any means or facility of interstate or foreign commerce), engages in an activity described in paragraph (2) shall be liable in a civil action brought under subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d351ffe600a4c639ab1f8cfca8e572d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>An activity described in this paragraph is either of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id696a6d5f35df4c5b810342b82d7fefc9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The public display, distribution, transmission, or communication of, or the act of otherwise making available to the public, including by acting as a third party commercial supplier of sound recordings to a digital music provider, a digital replica without authorization by the applicable right holder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd60104697b164b859046b20fd14000fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Distributing, importing, transmitting, or otherwise making available to the public a product or service that—</text><clause id="idad969a0049df4ed99d17357940639d14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is primarily designed to produce 1 or more digital replicas of a specifically identified individual or individuals without the authorization of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id396f50eab2474be6bf251f455f311307"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual or individuals;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd3fd306cecd24a02916236ff1f181a24"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable right holder; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1aa452089a77419b8466462a9a6be37d"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb1d31b16f31841a7bb5f8ae2ec8e9075"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has only limited commercially significant purpose or use other than to produce a digital replica of a specifically identified individual or individuals without the authorization of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c1c897eaca347aeae8f80e07bac1fd5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual or individuals;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad68b110565b478eb081c099a081c488"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable right holder; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd70feafb1423419bae52c1eb1262a048"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6c90f157602f4f5dac32bc7f512b4f8b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is marketed, advertised, or otherwise promoted by the individual or entity described in paragraph (1), or another individual or entity acting in concert with the individual or entity described in paragraph (1) with the knowledge of the individual or entity described in paragraph (1), as a product or service designed to produce a digital replica of a specifically identified individual or individuals without the authorization of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc098e45a962744a29edaa0db107168bd"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual or individuals;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42d5a7d4ac6b4cf198a9dfd1ed066bd0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable right holder; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62baf88b360e4c90b206f81dfaf848aa"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id539a40c4e2d74192b0daa86bfa34d5ae"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice or knowledge required</header><text>To incur liability under this subsection, the following shall apply:</text><subparagraph id="idb6dea22972a94f23aebbd99448c33578"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idd2a7cc08b5824aab9368e0af1783df2c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>With respect to an activity carried out under paragraph (2) by the provider of an online service described in clause (ii), the designated agent with respect to the provider must have received a notification that satisfies the requirements under subsection (d)(3), or a court order stating, or must have willfully avoided receipt of such a notification or court order, that the applicable material is—</text><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a1ba18fa3f245e3b9b87bdee52fed18"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a digital replica that was not authorized by the applicable right holder; or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34e4023c756c4643b182d34418306bd9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a product or service described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide2bf02fc16b34b02ad2f00dc6dc43903"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An online service described in this clause is an online service that is—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41f0b71dd00b4080934a3b52b679d75b"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(i);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0891f822ce244a34905244a824f38288"><enum>(II)</enum><text>described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(ii), with respect to sound recordings that are predominantly the fixation of sounds of a performance of a musical composition and are user uploaded material; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffe6de7b9114416bb61bc935bcacf5ce"><enum>(III)</enum><text>described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(iii), with respect to material placed on that online service by or at the direction of a third party.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1c8397438104e0ca6031f66c4156069"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to an activity carried out under paragraph (2) by an individual or entity that is not an online service, or an activity carried out under paragraph (2) by the provider of an online service that is not described in subparagraph (A)(ii), the individual or entity must have actual knowledge, or must willfully avoid having such knowledge, that the applicable material is—</text><clause id="id5f08cc70f2c8438b9efa8778935cbe11"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a digital replica that was not authorized by the applicable right holder; or</text></clause><clause id="id85bff2fb5f82456288b0c9aefb817085"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a product or service described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaacc8b845a284444884eabc2990ccb53"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Liability under this subsection shall not extend to—</text><subparagraph id="id193ae789fc1242ceb9b72071ae116263"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a service by wire or radio that provides the capability to transmit data to and receive data from all, or substantially all, internet endpoints, including any capabilities that are incidental to enable the operation of the communications service of a provider of online services or network access, or the operator of facilities for such service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf03bb9a17a2e4e0c89220c27a6fc526b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a provider of an online service described in paragraph (3)(A)(ii) alleged to have undertaken an activity described in paragraph (2) if—</text><clause id="idaee64fa723e94a61ad1e9b88669d0f13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it is not technologically or practically feasible for that provider to disable access to the offending material, or disable the reference or link to that material, at the specific location identified in the applicable notification sent under subsection (d)(3); or</text></clause><clause id="ide3f706f06364485d90708078a3642708"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disabling access to the offending material is prohibited by law;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf754c14ebef64464b9c2284ba6e2f862"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit library or archives—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2333e3116ed34fd5a6154b992734a623"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is eligible for the limitations on exclusive rights under section 108 of title 17, United States Code;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ea8b41a19fd437fb7b7bfe725562fae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the collections of which are—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7673bb5891934aa5a8c9f4b2ad316148"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">open to the public; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0737a2f6979a41029eca17e773fea1b2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>available not only to researchers affiliated with the library or archives, or with the institution of which the library or archives is a part, but also to other persons doing research in a specialized field;</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id157991929763427294f4dcb4fa4c3fbb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that has a public service mission;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd76973ce5e84d1e852fc98f803a980c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the trained staff or volunteers of which provide professional services normally associated with libraries and archives; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ea455b2618b4219bb458d3d82b849ee"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the collections of which are composed of lawfully acquired or licensed materials that are made available consistent with the requirements of title 17, United States Code;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec40b913546f4ed7a89e4cbbc252d59f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an accredited nonprofit educational institution with respect to an activity undertaken without any purpose of direct or indirect commercial advantage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fe9f63d530c478996f01cba45b7065a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an employee of an institution described in subparagraph (C) or (D) acting within the scope of the employment of that individual;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49a42f74ceab4ec880eb57556f511df8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other person solely with respect to providing online or network access services to an institution described in subparagraph (C) or (D) in the course of providing those services to that institution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id634193210e5543d097b98eda5dc93045"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an individual or entity that is not an online service, if, upon obtaining actual knowledge of an activity described in paragraph (2), the individual or entity acts as soon as technologically and practically feasible to remove or disable access to the applicable material.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idde5066bc0b1242af95ada41b4a139351"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional exclusions</header><subparagraph id="id4c203218278e4e4fb5692e8ae2067d83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An activity shall not be considered to be an activity described in paragraph (2) if—</text><clause id="id02465713a85e483baec451bfd120edc2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is produced or used in a bona fide news, public affairs, or sports broadcast or account, provided that the digital replica is the subject of, or is materially relevant to, the subject of that broadcast or account;</text></clause><clause id="idd48bb34ca9144595a5a1ab3273bfdab9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is a representation of the applicable individual as the individual in a documentary or in a historical or biographical manner, including some degree of fictionalization, unless—</text><subclause id="id139487712f794f72b12087701d84b3a7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the production or use of that digital replica creates the false impression that the work is an authentic sound recording, image, transmission, or audiovisual work in which the individual participated; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id8bf642f9bd0a4a4fb1c4a838c944bf70"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the digital replica is embodied in a musical sound recording that is synchronized to accompany a motion picture or other audiovisual work, except to the extent that the use of that digital replica is protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id84601c25366148f490ff8d15fd4f99f7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is produced or used consistent with the public interest in bona fide commentary, criticism, scholarship, satire, or parody;</text></clause><clause id="idf778b6bed77e4331be5d930f7d691fe3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the use of the applicable digital replica is fleeting or negligible; or</text></clause><clause id="idab7f279c99c043fb883a9defac77d4b2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is used in an advertisement or commercial announcement for a purpose described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) and the applicable digital replica is relevant to the subject of the work so advertised or announced.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8c68ba6f099b403d9c9c7be47069f29b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply where the applicable digital replica is used to depict sexually explicit conduct, as defined in section 2256(2)(A) of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0688f9459fd4e07bd4ba40ef410624d"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Voluntary use of tools to remove or disable access</header><text>The voluntary use of any tool to remove or disable access to content shall not alone confer actual knowledge of a particular violation of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1e22d21e32c042bb9ee8310d2c9a63a9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safe harbors</header><paragraph id="ide89a23ac887f4ecb8f06f3fb6a5e47af"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="id9c9980cc1fcf4e1b931dff19eab754b6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Products and services capable of producing digital replicas</header><text>No individual or entity shall be directly or secondarily liable under this section for an activity described in subsection (c)(2)(A) by virtue of distributing, importing, transmitting, or otherwise making available to the public a product or service unless the product or service is a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbef7acdbdf234b48ada4b38c9aa034b1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Online services</header><text>The provider of an online service shall not be liable for an activity that violates subsection (c), or for referring or linking to the material containing an unauthorized digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), if—</text><clause id="id215b6cafd38043c985b7e92f0b73fab7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the provider of an online service described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(iii) (other than a search engine or a search component of a service), the provider has adopted and reasonably implemented, and has informed users of the online service of, a policy that provides for the termination in appropriate circumstances of account holders of the online service that are repeat violators of subsection (c)(2), provided that the failure to terminate a particular account holder in accordance with that policy shall subject the provider of the online service to potential liability only with respect to violating content posted by that account holder; and</text></clause><clause id="id0a90136e786e45f785c433fb2d5c9ffe"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idec2daec94fa94964bef3b2e827eccf26"><enum>(I)</enum><text>upon receiving a notification that satisfies the requirements under paragraph (3), the provider—</text><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida69cfd31e36642c096a15979bca822f2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>removes or disables access to the work embodying the claimed unauthorized digital replica or the product or service specifically identified in a notice sent under that paragraph, or, as applicable, the link or reference to the unauthorized digital replica or product or service, as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for that provider;</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd5ebaa382d64c8d97f18dc2a63d08f8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for the provider of an online service described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(i), as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for that provider, removes or disables access to all other publicly available instances of the work embodying the claimed unauthorized digital replica that—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idafc390c5eda54d4fb78e4d3b2fede882"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">match the digital fingerprint of an unauthorized digital replica specifically identified in a notification sent under paragraph (3); and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide713301ce4514fe5ba9cd406196f58e6"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are uploaded after valid, applicable notice was submitted to, and processed by, the provider;</text></subitem></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31dc0c0187314ea5a4e0f1cb7ef0122d"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>for the provider of an online service described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(ii), with respect to sound recordings that are predominantly the fixation of sounds of a performance of a musical composition and are user uploaded material, as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for that provider, removes or disables access to all other publicly available instances of the work embodying the claimed unauthorized digital replica that—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0915fe55ce4842388a074b37314714b5"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">match the digital fingerprint of an unauthorized digital replica specifically identified in a notification sent under paragraph (3); and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27cc9c3402894a41ab8fa80cfe1a1652"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>are uploaded after valid, applicable notice was submitted to, and processed by, the provider; and</text></subitem></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67363292b1f244cfb2a5576d920a30e5"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">takes reasonable steps to promptly notify the right holder, and the party that placed the material on the online service, that the online service removed or disabled access to the material; and</text></item></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb628919387a4402abc46c5048fa3196d"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the provider, in the case that the provider receives a counter-notification that satisfies the requirements under paragraph (4) and opts to replace the removed material or cease disabling access to that material—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51e2acfd0f39411092f24092649536e9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">takes reasonable steps to promptly provide the individual or entity that provided the applicable notification under paragraph (3) with a copy of the counter-notification; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba0414686ca0490798e76b60ec0f87c9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not less than 14 days after the date on which the provider receives that counter-notification, replaces the removed material or ceases disabling access to that material, unless an eligible plaintiff described in subsection (e) brings an action under that subsection, in which case the provider shall remove the material or disable access to the material as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for the provider.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idebdeb054bcff4515a2ceff74e6b4134f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designated agent</header><subparagraph id="id85c7a4de448d48fca7a92d4cbc9711e5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id964279a6a72f40f9857e228c902b1712"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A provider of an online service described in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (a)(5)(A) shall, and a provider of an online service that is described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(iii) and is eligible for registration may, register a designated agent in accordance with this paragraph.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e10774491d04007888e2dcf6bcec553"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To designate an agent under clause (i), the provider of an online service shall make available through that online service, in a location accessible to the public, and provide to the Copyright Office, substantially the following information:</text><subclause id="id9bd07fea9b2448bea40e54c56b2c8dff"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The name, address, telephone number, and electronic mail address of the agent.</text></subclause><subclause id="idca24e890cbbc4d42865fab0848de865b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Other contact information that the Register of Copyrights may determine appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4ff030a6f83846709b363e9da7f754fe"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Directory</header><text>The Register of Copyrights—</text><clause id="ide538056a8a4f464f98ca04de413007c0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall—</text><subclause id="id5150c27994e149609065ee995914aab6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>maintain a current directory of designated agents for the purposes of this paragraph; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idda9760bf69454421bdbe13f11eb3e331"><enum>(II)</enum><text>make the directory described in subclause (I) available to the public for inspection, including through the internet; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idbe53c8e0e93149ef8d0de298eca63459"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may require payment of a fee by the provider of an online service to cover the costs of maintaining the directory described in clause (i)(I).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cd68581037d4c9eb8bb056f83f7307f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of failure to designate</header><text>There shall be established a presumption that a provider of an online service described in subparagraph (A)(i) has not undertaken a good faith effort to comply with this subsection if the provider has failed to register a designated agent under this paragraph by the later of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08b4e3f3c87b48fbafa95ef3c4b0dd9d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 90 days after the effective date of this section; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id409d227daece4cb0843159737c69322e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date that is 90 days after the date on which the provider becomes a provider described in subparagraph (A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa921caa3c674149b98421683502dd4b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements of notification</header><text>To be effective under this subsection, a notification of a claimed violation of the right described in subsection (b) shall be a written communication provided to the designated agent registered under this subsection with respect to the applicable provider of an online service that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="id3956cd5e28884959ba5e65f907727367"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A physical or electronic signature of the right holder, an individual or entity authorized to act on behalf of the right holder, or an eligible plaintiff under subsection (e)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5c3f23fcfa54fa6a7695eadc8fdf586"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identification of the individual, the voice or visual likeness of whom is at issue with respect to an unauthorized digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21aa3815b8ec4585ba5bc5da5a27cb66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identification of the material containing an unauthorized digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), including information sufficient to allow the provider to locate the identified material.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd436aa0769b4dee81d9bec4737e3de2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information reasonably sufficient to permit the provider to contact the notifying party, such as an address, telephone number, and email address.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5aa735d269b24bbf9dc4d9c1749c7aa7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A statement that the notifying party believes in good faith that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3701b215b97a430bbeda2f9d649f6eec"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the material is an unauthorized use of a digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fb34c826fe243ea928058238e8950a7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the exclusions under subsection (c)(5) do not apply.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd90cf1e5b522471c8de264256ebd9f86"><enum>(F)</enum><text>If not the right holder or an eligible plaintiff under subsection (e)(1), a statement, under penalty of perjury, that the notifying party has the authority to act on behalf of the right holder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2b1cc29ab434e389ea7167014b74b30"><enum>(G)</enum><text>For the purposes of paragraph (1)(B), information reasonably sufficient to—</text><clause id="id1c057da997864798bac249c6326f86a3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify the reference or link to the material or activity claimed to be or containing an unauthorized digital replica, or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), that is to be removed or to which access is to be disabled; and</text></clause><clause id="id58de39d4b1fb4efe81cd30744880e683"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permit the provider to locate the reference or link described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2fa11f5dab87413d8c15efc7b78a4c31"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Elements of counter-notification</header><text>To be effective under this subsection, a counter-notification with respect to a notification provided under paragraph (3) shall be a written communication that satisfies the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id532f6b29420d4ea3b4d37c64287f4693"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The counter-notification is provided—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id860f4fe24bdc451a970e220f3e37bcec"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the designated agent of the online service provider to which that notification was submitted under paragraph (3); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5aa82e9f763944f1b32f3bd18f3b1e9c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the party that placed the applicable material on the online service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5495e7da9ba1469fa61a1c4e0b3ef026"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The counter notification includes the following:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id634617404be84f27b1e0db61e70e0f03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A physical signature, witnessed or attested to in person by a licensed notary public, of the individual or entity that placed the applicable material on the online service.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id633f02dddc8949e986099b1e94062cd5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An identification of the material that has been removed or to which access has been disabled and the location at which the material appeared before the material was removed or access to the material was disabled.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id248afb9b4a8a473aa3700127fffebb45"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Information that is reasonably sufficient to permit the provider of the online service and the individual or entity that provided the notification under paragraph (3) to contact the party providing the counter-notification, including an address, telephone number, and email address.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b4b82174a8d45e1a419a7750b4d656a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A statement made under penalty of perjury that the party providing the counter-notification has a good faith belief that the applicable material was removed, or access to that material was disabled, as a result of mistake or misidentification of the material to be removed or access to which was to be disabled, which shall include a specific assertion by the party providing the counter-notification that such material—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30f6569b78864f19b1cba43706892467"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not a digital replica;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc66e51fbf04422081ad021a484809b6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is an authorized digital replica; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id864074c7b64441f29566cdc1a46722e9"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an unauthorized digital replica that satisfies an exclusion under paragraph (4) or (5) of subsection (c), or any other requirements with respect to a valid legal defense, which shall include a succinct explanation of how such material satisfies the applicable exclusion or requirement.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b67c5fbfb6a4fd6a6551209966ef189"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A statement that the individual or entity described in clause (i)—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9cb1293d355943d5819b461d3c4c0bcf"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consents to the jurisdiction of the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the address provided under clause (iii) is located (or, if that address is outside of the United States, for any judicial district of the United States in which the provider may be found); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf5e325c7fa949f4ba4772239eb34bb6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will accept service of process from—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc01a5e3c2c514aec88c7fe9f44f0db14"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual or entity that provided notification under paragraph (3); or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc800068329c4b44b1dff76045b2f897"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an agent of the individual or entity described in item (aa).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id566c44e533984960976db06441708c76"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Penalties for false or deceptive notice</header><subparagraph id="id0e0fedeeb34040678a603ba4dba0e9b4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Knowing material representations</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id073d17bf5b4d436eae6aee72f1e09c1c"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful to knowingly materially misrepresent—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f4e6675dfa943ff8a9c33c844e8d805"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a notification provided under paragraph (3)—</text><item id="id0779e90c04654bdb8ac5b106dddbca25"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>that the material requested to be removed, or access to which is requested to be disabled, is an unauthorized digital replica;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7d0f789bc8548ad98d7b5d7a087cef8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that the exclusions under subsection (c)(5) do not apply; or</text></item><item id="idcb4341a997d74dbeac4bf9f750b5f176"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>that an individual or entity has the authority to act on behalf of the right holder; or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9e2dd47a545f4c628ec00c8f8a3059f8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in a counter-notification provided under paragraph (4)—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7291993be204fa98d971f79298dc798"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>that the material removed, or to which access was disabled—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8a77be3368f40c08e79003ab0857e02"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was removed or disabled by mistake or misidentification;</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1bd3b0d9a90a4d9ea628b6532a17d775"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>is not a digital replica; or</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9535dbe8a5eb4e05a4f4764e355a2128"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>is subject to an exclusion under subsection (c)(5) or any other valid legal defense.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id24fde50840aa4893a65758273059a145"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Failure to perform good faith review</header><text>The failure to consider in good faith any of the issues described in clause (i)(I) before providing a notification under paragraph (3), or any of the issues described in clause (i)(II) before providing a counter-notification under paragraph (4), shall constitute a knowing material misrepresentation under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5a6537d584bf4342b08a01dd7c7d24e2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>In addition to a cause of action and remedies made available under subsection (e), any individual or entity that violates subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall be liable to the applicable right holder, the alleged violator that uploaded the applicable material, or the provider of an online service injured by the misrepresentation, for an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="id26f4e176c1c54f13a0134402e562efc2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$25,000 per notification provided under paragraph (3), or counter-notification provided under paragraph (4), that contains a misrepresentation described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; or</text></clause><clause id="id1ad3642b5c5748719eccd219123bb25a"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1d9fa90248544394acc0a1a8020704eb"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any actual damages incurred by the applicable right holder or alleged violator, as well as by any provider of an online service or other individual or entity injured by the misrepresentation; and</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe446b3f78144e54930cc5f125e14e5a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any costs and attorney’s fees incurred by the applicable recipient of a notification under paragraph (3), or a counter-notification under paragraph (4), that prevails in an action alleging that the notification or counter-notification, as applicable, was false or deceptive.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id70aa7e5b2b5f49ed8eb47da7274931fa"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Civil action</header><paragraph id="id9ee1f0d90a48484f9d5c419330117d52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible plaintiffs</header><text>A civil action against an individual or entity that, in a manner affecting interstate commerce (or using any means or facility of interstate commerce), commits a violation of subsection (c) may be brought by—</text><subparagraph id="id38b0b1ac6eb24cbea22071b7f0793c1a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable right holder;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73905f1f84c6430598c5c6e3d76e65c0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the applicable right holder is an individual who is younger than 18 years of age, a parent or guardian of that individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idab91d69d3bf3400992c2853c23a3ae95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a digital replica involving a sound recording artist, any individual or entity that has, directly or indirectly, entered into—</text><clause id="id9073adce6acf4b85a30218bf720f9b69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a contract for the exclusive personal services of the sound recording artist as a sound recording artist; or</text></clause><clause id="idd39ae4e082f34a29b925ee0395f6bb79"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an exclusive license to distribute or transmit 1 or more works that capture the audio performance of the sound recording artist.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id27fc21548ac94643b2ac5bb89916f7b4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations period</header><text>A civil action may not be brought under this subsection unless the civil action is commenced not later than 3 years after the date on which the party seeking to bring the civil action discovered, or with due diligence should have discovered, the applicable violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id488512bee324463baa89bafeeb97ce75"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Defense not permitted</header><text>It shall not be a defense in a civil action brought under this subsection that the defendant displayed or otherwise communicated to the public a disclaimer stating that the applicable digital replica, or the applicable product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), was unauthorized or disclosed that the digital replica, product, or service was generated through the use of artificial intelligence or other technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa643d3410b44791985602f117e85c30"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Remedies</header><subparagraph id="id6a7840a45a8248c69964972d9ac47bac"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any civil action brought under this subsection—</text><clause id="idbe2321772afe46c6819a6935171e25da"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual or entity found to have committed a violation of subsection (c) shall be liable to the injured party in an amount equal to the greater of—</text><subclause id="id908b67eefd7244b6b9d692f3410e3189"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id7a3fbb2174a84363a65bb2ca85107b00"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of an individual, $5,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized digital replica;</text></item><item id="id632007a9a7314ac7aa03f69065c301f1" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $25,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized digital replica;</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd40f76ea7aea4c26a7e7ca5b0c98c0bd"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has not undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $5,000 per display, copy made, transmission, and instance of the unauthorized digital replica being made available on the online service in a sum of not more than $750,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized digital replica; and</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93457948dd66429080ede3e8e531aa63"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in the case of an entity that is not a provider of an online service, $25,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized digital replica; or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa80d41357b04d818121dce421dac9af"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any actual damages suffered by the injured party as a result of the activity, plus any profits from the unauthorized use that are attributable to such use and are not taken into account in computing the actual damages;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id26c5e9abbebf4a3c8659e9eb9ed7d876"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual or entity found to have violated subsection (c) by virtue of engaging in an activity described in subsection (c)(2)(B) shall be liable to the injured party in an amount equal to the greater of—</text><subclause id="id43da005832b2410d856be3583fb86554"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1c7985130d5744c29878d2fa5c3d7936"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of an individual, $5,000 per product or service;</text></item><item id="id2bc63c59080f4eb1844123e749a81628" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $25,000 per product or service;</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81b39bee77134c8fabc5def5f961607a"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has not undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $750,000 per product or service; or</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ac4481a64e44b208dde5398d5f5ad98"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an entity that is not a provider of an online service, $25,000 per product or service; or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide15f686b7e1d4a3f934cbfa7a15256a3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any actual damages suffered by the injured party as a result of the activity, plus any profits from the unauthorized use that are attributable to such use and are not taken into account in computing the actual damages;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7719b8c06a8743879bb25464d9f04b94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the plaintiff may seek injunctive or other equitable relief;</text></clause><clause id="id1da257c2bc1c426699807721aefb2344"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of willful activity in which the injured party has proven that the defendant acted with malice, fraud, knowledge, or willful avoidance of knowledge that the conduct violated the law, the court may award to the injured party punitive damages; and</text></clause><clause id="id24289c3f817c4db38a24259509960c04"><enum>(v)</enum><text>if the prevailing party is—</text><subclause id="id3a47967b47ae49ddb092978539ada1f9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the party bringing the action, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id8d4231d587d54408bd355c6081081563"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the party defending the action, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees if the court determines that the action was not brought in good faith.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd45b8e8d84db4ea898435b5eb2d147ac"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Objectively reasonable belief</header><text>A provider of an online service that has designated an agent under subsection (d)(2) and has an objectively reasonable belief that material that is claimed to be an unauthorized digital replica does not qualify as a digital replica shall be liable only for actual damages under subparagraph (A) if the material is ultimately determined to be an unauthorized digital replica.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf2738c75c8ed4344a418ed7925811248"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subpoena To identify violator</header><paragraph id="idad70e227f29b4022b5f27b717171ece1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request</header><text>A right holder, an individual or entity authorized to act on behalf of a right holder, or an eligible plaintiff under subsection (e)(1) may request the clerk of any district court of the United States to issue a subpoena to a provider of an online service for identification of an alleged violator of this section in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id53d6e9cc4efe497ab569431fa82a9e8a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of request</header><text>A request under paragraph (1) may be made by filing with the clerk—</text><subparagraph id="id6cdebf17805041cab209eca430c19165"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of a notification described in subsection (d)(3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida96e821bd0fd4b909196bbd276319394"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a proposed subpoena; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idccd2eaf94ecb4f82a66058e22c1e2ac7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a sworn declaration to the effect that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb89eed633354408b821d19e121487bb5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the purpose of the subpoena is to obtain the identity of an individual or entity alleged to be liable under subsection (c); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb680060d9a2946498d990f4348604971"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information described in clause (i) will only be used for the purpose of protecting rights under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0addc9120564c04bdb168ab626f2a93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of subpoena</header><text>A subpoena issued under this subsection shall authorize and order the provider of the applicable online service to expeditiously disclose to the party that sought the subpoena information sufficient to identify the alleged violator by virtue of the activity described in the notification to the extent that information is available to the provider of the online service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd561ed099e19432d877b992719b9871f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Basis for granting subpoena</header><text>If a proposed subpoena under this subsection is in proper form, the applicable notification filed satisfies the requirements under subsection (d)(3), and the accompanying declaration is properly executed, the clerk shall expeditiously issue and sign the proposed subpoena and return the subpoena to the requester for delivery to the provider of the applicable online service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id67adbe58e53a431f9d837c55c0ecef7a"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preemption</header><paragraph id="idaf601057c5eb4487b2752a3a741ea84b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The rights established under this Act shall preempt any cause of action under State law for the protection of an individual’s voice and visual likeness rights in connection with a digital replica, as defined in this Act, in an expressive work.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bccb8df25ff428f999d957ad8186e74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), nothing in this Act may be construed to preempt—</text><subparagraph id="id5cffa061d2c84a2cbc9badef9bd1b965"><enum>(A)</enum><text>causes of action under State statutes or common law in existence, as of January 2, 2025, regarding a digital replica;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id12b6533ab14a4d5b8d2eb86c62f2d637"><enum>(B)</enum><text>causes of action under State statutes specifically regulating a digital replica depicting sexually explicit conduct, as defined in section 2256(2)(A) of title 18, United States Code, or an election-related digital replica; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id271fe8cb89604fb5812256bc50ffc368"><enum>(C)</enum><text>causes of action under State statutes or common law in existence, as of January 2, 2025, for the distributing, importing, transmitting, or otherwise making available to the public a product or service capable of producing 1 or more digital replicas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida3b6193bc9f3426ea9b22d5dee7f4fdd"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id10f48eea7fd6477d835526ec31d423ae"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Laws pertaining to intellectual property</header><text>This section shall be considered to be a law pertaining to intellectual property for the purposes of section 230(e)(2) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(e)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72aa7ce82a6c44b68ccd0018a0d35a5d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No duty to monitor</header><text>Except as expressly provided in subsection (d)(1)(B)(ii), nothing in this section may be construed to require the provider of an online service to—</text><subparagraph id="id4803cd2d335f49ffb901db8c2e3f1c68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitor the online service for, or affirmatively seek facts about, any digital replica; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd661f2d8d8f499699200c4657d3cae3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gain access to material.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7da140be727847fc974014e8115122bb"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this section, or the application of a provision of this section, is held to be invalid, the validity of the remainder of this section, and the application of that provision to other individuals, entities, and circumstances, shall not be affected by that holding.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc0e3c062370b40d7ac40fc0d5ffca446"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Retroactive effect</header><paragraph id="idb208f5528b1f446e9c0e1d9e822fb8ea"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Liabilities</header><text>Liability under this section shall apply only to—</text><subparagraph id="id28cd5e5cd5c942fbaa5cec79702d7aaa"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct occurring after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2024c55c62494445bcd0a0496d298d0f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of conduct covered by a license or contract, a license or contract that is executed after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0c80f90d7ae44ef0881be6459db7dc6b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital replication right</header><text>The right granted under subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="id257c9db2539440f49ea3de224bf6fdbf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall apply to any individual, regardless of whether the individual dies before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b601430c30d4013a92e06c5d4ffcb59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a right holder who has died before the date of enactment of this Act, shall vest in the executors, heirs, assignees, or devisees of the right holder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1b0444f876f640c680c2f1ffe202c63a"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section id="id41ae6efe-c745-430d-b11a-370b70dba216" section-type="section-one" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSJU00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nurture Originals, Foster Art, and Keep Entertainment Safe Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NO FAKES Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id7a12b5f8-a1bc-4d47-b8a3-eec59fdf3f6d" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSJU00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Voice and visual likeness rights</header><subsection id="idfe34a03d-9750-4922-9006-404d4179be11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idcc1adfcf-5595-419e-856b-d72b0877ad56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital fingerprint</header><text>The term <term>digital fingerprint</term> means an electronic label or identifier created by a cryptographic hash function (or similar function), or any other digital process, tool, or technique selected by the provider of an online service, that is unique to a specific piece of material such that it is effectively certain that such piece of material will not be misidentified as a match for a different piece of material. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idadc6a1ed-f578-41ac-8069-e8664e6e9bda"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital replica</header><text>The term <term>digital replica</term>— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4240aae2-aff3-453f-b8e1-bd375eb506dd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a newly created, computer-generated, highly realistic electronic representation that is readily identifiable as the voice or visual likeness of an individual that—</text><clause id="idcf0b6d4a-43cf-4fad-aadd-cf5e21e1f209"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is embodied in a sound recording, image, audiovisual work, including an audiovisual work that does not have any accompanying sounds, or transmission—</text><subclause id="idda8052ff-bc14-471b-bb01-bd2376de8777"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in which the actual individual did not actually perform or appear; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id947056d3-f917-4df8-8036-3e3387d4c658"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that is a version of a sound recording, image, or audiovisual work in which the actual individual did perform or appear, in which the fundamental character of the performance or appearance has been materially altered; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc53bb5d4-d799-4f23-8ca7-ec7108d67778"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the electronic reproduction, use of a sample of one sound recording or audiovisual work into another, remixing, mastering, or digital remastering of a sound recording or audiovisual work authorized by the copyright holder.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f5f4ae9-cf45-4013-a739-b8370f3818e8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individual</header><text>The term <term>individual</term> means a human being, living or dead.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id40b63859-2646-40a3-b484-40bec5896ebb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interactive computer service</header><text>The term <term>interactive computer service</term> means any information service, system, or access software provider that provides or enables computer access by multiple users to a computer server, including specifically— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4fc5e10f-6a50-4f10-bace-313b8d7275f5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a service or system that provides access to the internet; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id656b42dc-a001-4e95-bf9b-fe3f3edb65c9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such systems operated, or services offered, by libraries or educational institutions. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idce87a9f6-290d-4458-be56-9e1b6ed5bbc5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Online service</header><text>The term <term>online service</term>— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0cca6fd9-b592-40b8-b52a-08ecd99fc8a6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means—</text><clause id="idc2c5f477-fbe4-4bef-8e1d-7fdc4aed1f1a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any website, online application, mobile application, or virtual reality environment that predominantly provides public access to user uploaded material;</text></clause><clause id="ide6416951-29ba-4d1f-ad11-9db04c9ee04a"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any digital music provider to which section 115 of title 17, United States Code, applies, to the extent that the digital music provider provides public access to a significant amount of sound recordings that are predominantly the fixation of sounds of a performance of a musical composition and are user uploaded material, if that digital music provider is not covered under clause (i); and</text></clause><clause id="idfa94c033-c9c8-4fbf-b04e-c64f2411f27d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any online application, mobile application, virtual reality environment, application store, search engine (including any feature that provides web search results), advertising service or network, online shopping service or platform, electronic commerce provider, mapping service, cloud storage service, aggregator of visual and audiovisual works for licensing, or website hosting service or any other interactive computer service that is not covered under clause (i), and is not a digital music provider to which section 115 of title 17, United States Code, applies, but only if the provider of that interactive computer service has registered a designated agent with the Copyright Office under subsection (d)(2); and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc70a45f1-ad9b-4e0c-afb4-4d571889f9cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any website, online application, mobile application, virtual reality environment, application store, cloud storage service, or search engine, if the primary function of that website, online application, mobile application, virtual reality environment, application store, cloud storage service, or search engine is to distribute, import, transmit, or otherwise make available to the public a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id69ab7070-bd99-44e8-8ec6-b5c06dd3ca39"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Right holder</header><text>The term <term>right holder</term> means— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e9677c1-e85e-4a7f-8c78-04c2c69df933"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual, the voice or visual likeness of whom is at issue with respect to a digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf308f195-d23b-4397-a3fa-ae3df1169e1f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other individual or entity that has acquired, through a license, inheritance, or otherwise, the right to authorize the use of the voice or visual likeness described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb473fd7-4fc0-4989-8636-c792faaaf29d"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sound recording artist</header><text>The term <term>sound recording artist</term> means an individual who creates or performs in sound recordings for economic gain or for the livelihood of the individual. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6b88856-09ff-4667-91a1-6c7feacf2f3e"><enum>(8)</enum><header>User uploaded material</header><text>The term <term>user uploaded material</term>— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c317cbb14d04928b66d23781cf7cd55"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means material, such as a video, image, audio file, or other similar material, that is placed on a service directly by, or at the direction of, a consumer end user of a service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a72e418f434447abef4c080671a96e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include material that is—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2befd73c63774b56a50905ddaaeb62b7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">embodied in a video game; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0760751c458845bebc140ba7161aee1d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">generated or customized by a consumer end user of that video game.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id01f12f55-44bf-475e-a8a6-6514ea5f5f76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Digital replication right</header><paragraph id="id72bffed6-076c-43ca-949a-38704f0f9131"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the other provisions of this section, each individual or right holder shall have the right to authorize— </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28bc30b6-ac9c-4d73-8f44-66739bd2bd33"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of a digital replica embodying the voice or visual likeness of the individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8c1298c-60ef-4b90-b1b9-dd016f7e60c6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of the voice or visual likeness of the individual in connection with a product or service for which authorization of the individual or right holder is required to avoid liability with respect to an activity described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf7e55f0f-75b9-43f6-9d7e-4dd50a574114"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nature of right</header><subparagraph id="idb1f0e360-d867-4dee-b7a1-ee9a151d7eea"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The right described in paragraph (1) shall have the following characteristics:</text><clause id="idd15883d7-6bdb-4107-b5f4-cb510d0db899"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The right is—</text><subclause id="iddd6935f2-78b7-446a-b047-a2fa48692922"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a property right;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8afa007a-5432-4065-a4d6-c38aa1b39bdc"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not assignable during the life of the individual, including through involuntary transfer, such as by means of bankruptcy, levy, lien enforcement, court order, or other legal process; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idd66df2d5-f963-413f-b5b9-f4d366dbef6a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>licensable, in whole or in part, exclusively or non-exclusively, by the right holder.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id12862696-1458-4b0c-bf54-f7e94f62af7e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The right shall not expire upon the death of the individual, without regard to whether the right is commercially exploited by the individual during the lifetime of the individual.</text></clause><clause id="idcb3f1c74-2c7d-417b-aad5-a01723b1987f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Upon the death of the individual—</text><subclause id="idf195169b-5fc9-4d21-8ac7-2910bdfd576f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the right is transferable and licensable, in whole or in part, by the executors, heirs, assignees, licensees, or devisees of the individual; and</text></subclause><subclause id="iddab3a5b6-2595-461d-a893-074080a1979e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ownership of the right may be—</text><item id="id4cf06513-b17a-47a5-a43a-5202ad507d49"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>transferred, in whole or in part, by any means of conveyance or by operation of law; and</text></item><item id="id034a9cdd-f1d6-4d3c-9bf7-45f06fcde099"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>bequeathed by will or pass as personal property by the applicable laws of intestate succession.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idd68e6f09-95ac-4ad6-9e52-8b39eb180520"><enum>(iv)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id6d3e679cbad74b5d864c5f1ba8c4db1b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The right shall be exclusive to—</text><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8aab9d2eda04dfc9dca887d1fc16196"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the individual, subject to the licensing of the right during the lifetime of that individual under subparagraph (B); and</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c07d549adf24e16a5e1faaee9b08fc3"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the right holder—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd4ce061586a4c789041603e45cd6044"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a period of 10 years after the death of the individual; and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2b01e05a8aa4ba98b3da7df1a85679d"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>if the right holder demonstrates active and authorized public use of the voice or visual likeness of the individual in interstate or foreign commerce during the 2-year period preceding the expiration of the 10-year period described in subitem (AA), for an additional 5-year period, subject to renewal for additional 5-year periods, provided the right holder can demonstrate authorized public use of the voice or visual likeness of the individual in interstate or foreign commerce during the 2-year period preceding the expiration of each additional 5-year period.</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8dde5db18054133adca54579fd29c38"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The commercial availability of a sound recording or audiovisual work in which the voice or visual likeness of an individual is readily identifiable shall constitute active and authorized public use of that voice or visual likeness for the purposes of subclause (I)(bb)(BB).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id8b14be96-4f9d-45c2-b508-4eff2639cfca"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The right shall terminate on the date that is the earlier of—</text><subclause id="id90599cc7-eba2-44b4-95e4-85d54eda1cf6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date on which the 10-year period or 5-year period described in clause (iv)(I)(bb) terminates without renewal; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idbe198176-a78c-4965-8286-cece9cec4e20"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date that is 70 years after the death of the individual.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id175efac3-6336-4e3b-b2ce-3380e69a149e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for license</header><clause id="idc894c1ca-8f35-48af-b0ce-aff5f9ad2370"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A license described in subparagraph (A)(i)(III)—</text><subclause id="id238f9165-bf3a-447e-8a4c-4a54dadeca7b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>while the applicable individual is living, is valid only to the extent that the license duration does not exceed 10 years; and</text></subclause><subclause id="iddf0c81b4-3fb5-4f06-98a5-f88254d61a63"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be valid only if the license agreement—</text><item id="ida42d1ffb-f804-4cb4-9b77-2edde503417b"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is in writing and signed by— </text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4342d8b9d2c948f0b2567737223d11c6"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable individual; or</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id624cc125d7314a6da2ed3e111a432002"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>in the case of a deceased individual, the right holder or an authorized representative of the right holder; and</text></subitem></item><item id="idff0a134d-56d7-4bb2-8c92-563e32e894d4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>includes a reasonably specific description of the intended uses of the applicable digital replica.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="ide2334309-009e-4d4d-abe6-2d23277f08ea"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Licenses involving a minor</header><text>A license described in subparagraph (A)(i)(III) involving a living individual who is younger than 18 years of age—</text><subclause id="idd1e9ff8d-fe0c-4514-ad27-5f18526d54c8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is valid only to the extent that the license duration does not exceed 5 years, but in any case terminates when the individual reaches 18 years of age; and</text></subclause><subclause id="iddc7d14fc-85b7-4bd9-92fa-05a02db6d002"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be valid only if the license agreement—</text><item id="idc0de95e7-1906-478d-9e24-08839c77db4c"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is in writing and signed by the individual or an authorized representative of the individual; </text></item><item id="id1d1f9223-4537-4c67-8f4c-f9b3cd2c7c6f"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>includes a reasonably specific description of the intended uses of the digital replica; and</text></item><item id="id38dc7505-45ba-49e8-a9fe-eb77e444c439"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>is approved by a court in accordance with applicable State law.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id9192166b-9afb-4ba3-9cf3-3bdfb62a7617"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Collective bargaining agreements</header><text>The provisions of clauses (i) and (ii) shall not apply with respect to a license if the license is governed by a collective bargaining agreement that addresses digital replicas.</text></clause><clause id="id1cabcc3f-80c4-40cd-953c-00c5f5ffc1d7"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The provisions of clauses (i) and (ii) shall not affect terms and conditions of a license or related contract other than those described in this subparagraph, and the expiration of that license shall not affect the remainder of the license or related contract.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idde0e55a5-eb07-45bb-80b8-e18ec241f9b1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements for post-mortem transfer</header><text>A post-mortem transfer or license described in subparagraph (A)(iii)(I) shall be valid only if the transfer agreement or license agreement is in writing and signed by the right holder or an authorized representative of the right holder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5072c31f-214f-42d6-a26a-6ae73e409567"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Registration for post-mortem renewal</header><clause id="id4145c833-22ce-4e90-be9b-84db602073f7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The renewal of a post-mortem right under subparagraph (A)(iv)(I)(bb)(BB) shall be effective if, during the applicable 2-year renewal period described in that subparagraph, the right holder files a notice with the Register of Copyrights that complies with such requirements regarding form and filing procedures as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation, which shall include—</text><subclause id="idcb441231-664b-4a7e-9f12-e337c85b992e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the name of the deceased individual;</text></subclause><subclause id="id47c99b0d-12fb-4369-9ca9-82cbe2cf3d78"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a statement, under penalty of perjury, that the right holder has engaged in active and authorized public use of the voice or visual likeness in interstate or foreign commerce during the applicable 2-year period;</text></subclause><subclause id="id482a3d07-f80b-4caa-9107-5a64a8303a7f"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the identity of and contact information for the right holder; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idaf9fc768-2068-494c-a2ed-a45fec360424"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>such other information as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id83595c7c-c38b-47a3-8661-abdef08f33d9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Directory</header><text>The Register of Copyrights—</text><subclause id="id56d8f91f-d1ed-4890-9ccc-fee6efd2fda3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall—</text><item id="idac470a16-cf7d-4288-8192-bf85d20103a3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>maintain a current directory of post-mortem digital replication rights registered under this subparagraph; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2919d52-7c3c-45c9-9f37-5b3c6d0653da"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the directory described in item (aa) available to the public for inspection online; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idf651d543-6b71-4116-986c-a04f053f78ec"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may require payment of a reasonable filing fee by the right holder filing notice under clause (i), which may take into consideration the costs of maintaining the directory described in subclause (I) of this clause.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id233c3812-c320-44aa-a62f-5f2b2f0307f9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Voluntary initial registration</header><subclause id="id6ec1d9f3-ff10-4efb-bbc6-09b7e19bc755"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A right holder may voluntarily register the post-mortem right under subparagraph (A)(iv)(I)(bb)(AA) by filing a notice with the Register of Copyrights that complies with such requirements regarding form, content, and filing procedures as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation.</text></subclause><subclause id="idc465e8da-1fa2-4d28-a8a3-1146435689ba"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authority of Register of Copyrights</header><text>The Register of Copyrights may—</text><item id="id1425e83f-1953-479b-a5c8-093753fc7d21"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>include a voluntary registration of the post-mortem right under subparagraph (A)(iv)(I)(bb)(AA) in the directory maintained under clause (ii)(I)(aa) of this subparagraph; and</text></item><item id="iddc09e4da-df07-4de9-82f9-a8e58ad07a6b"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>require payment of a reasonable filing fee by a right holder registering a right under this clause, which may take into consideration the costs of maintaining the directory.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fe4b9c5d8a049fbb4e251d5ccd6e7ed"><enum>(iv)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initial post-mortem registration for individuals deceased 8 years or longer as of date of enactment</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id605e5943b09c422c89f62c7919224fb6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to an individual who died not fewer than 10 years before the date of enactment of this Act, the applicable right holder may, not later than 90 days after the effective date of this section, voluntarily register the post-mortem right under subparagraph (A)(iv)(I)(bb)(BB) by filing with the Register of Copyrights a notice that complies with such requirements as the Register of Copyrights may prescribe by regulation under clause (i), if the right holder demonstrates the required authorized public use of the voice or visual likeness of the individual in interstate or foreign commerce during the 2-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act, subject to protection during the periods of exclusivity and termination under clauses (iv) and (v) of subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81560779f777472a88c89269e1e3bc11"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to an individual who died not fewer than 8, and fewer than 10, years before the date of enactment of this Act, the applicable right holder may file a notice under clause (i) or subclause (I) of this clause.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id256ab216735b4bc28ff68e8f5439bf5d"><enum>(v)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority of Register of Copyrights</header><text>The Register of Copyrights may make such interpretations and resolve such ambiguities as may be appropriate to carry out this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb873d96-08f0-420d-a0f5-ab5e51e7dae0"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Post-expiration or termination utilization of authorized uses</header><text>A digital replica that is embodied in a sound recording, image, audiovisual work, including an audiovisual work that does not have any accompanying sounds, or transmission, and the use of which is authorized pursuant to the terms of a license, may continue to be utilized in a manner consistent with the terms of that license after the expiration or termination of the license.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id80627627-2f5c-4096-bcd2-6cac1ca96346"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Liability</header><paragraph id="id533b41ac-650d-4c45-bcfd-7e3ab7b5712f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual or entity that, in a manner affecting interstate or foreign commerce (or using any means or facility of interstate or foreign commerce), engages in an activity described in paragraph (2) shall be liable in a civil action brought under subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd9781e3-205e-48d0-b055-2675d8ab2ed6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>An activity described in this paragraph is either of the following:</text><subparagraph id="ide2932174-06a3-456a-ae2d-e5d42d6fe83f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The public display, distribution, transmission, or communication of, or the act of otherwise making available to the public, including by acting as a third party commercial supplier of sound recordings to a digital music provider, a digital replica without authorization by the applicable right holder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide040204d-0691-474b-b564-1626667b26d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Distributing, importing, transmitting, or otherwise making available to the public a product or service that—</text><clause id="idae2f7c98-2ad1-4ea4-a19e-57b4ceb0455e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is primarily designed to produce 1 or more digital replicas of a specifically identified individual or individuals without the authorization of— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5bc4dac-71d2-449b-be84-b004a2f434cd"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual or individuals;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id03d4e7e1-997e-4487-9c17-e9c12609444b"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable right holder; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43f64479-4481-41fe-b405-256e1b3f4e49"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idbedefade-574a-4c01-ad64-e7f8d7aa3bda"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has only limited commercially significant purpose or use other than to produce a digital replica of a specifically identified individual or individuals without the authorization of— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida858a620-b1ce-4894-808c-97199b6b4d36"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual or individuals;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9b8b06a3-d4a1-4b92-993f-77c3d9d5e652"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable right holder; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec11aece-713b-40a7-81ed-d7b2bc8faf8d"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id62f1c317-8d1d-46a2-b20c-614c82dbf28d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is marketed, advertised, or otherwise promoted by the individual or entity described in paragraph (1), or another individual or entity acting in concert with the individual or entity described in paragraph (1) with the knowledge of the individual or entity described in paragraph (1), as a product or service designed to produce a digital replica of a specifically identified individual or individuals without the authorization of— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32174e73-9bec-4489-bdfd-961f037a9da7"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such individual or individuals;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba06d1b6-dd6e-4319-907c-82cf24cac1d7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicable right holder; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1ec8994e-c308-42c4-8b5c-8b690386ca00"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the law.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3a33146-c35c-487b-b9e9-e8c25ebef0eb"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice or knowledge required</header><text>To incur liability under this subsection, the following shall apply:</text><subparagraph id="idd958d0f4-3031-4555-80b8-9a829dd7ff27"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idad1edff4-db94-4683-8d9d-ac2900a437ab"><enum>(i)</enum><text>With respect to an activity carried out under paragraph (2) by the provider of an online service described in clause (ii), the designated agent with respect to the provider must have received a notification that satisfies the requirements under subsection (d)(3), or a court order stating, or must have willfully avoided receipt of such a notification or court order, that the applicable material is—</text><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8dd507ac-c1f1-4a4f-8dba-b5ffc57d59fe"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a digital replica, the use of which was not authorized by the applicable right holder; or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc97abe44-1277-45df-bed0-309c81e26646"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a product or service described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd22e61e1-6453-4d0b-8518-e3a3b0b4efd9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An online service described in this clause is an online service that is—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id576589b5-8a3f-44b0-af06-a03eca55064d"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(i);</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide85412c7-4273-4cbc-ba23-80a639983625"><enum>(II)</enum><text>described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(ii), with respect to sound recordings that are predominantly the fixation of sounds of a performance of a musical composition and are user uploaded material; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfe08d2ec-f5e9-4af0-8d7c-1afdc42b5c2e"><enum>(III)</enum><text>described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(iii), with respect to material placed on that online service by or at the direction of a third party.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf64a9695-e2a6-484a-a2c7-57d87d6b127d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to an activity carried out under paragraph (2) by an individual or entity that is not an online service, or an activity carried out under paragraph (2) by the provider of an online service that is not described in subparagraph (A)(ii), the individual or entity must have actual knowledge, or must willfully avoid having such knowledge, that the applicable material is—</text><clause id="ide0f59a4f-6d4e-48ce-ac2c-afd3e250710c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a digital replica, the use of which was not authorized by the applicable right holder; or</text></clause><clause id="id6bd9d464-ff78-4a9b-8bed-277083f514a6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a product or service described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e2ce18a-19a7-48ee-9626-5bb41b298433"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>Liability under this subsection shall not extend to—</text><subparagraph id="id85afcbb0-97cd-42de-a289-990b0a0eeb7c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a service by wire or radio that provides the capability to transmit data to and receive data from all, or substantially all, internet endpoints, including any capabilities that are incidental to enable the operation of the communications service of a provider of online services or network access, or the operator of facilities for such service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idedae60e6-83b5-43d3-8fde-7a30abbc1dc2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a provider of an online service described in paragraph (3)(A)(ii) alleged to have undertaken an activity described in paragraph (2) if—</text><clause id="id5ad339b5-e204-4e3e-aa77-1ea8752affe2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it is not technologically or practically feasible for that provider to disable access to the offending material, or disable the reference or link to that material, at the specific location identified in the applicable notification sent under subsection (d)(3); or</text></clause><clause id="iddc4d5374-2211-4e17-b254-dee3672909ab"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>disabling access to the offending material is prohibited by law;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f9901a0-d0c6-47b0-a8c8-4c8f3665e2eb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit library or archives—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd4adf35-04e0-4a1f-b6df-6b300158b12b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is eligible for the limitations on exclusive rights under section 108 of title 17, United States Code;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8cbb9a11-02bc-41e1-8b46-c5d536428fa5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the collections of which are—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c4990e3-1633-48cd-bebc-1c7d98b60c51"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">open to the public; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9740e311-0478-4a92-9f39-02e3b54bd4e3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>available not only to researchers affiliated with the library or archives, or with the institution of which the library or archives is a part, but also to other persons doing research in a specialized field;</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide39f6387-b7cc-4344-a4c3-ce7229b7da63"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that has a public service mission;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f866e68-d648-49b6-9525-0d252c00f049"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the trained staff or volunteers of which provide professional services normally associated with libraries and archives; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5bbc9fd-4dfd-451f-8cf9-da6a00cd3147"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the collections of which are composed of lawfully acquired or licensed materials that are made available consistent with the requirements of title 17, United States Code;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbea9e61c-6aee-4150-bf4a-914f77cff13f"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an accredited nonprofit educational institution with respect to an activity undertaken without any purpose of direct or indirect commercial advantage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0e933db-8fc8-45ba-8f6e-c10647755808"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an employee of an institution described in subparagraph (C) or (D) acting within the scope of the employment of that individual; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14b2b3ba-32c2-4030-9601-c3b937394a49"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other person solely with respect to providing online or network access services to an institution described in subparagraph (C) or (D) in the course of providing those services to that institution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfbc8dcc9-f5db-491a-a214-67a337a97cd9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an individual or entity that is not an online service, if, upon obtaining actual knowledge of an activity described in paragraph (2), the individual or entity acts as soon as technologically and practically feasible to remove or disable access to the applicable material.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id97041437-ffba-4f29-a9a8-51d3b6af24b0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional exclusions</header><subparagraph id="id620f6c95-c84d-4b3a-980f-7f0d1646218e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An activity shall not be considered to be an activity described in paragraph (2) if—</text><clause id="id05525543-50b3-4a78-9c20-c89e6f24aead"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is used in a bona fide news, public affairs, or sports broadcast or account, provided that the digital replica is the subject of, or is materially relevant to, the subject of that broadcast or account;</text></clause><clause id="id80c14bc8-3037-413c-bf45-9217abf34b76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is a representation of the applicable individual as the individual in a documentary or in a historical or biographical manner, including some degree of fictionalization, unless—</text><subclause id="id56d96c51-1a64-4b02-b9b7-b00b37e225fd"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the use of that digital replica creates the false impression that the work is an authentic sound recording, image, transmission, or audiovisual work in which the individual participated; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id4589608e-a8c9-466b-ac8b-56985a32462b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the digital replica is embodied in a musical sound recording that is synchronized to accompany a motion picture or other audiovisual work, except to the extent that the use of that digital replica is protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id7a5c2b1e-4a50-43bd-aa82-acc3b30e9788"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is used consistent with the public interest in bona fide commentary, criticism, scholarship, satire, or parody;</text></clause><clause id="id6c0c8b0f-0fdb-41ab-8c6c-eca81f422e52"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the use of the applicable digital replica is fleeting or negligible; or</text></clause><clause id="ide5af1178-b3c6-4373-bca1-a46f4366c779"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the applicable digital replica is used in an advertisement or commercial announcement for a purpose described in any of clauses (i) through (iv) and the applicable digital replica is relevant to the subject of the work so advertised or announced.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id582fdd1c-e0a9-4133-a74e-b45fb09e1052"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply where the applicable digital replica is used to depict sexually explicit conduct, as defined in section 2256(2)(A) of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb7b44d1-a5af-4d85-a754-54f4c389b86b"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Voluntary use of tools to remove or disable access</header><text>The voluntary use of any tool to remove or disable access to content shall not alone confer actual knowledge of a particular violation of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idede93d83-728a-47b8-aebb-d9939cb394b8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safe harbors</header><paragraph id="id13fa70a1-2cbf-4ee2-9872-2b1a9e6dbae2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="id0bb676ca-78e0-4ef1-8edf-7cad58357dfd"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Products and services capable of producing digital replicas</header><text>No individual or entity shall be directly or secondarily liable under this section for an activity described in subsection (c)(2)(A) by virtue of distributing, importing, transmitting, or otherwise making available to the public a product or service unless the product or service is a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36179040-cd07-4345-93bd-c0950cc1c732"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Online services</header><text>The provider of an online service shall not be liable for an activity that violates subsection (c), or for referring or linking to the material embodying an unauthorized digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), if—</text><clause id="id29bed8af-8c0f-43cf-bf05-9e48162917e6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the provider of an online service described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(iii) (other than a search engine or a search component of a service), the provider has adopted and reasonably implemented, and has informed users of the online service of, a policy that provides for the termination in appropriate circumstances of account holders of the online service that are repeat violators of subsection (c)(2), provided that the failure to terminate a particular account holder in accordance with that policy shall subject the provider of the online service to potential liability only with respect to violating content posted by that account holder; and</text></clause><clause id="id35a74cd4-6eea-4c99-bba3-7d0efd50d062"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id070a8dbb-f514-4670-9da9-423beb0f56ab"><enum>(I)</enum><text>upon receiving a notification that satisfies the requirements under paragraph (3), the provider—</text><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1353c602-e6ac-472d-acde-2cda11d6f093"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>removes or disables access to the work embodying the claimed unauthorized use of a digital replica or the product or service specifically identified in a notice sent under that paragraph, or, as applicable, the link or reference to the unauthorized use of a digital replica or product or service, as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for that provider;</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7cdab85-f739-4acd-9876-56c30469f00e"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for the provider of an online service described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(i), as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for that provider, removes or disables access to all other publicly available instances of the work embodying the claimed unauthorized use of a digital replica that— </text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9e9abca-5c63-4844-b653-0fd0263a236d"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">match the digital fingerprint of an unauthorized use of a digital replica specifically identified in a notification sent under paragraph (3); and </text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3bd5922-7342-4a82-95b0-e3b895b5e5db"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are uploaded after valid, applicable notice was submitted to, and processed by, the provider; </text></subitem></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62a1c0d4-5313-49c2-a805-c1074b84cef7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>for the provider of an online service described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(ii), with respect to sound recordings that are predominantly the fixation of sounds of a performance of a musical composition and are user uploaded material, as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for that provider, removes or disables access to all other publicly available instances of the work embodying the claimed unauthorized use of a digital replica that—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6b18de7-df00-4a21-b0a1-e1a906ee7586"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">match the digital fingerprint of an unauthorized use of a digital replica specifically identified in a notification sent under paragraph (3); and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide3099923-ea55-47b0-baf1-02aea01bf8f9"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>are uploaded after valid, applicable notice was submitted to, and processed by, the provider; and</text></subitem></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e01d407-6c4d-4cb5-b93e-7104bbf3a8e7"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">takes reasonable steps to promptly notify the right holder, and the party that placed the material on the online service, that the online service removed or disabled access to the material; and</text></item></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77e20d1f-48ac-4479-92a6-c12584bea480"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the provider, in the case that the provider receives a counter-notification that satisfies the requirements under paragraph (4) and opts to replace the removed material or cease disabling access to that material—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78285c90-cc7e-4e56-9179-c839e99e9593"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">takes reasonable steps to promptly provide the individual or entity that provided the applicable notification under paragraph (3) with a copy of the counter-notification; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id560dcb90-bbd5-4271-8897-73acffd95eef"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not less than 14 days after the date on which the provider receives that counter-notification, replaces the removed material or ceases disabling access to that material, unless an eligible plaintiff described in subsection (e) brings an action under that subsection, in which case the provider shall remove the material or disable access to the material as soon as is technologically and practically feasible for the provider.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id29f6fd3a-91a1-4d7f-aa71-cadd8e069fed"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designated agent</header><subparagraph id="idb8ad5f42-4b33-410e-897e-eaea2628763c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Designation</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8aba1536-2a78-462b-8ad4-2e9762022797"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A provider of an online service described in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (a)(5)(A) shall, and a provider of an online service that is described in subsection (a)(5)(A)(iii) and is eligible for registration may, register a designated agent in accordance with this paragraph. </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd6b6831e-249b-4890-a3c7-9ef491ffbc6f"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To designate an agent under clause (i), the provider of an online service shall make available through that online service, in a location accessible to the public, and provide to the Copyright Office, substantially the following information:</text><subclause id="id39fd2ff1-9e17-43e4-985a-d098f7b4f637"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The name, address, telephone number, and electronic mail address of the agent.</text></subclause><subclause id="ida19693a5-ede8-408e-a4ad-f5af201b5e95"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Other contact information that the Register of Copyrights may determine appropriate.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f08ee12-0555-4c69-b2ea-ad24dcd52946"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Directory</header><text>The Register of Copyrights—</text><clause id="id0c7a1bf3-0052-4f08-b1c5-87d6c49abc43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall—</text><subclause id="idec3edc2f-3a50-4335-9a9f-d0ea8a0d55dc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>maintain a current directory of designated agents for the purposes of this paragraph; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idb273b176-fe2d-417b-a92d-9348aded5396"><enum>(II)</enum><text>make the directory described in subclause (I) available to the public for inspection, including through the internet; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3f4e66f1-db6e-42cc-841d-1619715e38b4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may require payment of a fee by the provider of an online service to cover the costs of maintaining the directory described in clause (i)(I).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide4036f04-4b1a-4ae4-ab9c-3d88192ddd7d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of failure to designate</header><text>There shall be established a presumption that a provider of an online service described in subparagraph (A)(i) has not undertaken a good faith effort to comply with this subsection if the provider has failed to register a designated agent under this paragraph by the later of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09d9555f-31c9-4ffa-b440-7237d14caefc"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 90 days after the effective date of this section; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5fc4fe67-cd28-4df1-b2b4-76091976d957"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date that is 90 days after the date on which the provider becomes a provider described in subparagraph (A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5470f5ac-39b7-4c15-a8af-b641507963f3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements of notification</header><text>To be effective under this subsection, a notification of a claimed violation of the right described in subsection (b) shall be a written communication provided to the designated agent registered under this subsection with respect to the applicable provider of an online service that includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="idaa18fc7e-f977-4a32-9a1c-a1eaaf1dab73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A physical or electronic signature of the right holder, an individual or entity authorized to act on behalf of the right holder, or an eligible plaintiff under subsection (e)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id35a2b4b9-2982-4499-8a68-c401735d81fc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identification of the individual, the voice or visual likeness of whom is at issue with respect to an unauthorized use of a digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id59a6b3a7-b26d-485f-a14c-be0da53086d9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identification of the material embodying an unauthorized use of a digital replica or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), including information sufficient to allow the provider to locate the identified material.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3e9a46f4-ec8e-4cf4-a559-349d3baf15d2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Information reasonably sufficient to permit the provider to contact the notifying party, such as an address, telephone number, and email address.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e10085b-8748-4a2c-bbce-281db15c0c99"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A statement that the notifying party believes in good faith that— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c5e4190-d9fb-4f9a-8ab5-72512e179aeb"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the material is— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67c98db26579438ca21790246e7b1949"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a digital replica, the use of which is unauthorized; or </text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4881ca526520457d9322e7eaac93ff3f"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B); and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5816040b-5d1a-4971-a60f-fec1cd04a7fe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the exclusions under subsection (c)(5) do not apply.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id707ea1b9-11f1-4f25-b453-8a74e6cb2ba7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>If not the right holder or an eligible plaintiff under subsection (e)(1), a statement, under penalty of perjury, that the notifying party has the authority to act on behalf of the right holder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id581ca585-853b-42af-8457-3c626484decf"><enum>(G)</enum><text>For the purposes of paragraph (1)(B), information reasonably sufficient to—</text><clause id="id4fdde90d-3e91-420f-b723-6f92dd6e9481"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify the reference or link to the material or activity claimed to be or embodying an unauthorized use of a digital replica, or a product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), that is to be removed or to which access is to be disabled; and</text></clause><clause id="idbf07df66-2e55-493f-a82f-6519fe2a3233"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>permit the provider to locate the reference or link described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d5064c6-9081-4800-b31f-b4d12a081af8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Elements of counter-notification</header><text>To be effective under this subsection, a counter-notification with respect to a notification provided under paragraph (3) shall be a written communication that satisfies the following: </text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id598b493a-a804-4f34-92aa-8389a413f821"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The counter-notification is provided— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id155f1882-67b3-4925-8bb0-e0fd000b750f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the designated agent of the online service provider to which that notification was submitted under paragraph (3); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4eba1523-20e1-4a20-9fce-0719ea221557"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the party that placed the applicable material on the online service.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16a0467c-e812-4d2f-8bd7-dd7b221f4f8d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The counter notification includes the following:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf4aa4f93-3398-4329-950b-9b88b97a8a6b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A physical signature, witnessed or attested to in person by a licensed notary public, of the individual or entity that placed the applicable material on the online service.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd91b13c-0248-4ae4-b7dc-566ececa6920"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An identification of the material that has been removed or to which access has been disabled and the location at which the material appeared before the material was removed or access to the material was disabled.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id146ddd3e-0596-48de-b907-755c46cf2562"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Information that is reasonably sufficient to permit the provider of the online service and the individual or entity that provided the notification under paragraph (3) to contact the party providing the counter-notification, including an address, telephone number, and email address.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f6932af-f9b2-4109-a3de-e9564e830ae0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A statement made under penalty of perjury that the party providing the counter-notification has a good faith belief that the applicable material was removed, or access to that material was disabled, as a result of mistake or misidentification of the material to be removed or access to which was to be disabled, which shall include a specific assertion by the party providing the counter-notification that such material—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5136161c-03aa-406f-8125-765418521027"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not a digital replica;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id967c0aa5-6725-46b3-9eb6-2b58e1915dcc"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is an authorized use of a digital replica; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d219972-2a66-4622-b6ce-b2427f4abe21"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an unauthorized use of a digital replica that satisfies an exclusion under paragraph (4) or (5) of subsection (c), a limitation on liability under subsection (e)(3), or any other requirement with respect to a valid legal defense, which shall include a succinct explanation of how such material satisfies the applicable exclusion, limitation, or requirement.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6649eeca-f47e-486b-bb08-17eda729d74f"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A statement that the individual or entity that placed the applicable material on the online service— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id195dfebf-82be-4d90-9f50-db523790d225"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consents to the jurisdiction of the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the address provided under clause (iii) is located (or, if that address is outside of the United States, for any judicial district of the United States in which that individual or entity may be found); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebadab64-98ea-479c-8c0b-88f903f0b37a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will accept service of process from— </text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida21308fb-3775-481f-b20f-2b0be0d53123"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual or entity that provided notification under paragraph (3); or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb25c195-b485-46cc-9ced-5095334354b9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an agent of the individual or entity described in item (aa).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9952bd3c-95b8-497e-ab15-742663c250fc"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Penalties for false or deceptive notice</header><subparagraph id="idf83621e1-3dce-409f-bb2f-ccadd2b26015"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Knowing material representations</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec9b1033-c538-4179-bf7b-8d8a3b634199"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful to knowingly materially misrepresent— </text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9a459ba-8edb-416d-8d00-0d67989f89c3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a notification provided under paragraph (3)—</text><item id="id9653b6c9-0088-4678-9632-e5b4e442ca7c"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>that the material requested to be removed, or access to which is requested to be disabled, is a digital replica, the use of which is unauthorized;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id569d1f78-54fe-438e-a8f0-f376a5b80917"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>that the exclusions under subsection (c)(5) do not apply; or</text></item><item id="id4710a555-73aa-4290-823e-4944e539022c"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>that an individual or entity has the authority to act on behalf of the right holder; or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffec6f17-6f73-4dc5-ad77-bfc274be41be"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in a counter-notification provided under paragraph (4), that—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f583ea1-9909-45b9-bdb0-cac2c1b1df3a"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>material was removed, or access to material was disabled, by mistake or misidentification;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1a26d42-607f-43a9-8140-9d8c9803cdc1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the material removed, or to which access was disabled, is not a digital replica; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc99c9059-c5d2-44e4-b431-f9a9c44d2b3c"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the material removed, or to which access was disabled, is subject to an exclusion under subsection (c)(5), a limitation on liability under subsection (e)(3), or any other valid legal defense.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idfd304c2a-e9ff-478f-946e-53be7bf96ff2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Failure to perform good faith review</header><text>The failure to consider in good faith any of the issues described in clause (i)(I) before providing a notification under paragraph (3), or any of the issues described in clause (i)(II) before providing a counter-notification under paragraph (4), shall constitute a knowing material misrepresentation under this subparagraph. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id66e396d3-3ea1-4ff1-a436-41fbeab70a15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>In addition to the cause of action and remedies made available under subsection (e), any individual or entity that violates subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall be liable to the applicable right holder, the alleged violator that uploaded the applicable material, or the provider of an online service injured by the misrepresentation, for an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="id642c95a3-7409-4072-a5cf-d24050239af6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$25,000 per notification provided under paragraph (3), or counter-notification provided under paragraph (4), that contains a misrepresentation described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph; or</text></clause><clause id="id360b71ec-2b70-4763-b0cf-05b7907e6431"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the sum of—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e3590a21c3643e2a8451033b9f2fcd2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any actual damages incurred by the applicable right holder or alleged violator, as well as by any provider of an online service or other individual or entity injured by the misrepresentation; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5abfcb5fd849401696a1986166033994"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any costs and attorney’s fees incurred by the applicable recipient of a notification under paragraph (3), or a counter-notification under paragraph (4), that prevails in an action alleging that the notification or counter-notification, as applicable, was false or deceptive.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3f9b04c2-220e-4a36-afd2-72416dcafc67"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Civil action</header><paragraph id="id81377e0d-2188-4fe3-b7b6-af393f10c787"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible plaintiffs</header><text>A civil action against an individual or entity that, in a manner affecting interstate commerce (or using any means or facility of interstate commerce), commits a violation of subsection (c) may be brought by—</text><subparagraph id="id03f0f23b-9fcb-449f-960a-8128fe55b24c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable right holder;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc2794ea0-0f0d-4447-990b-110e9737b55b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the applicable right holder is an individual who is younger than 18 years of age, a parent or guardian of that individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf11d1a18-002c-4068-841d-18583a81effb"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a digital replica involving a sound recording artist, any individual or entity that has, directly or indirectly, entered into—</text><clause id="idd9b22cd8-7975-40be-9d54-ab90f0a33a38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a contract for the exclusive personal services of the sound recording artist as a sound recording artist; or</text></clause><clause id="idaec1fd51-287f-4172-8e61-e7252902dbb1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an exclusive license to distribute or transmit 1 or more works that capture the audio performance of the sound recording artist.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1739457-eaf8-4375-a500-f1341568c15f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations period</header><text>A civil action may not be brought under this subsection unless the civil action is commenced not later than 3 years after the date on which the party seeking to bring the civil action discovered, or with due diligence should have discovered, the applicable violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2ffd62a-f9fe-49c0-87a7-80268e5fc133"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on liability for purely coincidental resemblance</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7b21d7933cb4c30ad80e3e8af7d20ea"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>An individual or entity shall not be liable for engaging in an activity described in subsection (c)(2)(A) if—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1775c005d2549d2940d096808c372f3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the resemblance of the voice or visual likeness embodied in the applicable digital replica to the voice or visual likeness of the actual individual is purely coincidental; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40c270623d0f4d6d8b6f5c3121ea69d9"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id340bd570fb6a4d71a60173e9d717c3a8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the actual individual has not achieved public recognition; or</text></subclause><subclause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide7e4071b9e7340a4bdfede18c1741328"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the voice or visual likeness of the actual individual does not have commercial value.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id93c188c3defb488fb4d31f3efe16e472"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclaimer not evidence</header><text>A disclaimer regarding the resemblance of the voice or visual likeness embodied in a digital replica to the voice or visual likeness of any actual individual shall not constitute evidence to support the limitation under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id241d9cdcda1244dd990f6f869bea2b05"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Defense not permitted</header><text>It shall not be a defense in a civil action brought under this subsection that the defendant displayed or otherwise communicated to the public a disclaimer stating that the applicable use of a digital replica, or the applicable product or service described in subsection (c)(2)(B), was unauthorized or disclosed that the digital replica, product, or service was generated through the use of artificial intelligence or other technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74363db5-0df6-435b-84b4-7d3ca50d1231"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Remedies</header><subparagraph id="ide47c2abb-a306-47c9-b7c7-95242356a87d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any civil action brought under this subsection—</text><clause id="idb499c8d5-da60-4072-9652-e48ee7f7afd4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual or entity found to have committed a violation of subsection (c) shall be liable to the injured party in an amount equal to the greater of—</text><subclause id="idb2397b1c-0a74-4d70-a044-69a72d1a417e"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id888a5bd1-f7da-46dd-bfc5-d9a0621664b8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of an individual, $5,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized use of a digital replica;</text></item><item id="id1f47c07b-0371-4064-9c6e-47edd28b7dc4" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $25,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized use of a digital replica;</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4e491295-e6cd-484e-acd3-b3e5d3a76fd0"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has not undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $5,000 per unauthorized display, copy made, transmission, and instance of the digital replica being made available on the online service in a sum of not more than $750,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized use of a digital replica; and</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37298190-9e96-4177-a5a7-7763b6c082a0"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>in the case of an entity that is not a provider of an online service, $25,000 per work embodying the applicable unauthorized use of a digital replica; or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id820ca894-ff44-4fe6-b49c-da0fc89e99d5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any actual damages suffered by the injured party as a result of the activity, plus any profits from the unauthorized use that are attributable to such use and are not taken into account in computing the actual damages;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id06ec0f76-81e6-417c-a876-42651ed549b8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual or entity found to have violated subsection (c) by virtue of engaging in an activity described in subsection (c)(2)(B) shall be liable to the injured party in an amount equal to the greater of—</text><subclause id="id8d06047f-6865-4261-9bf8-d20fa3da0339"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc149a9ff-bdd1-46f2-8933-4710b8feef02"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of an individual, $5,000 per product or service;</text></item><item id="id5a34fe68-a528-4c9b-97d6-871ad77be9d8" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $25,000 per product or service;</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf54f9413-24df-4833-b010-61b91d5855e8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>in the case of a provider of an online service that has not undertaken a good faith effort to implement all applicable obligations of paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (d), $750,000 per product or service; or</text></item><item indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96058571-875c-4837-b484-752f72c7b6e7"><enum>(dd)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an entity that is not a provider of an online service, $25,000 per product or service; or</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82899f79-c394-4418-b795-4c966a59dbc9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any actual damages suffered by the injured party as a result of the activity, plus any profits from the unauthorized use that are attributable to such use and are not taken into account in computing the actual damages;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id513a3ead-b4e2-4d3f-95d3-e6a09bff128f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the plaintiff may seek injunctive or other equitable relief;</text></clause><clause id="idd300e59e-432b-4428-a244-f1a741f7655a"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of willful activity in which the injured party has proven that the defendant acted with malice, fraud, knowledge, or willful avoidance of knowledge that the conduct violated the law, the court may award to the injured party punitive damages; and</text></clause><clause id="id075a10ed-7f00-4b5a-b3b4-1a7db3995e7e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>if the prevailing party is—</text><subclause id="idbb7fca1c-1fc6-4d15-aae4-efdd17967f9e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the party bringing the action, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id4faec038-b5bb-4b35-8703-9b6104710802"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the party defending the action, the court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees if the court determines that the action was not brought in good faith.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id647baee1-a8d9-432b-9c13-e48fb067a6da"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Objectively reasonable belief</header><text>A provider of an online service that has designated an agent under subsection (d)(2) and has an objectively reasonable belief that material that is claimed to be a digital replica, the use of which is unauthorized, does not qualify as a digital replica shall be liable only for actual damages under subparagraph (A) if the material is ultimately determined to be a digital replica, the use of which is unauthorized.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id16ecdaf0-d8ef-48c1-a845-b10c1a9457cb"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subpoena To identify violator</header><paragraph id="iddc6c3feb-4bd9-42dd-9982-ee7642041c6c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request</header><text>A right holder, an individual or entity authorized to act on behalf of a right holder, or an eligible plaintiff under subsection (e)(1) may request the clerk of any district court of the United States to issue a subpoena to a provider of an online service for identification of an alleged violator of this section in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4d23c4bc-5b1f-4147-bbf7-df338c2fc30c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of request</header><text>A request under paragraph (1) may be made by filing with the clerk—</text><subparagraph id="idca441e4a-66a8-45ed-8af1-efbf33e8e63b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of a notification described in subsection (d)(3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07805c85-67f0-4414-9efe-1638bb11716c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a proposed subpoena; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd5d9120b-e033-48cb-a6de-398ae1158e6b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a sworn declaration to the effect that— </text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id298234ce-6301-40a3-a668-a24f5ce17bd0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the purpose of the subpoena is to obtain the identity of an individual or entity alleged to be liable under subsection (c); and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcb1d0afc-a471-4673-8e8d-4818dd984e31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information described in clause (i) will only be used for the purpose of protecting rights under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id72a9a49d-c761-4999-b494-6c9273640ff8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of subpoena</header><text>A subpoena issued under this subsection shall authorize and order the provider of the applicable online service to expeditiously disclose to the party that sought the subpoena information sufficient to identify the alleged violator by virtue of the activity described in the notification to the extent that information is available to the provider of the online service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4892819a-efe4-49fe-9b86-75decb044c6c"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Basis for granting subpoena</header><text>If a proposed subpoena under this subsection is in proper form, the applicable notification filed satisfies the requirements under subsection (d)(3), and the accompanying declaration is properly executed, the clerk shall expeditiously issue and sign the proposed subpoena and return the subpoena to the requester for delivery to the provider of the applicable online service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3cd5e280-d5e2-44f6-ae5c-8e03ab805e19"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Preemption</header><paragraph id="ide385c44f-7c18-4dcc-949d-e0b267d4714b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The rights established under this section shall preempt any cause of action under State law for the protection of an individual’s voice and visual likeness rights in connection with a digital replica, as defined in this section, in an expressive work.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id453b270b-a501-4112-9011-d667a062e5a2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), nothing in this section may be construed to preempt—</text><subparagraph id="ide49798b8-7e82-49f7-a672-36e7ebd3764d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>causes of action under State statutes or common law in existence, as of January 2, 2025, regarding a digital replica;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5200bd30-8ba2-4d85-ac5f-901f99e4aa31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>causes of action under State statutes specifically regulating a digital replica depicting sexually explicit conduct, as defined in section 2256(2)(A) of title 18, United States Code, or an election-related digital replica; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idebd8f0b4-21e2-4bf9-8e20-f1ef6a0f00a5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>causes of action under State statutes or common law in existence, as of January 2, 2025, for the distributing, importing, transmitting, or otherwise making available to the public a product or service capable of producing 1 or more digital replicas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5f37b4bd-907e-4fb3-8c0a-0b373c422410"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id11266a00-4e30-4bd5-9096-6153b981a57b"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Laws pertaining to intellectual property</header><text>This section shall be considered to be a law pertaining to intellectual property for the purposes of section 230(e)(2) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(e)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5aded761-abb8-428e-83d6-3c5fa419d46b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No duty to monitor</header><text>Except as expressly provided in subsection (d)(1)(B)(ii), nothing in this section may be construed to require the provider of an online service to—</text><subparagraph id="id0ca5846d-162b-49cf-b5a9-16baf55fdeea"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitor the online service for, or affirmatively seek facts about, any digital replica; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id47197fe9-a07a-4880-9d05-77de2166f699" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gain access to material.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2fb2c815-cba0-4ee8-8276-b38cd91c35c7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this section, or the application of a provision of this section, is held to be invalid, the validity of the remainder of this section, and the application of that provision to other individuals, entities, and circumstances, shall not be affected by that holding.</text></subsection><subsection id="id106269d1-4238-4b9a-ab45-05f80015ae3b"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Retroactive effect</header><paragraph id="idab1f774c-46d4-4ddd-869e-365fe95ac341"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Liabilities</header><text>Liability under this section shall apply only to—</text><subparagraph id="idb98743f5-b3e3-454b-aa4d-448f00e1d1c1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct occurring after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb76d0303-abbc-4e98-a939-ee88c35f2646"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of conduct covered by a license or contract, a license or contract that is executed after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ed99eca-36f5-4c94-a80d-ced2b623e2e4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital replication right</header><text>The right granted under subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="id26c61097-03fb-4f13-bda5-fcb7d6003909"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall apply to any individual, regardless of whether the individual dies before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id895c59f2-5cca-4ee3-b95d-b93029932a4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a right holder who has died before the date of enactment of this Act, shall vest in the executors, heirs, assignees, or devisees of the right holder. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id704b45b7-eb17-42a5-9914-627e6aadba70"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

