<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9C91D762198241C1BFDD1192244ED342" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6062 IH: To transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain parcels of federal land in Harpers Ferry, West Virginia, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6062</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001148">Mr. Simpson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To transfer administrative jurisdiction over certain parcels of federal land in Harpers Ferry, West Virginia, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H86B602A4032947A3BBEE2C68355871B4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3BEB62B011FA4FEC98EA282B7DD936FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Transfer of Federal land in Harpers Ferry, West Virginia</header> 
<subsection id="H325EBF1E0CE042CEA5D14F522B5BB429"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer from DOI to CBP</header> 
<paragraph id="H7903254D101B480083E3946AEAE5CEA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Administrative jurisdiction over the approximately 25 acres of Federal land in Harpers Ferry, West Virginia, generally depicted as <quote>Area to be Transferred to CBP</quote> on the Map, is transferred from the Secretary to the Commissioner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C1FE80535DB4748AE18DC33FE85CBF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The land transferred under paragraph (1) shall be administered as part of U.S. Customs and Border Protection's Advanced Training Center in accordance with applicable law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF186708DFAF3470AAE925CAC68BEA9C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion from Harpers Ferry National Historical Park</header><text>The Secretary shall adjust the boundaries of the Park to exclude the land transferred under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC946CE05252E4E33B7F9AF079D376854"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Land Survey</header><text>The Commissioner—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC226B5F854F84676AD2DCF700FB0E613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall obtain a survey to finalize the exact acreage and legal description of the parcel of Federal land transferred under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF53CD962AFB4B1D9A11B7D2B92EF387"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in consultation with the Secretary, may modify any clerical or typographical errors in the legal description and maps of the land; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H787E5611AC2C471F8B24A70BCF124391"><enum>(C)</enum><text>upon completion of the survey, shall provide a complete copy of the survey to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7721E6650F06476497736B24ABC75F2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer from CBP to DOI</header> <paragraph id="HA908BB4C05654CB5A950A8E235BA0AD5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Administrative jurisdiction over the approximately 71.51 acres of Federal land in Harpers Ferry, West Virginia generally depicted as <quote>Area to be Transferred to NPS</quote> on the Map is transferred from the Commissioner to the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5AD43E9FFEE4F4693E71D28E8E285D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The land transferred under paragraph (1) shall be administered as part of the Park, and the Secretary shall adjust the boundaries of the Park to reflect the inclusion of the land under this subsection.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HA0FF3E91B0024B4996EC78C85C3E9D35"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No reimbursement of consideration</header><text>The transfer of land under this Act shall be without monetary reimbursement or additional consideration.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1FB88ED89D8B4D37BC71A4DD298213A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reversion and restoration</header> 
<paragraph id="HA9236F7FE5914B34A8D97527F3ECB2F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Commissioner determines that the land or a portion of the land transferred under subsection (a) is not required for the U.S. Customs and Border Protection's Advanced Training Center, administrative jurisdiction of such land or portion of land shall revert to the Secretary in a manner and condition acceptable to the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C58A1AC01BF4C5B8137C05B020A5307"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion in Park</header><text>Any land with respect to which administrative jurisdiction reverts to the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall be administered as a part of the Park, and the Secretary shall adjust the boundaries of the Park to reflect the inclusion of such land under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F092EA0E24A41BCB936FEA6DC76D68D"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Boundary limitation</header> <text>The acreage limitation in section 1(d) of the Act of June 30, 1944 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/450bb">16 U.S.C. 450bb(d)</external-xref>), shall not apply to the land transferred under this Act (including by reversion under subsection (d)).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H4B8ECE922E464B048EBCB259E20CB8B6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H395DFDE9B096436AB68C88A63627EA7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map published by the National Park Service titled <quote>Harpers Ferry National Historical Park Proposed Land Transfers</quote>, numbered 385/176,677, and dated May 2021.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF907AA80C808481DBDBED90414605059"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6FDD352AB6B432291C2F5F070DF9745"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Park</header><text>The term <term>Park</term> means Harpers Ferry National Historical Park.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52EE9E205AA348E480D7113206A6C373"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


