<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25B03-3SS-HS-YX1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3497 IS: Shelter Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3497</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit against tax for disaster mitigation expenditures.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H1A2D572AEA754A1D9476743662759B27"><section section-type="section-one" id="H076A4A697DD04890A638356CAE04E954"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shelter Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBFCBB2EE036946A19F721DB31AF0915E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nonrefundable personal credit for disaster mitigation expenditures</header><subsection id="H2D3E5FD601BD484EA46DA859868C6075"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as amended by section 70411 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/21">Public Law 119–21</external-xref>, is amended by inserting after section 25F the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73906A4BB09A45ACACA6BC96641DACD9"><section id="H29EAA887A6AA4CF5A49078B5EE472B4D"><enum>25G.</enum><header>Disaster mitigation expenditures</header><subsection id="H1EA98AA7E6F7467EB7C02E0D331325FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3d89c37ccd4c436bb67c750e55db32f4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this chapter for the taxable year an amount equal to 25 percent of the qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during such taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE7739935C114C8D8CBD60AD43A91AD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual limitation</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the credit allowed to a taxpayer under paragraph (1) for any taxable year shall not exceed $3,750 (or, in the case of a joint return, $7,500).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4fd541c67b32461aa9d5d1f9ba9e33d4"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cumulative limitation per qualified dwelling unit</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the credit allowed under paragraph (1) with respect to a qualified dwelling unit of the taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed the excess (if any) of $15,000 over the aggregate credits allowed under such paragraph with respect to such qualified dwelling unit for all prior taxable years ending after December 31, 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idA496013FC70346F9B50EF66510EBE07E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Income phaseout</header><paragraph id="id4F53B4BC81F04338B6D350A2F95F8279"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the credit allowed under subsection (a)(1) for the taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount under such subsection as—</text><subparagraph id="idD56E2F6054654E24A93093360F0DC9A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount (not less than zero) equal to the adjusted gross income of the taxpayer for such taxable year minus $100,000, bears to</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6DFC4984265D41308D7C6DBED8F26542"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$50,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFCE5166F1F604FFC8D8583350469E987"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any taxable year after 2026, each of the dollar amounts under paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="id554D30083D324E66A28346CC780A83AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEFA21BEB06874FF3B2578FE8AE8DC69F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD049A7B2A2F843938D32092A389FE385"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any reduction determined under paragraph (1) is not a multiple of $50, or any increase under paragraph (2) is not a multiple of $50, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $50.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf90a644899944f698ee56dd05cf2e794"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Joint return</header><text>If a joint return is filed by the taxpayer for the taxable year, for purposes of determining the amount of any reduction under paragraph (1) for such taxable year, the dollar amounts under such paragraph (after application of paragraphs (2) and (3)) shall be doubled.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13539FD2155946F39393EBC2188F1C2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HCA7A4B7B2EDA493DAE9EA0BB6BFD9A30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</header><subparagraph id="idC02E9CAC59884DCB9B22A13382DE4D87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the term <term>qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</term> means an expenditure relating to a qualified dwelling unit—</text><clause id="id4DCF78B897A54232B3B6FA896AB0458A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for property to—</text><subclause id="HC86A6585AEDC41DEBE91D4B27EBA366D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>improve the strength of a roof deck attachment,</text></subclause><subclause id="H33A74035519649D8978FAA4B84AD349A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>create a secondary water barrier to prevent water intrusion or mitigate against potential water intrusion from wind-driven rain,</text></subclause><subclause id="H21D212712CF7494A8296DD96C9B0BB8E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improve the durability, impact resistance (not less than class 3 or 4 rating), or fire resistance (not less than class A rating) of a roof covering,</text></subclause><subclause id="H09E4361C0168453088FA3532BAE2CBFA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>brace gable-end walls,</text></subclause><subclause id="HA877FA759397485796C03596E3FD1F02"><enum>(V)</enum><text>reinforce the connection between a roof and supporting wall,</text></subclause><subclause id="H2891DABF19B74999844C8767F0FF6710"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>protect openings from penetration by wind-borne debris,</text></subclause><subclause id="HDF7FFF3E2FBC4462919E7FA9BDFB8153"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>protect exterior doors and garages from natural hazards,</text></subclause><subclause id="idDFF24990073D4D02A9289708982BFBA2"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>complete measures contained in the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Wind Retrofit Guide for Residential Buildings</quote> (P–804),</text></subclause><subclause id="idDC2671051C464848948848FC781D405B"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>elevate the qualified dwelling unit, as well as utilities, machinery, or equipment, above the base flood elevation or other applicable minimum elevation requirement,</text></subclause><subclause id="idB41F0D526D41435AA904E0BF6EB3598B"><enum>(X)</enum><text>seal walls in the basement of the qualified dwelling unit using waterproofing compounds, or</text></subclause><subclause id="id24E997FAC6A94ED7BF75219C62F059A0"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>protect propane tanks or other external fuel sources,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idED55622F12434220A0C19CDFA31CB0B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to install—</text><subclause id="idC70A23209C634D57B01C918258327595"><enum>(I)</enum><text>check valves to prevent flood water from backing up into drains,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idB2EC87B177F7478DB04A931C3A933313"><enum>(II)</enum><text>flood vents, breakaway walls or open lattice for homes located in V zones,</text></subclause><subclause id="idFA335BBF74C540F29D4BB58B9D2E2071"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a stormwater drainage system or improve an existing system,</text></subclause><subclause id="idEF1412B764C34CA3956F888CFDEF5DD5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>natural or nature-based features for flood control, including living shorelines,</text></subclause><subclause id="idC31763DD73BC4BD6A177C3C4ADD46A00"><enum>(V)</enum><text>roof coverings, sheathing, flashing, roof and attic vents, eaves, or gutters that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause id="id1C547381A8C24DD480B94664F70975C3"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>wall components for wall assemblies that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id8E1ED7F09E634203991BCBD3B3F92650"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a wall-to-foundation anchor or connector, or a shear transfer anchor or connector,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id87DF06F840B8444F9CA5FD03C3DF2936"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>wood structural panel sheathing for strengthening cripple walls,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idF8FE1779318B4794AD0E3F247D27CBE8"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>anchorage of the masonry chimney to the framing,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id36D64DC3815D4FA7A6041D8478044024"><enum>(X)</enum><text>prefabricated lateral resisting systems,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id2C65F74AFF5D4A75BDE50BCA6246FA15"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>a standby generator system consisting of a standby generator and an automatic transfer switch,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idCFEA162CF4A346539D14961DAAFAE99E"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>a storm shelter that meets the design and construction standards established by the International Code Council and the National Storm Shelter Association (ICC–500), or a safe room that satisfies the criteria contained in—</text><item commented="no" id="idA60420148D44403CB0FC6D3C0B4422C3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Safe Rooms for Tornadoes and Hurricanes</quote> (P–361), or</text></item><item commented="no" id="id0631BE3A343140C5AC805EBADDD6770E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the publication of the Federal Emergency Management Agency entitled <quote>Taking Shelter from the Storm</quote> (P–320),</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idFDFF6410556346A78E8E74674A09A59D"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>a lightning protection system,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id7A9D0D05B9494209B5BB893A63D23A1C"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text>exterior walls, doors, windows, or other exterior dwelling unit elements that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id1F5449C15BFD44339D6CC252E3E576AA"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>exterior deck or fence components that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></subclause><subclause id="id688B2CC18B2B4B88A34856450368BB83"><enum>(XVI)</enum><text>structure-specific water hydration systems, including fire mitigation systems such as interior and exterior sprinkler systems,</text></subclause><subclause id="id63238A04C5FA465AB2490B365B5DED80"><enum>(XVII)</enum><text>water capture and delivery systems to accommodate drought events or to decrease water use, including the design of such systems,</text></subclause><subclause id="id7B63CD2134674EFDBE8A27CF53E8A6B6"><enum>(XVIII)</enum><text>flood openings for fully enclosed areas below the lowest floor of the dwelling unit,</text></subclause><subclause id="idEB91C67D6A8546C49F41928251E67416"><enum>(XIX)</enum><text>lateral bracing for wall elements, foundation elements, and garage doors or other large openings to resist seismic loads, or</text></subclause><subclause id="id25D2FB3279C64EF393B2FA93A0EF5ED0"><enum>(XX)</enum><text>automatic shutoff valves for water and gas lines, or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idFCD200F70CA644D3A380D1EA1BE59CF5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for services or equipment to—</text><subclause id="id6C0F899D536D4EF0B520DCB50652678C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>create buffers around the qualified dwelling unit through the removal or reduction of flammable vegetation, including vertical clearance of tree branches,</text></subclause><subclause id="id866095C2E88D4A9DB46BFA54A00FCF3C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>create buffers around the dwelling unit through—</text><item id="id881D7E1518A04DC3BE533E0E14DF6A40"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the removal of exterior deck or fence components or ignition-prone landscape features, or</text></item><item id="id7FDA27CC391B4146BDF4E508DB3C1573"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>replacement of the components or features described in item (aa) with components or features that conform to ignition-resistant construction standards,</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id0D88D6B6D7A440CC993063277A73AB8E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>perform fire maintenance procedures identified by the Federal Emergency Management Agency or the United States Forest Service, including fuel management techniques such as creating fuel and fire breaks,</text></subclause><subclause id="idD7B91F5B15F44487B8676444CB38C5E4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>replace flammable vegetation with less flammable species, or</text></subclause><subclause id="id709E3BD0A01E4AEAA10E78CE310C4585"><enum>(V)</enum><text>prevent smoke inhalation, such as air filters or other equipment designed to prevent smoke from entering the dwelling unit,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4472103E2160483CBC87FD146A2BE34B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for property relating to satisfying the standards required for receipt of a FORTIFIED designation or a Wildfire Prepared designation from the Insurance Institute for Business and Home Safety, or any third-party verified certification demonstrating compliance with nationally recognized and consensus-based hazard mitigation or resilience standards, provided that the qualified dwelling unit receives such designation or certifications following installation of such property, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23b79549aa224e2da0e8993525c1acf4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any other hazard mitigation activity which has been identified by the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, for mitigation of a natural hazard or compliance with other consensus-based resiliency standards.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB6C91B9946E14A7CAE21A4706D005606" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hazard-specific applicability</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbe76a691760438ba1454ef7df3612e1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), the term <term>qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</term> shall only apply to expenditures relating to a qualified dwelling unit which are described in subparagraph (A) if such expenditures address a hazard type identified in the applicable State or tribal Standard State Mitigation Plans or Enhanced State Mitigation Plans, as prepared under section 201.4 or 201.5 of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this section).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f5c1f4dc25e440db2a2148cdf875491"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Negative lists</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, may publish a list of inapplicable expenditures which are region-specific in order to prohibit the application of subsection (a) for expenditures relating to hazards which are not relevant to the location of the qualified dwelling unit.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcba2f4f4bc814e72bd998fc79b781285"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception</header><text>The term <term>qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</term> shall not include any expenditure or portion thereof which is paid, funded, or reimbursed by a Federal, State, or local government entity, or any political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7505DD50A0A647228F3577478C45F886"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified dwelling unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified dwelling unit</term> means a dwelling unit which is located—</text><subparagraph id="id9C7042F8F6E949F68B11BDE054DF8065"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the United States or in a territory of the United States, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id414576939186451D9383B6E138BB27C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in an area—</text><clause commented="no" id="idB7FDAA133A3F4F5892BF6AC8919460D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which, during the taxable year or the period of the 5 taxable years preceding such taxable year, has received hazard mitigation assistance through the Federal Emergency Management Agency in regard to any natural disaster which, with respect to the expenditure described in paragraph (1) which is made by the taxpayer, is applicable to such expenditure, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id167FD6D4DE434AB8A1A56B9672234F32"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id1e1b694234434108b18a8044fd3b64a2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in which a Federal natural disaster declaration has been made within the preceding 5-year period,</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id38f568462288430cbb048463d73aab03" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which is adjacent to an area described in subclause (I), or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="ide91e400dee44450e90a513fcdc800d5e"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which, with respect to any taxable year, has been designated as a community disaster resilience zone (as defined in section 206(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5136">42 U.S.C. 5136(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H132E85A025274D0D99921A685D94D0C9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="id1F8BB5B89FC6433FA6BD42E1DE171856"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an expenditure described in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (c)(1)(A), such expenditure shall be taken into account in determining the qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during the taxable year only if the onsite preparation, assembly, or original installation of the property with respect to which such expenditure is made has been completed in a manner that is deemed to be in compliance with the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards or any more restrictive Federal, State, or local floodplain management standards and consistent with floodplain management regulations for the local jurisdiction in which the qualified dwelling unit is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id16490DD19C234A5ABB58667B784BA2E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Latest published editions</header><text>The term <term>latest published editions</term> means, with respect to relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards, either of the 2 most recently published editions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3ADDF4E974B846B2B6070229AD75656F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Labor costs</header><text>For purposes of this section, expenditures for labor costs properly allocable to the onsite preparation, assembly, or original installation of the property described in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (c)(1)(A) shall be taken into account in determining the qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC5C46E5D31D944E98477F208EBAE96EC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Inspection costs</header><text>For purposes of this section, expenditures for the cost of any inspection required under subsection (d) which is properly allocable to the inspection of the preparation, assembly, or installation of the property described in clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (c)(1)(A) shall be taken into account in determining the qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="id74A24C67677145D0BC3A46F3F56C2E4A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Carryforward of unused credit</header><paragraph id="id15D7106545AC4FBB8BBEDA40A24C6CBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the credit allowable under subsection (a)(1) for any taxable year exceeds the applicable tax limit for such taxable year, such excess shall be a carryover to each of the 5 succeeding taxable years and, subject to the limitations of paragraph (2), shall be added to the credit allowable by subsection (a)(1) for such succeeding taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id10971F2C5F114A96BA16EE3DF31D29CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount of the unused credit which may be taken into account under paragraph (1) for any taxable year shall not exceed the amount (if any) by which the applicable tax limit for such taxable year exceeds the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="idF5EDEE67E2CC4DD494A42B56B06573EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the credit allowable under subsection (a)(1) for such taxable year determined without regard to this subsection, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4207DD5802B341FB9237CA898A37AF54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amounts which, by reason of this subsection, are carried to such taxable year and are attributable to taxable years before the unused credit year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF0AF6D6D277C48459C69C13811D85F9D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable tax limit</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>applicable tax limit</term> means the limitation imposed by section 26(a) for the taxable year reduced by the sum of the credits allowable under this subpart (other than this section).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id79BB4BFB2FA444B6A00449C75B4DF9CC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>Any taxpayer claiming the credit under this section shall provide the Secretary with adequate documentation regarding the specific qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during the taxable year, as well as such other information or documentation as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1CFBF6592A4C47C2ABEADAA650E7CB3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 25F the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF698101ED1AD4EB48121F40B2B1CA523"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 25G. Disaster mitigation expenditures.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H81D411D0650B4B09938A2E695DC7D382"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="H967FE83428AC4C43B1FB0E242863388A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Business-related credit for disaster mitigation</header><subsection id="H8B0FD14CCE044B098B6736560D666907"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 45AA the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4ECDA8CAC47041E09358DD31E01F9981"><section id="H9A22093A195E4B3589979ED8B33C7B3B"><enum>45BB.<?LEXA-Enum 45BB.?></enum><header>Disaster mitigation credit</header><subsection id="H1FFDE6326FBA49FAB085DFD10F13F011"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the disaster mitigation credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to 25 percent of the qualified disaster mitigation expenditures made by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3984BB2B088F463BA99A85BC2A50C365"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maximum credit</header><paragraph id="id85726EA74A904636A998B7AB3C291545"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall not exceed $5,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5294875439A544D5A73DC63D1728944F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Phaseout</header><subparagraph id="id70F5DD93F0524178BC56E431C5A194BC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount under paragraph (1) for the taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by an amount which bears the same ratio to the amount under such paragraph as—</text><clause id="id5AA7C7499C98409F857CF0242F7DF6D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount (not less than zero) equal to the average gross receipts of the taxpayer over the 3 preceding taxable years minus $5,000,000, bears to</text></clause><clause id="idE86ACCAAEF174D179AB56F6F56445FDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$5,000,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62D805763A73445AB96928FD251F2732"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any taxable year after 2026, each of the dollar amounts under subparagraph (A) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><clause id="idEC3A55B124DA4651BDF0792952772285"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="idFFA43F045CA94FF78BBCFE94366DBF8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8DF5B39DD2344DB89CB3B1836D99B623"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any reduction determined under subparagraph (A) is not a multiple of $50, or any increase under subparagraph (B) is not a multiple of $50, such amount shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $50.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16150F4A2411409FAD3F3F9BAF9A85CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6CAB05FFDD5E4415A1258A5E7751A59E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified disaster mitigation expenditure</term> has the same meaning given such term under paragraph (1) of section 25G(c), except that <quote>place of business</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>qualified dwelling unit</quote> each place it appears in such paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04247B12AE864FFD9883A36A6EE29E77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Place of business</header><text>For purposes of this section, an expenditure shall not be treated as a qualified disaster mitigation expenditure (as defined in paragraph (1)) unless the taxpayer's place of business is located—</text><subparagraph id="id21D87AF22E404CDEAC90EF3758A8C130"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the United States or in a territory of the United States, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id1F6AC56B0C9442FCA8B9A0815C0739E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in an area—</text><clause commented="no" id="id313ADE9D655245D5AF738EA250ADDAB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which a Federal natural disaster declaration has been made within the preceding 5-year period,</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id77F9890050AA46E0BFB71EBA8FB82751"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is adjacent to an area described in clause (i),</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id8BABB60771964E4E90D5D277D5B61AD3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which, during the taxable year or the period of the 5 taxable years preceding such taxable year, has received hazard mitigation assistance through the Federal Emergency Management Agency in regard to any natural disaster which, with respect to the expenditure described in section 25G(c)(1) which is made by the taxpayer, is applicable to such expenditure, or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde0e1c8c2cf14dcf83b1729bb40a0fa5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>which, with respect to any taxable year, has been designated as a community disaster resilience zone (as defined in section 206(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5136">42 U.S.C. 5136(a)</external-xref>)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4A6947FE5C6B477BB68C779E336295A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of subsections (d) through (g) of section 25G shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ad879eda8134597b29335ea29ee891f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No double benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be determined under this section with respect to any expenditures for which a credit was allowed under section 25G.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H23608127CA9D4D5FB6E71941FAA33BB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H25DFAE1C7818413292BA9C20F702E6E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7714C6E93D644DEC90DB4C0BE3FF1BAC"><paragraph id="HFAF59C0A0C804F36A14FBEE14BCDB497"><enum>(42)</enum><text>the disaster mitigation credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DD2624FA5114E3F983188A8C816DFB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 45AA the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BF91B2961F64A3ABF40360A6528CF09"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45BB. Disaster mitigation credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10586106A5E1479ABFE5D68D22F05014"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

