<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0025A82DDDFF49B2B3EBAB9B7CA0A334" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1122 IH: Honoring the life and legacy of Coach Louis Leo “Lou” Holtz.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1122</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001233">Mr. Messmer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and legacy of Coach Louis Leo <quote>Lou</quote> Holtz.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas Louis Leo <quote>Lou</quote> Holtz was born on January 6, 1937, in Follansbee, West Virginia, to Andrew and Anne Holtz, and grew up in East Liverpool, Ohio;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz earned his undergraduate degree in history from Kent State University, where he played football for 2 seasons until an injury led him to assist the coaching staff, and he later completed his master’s degree at the University of Iowa, laying the foundation for a life devoted to teaching, coaching, and inspiring others;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz married Beth Barcus on July 22, 1961, and their marriage endured more than 5 decades, with 4 children, 9 grandchildren, and 2 great-grandchildren;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz had a legendary career as a college football head coach at William and Mary, North Carolina State University, the University of Arkansas, the University of Minnesota, the University of Notre Dame, and the University of South Carolina, finishing with a collegiate record of 249 wins, 132 losses, and 7 ties;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, at each institution Lou Holtz served, he inherited a program with a losing record and transformed it into a winning team, earning the distinction of being the only coach in college football history to lead 6 different programs to bowl games and to guide 4 of them to final top-20 national rankings;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz was inducted into the National Football Foundation College Football Hall of Fame in 2008 in recognition of his contributions to college football;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz instituted several traditions at the University of Notre Dame, including the <quote>Play Like A Champion Today</quote> sign in the locker room and the removal of names from the back of the football jerseys to emphasize the team dynamic;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz taught 3 essential rules: do what is right, do it to the best of your ability, and show people you care—principles that not only shaped the teams he built but, more importantly, shaped character, instilled purpose, and helped young men become the best versions of themselves on the field and in life;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz became a trusted analyst for CBS Sports and ESPN’s College GameDay broadcasts from 2005 to 2015, a New York Times bestselling author, and one of America’s most sought-after motivational speakers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz received the Presidential Medal of Freedom, the highest civilian honor in the United States, from President Donald J. Trump on December 3, 2020, in recognition of his extraordinary impact as one of America’s greatest football coaches and a lifelong teacher of character and leadership;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz and his wife, Beth, demonstrated generosity throughout their lives, including through the Lou and Beth Holtz Family Scholarship and the Rockne Heritage Fund for student-athlete financial aid; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lou Holtz, a devoted husband, father, faithful Catholic, and one of college football’s most legendary figures, leaves behind a legacy defined by faith, family, perseverance, and an unwavering belief in the potential of others: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0502E5168ED945E8B30E0518E5C36EA2"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HC5FC85E3FF56460FA550EB2F549652DD"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HF679EB57AA684065BEDA954958C8C73B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the life and legacy of Louis Leo <quote>Lou</quote> Holtz, including his dedication to the game of college football and the promotion of excellence, character, and teamwork in student-athletes;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5F04BDEFD36546168407590FF1548107"><enum>(2)</enum><text>remembers the drive, faith, and character of Coach Holtz and all that he did to educate and mentor hundreds of players over his more than 3 decades as a college football head coach; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABF6FD0E15E5406D9FCC2146EB4107E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>extends a heartfelt thank you to Coach Holtz for his service to the game of college football and continues to honor his enduring legacy of faith, family, and the relentless pursuit of excellence.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

