<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H71A2A7F4AC08407BA2AB1FE1AF8B125A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6154 IH: Regional Leadership in Wildland Fire Research Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6154</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of regional wildland fire research centers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1531BFBB598B4729A0F6D4A3436007F9" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H114F13AC5FF84A9CA9FA4B8C39F49B18"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regional Leadership in Wildland Fire Research Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1F7A1C61FCC54E7EA1D4E5E02F49AAC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB66BFE02E7E14A3DA38149EDF24DCBA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC60B86E56D2143C990F15CA7230B47BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75A2252078B944F39D76DD5D51F74236"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Agriculture, the Committee on Natural Resources, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC017692EFFFB4C959349D9E5E8AA5292"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other committee of Congress with the authority to facilitate the development of wildland fire research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A6FAF788AE4714A7F7550A98F802B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board</term> means the National Center Coordination Board established by section 3(c)(1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA14DFEE8A31E4D7BAEB321420FAB9AA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Career pathway</header><text>The term <term>career pathway</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FECAB7E47444A68A02D30EF06984B0A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chief</header><text>The term <term>Chief</term> means the Chief of the Forest Service. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1887FAA85E54AB08DFEBF80148F2CC2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal science agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal science agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 103(f) of the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6623">42 U.S.C. 6623(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H873E63EF9BCF4CC88DE866FD97D89CAB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H181074FCFE6E4AC780C3DB0D5F7C5484"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3511818D81E546A9994FB75CCD4271BB"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Land-grant colleges and universities</header><text>The term <term>land-grant colleges and universities</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3103">7 U.S.C. 3103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22D7FAA72C2444C089048725715F410D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text>The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means an institution defined in any of paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC88256D8E4324B1EA58E9839696AD59A"><enum>(10)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA94CA55E817455C9B62FEB3072977EB"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Regional center</header><text>The term <term>regional center</term> means a regional wildland fire research center established under section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H847DF821104D46B4A7AFD6585B922A0D"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretaries</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF3090020FF74B94A58313BB81B20152"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>Tribal organization</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02B05B9A610647EF8F4151F0443C905F"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Wildland fire</header><text>The term <term>wildland fire</term> means any non-structure fire that occurs in vegetation or natural fuels and includes wildfires originating from an unplanned ignition or prescribed fire.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20E60612612A467299194BF1E6B087AB"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Wildland fire management agencies</header><text>The term <term>wildland fire management agencies</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC685C5E25E3240E2B8D46FFC76AC0882"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Forest Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6412769EA2243E6B8E159010C475CFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA58326BAFD54F04AA9FA4B548D34DED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Park Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBE2A03DEB5B4FD88C97D910062A6D17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF191D138D9BC459890AD515DAEF1AC92"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H047DB1E3E0B34D34A5DC0EB2F49A5BBB"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Wildland fire research</header><text>The term <term>wildland fire research</term> means research to better understand—</text><subparagraph id="H7BB763D9446B4A1F930D293834EA7170"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the causes and consequences of wildland fires, including antecedent and contemporaneous factors that increase the risk of catastrophic events;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB09A52F81C3E45A3AC208FE4052EC1C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the spread and behavior of wildland fires, including fires in the wildland-urban interface;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE815A6EA01C644699506BF9923D03DDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the efficacy of mitigation strategies for wildland fires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E09778905B94EAAAFB5B4184F510B65"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the impact of wildland fires on public health, safety, and the environment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB23530283ED5433DA3B63DB07850195F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the rehabilitation and restoration of affected ecosystems after wildland fires; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H546979CFDCA441228AB7841B7FB6D9EA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the development of mitigation strategies and techniques to improve the safety of wildland fire managers and firefighters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H58B48EA3F8F342D99D3C9465E2EDBD1B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of regional wildland fire research centers</header><subsection id="H962BCC984C874FAEA9CAA573F1DC8477"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretaries shall establish a competitive process for the selection and establishment of regional wildland fire research centers in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9278C867E12D46D5A7B7180768807842"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection and establishment of regional centers</header><paragraph id="H687DAD79141A420CB9BD10CF6E8A1BBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries shall select not fewer than 8 institutions of higher education or land-grant colleges and universities at which to establish, in accordance with the timeline described in paragraph (2), regional centers to coordinate the development of wildland fire research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7D977CE04DF4EF89DE47D9D8223A4AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeline</header><text>In establishing regional centers under paragraph (1), the Secretaries shall establish—</text><subparagraph id="H523E19298A0B4A5087B44F027366E6A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, subject to the availability of appropriations, a pilot program under which not fewer than 2 regional centers shall be established; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC39AE3E8E16C42999BD3895143E72919"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date on which the pilot program is established under subparagraph (A), the remaining regional centers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCC66DDD1E3D484894CEF268B5A42400"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Criteria for selection</header> <subparagraph id="H14986E77307944B4AA7BDDA506DB87F1"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing a regional center at an institution of higher education or land-grant college or university under this section, the Secretaries shall prioritize the selection of institutions, colleges, or universities that meet not fewer than one of the following criteria:</text>
                        <clause id="H4621A60B8B9C47E38D1B379A3622C8AB">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Have existing programs of record in wildland fire research.</text> </clause> <clause id="H23F920AA055C4853AE3E829DB93D5009"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>Have existing partnerships with research institutions of the Federal Government and other academic institutions and entities relating to wildland fire research.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H626891CF3380477789093BB8B71CCD47">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Participate in or lead a program under the Joint Fire Science Program.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HAAC1FCD254084F458BD6616AE86B0B6F">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Are a minority-serving institution.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD25176804DAE40B0B640C627AEFD454A"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Regions</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries shall establish not fewer than 1 regional center in each of the following regions of the United States, as defined by the Secretaries:</text>
                        <clause id="H6EC5A4F2EC054F4E9DF8E3274881F899">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>Alaska.</text> </clause> <clause id="H6245A8BF459A4761B296188E18C9793E"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>California.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HA092FAF453AC47C0A77082D7B179BCD3">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>The Pacific Northwest.</text> </clause> <clause id="HFDDED34FBB674824A7A600CD3E762FE0"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>The Pacific Islands.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HB89748BA2D6D4A7B94E2FB3528644025">
                            <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Plains and Northeast.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H48DBDFC93578408991986BE0339C49E3">
                            <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>The Rockies.</text> </clause> <clause id="H796F14875FEE4A17BAB113EF101DBE72"> <enum>(vii)</enum> <text>The Southeast.</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H0C096590FDDD4262A8FCC39118F908C2">
                            <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text>The Southwest.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph><paragraph id="H5FDBC8C2D8874212BD3F15E9076846EE"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Purpose</header> <text>Each regional center, with respect to the region covered by the regional center, shall—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H45C9E807220048CBB932F3A570129859">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>to the extent practical, coordinate research with other wildland fire research entities, such as other academic institutions, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Science Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Department of Energy, the research and development program of the Forest Service, the National Laboratories, the United States Geological Survey, and State and regional research organizations;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HA109876DE909466AA361B42FA6B85F7B">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>improve the understanding of wildland fire through wildland fire research that can be applied by wildland fire management agencies;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H2B60D75843144C019E629B5383AF2645">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>develop technologies and other tools to understand, monitor, and predict wildland fire, including—</text>
                        <clause id="H1A9F7F1D789A42ECA49770FB690F8353">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>models to predict fire potential and the spread and behavior of wildland fire and smoke;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H7F33B9D843FC43D68B3A1DF39CA0B695">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>models to predict how vegetation will respond to changes in the environment and wildland fire;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HAC2DB9349632479886346AF77538554B">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the integration of technologies to predict the spread and behavior of wildland fire and smoke in as near-real-time as possible; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HE3C7577AFE3B405DA8E8E6AEC312DDFC">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other innovations to be integrated into operational decision support systems relating to wildland fire, such as the Wildland Fire Decision Support System and the Interagency Fuel Treatment Decision Support System;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HF560CDCB485743E3BC2088A50C973482">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>develop technologies and other tools to safely support land management activities to reduce the severity of wildland fire;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H2C65CD35D61F4D22BDAD79735824990F">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leverage predictive capabilities to reduce the impact of smoke on communities and wildfire incident management teams, including wildland firefighters;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HB633FAB6CB4A419597C3B4268C2CDE4C">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>improve the understanding of post-fire risk to the landscape, including flash flooding potential and watershed impacts;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H47122F2E64E3478CB3B32D73EBE00D5A">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>test and operate models to support land management decision-making, including through—</text>
                        <clause id="H153993B0B3FF476B8B3D24C8760DB51C">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>operating models to support management of wildland fire and vegetation;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H9DA3CEF9F68C4D9299E7893AB78379CB">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the demonstration of integration technologies to support management of wildland fire in as near-real-time as possible; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HD74114EC36DA49FAAE1F96AC18F7B7C6">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the incorporation of decision science and social science that examines the perception and adoption of information related to wildland fire risk;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H061E4925EF0249BBB770A983E31051A2">
                        <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>develop a career pathway training program with respect to carrying out wildland fire research;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HC05A8D12EB3B433D9E5E7A811C2EC22E">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>develop data management protocols to allow for full and open exchange of data pursuant to the principles of findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability (commonly referred to as the <quote>FAIR principles</quote>) and archive and access that data;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HA5B0DEA99929493188E5D56337F344B1">
                        <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop training programs for prescribed fire implementation; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H16AC0ED8DAEC427297066A82D98A83D5">
                        <enum>(K)</enum>
 <text>make its work and data fully and openly available.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D35E12535DE497DBA61440362790F92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National Center Coordination Board</header><paragraph id="H0986753ECF7B48CDAE46EBE5C7558FDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a coordination board, to be known as the <quote>National Center Coordination Board</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBA5D3FD381D47D98FADC550C84A6BDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><subparagraph id="HF470F17F00B24C36B377EDAA39443F7F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Members</header><clause id="H5E9B4E2C08934A799DDD31A74770D0D6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall be composed of one member representing each regional center.</text></clause><clause id="H49C5B0BAEBA245708F1A8E5D3F4B3316"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Each member under clause (i) shall be selected by the relevant regional center.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8E8D73432EF46F1A91053BE8DE08B21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Administrator and the Chief shall serve as the Co-Chairs of the Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8733F08E48E49AB8001276D1622C960"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Board shall—</text><subparagraph id="HEBE002D3721541F2B00292CF7D72CC63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish wildland fire science, data management, and sharing protocols, and technological research priorities in cooperation with each regional center and informed by the operational needs of wildland fire management agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6AD51F3DDBB4E57B2357D30DD128091"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate data collection efforts supporting the efforts of each regional center, including—</text><clause id="H7053012D95EF4A4E9952512CF7E5F6E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>building data layers across each region described in subsection (b)(2)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="H188653F4F8054A8DB29F414C1A7D47BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing updates on the development of wildland fire research models; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78E97438EBB2469785C9974122EDCF7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure the coordination of, and avoid unnecessary duplication of, the activities of the regional centers and the activities of institutions of higher education, land-grant colleges and universities, Federal science agencies, and State research organizations with respect to wildland fire research, including—</text><clause id="H1B9B65CA008340A8ACA1C7DD743BBD98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></clause><clause id="HF40CB544728E4D55AC9B43E53822FF26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Laboratories;</text></clause><clause id="HABA17A5F69EB4DB78E905B765C555559"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text></clause><clause id="H4005254EB113440793873F79D5117A61"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></clause><clause id="H3CB3564C48AB416D893465C4D62E517A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the United States Fire Administration;</text></clause><clause id="H3C10AE9ED6C04604AB05661AD9684829"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the United States Geological Survey; and</text></clause><clause id="H8195306A5AD0421ABE49263B2A2EAE55"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other relevant entity with specialized expertise in wildland fire research; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC12A2C5A0D344ED38E4343C28F38AA87"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support end-to-end applications that assist wildland fire management agencies in adopting technologies and incorporating research findings produced by the regional centers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA73A31024B5463DBF0C9C5F90A8C8F4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="H7A5C66948CD04BFE92E076D553558C29"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Board meetings</header><text>The Board shall meet quarterly.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC83BA2A100A74C169DBBE1064BF10AE6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Public meetings</header><clause id="H5B73DFCF60914F10BBD650F8474C4CFA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall hold public meetings with affected stakeholders to solicit information from the general public regarding the development and implications of wildland fire research.</text></clause><clause id="H83EEA3B51BC44D2B8BE77B22A9997A30"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Board shall hold at least one public meeting in each State covered by a region described in subsection (b)(2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03850E044D0C4E9999FA9ED68E1343F6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 4 years, except that of the members first appointed, the Secretaries shall ensure that approximately—</text><subparagraph id="H29DCE9C75D3B4CBBB562AA332DB91816"><enum>(A)</enum><text><fraction>1/3</fraction> of members are appointed for a term of 4 years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7034CB708D541B685F2577E35D955C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text><fraction>1/3</fraction> of members are appointed for a term of 3 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7C5B466F4AC416DA9103DA519E2810A"><enum>(C)</enum><text><fraction>1/3</fraction> of members are appointed for a term of 2 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C75AC5E7449453C9B3A56265653BBDC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><subparagraph id="HA714E4F7CCA14875834023EF915192C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vacancy on the Board—</text><clause id="HC491F7A4AD134DC6884BFD7126F1B875"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Board; and</text></clause><clause id="H9799869A17EC413C8DBF7A0C676C5129"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made by not later than 180 days after the date on which the vacancy occurs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63A89C88530D4394BC1CDBFAF868549C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Filling unexpired term</header><text>An individual chosen to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the member replaced.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE3D4F786F1D4EE2A13BE4ECB2D29472"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than annually, the Board shall submit to the Secretaries recommendations to improve wildland fire research to be included in the report described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H943AF6C945614C1280EABA601973BE5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Advisory boards</header><paragraph id="H26750877F4694B5E86C3CE0E73780214"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), the Secretaries shall establish at each regional center an advisory board, to be known as the <quote>Regional Advisory Board</quote>, to carry out the duties described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ABBB1502B054E66B8238BA2D6676931"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><subparagraph id="HC3ED6CE9C15B4BDAAEB9F69008E5FBC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Regional Advisory Board shall consist of members, who shall be from, or have responsibility covering, the region covered by the relevant regional center, including at minimum—</text><clause id="H5844A2FD54CF4D10BE8012FA5F81203A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>1 regional representative from each wildland fire management agency, appointed by that agency;</text></clause><clause id="HD67D1863F5B94FF8A3C00E88B5564883"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>1 representative a State government agency from each State located in that region with expertise in forestry and wildland fire mitigation and management, appointed by the Governor of that State;</text></clause><clause id="H796EAB182CE745D191DC1B8764AE5D11"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1 representative from an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization from that region with expertise in forestry and wildland fire mitigation and management on Tribal or Federal land, appointed by the Secretaries; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H105D0303A18F4ED393109CBF8615A1B6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>additional representatives elected under subparagraph (B)(ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4448ADDAC1A2421295F7C4618BBCE3A0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elected membership</header><clause id="H678957AFED8D4148B1A0B8F6B828CA9C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Subcommittee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Regional Advisory Board shall solicit and approve, on at least an annual basis, nominations for individuals with operational expertise in wildland fire mitigation and management to serve as a representative on a subcommittee to the Regional Advisory Board for the purposes of clause (ii), composed of not more than 15 individuals, including representatives from, as applicable—</text><subclause id="H953FFF0A35DE45C0A26933205B141BAE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>institutions of higher education or land-grant colleges and universities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H357268056BEE4C76BF3AADF58BF5DECF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7854D14DEC1F4DD3AE62264AC991AB65"><enum>(III)</enum><text>private industry;</text></subclause><subclause id="H605D598823844700AF0B6940EF4B4DB4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the wildland firefighter community, including organizations that represent the interests of wildland firefighters; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAE45E9721BCE45E880525BAAF2BD567F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Southwest Ecological Restoration Institutes established under section 5(a) of the Southwest Forest Health and Wildfire Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6704">16 U.S.C. 6704(a)</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H90FC6F98355D455DA9D2DD24F9D41C98"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Election</header><text>The subcommittee described in clause (i) for a Regional Advisory Board may elect a member or members of the subcommittee to serve as a member of the Regional Advisory Board under subparagraph (A)(iv) for a 2-year term.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49A43E913D5547858342E0E2221955B5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Each member of a Regional Advisory Board shall serve on a voluntary basis without compensation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF969481D7FFB4BCB923DE29E7D484D68"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each Regional Advisory Board shall—</text><subparagraph id="HDEE4582AE6D2417D9797CAF4C3F84FA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure and support the coordination of wildland fire research between the relevant regional center and Federal and State land management agencies in that region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC830B0BC2EFA4126A10FCFAA45717C17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>communicate the operational needs of Federal and State land management agencies and wildland fire management agencies in that region to the relevant regional center and to the Board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA22E73A9BC26456AB5DAC39A07200653"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advise, in coordination with the relevant regional center, on research goals and objectives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H928788049A0C4D749FBC0669CD86A840"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assist the relevant regional center with the dissemination of research outputs and data to Federal and State land management agencies and wildland fire management agencies in that region.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3CC8E054754C018446FA3A057803A9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Each Regional Advisory Board shall meet quarterly.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AA150D5FA4A4C0497475DC9AF414C16"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Term</header><text>Unless specified otherwise, a member of a Regional Advisory Board shall serve for a term of 4 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DA2AE617F5C452CA80AB859C119BB74"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><subparagraph id="H6392763C05F2499B8EF7674FEB508AD0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vacancy on a Regional Advisory Board—</text><clause id="H6122AF6DE11F4330AC96A5536FAC1A2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Regional Advisory Board; and</text></clause><clause id="HEF8213A7086A4F228D12D999F88EA573"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made by not later than 180 days after the date on which the vacancy occurs.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E5F1A8EF85B48FA92753CC4330263B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Filling unexpired term</header><text>An individual chosen to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the member replaced.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21842D5235E743B8A56DC52395B73523"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report on wildland fire research</header><text>Not later than each of 2 years and 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries, in consultation with the Board, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing—</text><paragraph id="H8000C30F2F51466F9CD42ECB0AE5FFD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the progress each regional center has made in the development of wildland fire research; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28C543E40E90475BB838AA2D2FF72BEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations to improve wildland fire research.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED187B2E2EDD4AEAB3BA89AF6B9CAA59"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the requirements of this section, the Secretaries shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H23AABE605B014E2E97200358AD89F5E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal science agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD097AA1739FE4C139CA39682714DB20C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0C45079A1E94806BB9BAFD6CB6CBF1C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H9AC59463152D4B7FAF2D9E4337773174"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HED9BA1EB95CD4252B2B3D677AEB40DA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regional centers</header><text>For establishing and administering the regional centers established under subsection (a), there is authorized to be appropriated—</text><clause id="HB72F2F5393FC4F049B663D48E6510FB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$60,000,000 for fiscal year 2026;</text></clause><clause id="H75AA4EA06C9541C38A4E6869E5676628"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$61,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</text></clause><clause id="H9BA94F47C3924356A20B8639738C2FC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>$62,000,000 for fiscal year 2028;</text></clause><clause id="H979E550EC2A04027A4A5B28C6D2EC50A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>$63,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></clause><clause id="H401FDEB16520420BB741BF2C2FAF123C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>$64,000,000 for fiscal year 2030.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66F2B02D13424613AB256341CACA989E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Board</header><text>For the Board established under subsection (c), there is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BE767BC9BBE444C9F7F8D327BF643F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible use of funds</header><text>A regional center may use amounts appropriated pursuant to an authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1)(A) for construction or the acquisition of equipment necessary to carry out the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9689F82AFDCC47FDBC4929F1E036F302"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Flexibility</header><subparagraph id="H674043A6A39E4A57A40DF676A945FEC9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretaries shall adjust appropriations under paragraph (1) between the regional centers established under subsection (a) as needed to account for differences in administrative costs and research challenges specific to a particular region.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD996884899A14D05BF4E7EBD437001B1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Before adjusting appropriations under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year, the Administrator shall—</text><clause id="HEFEF274F30B14C4CA59A79F1D9DAD016"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include that adjustment in the budget justification materials submitted by the Administrator and the Chief in support of the budget of the President (as submitted to Congress under section 1105 of title 31, United States Code) for that fiscal year; and</text></clause><clause id="HED2527B90675483EA3E467316341CEC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide notice of that adjustment to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2F08CD3940F495AA1BF38CCAD0C3466"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>A Federal science agency may transfer, as necessary, additional appropriated amounts to a regional center for the purpose of carrying out wildland fire research described in subsection (b)(3)(B). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

