<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0ED48BA0C1B14BE0BE1B593FFCC25AD5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7717 IH: Community Health Profiles Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7717</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a pilot program at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to support local jurisdictions in developing neighborhood-level, publicly accessible health data platforms, to establish a National Neighborhood Health Data Repository, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCD559A5DD07E404490822CC51F45AF48" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8C43B4B3BD0B4370BE993A8F274C59C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Health Profiles Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H16AB8A21C97B405F8560BDF17D5286EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community health data pilot program</header> <subsection id="HD70129A4CC144582A22F42982388B0CD"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Establishment</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall establish a pilot program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to award grants, on a competitive basis, to not more than 25 eligible entities to develop or enhance neighborhood-level, publicly accessible health data platforms. Such platforms shall submit de-identified, aggregated data to the National Neighborhood Health Data Repository established under subsection (h), consistent with applicable Federal, State, and local privacy laws.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA18245950EA24D0589C4F838EAFB0243"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The objectives of the Program shall be to—</text> <paragraph id="H9935417E9A48491BA2E5437515E886CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote equitable access to local health data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3537AA046FEE449899AD00EEA7B9EE6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the integration of Federal, State, and local surveillance systems into user-friendly, publicly accessible health data platforms;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A49DBE95AD748DF912D71EBE984C462"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitate data-driven public health planning and community engagement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BED4C8968D143D782400DBD19CDCBD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide actionable insights at the State and local level, with a focus on addressing health disparities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6589E233A6294EF29EACDB524B4F58DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support the establishment and maintenance of the National Neighborhood Health Data Repository to enable national comparability while upholding local data privacy standards.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAFCD1ED6A8FD4CB4BCF40EBE89FDC0B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an entity shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H3F781E0E3FCB493E943C248994571A46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State or local health department; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5ED44B2C6B68437782DB0DDBE0DC8380"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a municipality or county government.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H705CBE2FEAB149E2921B9F8FCA010DDB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Partnership with academic and nonprofit institutions</header><text>In administering a grant under the Program, an eligible entity may partner with an academic or nonprofit institution.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7F66874E56342E094FB0EC5096CCC0D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under the Program, the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="H130F14C444BB49CB975FBB3F348387E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall prioritize eligible entities that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA34AC70FC3BA4FB1915DFA4B61C7A8A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve populations experiencing health disparities, such as medically underserved communities, low-income communities, or environmentally burdened communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A80FFA51F7B48EB8E82707ADFDE693A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>lack a neighborhood-level, publicly accessible health data system; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C263C85F8DA479CBE3CE3F9EC4A3F34"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrate plans to use the data collected from such a system to reduce health disparities; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFB52683C8FA43F1B1417DE0DE07105D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may prioritize eligible entities that propose innovative indicators beyond traditional public health surveillance (pursuant to subsection (f)(1)).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD1B23507FB064E24A045F877CD4D4817"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under the Program may only be used to—</text> <paragraph id="HDCF3B3D301B54651B0DC12C099D20442"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop or expand a publicly accessible health data platform to provide neighborhood-level data across key domains, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF2F793C8DA5E4722BA156E3E650DC03A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>social and economic conditions, such as education, economic stress, neighborhood, violence, and incarceration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA179EDA9912C4BA6A69C71FA994FCE0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>housing and neighborhood conditions, such as the prevalence and quality of air conditioners, housing quality, and the quality of the built environment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H638460C2FAA0439B934CFB34905DA535"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maternal and child health;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70BCA2E3AAA84320AF547218EDA5E941"><enum>(D)</enum><text>healthy living, such as self-reported health status;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD9EA512934004054A77D1F0602AD2C90"><enum>(E)</enum><text>health care, such as access to care and avoidable hospitalization and vaccination; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC518515C41E44EEA86BE221E5C2896AE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">health outcomes, such as chronic conditions, the prevalence or treatment of human immunodeficiency virus (commonly known as <quote>HIV</quote>) and Hepatitis C, binge drinking and psychiatric hospitalizations, infant mortality and premature death, and life expectancy;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA409885061AE44A59BB7A00BAD20D0E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integrate data from multiple sources, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H59E2A0FBD9BE483398DC31942C22D741"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal surveillance systems;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H629DF410BBD14352960D8A66A885F938"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State and local administrative survey data; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H799DFB4F8A684FA1B97670194F831168"><enum>(C)</enum><text>local education, housing, and public safety data;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HACC9BB1590614E648CDFE3B21398CF30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure data disaggregation by neighborhood, ZIP code, or census tract, and support comparability across local jurisdictions where feasible;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2726C605D51410E86CDCD6E2BC59ED0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>design neighborhood-level, publicly accessible health data platforms with clear citation of sources and transparent methodology;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB04A9CDC1D294836A0D5A87C0DCC287B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>incorporate into such platforms—</text> <subparagraph id="H3EE826D883F8463FAC6E9B8D5BAAC923"><enum>(A)</enum><text>visualization tools, such as charts, maps, and trend lines; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA24A051F008A4DC7A1EAAB18B9AD6C5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>downloadable datasets for public use;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC495263029034387ABEEDAAA6B3FBD80"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training or technical assistance to community and local institutions to ensure sustainability and usability of such platforms, including assistance in aligning such platforms with Federal interoperability standards and model legal frameworks for privacy, confidentiality, and data-sharing compliance; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H638EC3FD109342DD88E86652E77D0EA3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>submit de-identified, aggregated data collected or generated using grant funds under the Program to the National Neighborhood Health Data Repository, in such standardized format as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8385B7738C145B193D9820B0C83D916"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administration and evaluation</header> <paragraph id="HDDBB7E2FE0394269960566CDF760D27D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In administering the Program, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBD90B2F4EAF84A61AAA29143E6DA73B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue program guidance and technical assistance for platform development, data integration, and public accessibility, including—</text> <clause id="HBC930575602E4C70BAB8B4BF97AB031C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>standards for secure data reporting to the National Neighborhood Health Data Repository and alignment with Federal, State, and local laws; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H93D0FF13FE51422BB95F3B7560878808"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>model provisions on confidentiality and comparability;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H084C556909D249179ECD4D6A6184E6D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to grant recipients on data methodology, privacy protection, and system interoperability; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF92151BE010D458B9C5A4C429FE72A90"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate collaboration and peer learning among grant recipients to share best practices and promote replicability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22802128BE4A470FB05E811A6AA0317F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header> <subparagraph id="H543254DFEC314955B147DF8FCA8ADCB2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the Program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> 
<clause id="H9D31FC36835D48BE9344F96C75926A77"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">summarizes the outcomes of the Program and the progress made on the development of neighborhood-level, publicly accessible health data platforms;</text></clause> <clause id="H6228A19F41DE451E9BE4D1F1167AC2A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assesses improvements the Program has made in public access to health data, data usability, and community engagement; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9F174D022A17429AA43ED08383E19B79"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identifies lessons learned and makes recommendations for whether and how the Program could be expanded nationally or extended beyond the 4-year termination period described in subsection (k).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5785AA9DCB34EDC93F6E0E80E44213B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary may update or supplement the report described in subparagraph (A) as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1DC4C67BF79469BBAE7C1AF3A5B031A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>National Neighborhood Health Data Repository</header> 
<paragraph id="HB4A970B0704B43D8833E617E4CA78E9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and maintain a publicly accessible, searchable National Neighborhood Health Data Repository to aggregate de-identified, neighborhood-level health data from recipients of grants under the Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEEE5A789E104A468FAD760A596461CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The Repository shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4D85435BE941428AAC705F0B5A8B1D1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>display data submitted by recipients of grants under the Program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC59CDDE13A84570800C7578AB1B0486"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enable comparisons across local jurisdictions; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B6EE9158C954E8A8864524D8B729C68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include tools for visualization, filtering, and downloading of data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2AD0A2C33F3407DB15A021FD83DB09B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Secretary shall provide oversight of the Repository by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H84169B97B43A45D6A473C3610637DA2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviewing data submissions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B886A5C78084D0E906CEE9957B46239"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing and implementing a methodology for the aggregation of health data as described in paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD704AB820CEB42AC8A3DA6B1F77ED7F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in consultation with States and local jurisdictions, enforcing national data standards for quality and consistency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF31F7FAA51E04427849DA76151B2E51C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review of methodology by independent panel</header> <subparagraph id="H012AF3E7AF574DA39B51D8FAE38CCDA3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an independent advisory panel (in this paragraph referred to as the <quote>panel</quote>) for the purposes of reviewing the methodology developed by the Secretary under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59854E52E4094CB3A1640F53044293F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appointment of members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall develop, maintain, and make publicly available a list of nominees to serve as members of the panel. The Secretary shall appoint a member of the panel only after reviewing such list. Such members shall be experts in epidemiology, statistics, public health surveillance, and data privacy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2222F5F2AF745F7BA33FE2C48F702E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review authority</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement a methodology for the aggregation of health data for the purposes of the Repository, which shall go into effect only upon certification by the panel that such methodology—</text> 
<clause id="H24E6FFA79142460DA765E6B90E3389A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflects scientific best practices; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAEC155917132416B8584FAA977DE893B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maintains public accessibility, privacy protections, and data comparability across jurisdictions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C376A0D457F49E081B804FD7FA005E7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H2C7712243A4F48BEAF3A68FD6C20836D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Health disparity</header><text>The term <term>health disparity</term> means a difference in health outcomes or access to health services that is closely linked to social, economic, environmental, racial, ethnic, or other demographic factors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE48C8BFA7A724494A56C3D0A12FD2883"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local jurisdiction</term> means a municipality, county, local health department, or regional public health authority with the capacity to implement a neighborhood-level, publicly accessible health data platform.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H071599508F4C4B0EB032C09E1188CBA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medically underserved community</header><text>The term <term>medically underserved community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 799B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295p">42 U.S.C. 295p</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H545263B6E6964571A7EE76CF14AE582A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National Neighborhood Health Data Repository</header><text>The term <term>National Neighborhood Health Data Repository</term> means the National Neighborhood Health Data Repository established under subsection (h).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70149E94FC8F4C4B8E8A887CF1981EC7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Neighborhood-level</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>neighborhood-level</term> means, with respect to a publicly accessible health data platform, that such health data platform focuses on a geographic area within a local jurisdiction that is smaller than the municipal or county level, such as a ZIP code, census tract, or community district.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAEA452D7B3F04D4DAA2B819DC3DCD79C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Publicly accessible health data platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>publicly accessible health data platform</term> means an online tool, website, or dashboard that makes health data accessible to the general public through visualizations, downloadable datasets, or written summaries.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H07E9150A17A64284948E5AB8BF056A3F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt or supersede any applicable Federal, State, or local privacy laws.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H33CD2FF665F74E0D91BFD8E314ACB929"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Program shall terminate on the date that is 4 years after the date on which the Secretary establishes the Program.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

