<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26B09-7W1-8R-KKV">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4610 IS: Pacific Promotion of Workable Energy Resources Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 4610</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To promote the development and use of geothermal resources in the Pacific, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HAD043349B9404314A23B078C812DA600">
<section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pacific Promotion of Workable Energy Resources Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Pacific POWER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="id84013c4a157041f5aefa4e34bbb4bd9c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="ID595f82e972d04169a261b45d81684d4f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="IDd0b5c53150684b119ee199d63aca096a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="ID19b37b286fcf420996032e0163bbcf73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id64998ace48a6459babc7d7ca0dceeb2d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct use</header><text>The term <term>direct use</term> has the meaning given the term in section 616A of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17195a">42 U.S.C. 17195a(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="IDca8c1a2f71394b94be3b847c00e0afb4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Geothermal partners</header><text>The term <term>geothermal partners</term> means the United States allies and partners selected pursuant to section 6.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id0ddae58974684d91bdd0d3aabfb4fb14"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Next-generation geothermal</header><text>The term <term>next-generation geothermal</term> means a geothermal power production technology that has the potential to greatly expand the scale and geographical range of geothermal power production, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="idac8646d5ba824441abc5ce13a467bc3a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhanced geothermal systems, as defined in section 612 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17191">42 U.S.C. 17191</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idb461597fba584272b1db8ac24ef57196"><enum>(B)</enum><text>closed-loop geothermal systems, meaning systems that use one or more wells drilled into hot rock with fluid circulating through a closed-loop system to bring heat to the surface;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="idac222f21be954c9b87b1a31110bcbea9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>geothermal systems which harness heat from supercritical temperatures, meaning at or above 375 degrees; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id6428eb5941d94377b3eea0dd0c97b98d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other innovative geothermal power technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="IDf9440d6b85e34f11bb3e86155996369f"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant United States agencies</header><text>The term <term>relevant United States agencies</term> includes the Department of Energy, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Commerce, the Department of the Treasury, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the United States Trade and Development Agency, and the Millennium Challenge Corporation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="IDbbbf954caa074cd68f2989c15330aeb2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="ID527962725dc94dcd8cfaa72b12603bc9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="IDc63e5b217eeb4c799c740d855a6b079e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The November 2025 National Security Strategy prioritizes the United States having <quote>the world’s most robust, productive, and innovative energy sector—one capable not just of fueling American economic growth but of being one of America’s leading export industries in its own right</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ID7787536b477b436d9aa2f70c3c2725da"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The November 2025 National Security Strategy further states that <quote>[e]xpanding our net energy exports will also deepen relationships with allies while curtailing the influence of adversaries, protect our ability to defend our shores, and—when and where necessary—enables us to project power</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ID5ad0337b9f654e98adf51c68a2fc412f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Numerous allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific experience energy security vulnerabilities that have implications for their autonomy, ability to resist coercion, defense requirements, and democratic freedoms, which could implicate United States national security decisions, including military deployments and the potential use of force, to come to their assistance and otherwise promote regional stability.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ID336beac0ec7b4f4d927f8937141ca59a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Taiwan relies on imports for more than 95 percent of its energy needs and is increasingly vulnerable to blockade from People’s Liberation Army forces, with direct implications for United States military operations and national security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="iddc8ae99abd3446198b397b72f7da884f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission, the People's Republic of China is a leading producer of key grid components, and its growing footprint in global energy systems raises numerous national security concerns for the United States and other countries.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ID89f02570a39e4104a61b6e96e9fabbaa"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China is responsible for almost half of final geothermal energy consumption globally by harnessing low-temperature resources for space heating.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ID26dd8bc810e647a2931e96bee0de0fb3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China is developing and deploying geothermal technology domestically, which may reach an installed geothermal power generation capacity of 200 megawatts in 2030 and more than 1,000 megawatts in 2050.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ID870a5be8af894e52a55536070b9e5edc"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Key allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific have both energy security vulnerabilities and geothermal resources that could help reduce those vulnerabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ID497eaaf03adc45789ab4bea8e8768ee1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to the International Energy Agency, geothermal energy is a dispatchable source of power that has the potential to meet up to 15 percent of global electricity demand growth to 2050, making it a strong candidate to help meet the growing energy demand from artificial intelligence and other sectors.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ID4fa43c52463149c9a03f3dd075e33d3a"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Despite this potential, policy support and investment in geothermal energy is significantly lacking compared to other energy sources globally.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ID096ddb251bc4425699818a398fbe6902"><enum>(11)</enum><text>According to the Department of Energy, the United States leads the world in geothermal electricity generation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="IDfc2150aa8ba34e4b859a77e02ec1fdd8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>According to the International Energy Agency, Indonesia, Türkiye, the Philippines, and New Zealand are among the top sources of geothermal electricity generation in addition to the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id9dcbe6a7daec45099829c61ed3886dab"><enum>(13)</enum><text>According to the International Energy Agency, geothermal energy already provides more than 10 percent of total electricity supply in Kenya, Iceland, El Salvador, New Zealand, Nicaragua, and Costa Rica.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id454705dd5cca4fecac4a3620a3e03104"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The United States has the necessary resources, personnel, commercial capabilities, and technical expertise to assist allies and partners in developing geothermal upon request.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="IDc300b2f1314e4ffab75abf4f0edf84da"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="IDc5383a44d45b4eeb8e0a9aa4cb37324f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Indo-Pacific is critical to United States national security and economic interests, particularly given the rise of the People’s Republic of China as a competitor, and has some of the world’s highest geothermal potential;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ID53f7485ea4304f92afb2ac57dd394734"><enum>(2)</enum><text>achieving United States foreign and national security policy objectives, including deterring conflict and reducing vulnerability to coercion, requires further strengthening relationships with key regional allies and partners;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id4645ce7da46d4c40ac7cb45cc1490bb4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should expand its engagement with key allies and partners on geothermal, including through commercial partnerships and technical assistance to support the development of their geothermal capabilities to reduce reliance on the energy exports of adversaries and to develop markets for United States companies; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="IDf802d2ff31964c098f4739fdcafb7f26"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States should prioritize the pursuit of bilateral memoranda of understanding or other appropriate agreements on geothermal energy with key allies and partners, where doing so furthers United States foreign policy and national security interests.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="id4d4061ad742748d58a9e81251171c7bd"><enum>5.</enum><header>Geothermal diplomacy</header>
<subsection id="id15ed9f89e0fe4b4ab95a765b929a97c1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall work both bilaterally and multilaterally to advance geothermal energy in support of United States interests, including to develop—</text> <paragraph id="idcac82f2bf889470882b72ab4e080a161"><enum>(1)</enum><text>goals to increase geothermal deployment, including for electricity and direct use applications;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id6f37527ebf6a4371baedafc1d3691065"><enum>(2)</enum><text>forums for collective learning and research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5425ebe7fb474c4da97b1404960610de"><enum>(3)</enum><text>risk-sharing and financial tools for geothermal exploration and development;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id23707a83c32e4a40b353d2743582125f"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>potential regulatory and power market reforms that support geothermal power production, direct use applications, and grid interconnection; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id41f0ed6da65a439db5f6f03d5037a615"><enum>(5)</enum><text>technical, environmental, safety, and community engagement standards and best practices, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="ida27c987537a34d70a345a4b7ecbda11f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>early and consistent community engagement, including the free, prior, and informed consent of Indigenous Peoples and other communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id9e92198219094c37babe380da4b9b6d4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>revenue sharing to create local economic benefits;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="idb6ff37943f42492caac7c0f70a9449cc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reservoir management;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id50e29eaa3d794b3f88beae165299cc27"><enum>(D)</enum><text>mitigation of seismic risk through real-time monitoring, operational guardrails, and engagement with impacted communities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id45a4d01f5d5f483c9686ec92237ebf05"><enum>(E)</enum><text>mitigation of impacts to water resources; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idf4d006e3ec2142cc8b0fda36ddfc53c1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>standardized, transparent, and secure mechanisms for sharing geological and project-related data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="IDeb561a4259f94855830a8f11051d9583"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Indo-Pacific engagement</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize engaging with allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific on opportunities to collaborate on geothermal energy and as potential geothermal partners to be selected pursuant to section 6, including—</text> <paragraph id="ID78c8789b5c404dab9fe9454a51b2cdbc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Taiwan;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ID8fdcabdf64cb453592b0f9dd465cf6c8"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the Philippines;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ID2b7df89816bd4101875907dbbf2ac883"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Japan;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="IDb81fde42497946eba572a853351581b5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Australia;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ID37e2dd693b02431c9714294687285b5a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Indonesia;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="ID45245595ef6d413c833b4acb1959cbf8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>India;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id3a6c021ab6a843f4881f4e9b3b74b2db"><enum>(7)</enum><text>New Zealand; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idca18ce32824f4388884d85d07c4c7256"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Papua New Guinea.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="idab5378069c134f2987c6303312fc9e53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Multilateral mechanisms</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall use existing multilateral mechanisms to advance cooperation on geothermal energy, including—</text>
<paragraph id="id37c4d1247c9f4203b471e2d5c1c0d0ff"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Quadrilateral Dialogue, or <quote>Quad,</quote> comprising the United States, Australia, India, and Japan;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id06a13820e87642f5abaa1efa537569b6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States-Japan-Philippines trilateral dialogue;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idcb7a5642ba3546dcaa33c782779e43fc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States-Japan-Republic of Korea trilateral dialogue;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id79dba108d5314596b475f5128fa7805f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Pacific Community, the principal scientific and technical organization in the Pacific region;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd301f40ff0a8450b804e341ab9b0c3c6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the International Energy Agency; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id54e31d2c2fe444fcbb13b77628b95726"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Group of Seven, comprising the United States, France, the United Kingdom, Germany, Japan, Italy, and Canada.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="id35593ec410d44373b26171b7048248a0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Establishment of international geothermal program and country selection</header>
<subsection id="id383c264ee87b42f7b3cf249f140a5171"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with relevant United States agencies, shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text> <paragraph id="idb38aba5a50df4649a80c65e990f51768"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses global geothermal resources, including mapping the areas of highest potential for geothermal development based on factors, such as—</text>
<subparagraph id="idbf50e2a2d5fc4fea9cf986b2dc905d6b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing geothermal generation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ida2b6d80570cc42339585eb78fa273074"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsurface data;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id30aff65f67c04c51b0989ff1e2c0bb20"><enum>(C)</enum><text>proximity of geothermal resources to existing or potential energy infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4ea29dd1e62f4e30a917f10d75fe2e39"><enum>(D)</enum><text>regulatory and economic conditions, including financial incentives for geothermal;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id6b96b2595f7a4cadab1afb37825e94b8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>current and projected energy mix and demand;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="idd34df388405a4d57af2da5093a5234b7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>workforce;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="ide44cb51061f94a8ab846f6d44f12658a"><enum>(G)</enum><text>supply chains, including the distribution of assets relative to projected demand; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id4d0fb977a76f44d28c4a77f91705817c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>energy reliability conditions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idaa2eeee7058f46809388738cd0aa7eac"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses countries, regions, and other locations in which geothermal development or expansion is most beneficial to United States national security and economic interests, including in support of United States Indo-Pacific strategy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idc1bed55a235844368bb11c48d0c6222b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>explains the strategy for addressing the challenges to geothermal energy development or expansion in the countries, regions, and other locations most beneficial to United States national security and economic interests.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id86f9ebdc411b41458c8b51fc2fb16d65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the report required in subsection (a), the Secretary and relevant agencies shall consult with—</text> <paragraph id="id3e4d1b8143c746ea856b4921277dae11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Department of Energy National Laboratories (as defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>));</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id50582c5d35564a5395c1914639938396"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>institutions of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1001">2 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>));</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id82134aac88734a04ad935548abd12991"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nonpartisan and nonprofit organizations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id10152245d9e24fd2b0e5aa247ebba716"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the International Energy Agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idee01ebc0605342618c134e4ff2af8ba0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the advisory group established pursuant to subsection (g); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id71e81b1883dc4026b042fb9b83e43ace"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id9c78b3bf7f694085b67d28c5890bee46"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, shall establish the International Geothermal Program (the <quote>Program</quote>) for international collaboration on geothermal exploration and development to carry out section 5 and to pursue bilateral and multilateral partnerships as described in subsection (d) to further United States foreign policy and national security interests.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="idd6a7461c87ab4952a6bf995a00699521"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The Program established pursuant to subsection (c) shall include public-private partnerships for the exploration and development of geothermal resources and next-generation geothermal systems, including—</text> <paragraph id="ide5d006b60f9a41b7a7f280b6bc97f1ea"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support large-scale geothermal deployment, including for next-generation geothermal technologies and direct use applications;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id2a93fb6f5dcc4f9f8473a80840e8bfc2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to conduct research of next-generation geothermal technologies, including through coordination with existing international research initiatives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="iddfbced8e37704103b1d48c3320acdbf6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to conduct geothermal resource exploration and characterization;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd73a0e52cadc447a85df4a8b14b31188"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support the integration of geothermal energy into energy system planning and regulations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id62a8b447197a4032a3e2efb795b657a4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to identify opportunity zones where geothermal could meet industrial, heating and cooling, agricultural, and electricity needs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd9ef9de8d52747be903ef9b036780b54"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to support the workforce and supply chains necessary for geothermal deployment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1000dfcca65e442da3b2031fa6611229"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to support community engagement and education;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9ccd92cbe9e8411e8e840f555cd8720a"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to assist in the development and implementation of risk-sharing mechanisms and other financial tools for the cost of geothermal exploration and development;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id79d3ad1001ed4066961d1dc9d5cd410b"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to assist in the development of predictable siting and permitting processes for partners selected pursuant to subsection (e);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id6cc6ed6ff22e4a50909588643c7249d8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to create financial incentives for investment in geothermal energy; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id6f59ad33c3ce4349a82f83ffe74c0616"> <enum>(11)</enum> <text>to identify investment and export opportunities for United States companies.</text> </paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="id4f2f4a6b324947d6b0a7649bbb2e23ae"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection of geothermal partners</header><text>Concurrent with the establishment of the Program pursuant to subsection (c), the Secretary, in coordination with relevant United States agencies, and in consultation with the appropriate congressional committees, shall select at least five geothermal partners that—</text> <paragraph id="id2aa64c9b307749b5a06dbf8362b84405"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include—</text>
<subparagraph id="idd989690cc98f485b88773d33bdb401bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not fewer than three countries in the Indo-Pacific;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="ide03485d070a24ab1b8e7ca8db9de8be3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not fewer than one country that currently does not produce or consume geothermal energy at commercial scale; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="idf0e12fee4d0b4924997d82277ab43747"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not fewer than one country that demonstrates significant potential to expand existing capacity for geothermal energy generation, such as through recent success in adding more geothermal energy to its grid and through the inclusion of geothermal in utility resource plans; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id61eca38fd1c441d6b9adcd49d691fa33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are informed by the report required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="ide9a526d1e1be4ace967bbd3041f8c483"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Secretary shall pursue memoranda of understanding or other appropriate agreements with countries selected pursuant to subsection (e) and that are willing to work with the United States to implement the Program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="idfbcf404bf9764704b6a553c36a8210c5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Engagement with the private sector and nonprofits</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with relevant agencies, shall establish an advisory mechanism to engage United States geothermal developers, equipment manufacturers, financial institutions, industry associations, and nonprofit organizations with geothermal expertise in the implementation of the Program, including to—</text>
<paragraph id="id7addbf80d5b34127921a1be858d2372a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify export opportunities for United States geothermal technology and services in geothermal partner countries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id427ad294e5fa482384cf25c2e25daa4b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advise on technical standards, data, policy, supply chain development, and workforce needs; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id0754df721c1c4d10bab5c18f8caad751"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitate connections between United States companies and organizations and geothermal investment opportunities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="idef58543902674be0a4c6b6ab89c3d6d9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Implementation of the International Geothermal Program</header> <subsection id="id5bd5f2ffaddd4308ab66a52e76fbb724"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the Program and selection of geothermal partners pursuant to section 6, the Secretary, in coordination with relevant United States agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes the United States strategy for advancing geothermal energy with each of the geothermal partners.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="id76601a0ee2094f909ebf39ae1f073cd0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy submitted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the estimated personnel and assistance resources required on an annual basis for successful implementation of such strategy, and the identification of opportunities for—</text> <paragraph id="id8637a3931ef64f8d9a5c275e7e4173bc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting regional partnerships on geothermal energy;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id0ced28caeb6c41f1a1cb9e2b48f5085d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengthening the resilience of geothermal supply chains, including—</text> <subparagraph id="id5cf93de788524bae8bd59fad8da4136f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>equipment and services related to geothermal resource exploration, characterization, and production; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="id8dba4b1f4d6a4bdba827fe8bd2ba6afa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through partnerships with domestic and allied manufacturers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="id494d4facfde54618a3b45f68057e0891"><enum>(3)</enum><text>leveraging existing and developing new multilateral financing tools to support geothermal energy;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idde35515d742047978133ab76f8968c78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conducting geothermal-specific feasibility studies and other support by the United States Trade and Development Agency; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id0f13035247964c9eb1fbaec62a24b28b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States Export-Import Bank, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, and the United States International Development Finance Corporation to provide financial support to geothermal partners that meet the eligibility requirements of the agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="ide785976bdaee4fc3b164a54b00b78a11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The implementation of the Program established in section 6 shall be led by the Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment and coordinated with the leadership of the Office of International Affairs and the Geothermal Technologies Office.</text></subsection> <subsection id="idd8861a7cd0e74a51b7307cafb407cee3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with relevant United States agencies, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes—</text>
<paragraph id="id7d8048cd5f9543fea0359798f854d72c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of United States activities and engagement with each geothermal partner, including the status of negotiations to establish memoranda of understanding or other agreements pursuant to section 6(f);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idf5749775e25a4196ae713a5e7377c11d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any changes to the strategy required by subsection (a) for each geothermal partner;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd8e0663ee0c94732b9af1f37dd231db9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of personnel assigned to implementation of the Program, by operating unit; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5a2b348864ee43b48401a7491cc90c4e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assistance provided to implement the Program to date by operating unit, amount, account, and purpose.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="idecd2625f90414e71a5e1debff0e7122e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and financial assistance</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to work with relevant United States agencies to promote and coordinate the development and underwriting of grants, loans, loan guarantees, and other technical and financial assistance to geothermal partners and United States companies that work with geothermal partners through the Program established in section 6.</text></subsection> <subsection id="idba4087d7ab294fa2be3902c3d79a6f1d"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In preparing the strategy required under subsection (a) and the annual report required under subsection (d), and implementing the Program established in section 6, the Under Secretary of State for Economic Growth, Energy, and the Environment shall convene relevant agencies and the advisory group established in section 6(g) and brief the appropriate committees of Congress not less than twice per year.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="id848c0ac4de6646c6ade93ee705107c96"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as necessary to carry out section 6 for fiscal years 2027 to 2031.</text></subsection> <subsection id="iddc32037e8b804f27adfc71cfcf35b096"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Transfer authority</header><text>Funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State pursuant to subsection (g) are authorized to be transferred to the relevant United States agencies if the Secretary determines and reports to the appropriate committees of Congress that to do so is necessary to carry out this Act, and concurrently notifies such committees detailing the intended use of such funds, not later than 15 days in advance of the transfer of such funds.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>


