<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H971EFA724ADF495B99AE34A16D136264" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9377 IH: Protecting America’s Herds Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9377</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program for preparing and responding to New World screwworm outbreaks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17834E0C048840C4A8562FBEA4FBC772" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD1BF69043F154F5790821D8A315A6141" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting America’s Herds Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9F5F89C1D15D48A3B6F20BE4365D3156"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for preparing and responding to New World screwworm</header> <subsection id="HF70C010FDEFC4C49BC57DF3CD1EC77D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish a program to award grants, on a competitive basis, to cooperative extension services to prepare and respond to New World screwworm outbreaks.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1842F1109E8E4426A3B90229ED474E9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a cooperative extension service shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCA92119D6A454A589B5DB6CF7F50A645"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under this section may be used to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H94A555B9977744CB8FF0CF1B923D0F34"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train personnel of the cooperative extension service on New World screwworm identification, treatment, management, prevention, and reporting;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DB7239BF94D4B6582533C8D82770CD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support livestock inspections, including the training of inspectors, for New World screwworm;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD949252C27D647BCA84B1305FD06CE51"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support producer education regarding New World screwworm through workshops, field demonstrations, outreach campaigns, and educational materials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE024573158F0479790E26E949B6619B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support the provision of direct technical assistance by personnel of the cooperative extension service to livestock producers regarding prevention, monitoring, treatment, biosecurity practices, and reporting of suspected infestations of New World screwworm.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCED4DDC833514B1380052B1277F6E3DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give priority to cooperative extension services in States or Tribal communities at elevated risk of New World screwworm introduction or spread.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H378133FC36404F4EBC675B990483543F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with cooperative extension services, the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, State animal health officials, veterinarians, Tribal agricultural programs, and land-grant colleges and universities conducting veterinary or agricultural research.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB9EB1B2C2EB24B888E8DFB7AB7A1BA6C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H73794482F7684183B203DC6FA171B644"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cooperative extension service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cooperative extension service</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3103">7 U.S.C. 3103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1096E4AABB0400FACF6F70445D36379"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land-grant colleges and universities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>land-grant colleges and universities</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3103">7 U.S.C. 3103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF47E6DB753C4777B0C2740D97A8E374"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and the territories of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA5BCFFBD5184C4A99AF30F4FB449FDD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

