<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H814AEB3A4F484ECD9FDAEDB4F3C3877B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8238 IH: Revitalization Efforts for Sustainable Transformation And Remediation for Thriving Communities Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8238</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Commerce and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide for collaboration between the Economic Development Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency to promote economic revitalization efforts of environmentally contaminated sites, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEC13F31DA7E8488AB04699E510D0EDF2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H27FF6441AA9345E1A496EC8DEEF851C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Revitalization Efforts for Sustainable Transformation And Remediation for Thriving Communities Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RESTART Communities Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDE121B0E7A3B44A098CE0D07C7E5AC4F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Economic Development Administration and Environmental Protection Agency revitalization coordination</header> <subsection id="HF021589FBAFB432EAFFAFDB432FAD8DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>), and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall carry out interagency activities to promote the economic revitalization of eligible sites before, during, and after environmental remediation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H67E802B2B5564601BB956E3862161A69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>The Assistant Secretary and the Administrator may coordinate the activities under subsection (a) through the establishment of a memorandum of understanding, or other appropriate interagency agreement.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H621A82475CC44F23AB2EA88142214E02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency activities</header><text>In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary and the Administrator may engage in any interagency activity, including any of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA35D330744048FBA20E8ED8B269D6A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Establish any interagency process to promote the economic revitalization of an eligible site, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4C10279CFCD4DA78B076788EEE6589F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any process that—</text> 
<clause id="H7A56D100A75A4CDE932108554E9AD047"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes timely action by the Assistant Secretary or the Administrator in supporting the economic revitalization activities of an eligible site;</text></clause> <clause id="H2774293891994CBAB7DFA345657E8F4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supports access by site stakeholders to technical assistance resources and services available at or through the Economic Development Administration or the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4A0F3658D2AB498890C1EF70120928C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to policies promoting fair and open competition, supports access by site stakeholders to relevant Federal grant and loan programs, including such programs at or through the Economic Development Administration or the Environmental Protection Agency, to promote economic revitalization after environmental remediation activities; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB660C0036D084C8396B46BEA682073C6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>supports access by site stakeholders to best practices, frameworks, and other information, as appropriate, for the development of economic revitalization plans that focus on community engagement, environmental justice, and the benefit of economically distressed communities; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5145BC180924ACE886FBB9E567A72B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other interagency process as determined necessary by the Assistant Secretary and the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68A14F645B7B497CA5BEA01A3C385CB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support the collection of public input by site stakeholders and surrounding communities of an eligible site to promote community support for economic revitalization activities at the Economic Development Administration or the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD06B92AB898456FAFFF2BE1569CEFEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Support the development and dissemination of best practices, frameworks, and other tools, metrics, and resources to promote the success of economic revitalization of an eligible site.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07AF35347D0F4E4FA9E4E8A2A02F1321"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support data collection and data sharing practices, as determined by the Assistant Secretary and the Administrator, to monitor and report on the success of economic revitalization at an eligible site.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46F75E24B84C4684946B771ED67C61AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Support education, training, and workforce development activities for site stakeholders to increase the success of economic revitalization before, during, and after environmental remediation at an eligible site, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D1F8A3AF8384A4E9632C216399AC75C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">internships, fellowships, and other work-based learning opportunities at the Economic Development Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency, subject to the availability of appropriations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0A849FF0DE54D378D2298485396CA62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>development of postsecondary or credential curriculum, experiential learning, or other project-based learning opportunities through collaboration with stakeholders that support the activities of this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0992CB37DEEF460AAA29458BDFCA46AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>professional development opportunities for site stakeholders in professional fields relevant to environmental remediation or economic revitalization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D2C38351B794801B256FDC86AF21647"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary and the Administrator are authorized to consult other Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial governmental entities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC77F213AED3B4F8AAA652021D033481A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary and the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4126095ED71040C8A84B37F1C5FCA49C">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Interagency activities between the Economic Development Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency carried out under this section.</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD504707E48E2485EB9BFB172CBFC5733"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Collaborative economic revitalization achievements at eligible sites and supporting communities as appropriate, including the engagement of site stakeholders in supporting the activities carried out under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F5288A55BF9441F847AB2F84DFBB2A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Interagency education, training, and workforce development activities for site stakeholders, including the dissemination of best practices and engagement of students to establish a robust future workforce for economic revitalization and environmental remediation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8583E50CF5D4B0C921BDF9168336227">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Potential opportunities to expand the interagency activities of the Economic Development Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDA69B23DCE5E4281ACAC4DFAA15BBAA6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HEA56152E1E3547BF89841CE9C0C495FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H78406D6D3DCB4606AEEA5C82E94F6648"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAAADB3847FD948D4BCBF9010307B81AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0D53F83E9ABE40C5861825DE363BFC27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82906958493C4CFA87321A4A55FD075E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Economic revitalization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>economic revitalization</term> means any effort by a site stakeholder, the Assistant Secretary, and the Administrator to establish favorable conditions for the creation of new, or retention of existing, long-term private sector job opportunities in a community, including the expansion or upgrade of existing physical infrastructure at an eligible site.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC63B41ECF27F42E58923942A77C25DD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible site</header><text>The term <term>eligible site</term> means any site of current or former environmental contamination, including any current or former manufacturing facility, at which the Assistant Secretary or the Administrator plans to do, currently is doing, or has previously done any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H54A0A2BD432F424AB5C289FFFF5DFD34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Engage with site stakeholders.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE09841240914E198DFF6C3A1E1ADAA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provide Federal funding or resources.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBDBE8C5917514409A6D938B68B2A5A6F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Provide technical assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54F87F3C95854C2D871E35C0C9190F19" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental contamination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental contamination</term> means any hazardous substance, pollutant, or contaminant that harms public safety or the surrounding environment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12EAB070A99B4635B5248CD70DF63054"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Site stakeholder</header><text>The term <term>site stakeholder</term> means any entity other than the Department of Commerce or the Environmental Protection Agency that is engaged in the economic revitalization of an eligible site.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2135FD5CED264B94A4A3A55AC7D7B6BA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

