<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B3273EE0D9847DF9D4CDC5344F19EBD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7138 IH: Stop Wall Street Landlords Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7138</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260116">January 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to disallow the deduction of certain expenses relating to ownership of single-family homes by specified large investors, to impose an excise tax on the sale of such homes by such investors, and to prohibit Federal mortgage assistance relating to certain large investors.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2DC56A46CE2D4DB3868B350B7BC7415A" style="OLC"><section id="HEE004AF5145F401E98493BD5D9C27BAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Wall Street Landlords Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9D9D42AD2A9F4F52B6A688A2E0621C51"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disallowance of deduction of certain expenses related to single-family homes held by specified large investors</header><subsection id="HD2F18D7AD0B44BE2AF07F2EC926D8B6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part IX of subchapter B of Chapter 1 of subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HFECA9657E08248919A79876DBE0AEF31" style="OLC"><section id="HF778618AD37E410BBEB983DB373E4F9F"><enum>280I.</enum><header>Certain expenses related to single-family homes held by specified large investors</header><subsection id="H8BA4487281EF47A8979BB6B75B5DEF4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a specified large investor, no deduction shall be allowed under this chapter for the following expenses relating to the ownership of a single-family home:</text><paragraph id="HDF9883A30DD44150AF3110C27A6D51C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for the interest on a mortgage relating to such single-family home or to insure such single-family home.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H441C05470D614E65B1A6316CAE1F501C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Depreciation of such single-family home.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5D0B8615085437D84816476A7869158"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified large investor</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H9CB7EAA4C34D4C93ADAC6F3112D78605"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>specified large investor</quote> means any person for any taxable year if the aggregate fair market value of all assets of such person (reduced by the aggregate debts of the taxpayer) exceeds $100,000,000 at any time during such taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBF263508AF747D79C9E5DA219DFC46A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of controlled groups</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HC7B9435F5F284D0A9871CCF2016AD26D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All persons which are part of a controlled group (within the meaning of section 1563(a) applied by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 80 percent</quote> each place it appears) shall be treated as 1 person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B54FCD9B7834A6199ECF7158C4819AF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Nonincorporated persons under common control</header><text>Under regulations or other guidance provided by the Secretary, principles similar to the principles of subparagraph (A) shall apply to a group of persons under common control where 1 or more of such persons is not a corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85BF5F3ACE674DC58650A9806EFFC49E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Government entities and certain tax-exempt entities</header><text>Such term shall not include either of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7294C2A9493049C880A8766C9A767105"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any governmental entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28FBADCFC2BC4AA3825EF36649788BC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any organization which is described in section 501(c)(3) and exempt from tax under section 501(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0D642AF85EE49568CAA36EDB9A7163A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Single-Family home</header><paragraph id="H459AC01280DC48178BDF17D38CE3D0F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>single-family home</quote> means any real property located in the United States if such property includes at least 1 dwelling unit and not more than 4 dwelling units.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBA6943BBB0B434B8F8E904557F83968"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for federally-assisted buildings</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><subparagraph id="HEC76A0B8E5624BDF86C4BEE175ED2677"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Such term shall not include any federally-assisted building.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FA7BB598A2A44EB970A9BC006C03FED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federally-assisted building</header><text>The term <quote>federally-assisted building</quote> means any building—</text><clause id="id9b4c66d0eb274e6092edd9a920619592"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is substantially assisted, financed, or operated under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, section 221(d)(3), 221(d)(4), or 236 of the National Housing Act, section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949, or any other housing program administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development or by the Rural Housing Service of the Department of Agriculture,</text></clause><clause id="ida596897be99d41ef8c70c2cc44260ca5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to which a credit is allowed to the taxpayer under section 42, or</text></clause><clause id="idd6a230cbf99c4501807d7a1fc7aebccb"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for which financing is provided by a qualified bond (within the meaning of section 141).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF38F14C00C9F4BFEA8CA8ED2318401BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H54FBB973D3C045EDAA483FC641BD4BDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>In the case of a specified large investor who is an individual, subsection (a) shall not apply to any single-family home if such home is used as the principal residence of such investor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4452D8C5A1334898B6E403D7B17B7580"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Original construction or substantial rehabilitation</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a single-family home originally constructed or substantially rehabilitated (as defined in section 47(c)) by the taxpayer.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H89B1340F376449AD92D240AAF06D6ED7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part IX of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 280H the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H0F550302DFA04F6ABD09BB4447AD3847" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 280I. Certain expenses related to single-family homes held by specified large investors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7BF837626A30488EA26186691200AEE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred and depreciation that occurs after the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0B638048F05148BD963AF8BA121D547D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Excise tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors</header><subsection id="HB1658735124449ADBCFE990692E95F2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 36 of subtitle D of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after subchapter D the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H384A70F7948B481BB7B59D55C2E2DF15" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subchapter id="HB2AAEE6E890C405EAC1D25C580A2D8C0"><enum>E</enum><header>Tax on Transfers of Single-Family Homes by Specified Large Investors</header><toc container-level="subchapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HB2AAEE6E890C405EAC1D25C580A2D8C0" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HD91BD6532D20423D874162DC1141BC00" level="section">Sec. 4491. Tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors.</toc-entry></toc><section id="HD91BD6532D20423D874162DC1141BC00"><enum>4491.</enum><header>Tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors</header><subsection id="H3C85D7E45DAE42A9873870F301A1C55C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is hereby imposed a tax on the sale or transfer of a single-family home by a specified large investor in an amount equal to the sale price of the single-family home.</text></subsection><subsection id="H577997547F0740B3BF6D4C01295257A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified large investor; single-family home</header><text>For purposes of this section, the terms <quote>specified large investor</quote> and <quote>single-family home</quote> shall have the respective meanings given such terms in section 280I.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE32F76DA7E514E9FA3D6C4A8EB943981"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsections (b)(2), (d)(1), and (d)(2) of section 280I shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H401C5716BD6B4A4392D47A6935030EDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 36 of subtitle D of such Code is amended by adding after the item relating to subchapter D the following new item:</text><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="subchapter">“Subchapter E. Tax on transfers of single-family homes by specified large investors.”.</toc-entry></toc></subsection><subsection id="H3C30E9B9A16D4D9EB8A6CA5A5616AB27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to sales and transfers occurring after the date that is 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H767E295C3D3F4D5BA810B19606A53190"><enum>4.</enum><header>Low-income housing assistance</header><subsection id="HE456E31B419A46A1876C7C4ECBA63CB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deposit of funds</header><text>Amounts collected in any penalty under section 3 shall be deposited in the Housing Trust Fund established under section 1338 of the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H264E8EEF2FF2430DB425A15102399ED4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>To the extent provided for in advance in appropriations Acts, the amounts deposited in the Fund shall be used to increase and preserve the supply of rental housing affordable to extremely low- and very low-income families, including homeless families, in accordance with such section 1338.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6827566AE29A4489BE8F1A1D1309E2A9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibitions on Federal mortgage assistance</header><subsection id="H364692FDC0EC472DAF202E8F1DEC94BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part 2 of subtitle A of title XIII of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4541">12 U.S.C. 4541 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HE03B9BF08D954D1DA299D321760544BE" style="OLC"><section id="HAC05427625FD4338831BAFFD2FF83844"><enum>1329.</enum><header>Prohibition relating to specified large investors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director shall, by regulation, prohibit the enterprises from newly purchasing any mortgage on a single-family housing or any portion thereof (or any interest in such a mortgage), and from newly lending on the security of or securitizing any such mortgage under which the mortgagee is a specified large investor (as such term is defined in of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6CBD8E4C331F4100AD60D0317F924727"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ginnie Mae</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(c) of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1717">12 U.S.C. 1717(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H0AA8DBE6D3D0431797F1A851737B81B8" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H66B853073B14450199AA7739F2AFA8E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Association may not newly guarantee the payment of principal of or interest on any trust certificate or other security based or backed by a trust or pool that contains, or purchase or acquire, any mortgage under which the mortgagee is a specified large investor (as such term is defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/280I">section 280I(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

