<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL26380-1D8-NL-842"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 684 IS: Recognizing the 56th anniversary of Earth Day and the leadership of its founder, Senator Gaylord Nelson.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 684</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 56th anniversary of Earth Day and the leadership of its founder, Senator Gaylord Nelson.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Earth Day is observed annually around the world to demonstrate support for preserving, protecting, and defending the environment, the planet, and the inhabitants of the planet;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Senator Gaylord Nelson, a native of Clear Lake, Wisconsin—</text><paragraph id="idfbf777686e964c83aca630a18ac3939d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>established Earth Day as an event and movement led by young people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5113840d40f046839a825df7ed952f47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is recognized as one of the leading environmentalists of the 20th century; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida32bcd8cd4cf49fb95008210862734aa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>received the Presidential Medal of Freedom for his public leadership;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Earth Day movement established by Senator Gaylord Nelson helped launch an era of international environmental awareness and activism;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas young individuals were critical in the organization and mobilization of 20,000,000 individuals on the first Earth Day in 1970, making that celebration the largest environmental grassroots event in history at that time;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas ongoing environmental degradation, accelerating climate change, and increasingly severe weather events threaten the well-being and livelihoods of the individuals of the United States and individuals around the world, including—</text><paragraph id="id9d9c8ddb124b479da46a5a66043adaa1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coastal communities, which are especially vulnerable and are experiencing erosion, flooding, and pollution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf16284e6dfb54673ab9078b7153bd809"><enum>(2)</enum><text>rural and agricultural communities, which are facing increased risk of drought, diseases, pests, and soil degradation;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas pollution, environmental degradation, and the climate crisis are generational justice issues that disproportionately impact young individuals and future generations, who will face difficulties accessing clean water and clean air;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas low-income communities and communities of color continue to face disproportionate harm from climate change, pollution, and environmental degradation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas multiple national and international scientific reports have concluded that the climate crisis is a threat to the planet that requires urgent action;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the first Earth Day spurred broad support for environmental conservation and contributed to the creation of the Environmental Protection Agency and the enactment of bipartisan legislation with bedrock Federal environmental protections, including the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>), the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has experienced a youth-led resurgence in environmental and climate activism that has led to hundreds of thousands of individuals in the United States demanding climate action; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the mission and purpose of Earth Day remain relevant in 2026, for a new generation to face environmental challenges that lie ahead: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id37a554e0b4c845fbb5f5c9bd12f151ef"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes April 22, 2026, as the 56th anniversary of Earth Day; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc1f380ccd4846b0b9a8a5afd6645fb1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the leadership and vision of the founder of Earth Day, Senator Gaylord Nelson. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

