<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H220250329D9C4407AD59AD85AF3322AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7857 IH: No Escaping Justice Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7857</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions on foreign persons the President determines to have knowingly engaged in, facilitated, or benefitted from severe forms of trafficking in persons in connection with the Jeffrey Epstein sex trafficking enterprise or in connection with efforts to conceal, facilitate, finance, or profit from such enterprise.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB6BD7E18C01F4E24B6AF2F3233F00E29" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HED8F504FD81143AB99486BD1B08DDE79" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Escaping Justice Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H970A7BC8AE3C4F60B0F41A1455488851"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEEF36429EC0A4AB99E7204602319EC99"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H25595BFE15A84A68ABE8BD89EB9B189F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H009BA42ADD9F4FC8A98FA14FF7A7723F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43D5F20A41BF4ABB834CA290FEF7A7AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Epstein-related records</header><text>The term <term>Epstein-related records</term> means all records, documents, communications, and investigative materials in the possession of the Department of State or Department of Justice, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation and United States Attorneys’ Offices, that relate to the contents of paragraphs (1) through (9) of section 2(a) of the Epstein Files Transparency Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/38">Public Law 119–38</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8084F0500DE4E63982AA38F178E9B79"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14B4DD5CFB8C49C487D3FB5F512656F1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H325C3AC5FDAD46D0963354852BFBDBF0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Severe forms of trafficking in persons</header><text>The term <term>severe forms of trafficking in persons</term> has the meaning given that term in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0D6588A1A5644289F2AABA29BF44C39"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H911032C3C83A4BD7A2542C1B4E410217"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37E6A76960E84D88B6F34CB758EEAA32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HACE79401B9CB4EE28B79BB31B4FE65E3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Identification of sanctionable persons</header> 
<subsection id="H36CF666FD6004B07A81B9BA92F6F12EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the President shall, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Attorney General, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report identifying each foreign person that the President determines, based on credible information, knowingly engaged in conduct described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H09CF02180EA84E6A972BA2E710611123"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctionable conduct described</header><text>The conduct described in this subsection is any of the following, when undertaken knowingly in connection with the Jeffrey Epstein sex trafficking enterprise or in connection with efforts to conceal, facilitate, finance, or profit from such enterprise:</text> 
<paragraph id="H00255DB4D34B406DAD287AE9E9A2A974"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Engaging in severe forms of trafficking in persons, including sex trafficking involving a person under 18 years of age.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C77DF1A682649B1AFCB24D43FBB69ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Aiding, abetting, commanding, inducing, financing, organizing, or otherwise facilitating severe forms of trafficking in persons or the sexual exploitation of minors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6474791C36024E44AACDA4BCEC591745"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Knowingly benefitting financially or receiving anything of value from participation in, or facilitation of, severe forms of trafficking in persons or the sexual exploitation of minors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF92714F299E48169076B4F020F7AEC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Obstructing, intimidating, retaliating against, threatening, or corruptly influencing a victim, witness, or law enforcement officer in connection with an investigation, prosecution, or civil action relating to conduct described in paragraphs (1) through (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H61BBFA1C179D4AF9AE2CBBBC0A6FE7D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credible information standard</header><text>For purposes of this Act, <quote>credible information</quote> may include information from—</text> <paragraph id="HC0FA5E223A6E426B9333F5D50C5038B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States Government agencies, including law enforcement and intelligence components;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61D6336F46BF41DDA38C357C91966FD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>judicial proceedings, including indictments, judgments, plea agreements, sentencing findings, and sworn testimony;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC753440FD0654FF1802FA5462AE51AD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>foreign governments, international organizations, or multilateral bodies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF60048365B94853BCA3051D61467F5F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>credible reporting by nongovernmental organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2324558B4EC94F22BD6D9121FCF7A020"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Epstein-related records, provided that the appearance of a name in such records shall not be sufficient to support a determination under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48CC66B30A5745E0AFDE804124417786"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex. The unclassified form shall be prepared in a manner that protects the privacy and safety of victims.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6F15328A86D74F14BA8B1A397C47FEE7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header> <subsection id="H7AA8C99B3AF94F6FB586792EF3574C6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition</header><text>Except as provided in section 5, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsections (b) and (c) with respect to each foreign person identified in the report required under section 3(a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20C2A0D506304796B4A6CF38F84143E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> The President shall exercise all powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H0BBF2D379FF04093AAB2EA8266EFF939"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inadmissibility and visa restrictions</header> <paragraph id="HD9996B9FE5A3489ABC200E43B0E021B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The foreign person shall be—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCD377B3B2EFE44C49603FD40B1EBD3A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5E7B2886DA642389D598E115E7AA6FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C306C473BCD427EA683252AAB998AA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE82735C5D274B0DAAEAD842E4D91A7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><text>The Secretary of State shall revoke, in accordance with applicable law, any visa or other entry documentation issued to a foreign person described in subsection (a), regardless of when the visa or documentation is or was issued.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98837B98DC6C4A05B034A5B8B22526D9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to any person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of any prohibition of this section, or an order or regulation prescribed under this section, to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection section 206(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDB3F7774665E4E4AAD10C704C0B942C0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Waiver; exceptions; termination</header> <subsection id="H03FB4C60904C43B2A3CDB78B326FDF53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under section 4 with respect to a foreign person if the President—</text> 
<paragraph id="HADAD487AEF334BFBB4D0DCEFE514CDB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines—</text> <subparagraph id="HD5AC520E94404456836E34A9280577C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that such a waiver is in the national interest of the United States; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBC34516EC8314F1C8221C6C68C500BFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the sanctions would be applied with respect to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activity of the United States; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30913F253BB742548100C1E261D0013A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees, not later than 15 days before the waiver takes effect, notification of the determination and a justification for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A3E9927C49A476FA6ABBE23EAB8A3D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Sanctions under section 4(c) shall not apply to the extent necessary to comply with the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, or other applicable international obligations of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9D32FBA62C6744A4B4448CACC9D872FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header> <paragraph id="HB2964DE6594040E2867FDE842CE3A802"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall terminate the application of sanctions under section 4 with respect to a foreign person if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9508F88AF5EE4AD59FA0FF6342E5142C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person did not engage in the conduct for which the person was sanctioned;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A914BE18B50419F8742AB1F28D28913"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the person—</text> 
<clause id="H00CB85ADF82A46EB947FE262D0985C09"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been prosecuted and sentenced appropriately for the conduct in the United States or under the jurisdiction of another country;</text></clause> <clause id="H44AEBCC2186B4660BB2387ADAA23D6AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has served the sentence imposed; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA9E2585461C548229AFF10DCD5E42DDE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has taken verifiable steps to remediate harm to victims; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3161DFDC9FB54623922BCC387FD50243"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the person—</text> 
<clause id="H57D9468DC1C847E9BB4C7803795CC8FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has credibly demonstrated a significant change in behavior;</text></clause> <clause id="HDAC3E27FDA5B427D8D4EAA1F0E0C3C1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has provided substantial cooperation to United States law enforcement or judicial authorities; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H436AD427F1164DA1A63CA7F619B3F388"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has taken verifiable steps to remediate harm to victims.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48BF225154C24A7D998BC235413CECDE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Petition</header><text>The President shall establish a process by which a person sanctioned under section 4 may submit a petition for the termination of such sanctions pursuant to this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8B9E8C919F514391A15830003048B060"><enum>6.</enum><header>Briefing</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon request, the President, acting through the heads of the applicable Federal departments or agencies, shall provide to any of the appropriate congressional committees a briefing, which may be classified, on the status of the implementation of this Act.</text></section> <section id="H9E6878C84CE044DCAE2444144A8C9265"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to alter, affect, or otherwise relieve the Attorney General of the obligations under the Epstein Files Transparency Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/38">Public Law 119–38</external-xref>).</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>


