<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8DC032B7E5834373957331563B837707" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8395 IH: Payments Access and Consumer Efficiency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8395</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260421">April 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the regulation of registered covered providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA79C53F970E64D7CA0101C037A86E049" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5EC99C076F9B470DB19D4C4797EBE0ED" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Payments Access and Consumer Efficiency Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PACE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H951C4FCF0FA2417ABFEC877B2B4772AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H25F60DF363C048048BBC027A50896A84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board</header><text>The term <term>Board of Governors</term> means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H99C3F68EF988451B9571667A89B91941" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comptroller</header><text>The term <term>Comptroller</term> means the Comptroller of the Currency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB62E63DE784D46B48AEBB02EA5C2C6F6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered provider</term> means a person that provides payment services and—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCB9ECD6725F24375A39404393B0FFE49" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">holds at least 40 active money transmitter licenses issued in accordance with the laws of each applicable State in which the applicant seeks to offer such payment services;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H198DFD18848D414F829B9E240BBB4B02" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">holds a depository institution (as defined in section 3(c) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(c)</external-xref>)) charter from the State in which the applicant seeks to offer such payment services; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6D573EED770427CA832A8987D868ED6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">holds a State credit union (as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>)) charter from the State in which the applicant seeks to offer such payment services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6086E50E8C5746B98162D52D455E4170"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered State regulator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered State regulator</term> means a State agency that has issued a charter or license to a registered covered provider.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0C9D96664574A66A2C8650CD30C168F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deposit</term> has the meaning given in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08A56816A40746B09EDC28A16E623B46"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Insured depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>insured depository institution</term> has the meaning given in section 2 of the GENIUS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5901">12 U.S.C. 5901</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F788EF7547C46E79082FCD218D8905F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Monetary value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>monetary value</term> means a medium of exchange.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F58B20D3E3A4663A2FF078DAEB7D672"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Outstanding payment obligations</header><text>The term <term>outstanding payment obligations</term> means the amount of payment service obligations incurred by a registered covered provider but not yet paid.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8129C91848604B5CA8C9F66A1F4C11BE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Payment instrument</header><text>The term <term>payment instrument</term> means a physical or electronic check, draft, money order, traveler’s check, or card or other means of access to an account or other instrument for the transmission or payment of monetary value. The term does not include stored value.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H999CD1E3F01F4867A3AA8ECCC5204EA0"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Payment service</header><text>The term <term>payment service</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H81CC3D022D4744A083B7AE50A027F714"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> <clause id="HDD3D4FDC74E74A558E9FD5DFA7F5A471"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receiving monetary value for transmission or transmitting monetary value;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H26A8B0FC13D0444C923BDE6C5DEBDD5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receiving monetary value from a payor on behalf of a payee for goods or services provided by the payee;</text></clause> <clause id="H4573D645098A4F9D961F449CF4F5E32C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>selling or issuing stored value;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0877434426E8450AA0DBE186D45AC46E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>selling or issuing payment instruments; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB07D49131676447682A669679F8DFB8A" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing access or custody services with respect to monetary value; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H536DACE9E0E447C9B01B40B691DD6649"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include the provision solely of online or telecommunications services or network access.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC44F1C229CC944F0A2B8E97E32B122BD" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Payments reserve account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>payments reserve account</term> means an account held at a Federal reserve bank that includes access to Fedwire Funds Service, FedNow Service, and FedACH Services (including access to necessary relevant contingent services, as determined by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52454251C89542FE902E97011775D773" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Registered covered provider</header><text>The term <term>registered covered provider</term> means a covered provider that has registered with the Comptroller in accordance with the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC262D3DB95F14C10A8D4EA576341FEEE"><enum>(13)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1878F3708641466DAC9950726C87B4F5"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Stored value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>stored value</term> has the meaning given in section 1002(28) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481(28)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="H3A792D61D89A4CEAA8DDD0E27474E896"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal registration of eligible state payment service providers</header> <subsection id="HFCC17013F25E4023B7AC6281EC2D4E57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Registration of payment service providers</header> <paragraph id="H8A9B991C37FF4287B9E57EA2807E60FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Registration</header><text>A covered provider may submit an application to register with the Comptroller to become a registered covered provider.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9445CB03796D462CADE82F29BF63D29D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Comptroller shall evaluate an application received under paragraph (1) using only the factors specified under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6C191F2558144AB8DDCC867D10760A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>The factors specified in this paragraph are the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H762DDE14713345CBB586D12A79B69DD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The applicant is limited to engaging in activities that directly support or are incidental to the provision of payment services.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA98CAB012F22496EA56F4813C27C8FF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicant is able to meet the requirements of sections 4 and 5.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEB1394872FC1458283B0CB80EC964827"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicant has adequate financial resources, managerial or technical expertise, and a governance system tailored to the business model and risk profile of the covered provider.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACEEEF136F7C4C338088CFFBF3E356F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicant is able to comply with the requirements of the Bank Secrecy Act (as defined in section 2 of the GENIUS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5901">12 U.S.C. 5901</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D8AD6731D0446AEA689EC6DE3EE09E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicant demonstrates benefit to the public, including with respect to innovation, competition, and enabling widespread access and use of payment services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19F0FDFB8F3547AFAEBD2DAEC7AAF1CC"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The applicant is not a designated financial market utility (as defined in section 803(4) of the Payment, Clearing, and Settlement Supervision Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5462">12 U.S.C. 5462(4)</external-xref>)).</text>
          </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F67CCA7617F419B92F80A41FCFB5741"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Holders of money transmitter licenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered provider described in section 2(3)(A) that becomes a registered covered provider under this Act may provide payment services in any State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBE11C058AF8C45A09B24EB800A3F6E6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing for decision; grounds for denial</header> <paragraph id="HCD6F1199B6F84C519D6295558779171F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an application under subsection (a) received during the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller shall notify each applicant, not later than 180 days after the receipt of such application—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE60E7EF6ACAF42E7909A032978354E30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the application is complete; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0990E62B19A94A7698B7F0FDD449781F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the application is incomplete and the specific information required for the application to be considered complete.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BBB022E0305411692A3A0D7BA1B8EA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Comptroller may extend the period described in paragraph (1) by an additional 60 days.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC258837CE0F41F6B28F9A1A40F1675F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an application received after the end of the period described in paragraph (1) (including any extension made under paragraph (2)), the Comptroller shall provide the notification required under such paragraph to each applicant not later than 30 days after receiving such application.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40E3D3CD3EEC43FC9E69B6FA9D05C568"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after notifying the applicant that an application is complete, the Comptroller shall notify the applicant of whether the Comptroller approved or denied such application. If the Comptroller fails to submit a notification with such 180-day period, such application shall be deemed to be approved.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H1947E0C7EE614BD4A0E66C65C37B0AE8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Denial</header> <subparagraph id="H2018138F05BF47DA8B7222BE085FB47A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grounds for denial</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller may deny a complete application received under subsection (a) only if the Comptroller determines the factors described in subsection (a)(3) are not satisfied.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C76F7E589954A25814A9102F8D35E07"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Explanation required</header><text>The Comptroller shall provide each applicant of a complete application that was denied a written notice explaining such denial, including all findings made by the Comptroller with respect to the factors described in subsection (a)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9CFEDFF792874F1FB463B6AD2EF77E6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller shall establish, by rule, a process by which the Comptroller may review and revoke a registration granted under this section to a covered provider if the Comptroller determines the factors described in subsection (a)(3) are not satisfied. Such process shall include a process for providing notice to the covered provider and a process for review of the decision to revoke a registration.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H475D6E1321F34613977B2ABB02FA960C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Customer protection standards</header> 
<subsection id="H0FD9FCE1D75241589E75F8BF8AE34711"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reserve standards</header> 
<paragraph id="H6910D2330678495BB3188C69108AABA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A registered covered provider shall maintain identifiable reserves backing outstanding payment obligations on at least a 1 to 1 basis, with reserves comprising—</text> <subparagraph id="H9823F6401A89408080AB9EF36DED226D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States coins and currency (including Federal Reserve notes) or money standing to the credit of an account with a Federal Reserve Bank;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1B5CE1A3F4A4BFB9CE788C7CA7588E5">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funds held as demand deposits (or other deposits that may be withdrawn upon request at any time) or insured shares at an insured depository institution (including any foreign branches or agents, including correspondent banks, of an insured depository institution), subject to limitations established by the Corporation and the National Credit Union Administration, as applicable, to address safety and soundness risks of such insured depository institution;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5AFC333F677D490BA81788A893A5A605"><enum>(C)</enum><text>funds in transit to the registered covered provider that are owed by an insured depository institution or another registered covered provider, including funds from the automated clearinghouse system or funds receivable from a payment instrument;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H380A4D2C09E3470AAB8AB653CE82EAF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treasury bills, notes, or bonds—</text> 
<clause id="H4C362C5701014C4FADC84D2028A2F29C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a remaining maturity of 93 days or less; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEA469191F3A9444291A28A5BFD6E9758"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>issued with a maturity of 93 days or less;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA5F79A5AE9554AE3BFFF3A4267F65FC2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">money received under repurchase agreements, with the registered covered provider acting as a seller of securities and with an overnight maturity, that are backed by Treasury bills with a maturity of 93 days or less;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B7D6A15945A4235B7CA79C6FE915277"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reverse repurchase agreements, with the registered covered provider acting as a purchaser of securities and with an overnight maturity, that are collateralized by Treasury notes, bills, or bonds on an overnight basis, subject to overcollateralization in line with standard market terms, that are—</text> 
<clause id="H6C77CCDA2F514DD28894CC8867C7A0ED"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>tri-party;</text> </clause> <clause id="H285E13EED9A3470B98683BD7910E2257"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>centrally cleared through a clearing agency registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAA035F8D8EE74D2CA85C8A145C4801C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bilateral with a counterparty that the issuer has determined to be adequately creditworthy even in the event of severe market stress;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H924441E07FFD4ACCB200C67989D44136"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">securities issued by an investment company registered under section 8(a) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-8">15 U.S.C. 80a–8(a)</external-xref>), or other registered Government money market fund, and that are invested solely in underlying assets described in subparagraphs (A) through (F);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4CA57E2BD5F48AD90F9BD7E89021C6B"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other similarly liquid Federal Government-issued asset approved by the Comptroller; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A092225FBDF49269E46599DCA3132A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any reserve described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) or subparagraphs (G) through (H) in tokenized form, provided that such reserves comply with all applicable laws and regulations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEEF0696F49D4CA7BB6E24E927895717"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on rehypothecation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reserves described under paragraph (1) may not be pledged, rehypothecated, or reused, except for the purposes described in section 4(a)(2) of the GENIUS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5903">12 U.S.C. 5903(a)(2)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCA6252AE5F54A209F87956EA71AEF00" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Segregation requirement for access or custody services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A registered covered provider providing access or custody services for monetary value shall segregate and separately account for such monetary value and may not commingle such monetary value with the assets of such provider.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF91663A7FD1043959168180D56B78C0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recordkeeping standards</header> 
<paragraph id="H9958DF532081411F90917F582AF9C820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A registered covered provider shall maintain records of—</text> <subparagraph id="H37AFA2B5D12B48BA9C3C30D623FF1954"><enum>(A)</enum><text>outstanding payment obligations of the provider with respect to each customer of the provider; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE834C4DD7364C49895BA4843175F482"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reserves held pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCADAD6D8355D4A3ABC96E57C7FFC6A7A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access or custody services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A registered covered provider that provides access or custody services for monetary value shall maintain beneficial ownership records with respect to each applicable account and customer.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HDEA3A7AC54224CCA9A8017B956D707D4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Risk management standards and fair access</header> 
<subsection id="HEE33D50A20654CE8A7FDC42000169EF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller shall ensure that a registered covered provider shall be subject to the capital, liquidity, and risk management regulations issued pursuant to section 4(a)(4) of the GENIUS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5903">12 U.S.C. 5903(a)(4)</external-xref>) in a similar manner that such regulations apply to a permitted payment stablecoin issuer (as defined in section 2 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5901">12 U.S.C. 5901</external-xref>)), where such regulations are tailored to the business model and risk profile of the registered covered provider.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HA382DCD5BFC94BF2A01E6459337CEC0E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fair access obligation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A registered covered provider—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9EC318D7E542488E8E0A0E6F87156CC8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be subject to the requirements of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691">15 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.</external-xref>) in the same manner as a creditor under such Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05A692C08259412CAD2EF17C60E3C8C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not deny access to payment services to an individual because of the individual’s constitutionally or statutorily protected beliefs, affiliations, or political views;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D25C073D1AA4D54B1830EE33B59D5A0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may not cancel a payment services account of an individual as a tool to inhibit such beliefs, affiliations, or political views; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69FA37F1D2714AD1AE2A69138C156682" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall make all business decisions with respect to the provision of payment services on the basis of individualized, objective, and risk-based analyses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7EFCB82137A84E6C925D44BBFA290B21"><enum>6.</enum><header>Examinations, contracted services, and enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="H26325C9632E24415B8F2649F24FAAB06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller may make examinations of a registered covered provider with respect to the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFE64A8D46A7042E8BEFB687EDAD03E81"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The nature of the operations and financial condition of the registered covered provider.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H503715ADCCC94A24AD0F22B088A17DDD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The financial, operational, and other risks that may pose a threat to—</text> <subparagraph id="H85BA0289176C4F7299DCA6694CA5D2FD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the safety and soundness of the registered covered provider; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H57CB36EF8EE34D1087AAEEA05A41A462" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the stability of the financial system of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0971B2FF64BB44FDBF4E5A5498E0BE5A"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The systems of the registered covered provider for monitoring and controlling the risks described in paragraph (2).</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3A47BCCDDED4F79A1B2AD50EFACE422"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The compliance of the registered covered provider with the requirements of Federal consumer financial law (as defined in section 1002 of Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481</external-xref>)), including by—</text> <subparagraph id="H7119F23ECCE0424BBE7459CFC13B8168"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtaining information about the activities and compliance systems or procedures of such provider; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DB2737CD9174DD6830F2B707DB320CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detecting and assessing risks to consumers and to markets for consumer financial products and services (as defined in such section 1002).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A2DC48EB1384CF492B9158B8B27B942"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contracted services</header> <paragraph id="H4D8BB9C24DB440BAAD4379AE79795FDE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever a registered covered provider relies on or contracts for any services or activities that are directly related to and are critical to the provision of payment services by the registered covered provider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E5039506667426DA4F6606B44C29F5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person that performs such services or activities shall be subject to regulation and supervision by the Comptroller to the same extent as if such services were being performed by the registered covered provider; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA54A1A4ABE994F73B74C0E0C5F81E273"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the registered covered provider shall notify the Comptroller of any relationship between the provider and the person that performs such services or activities not later than 30 days after the date which is the earlier of the date on which—</text> 
<clause id="HFC91D20BF51048BDBC479FCD149D2721"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such provider and such person enter into a contract for provision of such services or activities; or</text></clause> <clause id="H9B39724CA6F24692815316A7B2885EB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such person begins performance of such service or activity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9AA561BE62224875A7DA23CF5FEF2A34" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Comptroller may enforce the requirements of sections 4 and 5 of this Act against a registered covered provider and take such actions against such provider as permitted under section 8 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1818">12 U.S.C. 1818</external-xref>), as if such provider was an insured depository institution.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4129EC25837F4533AD0DDD8603BE9B66"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reports</header> <subsection id="H9F7DE309070D478FB5A24267414AE7C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Submission of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At the frequency established by the Comptroller, a registered provider shall submit to the Comptroller a report relating to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFD4E1C50106848689F7AC23CD07D2396"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the financial condition of the registered covered provider;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A0ABDDB881C4BB9AEA240846025290D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compliance by the registered covered provider with the requirements of this Act and other applicable laws relating to the provision of payment services; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F82FFF34DB645DB8C404F542EE3C2AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other information the Comptroller may reasonably require with respect to the registered covered provider and the scope of the provision of payment services of such provider.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF2698928DBF943668445E936C604C9EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Existing reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To comply with the requirements of this section, the Comptroller shall, to the maximum extent practicable, use existing reports and other supervisory information and avoid duplication of examination activities, reporting requirements, and requests for information.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF235FE7385944426947020E05E756034" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Priority for customers of registered covered providers</header> 
<subsection id="H6F6F651EDC2C4C8D90AC1D7F17F1BC70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonbank provider defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>nonbank provider</term> means a registered covered provider that is not an insured depository institution (as defined in section 2 of the GENIUS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5901">12 U.S.C. 5901</external-xref>)).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1DC23A75A37C4BC5B2DD90E7EB34F683" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusion from bankruptcy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonbank provider shall not be treated as a debtor for purposes of chapter 7 or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/11/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 11, United States Code.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD4234CE3B3554B2EB2C78C1A27A671CF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Insolvency standards</header> 
<paragraph id="H2559DF6152724258A4960915AC69FA43" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonbank provider shall be eligible to be subject to an insolvency proceeding administered by a covered State regulator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF0D1CE7DCDC4E02A155925FD3CBE300" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law or the law of any State, the Comptroller may be appointed by the covered State regulator to act as conservator or receiver for such a nonbank provider, pursuant to such rules issued by the Comptroller.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98C70E8B2F2F4A9AAE1A5428A6CE5F8D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Backup authority</header><text>If, with respect to an insolvent nonbank provider, a State does not promptly initiate an insolvency proceeding beginning on the date the nonbank provider becomes insolvent, the Comptroller shall initiate such insolvency proceeding. For purposes of this paragraph, the Comptroller shall issue such rules as necessary to define <quote>promptly</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC3DE5753755549B4935FB61E0B345E9D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent that a customer may hold balances with a nonbank provider, amounts realized from the liquidation or other resolution of the nonbank provider by the covered State regulator or the Comptroller (whichever is acting as a conservator or receiver under this section) shall be distributed to pay claims (other than secured claims to the extent of any such security) in the following order of priority:</text> 
<paragraph id="H08F5F4ACC41A4EC9BCF15E94A669865D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Administrative expenses of the conservator or receiver.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EB00B561EA6467F851EA77C3FD03694" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Outstanding payment obligations to customers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74A423B0BD4D48B7A6A247181DA20C85" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other general or senior liability of the nonbank provider.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8870F313525A4E6E84FD0D691CA81EE9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any obligation subordinated to liabilities described in paragraphs (2) and (3) not described in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71CEA7AB8E0E41BDB4C51E3DC9661B6E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any obligation to shareholders or members of the nonbank provider arising as a result of their status as shareholders or members.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE9CCEBBEA2F545D49EC817442EEE3A44" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Custodial assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Monetary value maintained in connection with access or custody services, properly segregated from the nonbank provider’s proprietary assets, are not general assets of the nonbank provider subject to the priority set forth in subsection (d). Any shortfall in custodial assets shall have the same priority as outstanding payment obligations to customers under subsection (d)(2).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDF77DB42C39F4F5FAF91211655604646" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Additional powers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to and not in derogation of the powers conferred and the duties imposed by this Act on the Comptroller or a State as conservator or receiver of a nonbank provider, the Comptroller or State, as applicable, shall have such additional powers and duties with respect to the nonbank provider as imposed on a conservator or receiver of an insured depository institution under any other provision of law.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="HB922506F77654592B1DCB60C97954EF2" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Access to payments reserve accounts</header> <subsection id="H0422AFB44A2045F9800DC445959DE10A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To obtain access to a payments reserve account in the same manner and to the same extent as such access would be granted to an insured depository institution, a registered covered provider may submit a request to the Board of Governors for such access.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1BEAF9CD8804DD0A343455056D933FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The Board of Governors shall approve or deny such a request not later than 120 days after receipt of such request, which period may be extended by an additional 60 days. If the Board of Governors fails to act on such a request within such period, the request shall be deemed to be approved.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H3F3A5AA3AD404ECEA823C879609F6C39" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement authority in unusual and exigent circumstances</header> <paragraph id="H297CDB8C421B4137A38F785AE957C17A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In unusual and exigent circumstances, the Board of Governors may issue a directive that has the effect of a cease and desist order against a registered covered provider that uses a payments reserve account for purposes of noncompliance with requirements of sections 4 and 5 of this Act, if the Board of Governors submits a written notice to the covered State regulator and the Comptroller not less than 48 hours before issuing such directive.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BBC267996F84041BE7B7F794F41BCA1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unusual and exigent circumstances defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and in consultation with the Conference of State Bank Supervisors, the Board of Governors shall issue rules to define the term <term>unusual and exigent circumstances</term> for purposes of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2F93BFFA9DE4F9F8480AE20D1C7BB9C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review</header> <subparagraph id="HAE53AB198EED465B99D1E1413A54A2E5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Administrative review</header> <clause id="H097F6690DE7547AF975739530AD679B6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After a directive described in paragraph (1) has been issued with respect to a registered covered provider, such registered covered provider may object and present to the Board of Governors, in writing, the reasons why the directive should be modified or rescinded.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8294DA0B29144265B09ABEB4FAE1FBDD" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Automatic lapse of directive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 10 days after the receipt of a response described in clause (i), the Board of Governors does not affirm, modify, or rescind the directive, the directive shall automatically lapse.</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD4B475C7A4946E4904033257AB00F67" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Judicial review</header> <clause id="H8CEB7C77080C46ED886B112042373B1D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Board of Governors affirms or modifies a directive pursuant to subparagraph (A), any affected party may immediately thereafter petition the United States district court for the district in which the main office of the affected party is located, or in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia, to stay, modify, terminate, or set aside the directive.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H89FE94BC9C0A4C14A0D2D7EB8DB5D012" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Relief for extraordinary cause</header><text>Upon a showing of extraordinary cause, an affected party may petition for relief under clause (i) without first pursuing or exhausting the administrative review under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H688AA9A94A0F401BAA049C93F940E37F"><enum>10.</enum><header>Effect on securities laws</header> <subsection id="HEA0E4FFE012D49E78E8E75FEDED9DB30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investment advisors act of 1940</header><text>Section 202(a)(18) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2(a)(18)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term <term>security</term> does not include a balance with a registered covered provider, as such term is defined in section 2 of the PACE Act of 2026.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF634A85E0A8F4F0DB25AB1149F75EF67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investment company act of 1940</header><text>Section 2(a)(36) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-2">15 U.S.C. 80a–2(a)(36)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term <term>security</term> does not include a balance with a registered covered provider, as such term is defined in section 2 of the PACE Act of 2026.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3037FA1E479C4875988C670C9B57059A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Securities act of 1933</header><text>Section 2(a)(1) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term <term>security</term> does not include a balance with a registered covered provider, as such term is defined in section 2 of the PACE Act of 2026.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0201D40944F7464FB5F58CCD044B6DF0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Securities exchange act of 1934</header><text>Section 3(a)(10) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(10)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term <term>security</term> does not include a balance with a registered covered provider, as such term is defined in section 2 of the PACE Act of 2026.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB6A7233B99C4B54912DD7E730DD2805"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Securities investor protection act of 1970</header><text>Section 16(14) of the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78lll">15 U.S.C. 78lll(14)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term <term>security</term> does not include a balance with a registered covered provider, as such term is defined in section 2 of the PACE Act of 2026.</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

