<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H97C10F8F30264BEA9519E71F4870F05E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9303 IH: Building Local Access for Needs in Key Emergency Temperatures Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9303</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend subtitle B of title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homelessness Assistance Act to establish supplemental severe weather emergency solutions grants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6AAB9529C5A54844AF6F97B242BABC2A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA61780231053460D8C1F87C2D5A80A51" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Local Access for Needs in Key Emergency Temperatures Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BLANKET Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA7EA560A91834973AAEBF7E0082AA5D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3C52792D65A842C99C1984813B2092F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Severe weather events including severe storms, heat waves, severe winter storms, flooding, wildfires, and cold snaps present serious risks to people experiencing homelessness.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC25463D7A9F947C6B621C014193FB1A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Temporarily increasing emergency shelter capacity during severe weather periods will prevent injury, reduce harm, and reduce strain on emergency medical services and hospitals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D467B06131E4626BB1B65EB1D1D41A6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Targeted Federal funding is necessary to protect life, prevent illness, and support State and local efforts to respond to emergencies.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HA2DB6BC549104055B05804D529D607F0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Supplemental severe weather emergency solutions grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle B of title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11371">42 U.S.C. 11371 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8B6321F3B8FB4908B2BB8D12C9BF0AA5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HCB54013DB92440ADBC17AA4B8D1A23CB"><enum>419.</enum><header>Supplemental severe weather emergency solutions grants</header> 
<subsection id="H8C62510819704C0F80E1987CC1E7737D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section establish a competitive grant program to award supplemental severe weather emergency solutions grants (in this section referred to as <quote>grants</quote>) to eligible entities to expand and improve the capacity of emergency shelters available during periods of severe weather.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEAA459C4C67241BF8425B9F6C16A815C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H960FBCA0E8F7485C87690127EF9C4CB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the population to be served by the grant project and anticipated severe weather events, including past weather patterns and any relevant research data;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC154EA718D554EB695DD8F8F0FB56CA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>data demonstrating a need for expanded emergency shelter services related to severe weather events, including the extent of unsheltered homelessness and weather-related risks in the area to be served by the eligible entity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38A734F63CAE40C39A6666EEA972EFD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to expand shelter capacity in the area to be served by the eligible entity during severe weather events; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA96C89F3623405192A3C87AA5D2C3CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan to coordinate with emergency management, public health, and local service providers to make use of grant funds to provide emergency shelter and related services to homeless individuals during severe weather events.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB97FE502AB684B80B9910F46E4F74BEB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>When awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider—</text> <paragraph id="H5658E54685DC43298376C3A299B840A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree of need for emergency homelessness shelter and related services in the area to be served by the eligible entity, including the extent of unsheltered homelessness in such area;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3831603FC524B83B7C159EAF0EA5993"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the demonstrated capacity, if any, of the eligible entity to deploy emergency shelters during severe weather;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2AB23DB6CCD74900B946C5A69620A914"><enum>(3)</enum><text>past performance of the eligible entity under programs authorized under this title;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3759DDC318D4449AD71D6A8491F30F1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>past coordination with local emergency response systems by the eligible entity; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BE2A02E7F414ACBB27760241D1A0177"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expected measurable benefits in health expenditures, injury, and loss of life to the community served by the eligible entity relative to costs of the activities proposed to be undertaken with grant amounts by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H87661C034E5549DEB1C83B797D520542"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header><text>Amounts from grants provided under this section may be used—</text> <paragraph id="H9F544B7603724DC4854893D3EFB79FF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to temporarily expand emergency shelter capacity, including seasonal warming and cooling centers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE270319DDC9E4C8BA0A19BF57060C807"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to finance vouchers for non-congregate shelter at hotels, motels, and comparable facilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D56E2950AE64080878CA0004E7414DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to finance shelter staffing, shelter security personnel, overtime compensation, sanitation, utilities, and necessary transportation involved in severe weather response;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A32387468AD41539EFF67C1A384E2BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to purchase emergency supplies and equipment, including water, heating and cooling equipment, generators, air filtration, and emergency medical support; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H506E696AD1BD4A1DB466DAB86EA5DC81"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other uses as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HED7EA1D6832F4ADCBF76256E83016EB8" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of other requirements</header><text>Any recipient of amounts under this section shall be required to comply with all requirements established under this subtitle, or any rule issued under this subtitle, that apply to recipients to recipients of grants under this subtitle.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4819439C818D4587B653D49DF2E90E89"><enum>(f)</enum><header>GAO Report</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall, not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section, submit a report to Congress that evaluates the effectiveness of the grants provided under this section and shall include information about—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7AD8B148793649AA908638BD80E26E66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>people served by emergency shelters funded using amounts provided under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27268329D7434A088450E21584FF2E21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>barriers to implementation of the grant program established under this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82BB2B4F39684FBEBC0C3F97C572F2C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>services used by people requiring emergency homeless shelter and related services during periods of severe weather during which amounts provided under this section are utilized.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD9E19BA187554355A9E1F719C3EDC59D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated $750,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2029 for the purpose of offering supplemental Emergency Solutions Grants addressing severe weather emergencies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2F7A0A0C088A41C890D629753C302F1F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H1AF8E6A745494E509B79FFBECC973D04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94436E8A412A4E678A78CBA710887E38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a unit of general local government;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6496CF7C957F41BDA4359ECCF8ED06BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E0117C0C0CA4A45BFAE93ECEF15B158"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a public housing agency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H60CC030BAE764B48A9C47D182F187E8F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>or any combination of the types of entities listed in paragraphs (1) through (6).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

