<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC11B84C18924484D9F5C2D3E4A4737A6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9513 IH: Community Schools and Health Equity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9513</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a grant program to support the integration of school-based health services into community schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2FE88FD43C6642D89FFA0B770D73DE97" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5D533896553648E5913E890295B2A339" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Schools and Health Equity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HE52A3B99BC1F4D81AC029A8402440A02"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program for community schools and health equity</header> 
<subsection id="HF33CD0D40FD04B62B48C0FECBDCBC9E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall carry out a program under which the Secretary of Education makes grants to eligible entities, on a competitive basis, to support the implementation or expansion of school-based health services in community schools.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0EEBD5A186B8462C8C07FC3BE22CE7FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary of Education an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H555DC3791C584CDCBB8A7356172F6BBE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant to carry out one or more of the following activities:</text> <paragraph id="H6E0937149A1B4D74AC88E9304A1F074D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expanding or establishing school-based health services, including partnerships with Federally qualified health centers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4205CF9C60A64796B34761F286B58B79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hiring and training personnel, including school nurses, mental health professionals, social workers, and community school coordinators.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BE1AA874C5641A69D7FD3E341301702"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing wraparound services including nutrition assistance, housing support referrals, family engagement, and legal services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C0C20994EF64706A51FB9A8F91087ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Supporting programs that address social determinants of health affecting students and families.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H666F9C6E94B14667A4F5D494BCE939DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Providing culturally and linguistically appropriate services for English learners and immigrant families.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35B889A67E3048E08B9B600F1D7A8F45"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Supporting trauma-informed practices and crisis response services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE320EBBB6E8047B0B712A93AB87BDF16"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Building partnerships with institutions of higher education to develop health career pathways for students.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H79C684280F3F4345ACA1A4F031999757"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary of Education shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <paragraph id="H6A185D108EBC42B0B67C99AAA3CA4BC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve high concentrations of low-income students;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C2A078A935249BF98B1004A631582BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve a significant number of English learners or students from immigrant families;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB8A202841424BEB9F9A6CED636B048B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demonstrate unmet health or mental health needs among students;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BD08CA8D4E8498C836C0B3C1E0C7526"><enum>(4)</enum><text>are located in medically underserved areas or health professional shortage areas; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB3DC7AB0ABF94A329F0C609D72B0FD77"><enum>(5)</enum><text>propose to partner with Federally qualified health centers or public health agencies to carry out activities supported with the grant.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C45F69364D049958F3B29CC0E87DC8D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>The Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall enter into a memorandum of understanding for purposes of coordinating the implementation of the grant program under this section. At a minimum, such memorandum shall provide for coordination between the Secretaries on—</text> <paragraph id="H8D15182FC7304EA4B1A57C87B58ECD27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reducing the administrative burdens of implementing the program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BE95A103F244ECE936DE216E7A6EA82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to eligible entities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9438915B49814C97B1D728467EB0A643"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting and oversight</header> <paragraph id="H981A782F1C4A4BA69B93369E848F3D96"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Grantee reports</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis for each year an eligible entity receives a grant under this section, the entity shall submit to the Secretary of Education a report on the activities carried out with the grant. Each report shall include, with respect to the year covered by the report—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H0DE47EAFB745481C8717A8D13617ED53">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>identification the number of students served by activities supported with the grant;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H107C3AF398944211B9F030117646E809">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a description of student outcomes related to health, attendance, and academic performance; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H85C33B1AF34341C38D9F6257AEA3EB8A">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to the extent practicable, the information described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) and other relevant student data disaggregated by income, race, ethnicity, and English learner status.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H599D2D8902CC48E4B197C9D27748FE87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than once every three years thereafter, the Secretary of Education shall submit to Congress a report on the grant program under this section. Each report shall include, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text> <subparagraph id="HA2138188EB084536B7780882B5D7EDFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBFE7788176864790902489E90B35B291"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on the results of the program, identification of any best practices or recommendations for improving coordination between the education and the health systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEDAC3E6632AB4D5FAD0985DA163CBBD1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to alter or supersede any Federal privacy protections, including section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232g">20 U.S.C. 1232g</external-xref>; commonly known as the <quote>Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974</quote>) and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H479ACAA908B948A1969C31AAD1E0060D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFC7F225C609644EF9D198544FD3C5D79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community school</term> means a full-service community school (as defined in section 4622 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7272">20 U.S.C. 7272</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10615D6514F84C309067961BF4EBBD61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H779BE9B5572A4437909966ED198A2766"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local education agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA00AB52322BC497280CC2F856751A944"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a consortium of local educational agencies; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6397822A00C4241A68906F626491F6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a partnership between a local educational agency and one or more—</text> 
<clause id="H6C6DBCB60C4C46CF8B177B060DBD80DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>community-based organizations;</text></clause> <clause id="H6CEEBB2730754393ADEF8FEEFB137122"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federally qualified health centers (as defined in section 1861(aa) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>));</text></clause> 
<clause id="H86F15B4ABCA443089CC921B47290516F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>public health agencies; or</text></clause> <clause id="H2F7D4E18C68D4AC7B5E2B26B28CE7C97"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>institutions of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F22E3F2416D4D9483238F0EE58A6A7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7164439D564048AAB73F678A1DD308FE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School-based health services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school-based health services</term> means comprehensive health services provided to students in a school setting, including primary care, mental health services, preventative services, and medical referrals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

