<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H54C10553475747D5A07B4545827C73E7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8722 IH: To require the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into a memoranda of understanding with CFIUS with respect to reports under AFIDA and to update the AFIDA handbook.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8722</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into a memoranda of understanding with CFIUS with respect to reports under AFIDA and to update the AFIDA handbook.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDAB0C1FA234A42FFA1B815EC4B053460" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H714CC7A1AD1D4548937AFEE73E692F12" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Implementation of AFIDA</header> 
<subsection id="H3A7FD608C8D54A21B8395F9AD0261582"><enum>(a)</enum><header>MOU with CFUIS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall enter into 1 or more memoranda of understanding with the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States under which the Secretary shall provide the Committee with all relevant information relating to reports on foreign ownership of United States agricultural land submitted to the Secretary under section 2 of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3501">7 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref>), including information on—</text> <paragraph id="H3DAB46C190D842D8AA9DC534F245E6B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each report submitted to the Secretary under such section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6FDEDD79BB24BECB01E2F9AB0FBFC94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to each such report, the identity of the foreign persons included in the report and the date of submission.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E636257CB6E42FC8600D90FBB98CB3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>AFIDA handbook updates</header> <paragraph id="H42E610EBB896484BA4038F5307BB0F54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First update</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB27306A5095C4C55A5B530F934ED0D3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update the most recent version of the Farm Service Agency handbook titled <quote>Foreign Investment Disclosure</quote> as determined necessary by the Secretary for the effective implementation of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3501">7 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD9A06A6EC5248D39DFF11ED37BC96EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate in such update the recommendations made by the report of the Government Accountability Office titled <quote>Foreign Investments in U.S. Agricultural Land: Enhancing Efforts to Collect, Track, and Share Key Information Could Better Identify National Security Risks</quote> and dated January 18, 2024.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0E3538963C5454FB52C61FE8D3091B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent updates</header><text>After carrying out the update of the handbook under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary of Agriculture shall carry out an update of such handbook every 10 years thereafter, including by incorporating any recommendations of the Government Accountability Office.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

