<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H498A23DD50CC4776970A3F80B19AA84F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6373 RH: Air Permitting Improvements to Protect National Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 544</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6373</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–627]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000482">Mrs. Fedorchak</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Clean Air Act to establish authority for the President to waive the requirement for an advanced manufacturing facility or a critical mineral facility to offset increased emissions of any air pollutant, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC0BEA08BC1841818BA63931B3BE8934" style="OLC"><section id="H6EE6B2F0D81A4F63A616C534A14ADF74" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Air Permitting Improvements to Protect National Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6C56FA48E3E24D2D93EBB45524D30D16"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supporting critical manufacturing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 173 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7503">42 U.S.C. 7503</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7FA4BDA904F8444498AC19E5171CB21C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6C80A345630F45E6B29F196798CFBD0C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H10E6FD09F981402686EC72F7124F6514" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon application by the owner or operator of a new or modified advanced manufacturing facility or critical mineral facility (as such terms are defined in subsection (f)(2)), the President may waive, in whole or in part, any requirement that is in effect under this part for such advanced manufacturing facility or critical mineral facility to offset increased emissions of any air pollutant if the President determines it is in the national security interests of the United States to waive such requirement. The President may not delegate such a determination to any other person. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B4A83BB65F742DD8EC2EC5A0E4E2AFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H223D2DF554F5464E9D55574B25049E46" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H0468EF10D2FF4A06850E112E87312154"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Alternative requirements for advanced manufacturing facilities and critical mineral facilities</header><paragraph id="HC615C5350E2C4FAC9B36469ECBD9744F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The permitting authority of a State shall allow a new or modified major stationary source that is an advanced manufacturing facility or a critical mineral facility to offset emissions from such source by alternative or innovative means under the following conditions:</text><subparagraph id="H90509F0CB001443784C8831A63AC2B27"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The source demonstrates to the satisfaction of the permitting authority of the State that it has used all reasonable means to obtain and utilize offsets, as determined on an annual basis, for the emissions increases beyond allowable levels, that all available offsets are being used, and that sufficient offsets are not available to the source.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H664459A3DA39424CB1BA33D656BBD04B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The source will comply with an alternative measure, imposed by the permitting authority, designed to offset any emission increases beyond permitted levels not directly offset by the source. In lieu of imposing any alternative offset measures, the permitting authority may impose an emissions fee to be paid to such authority of a State which shall be an amount no greater than 1.5 times the average cost of stationary source control measures adopted in that area during the previous 3 years. The permitting authority shall utilize the fees in a manner that maximizes the emissions reductions in that area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7504EB0C0A3247AF8295F8F6977738F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H1460E0EEFF96415FA1E58A4C9DE62A1B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Advanced manufacturing facility</header><text>The term <term>advanced manufacturing facility</term> means a facility the primary purpose of which is the manufacturing of semiconductors or semiconductor manufacturing equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9384097CF24A4BAC8959678A969064C1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Critical mineral facility</header><text>The term <term>critical mineral facility</term> means a facility primary purpose of which is the extraction, processing, refining, or milling of a critical mineral (as designated by the Secretary of the Interior).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

