<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC26937-9N9-62-2F9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4633 IS: Unmanned and Autonomous Systems Strategy Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4633</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require a strategy for the deployment, employment, integration, exportability, and scaling of unmanned and autonomous systems in the Indo-Pacific region and the Western Hemisphere, to strengthen homeland defense, to support counter-narcotics and counter-trafficking operations, and to increase ally and partner burden sharing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unmanned and Autonomous Systems Strategy Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id38b3cb090c9c49879e6735ab7eb39c7b"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy for deployment of unmanned and autonomous systems in Indo-Pacific region and Western Hemisphere</header><subsection id="id510443627b8843cb919c2ed5282d13bf"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the officials specified in subsection (b), shall develop a strategy for the deployment, employment, integration, sustainment, exportability, and scaling of unmanned and autonomous systems in the Indo-Pacific region and the Western Hemisphere.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc409cf91384044fb975324b6ec4ee076"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Specified officials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The officials specified in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id087c34873f14438285f5c26657261d18"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commander of the United States Indo-Pacific Command.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0d55c84129740ba9727da17bb923ac5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commander of the United States Southern Command.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cfffc44908d4608b58a8760ca5665bb"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commander of the United States Northern Command.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9f6928e6bdb4f17ac5e06bdfec05d50"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commandant of the Coast Guard.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35fa7df7b0f4452c821b40b53700fe31"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Defense Autonomous Warfare Group.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a9456c38fda4a3c86299bd03e62dc21"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ade4a2b053b487880d64e2f3636cf75"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id090bd314f2124666a2584d330faaf470"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries of the military departments.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67ccc77cda9f4108a80d8a4e9a59e7ed"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other United States Government official the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0acf43c3cbaa43fba635ef46c4587578"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id07bd318580344d819c30e68229e9d644"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>An assessment of current capability gaps and operational requirements with respect to the deployment of unmanned and autonomous systems within the areas of responsibility of the United States Indo-Pacific Command, the United States Southern Command, and the United States Northern Command, including with respect to—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="idbd766fcd30374178991b423dd32b275c">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>persistent maritime, air, littoral, and undersea domain awareness;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id0233161635c445fe8473068843e9df25">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>undersea surveillance and anti-submarine warfare;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="iddbe9dac4167846fbbb0cc083d4ed8817"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>long-range strike and attritable systems;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idf3eaa2613cf5404ab6b9d79980bbdb19">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>integration of artificial intelligence and decoy operations;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id5c985757abc3414392fff8196bf82d8f"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>counter-unmanned systems operations;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="iddb7fd9f6b21d42d7a6a1731b33ca54e5">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">logistics and communications relay;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id9b26ff3272e642838e22d71dd01a4684">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>electronic warfare and signals intelligence collection;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id8de7dce9d7f248b78654384d695910f3"> <enum>(H)</enum> <text>mine detect and defeat; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id3f9e3286394144e8ae2cce167e6c862d">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>United States homeland security missions to counter narcotics, trafficking, and transnational criminal organizations in the Western Hemisphere, including such missions in support of maritime interdiction and detection-and-monitoring operations.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ide32bd804323e401cb771a138b0b1de22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the scope of unmanned and autonomous systems that may be deployed across, air, surface, and subsurface domains in the Indo-Pacific region and the Western Hemisphere, including—</text><subparagraph id="id9095a93b5c2d45c696ff1fd9816cde94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an identification of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc067a771767f43bfa9b9801ad4d527ed"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unmanned aircraft systems;</text></clause><clause id="idab76696726d344429315cfac4a31899f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>small, medium, large, and extra-large unmanned surface vessels;</text></clause><clause id="idfa8d1224463d4831b7c6c9557b271ccc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>undersea vehicles, including remotely operated and autonomous such vehicles; and</text></clause><clause id="id0f685121703d4375b85ed96ce8d5310c"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>unmanned and autonomous systems platform attributes;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9d5173fae1d44aebbb2faa68576ec489"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the numbers of unmanned and autonomous systems, unmanned undersea vehicles available for such deployment, including remotely operated and autonomous vehicles; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id744949c3f8f54ccfba548eddfded0919"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each system identified under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id031a0304a5af4bf7818249b283be222d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of capability for artificial intelligence integration and autonomy-enabled software;</text></clause><clause id="id99633ac0134949c58b363a28e6edbc29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>operational range, time-on-station, payload capacity, autonomy levels, and survivability; and</text></clause><clause id="id328c7c52d76a43ef8d26d58cc7b6654f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>associated launch and recovery systems, control stations, communications links, sensors, payloads, and modular mission packages, and other operationally relevant performance parameters.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide085eeedd42f476d81a822903f6d095e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of prospective basing, staging, and forward deployment locations for UAS and UUV systems within the areas of responsibility of the United States Indo-Pacific Command, the United States Southern Command, and the United States Northern Command, including an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="id2ef58e9f4c8f43038538a7d39a0e2c26"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>existing United States military installations and their capacity to support unmanned systems operations and long-term storage of such systems;</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf43dfc472c524067a2391a42e1ffb23c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>partner country facilities and agreements necessary to enable forward deployment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb79be264455a4661a12c3ec1ecf680d9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at-sea and submarine-launched deployment concepts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4786143259e940cf8339e883e76a4eff"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An evaluation of the maturity and demonstrated operational suitability of endurance-enabling propulsion technologies, including hybrid-electric propulsion, with attention to efficiency, reliability, acoustic performance, and sustainment considerations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf05f97f147ff419ea48fcea939bc03d7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan for cross-domain integration of UAS and UUV systems into the broader joint force, including enhancement of conventional weapon systems, manned platforms, artificial intelligence systems, and command-and-control networks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0c055addd59452c8cceb7d278ba43a1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A summary of ongoing experimentation, prototyping, and operational demonstrations, including lessons learned from use by the United States Indo-Pacific Command and the United States Special Operations Command.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id338e2394125845c18c1d92138d6d4a56"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A plan for co-design, co-development, co-production, and interoperability of unmanned systems with allies and partners, with particular emphasis on—</text><subparagraph id="idc64010b3fb8543cca8c3079fbec22876"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Australia, Israel, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Taiwan, and Ukraine; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id88d3cb27b97e45b3891fc7c495971730"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>partners under the Advanced Capabilities pillar of the AUKUS partnership.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id14401b4a383e47989aa9e3aa9f19342b"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An assessment of adversary unmanned systems capabilities and counter-unmanned systems threats, and recommendations for measures to ensure survivability and mission effectiveness of United States and allied unmanned systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaab4772485049c5b8ce307b6b228f66"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A resource and procurement plan identifying near-term, mid-term, and long-term investments in UAS and UUV programs required to execute such strategy, including an identification of programs of record, rapid acquisition pathways, scalability and manufacturability, supply chain vulnerabilities, and commercial off-the-shelf options.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97eccf867db04e68a1a589212d0ae7f2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A plan for addressing supply chain dependencies and vulnerabilities for UAS and UUV systems, consistent with the requirements of the American Security Drone Act of 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/31">Public Law 118–31</external-xref>; 137 Stat. 691; 41 U.S.C. note prec. 3901), as applicable, to ensure that United States military unmanned systems are not dependent on components manufactured by entities subject to the influence or control of a covered foreign entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13db6e40407f4309a1fcc625d6042d2c"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Metrics and milestones for measuring the implementation and effectiveness of the strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda3a246c8ac9442b9bbff24ce79a4bef"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code) the strategy developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="idae75214335cf4c8e842938f8a4e935ad"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which the strategy required by subsection (a) is submitted, and annually thereafter through 2030, the Secretary of Defense shall provide the congressional defense committees with a briefing on—</text><paragraph id="id88d6bfdf1a864aa198988ce5faa9fe5a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of implementation of the strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8372fbf259c44fa59073f9d9d5683cb5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any changes in adversary unmanned systems capabilities or operational behavior that affect the strategy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3460f8f2fb494a4392461b0b8acf5e1a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>progress on allied and partner co-development and interoperability initiatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2a870c32aab4fa783ba67fc5556cf5a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>procurements, deployments, and exercises conducted in furtherance of the strategy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id07a98b40df42450e8307cb3891c80abe"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any recommended updates or modifications to the strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide74b96778a9649e881e23032b38e1dcf"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="id14c161ca96a442f9800d4e5553013668"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Covered foreign entity</header> <text>The term <term>covered foreign entity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1822 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/31">Public Law 118–31</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/4661">10 U.S.C. 4661</external-xref> note).</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idffc97ef4a2d94671be069d447f319101"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system; UAS</header><text>The terms <term>unmanned aircraft system</term> and <term>UAS</term> mean an unmanned aircraft and associated elements, including communication links and the components that control the unmanned aircraft, in accordance with section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94df1462e450434c875c09f9963b6ab6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unmanned undersea vehicle; UUV</header><text>The terms <term>unmanned undersea vehicle</term> and <term>UUV</term> mean an unmanned, self-propelled vehicle that operates below the surface of the water, including remotely operated vehicles and autonomous undersea vehicles.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

