<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26119-0R9-LY-4HR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3702 IS: Dignity for Detained Immigrants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3702</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide standards for facilities at which aliens in the custody of the Department of Homeland Security are detained, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H7277461FEF0B45DE84ED63BB5E1642CC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF1E209DC151D49FCB50B011897EBB491"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dignity for Detained Immigrants Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4EDEC89874B447D38581B067799DC7EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that detention, even for a short period of time, inflicts severe, irreparable harm on children and should be avoided.</text></section><section id="id4079FE67A3A248BF90FA9FC3C84CEA86"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id607171ADF03E48DEBD92946249C4EEB4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idE12793D6CF234EA2959814C5B4CE85A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56BD7C68CE0C49E19A4F4669F30C7485"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCB5A9B5C00A34CE5B813398E9E5015FC"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2F76245220EF4D2894ED9CBA82E1A05C">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7831E0D4C16640B7AE943943912E9AD5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id856e4d8d77f545868d47cfd16315dacd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inspector general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Inspector General</term> means the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82B1D0F86DBC4A8FAF14F79862DC82AD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H95C6FDD4E84D461497B61F8911741458"><enum>4.</enum><header>Standards for Department of Homeland Security detention facilities</header><subsection id="id4E4775EEFAD943A2867F541B5D0333F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, by regulation, shall establish detention standards for each facility at which aliens in the custody of the Department are detained.</text></subsection><subsection id="id54ED3F5284E645B5B5E068EE82181132"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standards established pursuant to subsection (a) shall provide, at a minimum, the level of protection for detainees described in the American Bar Association’s Civil Immigration Detention Standards (adopted in August 2012 and modified in August 2014).</text></subsection><subsection id="id591944D3252E45A385F68671C716F366"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than biennially, the Secretary shall review and update the standards established pursuant to subsection (a), as appropriate.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6827D87FB05F4682B7C767A45A59E021"><enum>5.</enum><header>Oversight and transparency</header><subsection id="H0EB90E6AA4B34DAB8878EEAE8A41FE93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Periodic inspections</header><paragraph id="HBC0D0AFA308147918314DDD84FA361C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On a periodic basis, not less frequently than annually, the Inspector General shall conduct an unannounced, in-person inspection of each facility at which aliens in the custody of the Department are being detained to ensure that each such facility is in compliance with the standards established pursuant to section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87A02F5A7A4E49D58ABC75567E98A165"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after conducting each inspection pursuant to paragraph (1), the Inspector General shall—</text><subparagraph id="idB759410B4A404E49BCFDB73BF88F6F69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit a report to the Secretary containing the results of such inspection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id58889E6287C441029DBC27BF8734BFDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>post such report to the public on an internet website of the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0795F8056E2D4380A4F8A7EF52A62AA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Failure to comply with standards</header><subparagraph id="H12632A62153F4F1DA02B025D2CDD5FF7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial failure</header><clause id="idF0BE92E3D9AD457F971511BAF7B4218B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Inspector General determines that a facility has failed to comply with the standards established pursuant to section 4 for the first time during any 2-year period, and such noncompliance constitutes a deficiency that threatens the health, safety, or rights of any detainees housed at such facility—</text><subclause id="id7BD68E4B13AF46C4972B6F67691800F3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Inspector General shall notify the Secretary of such determination; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idAD35382B35C34D52A11D716297F045E8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary—</text><item id="HD942E285312D4741B24E5FC0EC04AF58"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of a facility not owned by the Department, shall impose a meaningful fine of not less than 10 percent of the value of the contract with the facility; and</text></item><item id="H36AD4A9FAA2D4D7EBB1DBF4E7D1EE42A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a facility owned by the Department—</text><subitem id="HAF55387285854B62966376553DFD5710"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>shall issue a written warning to the facility not later than 30 days after receiving such notification from the Inspector General, which shall include remedial measures to be carried out not later than 60 days after the issuance of such warning; and</text></subitem><subitem id="HE4E9CD5E4ED4441E892702293F21CE27"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the issuance of the warning described in subitem (AA), shall certify to the Inspector General that the remedial measures have been carried out.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="id545C7AC87C2240BAB8199F30ED5061C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Follow-up inspection</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Inspector General makes a notification pursuant to clause (i)(I), the Inspector General shall conduct an in-person inspection of the facility to determine whether the facility has achieved compliance with the standards established pursuant to section 4.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC84B1BD65E944DD82D79B200FD64025"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent failures</header><text>If the Inspector General determines that a facility has failed to comply with the standards established pursuant to section 4 in 2 or more inspections conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) during any 2-year period, and such noncompliance constitutes a deficiency that threatens the health, safety, or rights of any detainees housed at such facility—</text><clause id="id41AC7488EDDB4F168FE3F502EF3A6FAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Inspector General shall notify the Secretary of such determination; and</text></clause><clause id="idE75CF80663F745BA9C2B2B239B1AA4AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary—</text><subclause id="H6A465AFD502B4B929E24F155CAD83B3E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a facility not owned by the Department—</text><item id="idE8AE2DCF2C2C41249442C802757B16CB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after receiving such notification, shall transfer each detainee housed at such facility to a facility that does comply with such standards;</text></item><item id="id35BE3097537F4060A79F2B0666DE14EC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall terminate the contract with the owner or operator of the facility; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98235e7b8f9a4cd98556832acea34031"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall ensure that no funds made available to the Department are used to continue such contract; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H159752AD909544AD9937FB1B69FE3097"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a facility owned by the Department—</text><item id="idD20B8761782A473D9913633C6A9FE072"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 60 days after receiving such notification, shall transfer each detainee housed at such facility to a facility that does comply with such standards; and</text></item><item id="id3E341103BBB04E039DA316CC90A82BBD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall suspend the use of such facility until after the Inspector General—</text><subitem id="id237E833168B546A68C778F785BD50F4D"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has certified to the Secretary that such facility is in compliance with such standards; and</text></subitem><subitem id="id9B96D0C1CB594ED9BE785003F896F3F2"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes available to the public on an internet website of the Department information relating to the remedial measures that have been taken at such facility.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idB473B954E82D4EDEA6371732DF54F859"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deaths in custody</header><paragraph id="HD4F6A3172C2449AB8BA06A4AFE3F1AD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 hours after the death of an alien in the custody of the Department, the Secretary shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of such death.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46FE00A517214D1FBC21DAA94D56BB7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigations</header><subparagraph id="idCEDDDDDAF3264ABEABCE7F12F516F227"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the death of an alien in the custody of the Department, the Secretary shall conduct an investigation into such death, which shall include a root cause analysis that identifies any changes to policies, practices, training curricula, staffing, or potential systemwide errors that may reduce the probability of such an event in the future.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2BB35397FEA045AF929107C5A6B83BAA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Root cause analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each root cause analysis required under subparagraph (A) shall be carried out—</text><clause id="idB0EA2508BF44448889FF979DE9A25181"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by appropriately qualified personnel, including 1 or more medical professionals qualified in a field relevant to the cause of death; and</text></clause><clause id="id6EECDDF4DA8E40F6A79164A44F8EAF3A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with professional medical standards for investigating sentinel events in medical care facilities, including the Sentinel Event Policy adopted by The Joint Commission in 1996.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC24C09429660447592281A07441CA322"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after a death described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="id6E9CECB1EA5E4E889A96039E8010D813"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a full report describing the results of the investigation required under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause><clause id="id6656DE49133045DA9263AE992AB484DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make such report available to the public on an internet website of the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA56C0065D03041B899F4CD2FB70FAF23"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Review by inspector general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the death of an alien in the custody of the Department, the Inspector General shall conduct a review of the report issued pursuant to subparagraph (C) with respect to such death.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92FBDA9C648472CB73BE51AD95ACB48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>death of an alien in the custody of the Department</term> means the death of an alien occurring while the alien is under the supervision of the Department, regardless of—</text><subparagraph id="id8655BF5F40764FF5B07DCA37159F4E53"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the location of the death; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC63A5C4DDA774BD5884ACB2F5D160B44"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the death—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida216f3f783a54abca04238a6367caa97"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may have resulted from a health problem that existed before or during the detention of the alien; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8e00740507d4b2f957d3d882eeb4485"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was exacerbated by such detention.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBECFF40E1F7749859491606CEC8D841A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><paragraph id="idF64DDAA9047E436788DB093A70A4300E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Secretary shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress regarding the inspections and oversight of facilities at which aliens in the custody of the Department are being detained.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0F8552F274DA4542BBBE3550C29595E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the preceding 12-month period—</text><subparagraph id="HE81C5968FA0F4187A46A27C984D2E8B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the detention facilities found by the Inspector General to be noncompliant with the standards established pursuant to section 4;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E5BD7CBDD164A8698B8F610FAD1E9CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each such facility, a description of the remedial actions taken, or planned to be taken, by the Secretary to achieve compliance with such standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD9A2025AB47482EA2C31BD60A31B508"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a determination as to whether such remedial actions have brought such facility into compliance with such standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE9331C80C3F949F8B3908445C562852D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Classification of documents for purposes of FOIA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reports required under subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2)(C) and any contract between the Department and a private or public entity that provides for the use of a facility not owned by the Department to detain aliens in the custody of the Department are considered records subject to public disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code, and do not qualify for the exception under subsection (b)(4) of such section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0C289721ADD47FC8D649474715D856F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Facilities matrix</header><paragraph id="id0D8359B9F9C747F6B2484788EC17FF03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the first day of each month, the Secretary shall ensure that a publicly accessible website of the Department contains the information described in paragraph (2) for each facility at which aliens in the custody of the Department are being detained.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF5406698CBF14066844BB9CD0762032A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The information described in this paragraph is, for each such facility—</text><subparagraph id="H4605BE6030B446EDAD0C0442D9E6B492"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and location of the facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90CFF8EA4C1F4BB28C07CE0FEEAB337F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the facility houses adults, children, or both;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2F477DCE814240018B2380EF2F1A9F85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of beds available in the facility on the last day of the preceding month, disaggregated by gender;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id493BA4C0211541FDA90B8F301C01D5A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the total number of aliens detained in the facility on the last day of the preceding month, disaggregated by gender and classification as a child or an adult;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H906632DB3CB94F1EB48613DF08CBB763"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the facility is used to detain aliens for longer than 72 hours;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5763463309A44928819D2DE071BAAB85"><enum>(F)</enum><text>whether the facility is used to detain aliens for longer than 7 days;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE775C6D6670A4672BB06021CD71BD5DD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the average number of aliens detained in the facility during the current year and during the preceding month, disaggregated by gender and classification as a child or an adult;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CE923521E254E90968CDC2B544F95A5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>whether the facility is in compliance with the standards established pursuant to section 4;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4C6C069181D48879BFD698F7DEC382B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the facility is not owned by the Department, a description of the nature of the contract providing for the detention of aliens at such facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9147E6BEB9854A5589FDDDFC8966C591"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average, median, 25th quartile, and 50th quartile number of days that aliens have been detained at the facility during the preceding month.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAB95289A37046B98F45BD4B5E9D0802"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Online detainee locator system</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure the online detainee locator system maintained by the Department, or any successor system, is updated not later than 12 hours after an alien is—</text><paragraph id="id3AEDD3A0BB63429F9179113CC05DB9CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>taken into, or released from, custody by the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22801A41FEC64AB4B013CA242CAB7DF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transferred to, or detained in, a detention facility; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5D5A2D4942B74A968CC0B81AD1EE95C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>removed from the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H86B72D694B6043CD9B7DA765A8FC66CA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Information collected and maintained regarding aliens in DHS custody</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall collect and maintain, for each alien in the custody of the Department—</text><paragraph id="HD0546140332B4C4CA200280187CA7ACE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the gender and age of the alien;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3D1C804B61D473B9DA3F27711027273"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the alien was taken into such custody;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7810BFDCF5F4CADBE77B4CFD2B31648"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the country of nationality of the alien;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5530DA5C7D0740C2A3680196EE632DD1"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>whether the alien is considered a vulnerable person (as such term is defined in section 236(c)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 9(a) of this Act);</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="H75E64200DA7A46319866AA85108DE7E2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the provision of law pursuant to which the Secretary is authorized to detain the alien;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81C82ABA048C471EBD271ED3EFF4DCAF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the name of the facility in which the alien is detained;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE185364790F54708A908B10003776DD4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>if the alien was transferred to another detention facility—</text><subparagraph id="id832367D995BA4D14975C40B4F461A203"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the transfer of the alien to the other detention facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD7E077E0D9F34C0F8C10344B85A4273C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reason for the transfer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id45CF7F878DB74DEF90C2CFF4D502678A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the transfer was effectuated despite the presence of the alien's legal counsel or immediate relative in the jurisdiction of the original detention facility, the justification for such transfer;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2360074C8A5743429887F50FB2EE33B1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the status and basis of any removal proceedings to which the alien is the subject;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB726684F23AA47648FA892A368ED8434"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the initial custody determination made by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, including any review of such determination;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0CE67E4CC0C4592B8FE40BF5C55C338"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date of the alien’s release or removal, and the reason for such release or removal, as applicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51466AC2D90643E681474DDA1CCEBA7F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>whether the alien is subject to a final order of removal;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C48D4BC9793411999C31A2474F5B04F"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the alien was apprehended as part of a family unit; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDC848878FE646F9B73A3737C8ED7F99"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the alien was separated from a family unit at the border or in the interior of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD6E0431FEE37423B9756D442A62E99EC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Civil actions for violation of standards</header><subsection id="idA9272FF3DAE6412E80968C4528674105"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is detained in a facility required to comply with the standards established pursuant to section 4 and is injured as a result of a violation of any such standard may file a claim in the appropriate district court of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC651F2FF4A304CD69435A7075250880A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recovery</header><text>In a civil action brought under this section, the court may—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45b7b5f365f34c0e800b02325cdb384c"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">order injunctive relief and award compensatory damages; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9b3f37690a14f57b9fec26505df539a"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">award the prevailing party reasonable attorney fees and costs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAF191B6CF6CF4D7AA2A0F87A7B34F4FF"><enum>7.</enum><header>Detention facility construction and maintenance</header><subsection id="H4B133EE1411147AA92BDCFA72ABDFD6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restriction on construction</header><paragraph id="id2862AA12727E4F3F9F0F4A58B1B992A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days before initiating, or entering into a contract for, the construction of a new facility or the expansion of an existing facility for the detention of aliens in the custody of the Department, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a notification of the plan to construct or expand such facility, including—</text><subparagraph id="id17BB0510052F4AA6B321CEEFB24E8494"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the location, size, and capacity of such facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD318A1D0BF244784B4489B1984FF9C15"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the anticipated timeline and cost of constructing or expanding such facility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16847307B7CD44BFA1D7CFC4C444B67A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the intended population to be detained at such facility, including the gender and ages of such population.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id960458261E13413D9E90BB11771E20A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make the information described in paragraph (1) available to the public on an internet website of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6C9BBC1CF5341F4A3DE669B123C3851"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Phase-Out of private detention facilities and use of jails</header><paragraph id="HE78E4C687BBB4F068D8354713D5C1CF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secure detention facilities</header><subparagraph id="id95511E1BA5A04C7695EB1CC81AFCA538"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary—</text><clause id="id6CBC4A54255D4F9DA569C75BD5E04638"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not enter into or extend any contract or agreement with any public or private for-profit entity that owns or operates a detention facility for the use of such facility to detain aliens in the custody of the Department; and</text></clause><clause id="id35C25F8EC29347B5A3855DC54B7B7C7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall terminate any contract or agreement described in clause (i) not later than the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA4DFC578980F40D19498A48B2DDE3EB6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ownership requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, any facility at which aliens in the custody of the Department are detained shall be owned and operated by the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H20FD2CB708E64B88AAF62BA045B6B5ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternatives to detention programs</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7B74D425F15941A8B1E480BCE8B770C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary—</text><clause commented="no" id="idA9712AE00893460CA9C62E8FBB7CAED4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not enter into or extend any contract or agreement with any public or private for-profit entity for the operation of a program or the use of a facility for nonresidential, detention-related activities for aliens who are subject to monitoring by the Department; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id1A16078781DF49C9A92B8FC726D7F244"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall terminate any contract or agreement described in clause (i) not later than the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idC46949E9C203454FA4223589918ECE2A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ownership and operation requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, any program or facility used for the activities described in subparagraph (A)(i) shall be owned and operated by a nonprofit organization or the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC875B88637574C2E82FD3C2C13732A73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop, and make publicly available, a plan and timeline for the implementation of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idef91b00ef8894718acd6f1da6e73d6ed"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Facility requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each facility used for the detention of aliens has a visitor waiting and security screening area that is indoor and climate-controlled.</text></subsection></section><section id="H459BB4CF19E2453EAB26F9903D31B374"><enum>8.</enum><header>Appearance of detained aliens for other legal matters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall promulgate rules to ensure that any alien detained in the custody of the Department who is required to appear in Federal or State court (including family court) for another matter is transported by an officer or employee of the Department to such court proceeding.</text></section><section id="H7382DBDF2FDA401FBC60DDDAD11C31A8"><enum>9.</enum><header>Procedures for detaining aliens</header><subsection id="HA6772BE47FD745F48A14A1078CBE6D35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Probable cause and custody determination hearings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 236 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226">8 U.S.C. 1226</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7863A796FAD54A398413DE408DD0401B"><section id="idF0B0200B848B486B8BEB72534E2531B0"><enum>236.</enum><header>Apprehension and detention of aliens</header><subsection id="H8F2EB859EDCF4DBAAC3AC52ED7FFFCA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Arrest, detention, and release</header><paragraph id="id61B8AD7FDB2446D1AAB914A9E5048879"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a warrant issued by an immigration judge, or pursuant to section 287(a)(2), the Secretary of Homeland Security may—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d1a7ff51aa240028cb643cb37165dbb"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">arrest an alien; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide98e618c204d4b39a458e77003737d76"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with this section, detain the alien or release the alien on bond, subject to conditions or recognizance, pending a decision on whether the alien is to be removed from the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id40058CA031DB419B8BFC4391575A8004"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption for unaccompanied alien children</header><subparagraph id="id9282100037E840A083E366740E29E0FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall not apply to unaccompanied alien children (as defined in section 462(g)(2) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)(2)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBA8D729CA52444BE87D2AAE849DE476A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transfer of custody</header><text>Any unaccompanied alien child in the custody of the Secretary of Homeland Security shall be transferred to the custody of the Secretary of Health and Human Services pursuant to section 235(b)(3) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(b)(3)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FAEBD26F1834E9DA51E7D869E4F186D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bond determination</header><paragraph id="id3A7755DC985341139D22A9ABDFBD4699"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An immigration judge who releases an alien on bond under this section shall—</text><subparagraph id="idD25B53B459064355B28434256EEAD8CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider, for purposes of setting the amount of the bond, the alien’s financial position and ability to pay the bond without imposing financial hardship on the alien; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAAC767F2F5FC430E93D96BB071255A7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">set bond at an amount no greater than necessary to ensure the alien’s appearance for removal proceedings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id6945C660A5664BCE837F785BA2BEF8F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inability to pay bond</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not continue to detain an alien solely based on the alien's inability to pay bond.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D4E94FFCE4F460F817EB1B0443505E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Custody determination</header><paragraph id="H8765536F93764869AE6FCD8E81D9ECCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial determination</header><subparagraph id="id6B3360A83ABF446F84557DA941BE0E5F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 48 hours after taking an alien into custody pursuant to this section or section 235, or with respect to an alien subject to a reinstated order of removal pursuant to section 241(a)(5) who has been found to have a credible or reasonable fear of return, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall make an initial custody determination with regard to the alien, and provide such determination in writing to the alien.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC65249C82D834372B1C9839FD0715D49"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Least restrictive conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a custody determination under subparagraph (A), if the Secretary determines that the release of an alien will not reasonably ensure the appearance of the alien as required or will endanger the safety of any other individual or the community, the Secretary shall impose the least restrictive conditions, as described in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACEFBABD5BAD4237ACE960CFD946D387"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph id="id1FEADA07AE5A4364A276F6EBFA5E6389"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien who seeks to challenge the initial custody determination under paragraph (1) shall be provided with the opportunity for a hearing before an immigration judge not later than 72 hours after the initial custody determination to determine whether the alien should be detained.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5E18F8D039CE4869A816FB2A0EE1B4BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Access to counsel</header><text>On request by an alien, or the legal counsel of an alien, an immigration judge may grant a reasonable continuance of a hearing under subparagraph (A) to provide the alien or such legal counsel additional time to prepare for the hearing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91FFFD4685144ACBA39F8ED65CB35969"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Presumption of release</header><subparagraph id="id591976A3E05C4AA18C98811F1AF6BE44"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a hearing under this subsection, there shall be a presumption that the alien should be released.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB256A581B80D45D08E74AE0B6B2C7811"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rebuttal</header><clause id="id5DBC5166E2DC4593852853BC070068F9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security has the duty of rebutting this presumption, which may only be established based on clear and convincing evidence, including credible and individualized information, that—</text><subclause id="idD12E12DFF1BF42629FE92C3E27DB0A59"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of alternatives to detention will not reasonably ensure the appearance of the alien at removal proceedings; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id841B1E0E0713427A911CC85E9296AEF0"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien is a threat to any other individual or the community.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id2E1C1D36CE7F4AD6A568D5231D26F40A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General—</text><subclause id="id8CF8BD0397C747329CF1EB38CB39363D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall consider the totality of each case; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id93FD58313E9D412C86D5E489EB7AB5A8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not rely on an alien's criminal conviction, arrest, pending criminal charge, or combination thereof as the sole factor to justify the continued detention of the alien.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC3DA2F9825C48C39257E7486A40AEF2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Least restrictive conditions required</header><subparagraph id="idD0AEC464FFA54DA7A4891103BBA0BA27"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an immigration judge determines, pursuant to a hearing under this section, that the release of an alien will not reasonably ensure the appearance of the alien as required or will endanger the safety of any other individual or the community, the immigration judge shall order the least restrictive conditions, or combination of conditions, that the judge determines will reasonably ensure the appearance of the alien as required and the safety of any other person and the community, which may include—</text><clause id="id42A9DB9F9036457C8C50BCA63B4D308E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">release on recognizance;</text></clause><clause id="idA376013DAFDD4FE1A64B2BCFD2EEBD23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">secured or unsecured release on bond; or</text></clause><clause id="id25F4933E8B0B48DFBEBD5F232CFFDDA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participation in a program described in subsection (f).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4A7E943CB6CF46DCA0D8115032AF3599"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Monthly review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than monthly, the immigration judge shall review any condition assigned to an alien pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idE24E6644359240B0ADBCB2078A686B29"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Modification of conditions of supervision</header><text>An immigration judge may modify or rescind conditions of supervision imposed on an alien by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7404669D22D548AD990B8367784C5F5A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special rule for vulnerable persons and primary caregivers</header><subparagraph id="idE83E087A884A47A1B34B630E4B5D5D47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an alien subject to a custody determination under this subsection who is a vulnerable person or a primary caregiver, the alien may not be detained unless the Secretary of Homeland Security demonstrates, in addition to meeting the requirements under paragraph (3), that it is unreasonable or not practicable to place the alien in a community-based supervision program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34272DC3A408494B9FD660DC32CD4861"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text><clause id="H818299EB31BF46C09B4FF8A7721A8F97"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Material witness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>material witness</term> means an individual who presents a declaration to an attorney investigating, prosecuting, or defending a workplace claim or from the presiding officer overseeing a workplace claim attesting that, to the best of the declarant’s knowledge and belief, reasonable cause exists to believe that the testimony of the individual will be relevant to the outcome of the workplace claim.</text></clause><clause id="HFFDF97464EFD4F19A5B42BCA06389A3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Primary caregiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>primary caregiver</term> means an individual who is established to be a caregiver, parent, or close relative caring for or traveling with a child.</text></clause><clause id="H1BA5EBAA9F16449EA6177D57E7559C79"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Vulnerable person</header><text>The term <term>vulnerable person</term> means an individual who—</text><subclause id="HBDDC5A931B2B499393F73C2E8529F75F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is younger than 21 years of age or older than 60 years of age;</text></subclause><subclause id="H76A76DC782434094AC3787459DBABA66"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is pregnant;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD6C3DEE323404CB2A6E1E3C1A5547E00"><enum>(III)</enum><text>identifies as lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, or intersex;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8BF1429623F44F86A8F90A791A90E869"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>is a victim or witness of a crime;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5CE9438D53D54CDE81249B2B26DC38AE"><enum>(V)</enum><text>has filed a nonfrivolous civil rights claim in a Federal or State court;</text></subclause><subclause id="H84DC22D3E12647DD9305B47FAE2BB21A"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has filed, or is a material witness to, a bonafide workplace claim;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0C43516D1B144EA7AFF66837F92B0BFA"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>has a serious mental or physical illness or disability;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFA078E17F3AA4179990480D551910235"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>has been determined by an asylum officer, in an interview conducted in accordance with section 235(b)(1)(B), to have a credible fear of persecution or torture;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBEF2E4C83CA6406996BFABA05817FFD9"><enum>(IX)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has limited English language proficiency and is not provided access to appropriate and meaningful language services in a timely fashion; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD8269F59620B4820AE013E0C5E33AAD5"><enum>(X)</enum><text>has been determined by an immigration judge or by the Secretary of Homeland Security to have experienced or to be experiencing severe trauma or to be a survivor of torture or gender-based violence, based on information obtained during intake, from the alien’s attorney or legal service provider, or through credible self-reporting.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4AA2094C43464A33AF38B59C27154584"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Workplace claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>workplace claim</term> means any written or oral claim, charge, complaint, or grievance filed with, communicated to, or submitted to the employer, a Federal, State, or local agency or court, or an employee representative, related to the violation of applicable Federal, State, or local labor laws, including laws concerning wages and hours, labor relations, family and medical leave, occupational health and safety, civil rights, or nondiscrimination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1737634F57524E56B6B9C22C264257ED"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Subsequent determinations</header><text>An alien detained pursuant to this section shall be provided with a de novo custody determination hearing under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="id452CD9EF6FA349F2AE2F2C05781AA3D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Dignity for Detained Immigrants Act</short-title>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEE88D00297F2491F940C9C6F130C4169"><enum>(B)</enum><text>every 60 days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1788ED2C9F5F43CBBDE6234DF1419CF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>upon showing of a change in circumstances or good cause for such a hearing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1023C3B3064C4DA4BAD4E40ECACEBC40"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Release upon an order granting relief from removal</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security—</text><paragraph id="idCD459DF80A3648E9823EC4451E0903C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall immediately release an alien with respect to whom an immigration judge has entered an order providing relief from removal (including an order granting asylum or withholding, deferral, or cancellation of removal) or an order terminating removal proceedings, which order is pending appeal, upon entry of the order; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13449B6AE76B430D8898996D34689E98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may impose only reasonable conditions on the alien’s release from custody.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A3C6AB8572B4E62805EEEEBB2B0F02F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on detention of children</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security may not detain in a facility operated or contracted by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement any individual who is younger than 18 years of age.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H232C050647BD4E42AA0B2001FFA9D2B7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Community-Based case management program</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H1F55B992A16B401883A8E8F4A16E8286"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish, outside of the purview of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, a community-based case management program that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idA0F7E1DB35B24A8094744F03E0C07934"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides alternatives to detaining aliens;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idCD381816A0A84E91AB2355C306ED89DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offers a continuum of community-based support options and services, including—</text><clause commented="no" id="id99204448F3EF4AB8BD449EC1093CE146"><enum>(i)</enum><text>case management; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id17B6F2F43CC24CBA9CB1826809A34EAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>access to—</text><subclause commented="no" id="idF8F6A7370D9342B5B31F39BCA28F0BEE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>social services;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id51AA5AC2F1C04315BE8DEE0665B2BA18"><enum>(II)</enum><text>medical and mental health services;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id2BEBDF71A54D4635BCA512C1095DF74D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>housing;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="idF8EE65CA04DA418EB904271D465B69AA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>transportation; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="id2CA3D5C6A1FC430A835F0CDC011462FC"><enum>(V)</enum><text>legal services; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7658CF6493D24C28B0D9058924D2446E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides services in the appropriate language.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idE140D77AD6524670AACEEE8965FE5200"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on electronic surveillance</header><text>The program under paragraph (1) may not include, as an alternative to detention, the provision of ankle monitors or other forms of electronic surveillance.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idba1510fb9ce444b8adde582eeddd9a4c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Case management study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Dignity for Detained Immigrants Act</short-title>, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall conduct a study to examine best practices of government-funded case management and related services, including exploring the feasibility of the Department of Homeland Security funding case management services.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b58cec2a9c04b3f88e7ae9aa1132849"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contracts</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id16E33953534A405686D1BE669EF8ED42"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may enter into 1 or more contracts to operate the case management program established pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id26E17EBD318241AEB3360EBA2991C036"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>In entering into a contract under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall give priority to direct contracts with qualified nongovernmental, community-based organizations that have experience providing services to immigrant, refugee, and asylum-seeking populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H62CC1D552B1242F189B94E798C78891B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Individualized determination required</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7CF6AAC2720240178D23C7F32C369120"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining whether to order an alien to participate in a case management program under this subsection, the Secretary of Homeland Security or the immigration judge, as appropriate, shall make an individualized determination to determine the appropriate level of supervision for the alien.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD85F11ADDD934B2B94AEF91751293EEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Participation in a case management program under this subsection may not be ordered for an alien for whom it is determined that release on reasonable bond or recognizance will reasonably ensure the appearance of the alien as required and the safety of any other person and the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H047EA0CC37B34F4291F8D660CD7A08D6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition on fees for alternatives to detention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien who is required to participate in a specific alternatives to detention program or service may not be charged a fee for such participation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idD79311F536764485AA21865E06238D7A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Case management review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Dignity for Detained Immigrants Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall conduct a review of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id969CB205F7174D93803A5C4073A12B84"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">best practices in federally funded case management programs; and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id0CC85BBA25B0467490D29E02CED757F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the feasibility of transferring alternatives to detention case management programs out of the purview of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDC482842A64B4FC4B8D1D659224C5F57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Probable cause hearing</header><text>Section 287(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the subsection designation and all that follows through the end of paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8e9915db08e64f65800640a506bff894"><subsection id="id06C8530C803D4F80BF2044BA3DBE1DEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any officer or employee of the Department of Homeland Security who is authorized, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall have power, without warrant—</text><paragraph id="id0E9C2CF1665B445790474825F693D736"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to interrogate any alien or person believed to be an alien as to the person’s right to be or to remain in the United States, provided that such interrogation is not based on the person’s race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, sexual orientation, color, spoken language, or English language proficiency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id933268082ff444a4b822608b24f7bfce"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to arrest any alien who, in the presence or view of the officer or employee, is entering or attempting to enter the United States in violation of any law or regulation made pursuant to law regulating the admission, exclusion, expulsion, or removal of aliens, or to arrest any alien in the United States, if—</text><subparagraph id="id7523359981d84cd0968a340db2f988e2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the officer or employee has probable cause to believe that—</text><clause id="id540B65107EA5451B8AAD00D43304E3B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alien is in the United States in violation of any such law or regulation; and</text></clause><clause id="idE9E86AE56DB94C8C8D6ADD75634E7F5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is likely to escape before a warrant can be obtained for the arrest of the alien;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idddf266ba9b214fdabf3aae98fcb951cb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the officer or employee has reason to believe the alien would knowingly and willfully fail to appear in immigration court in response to a properly served notice to appear; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe9aed39a3a94ed5a350461d3e35cb0f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not later than 48 hours after being taken into custody, the alien is provided with a hearing before an immigration judge to determine whether there was probable cause for such arrest, including probable cause to believe the alien would have knowingly and willfully failed to appear as required under subparagraph (B) if the alien had not been arrested, which burden to establish probable cause shall be on the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7D25F533FDDB4919887A0D964C710BC5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mandatory detention repealed</header><paragraph id="id0BF805B9F2E043E3B3629F5A78A8ED15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H446834FEA4704D0AB7666E0FED8B207B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 235(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1225">8 U.S.C. 1225(b)</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="H72060B6E02064D0CB9D6999E3812C4F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1)(B)—</text><subclause id="H223C3B96D3F444A7BF0CAB3032A62934"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), by striking <quote>detained</quote> and inserting <quote>referred</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8C7279624750412CA5F777F3CD2CCF33"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iii), by striking subclause (IV); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9CA3BE32308B4BF0862FAA5AD903BAF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>detained</quote> and inserting <quote>referred</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EDF3810BF5041F0828FEFBD9F774DC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking section 236A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1226a">8 U.S.C. 1226a</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46C653197D2040F891126C568D9745B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 238(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1228">8 U.S.C. 1228(a)(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>pursuant to section 236(c),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD035C12EE3C74D9FB714CEEF75E2A04A"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>in section 506(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1536">8 U.S.C. 1536(a)(2)</external-xref>)—</text>
                        <clause id="H124DA115EAF84C28BA0CDBD8103F2973">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>by amending the paragraph heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Release hearing for aliens detained</header-in-text></quote>; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H37874D962AE84CBDBDBC2176EF59F716">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> <subclause id="id8CFF047A045B4539A24B8D5A87860B4A"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>by amending the subparagraph heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text></quote>;</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HB0B36055263040D68F2E229CA9C5A7A2">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</quote>;</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HB6750D50B81F412C869A13564EFCA8CF">
                                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>by striking clause (i); and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H7FAD661578A245F880DE73DDD531E03C"> <enum>(IV)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating clauses (ii) and (iii) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively.</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id31966A3B57164D1984098CE918F9B3AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph id="id90B4DF6FF33F4182B7E2DC210707283D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by striking the item relating to section 236A.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5C18885AED3241AF95FE6A12E45428B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Technical amendments</header><text>Section 241(c)(3)(A)(ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(c)(3)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="idCE4BF075976043638FC95E4CC400CCF4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking the comma at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="idCFE028A40D0D4B8D8695CD7B409CAAB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (II), by striking <quote>, or</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCC59129FC1CE4087A1D0F4758191C55D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking subclause (III).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF798E19866CC4D71B05FE420F09D49EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Aliens ordered removed</header><paragraph id="idA7DE001D5D9D40158D5ED6EFD4EAFD9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 241(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1231">8 U.S.C. 1231(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H082FF0A986DD43079B9A6D4B19F71D0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>90 days</quote> each place such phrase appears and inserting <quote>60 days</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B9611B9C23047678677BAC2286DEA81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB62AB368DF344E7A7CD3CE0ABF77417"><paragraph id="H6AEE7BA6A8954FB0ADC9A57216828A86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial custody redetermination hearing</header><subparagraph id="HBBC1D79E319C46D5BDFB41A621B059ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 72 hours after the entry of a final administrative order of removal, the alien ordered removed shall be provided with a custody redetermination hearing before an immigration judge.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5375B491A5E244FCBD340220A1BD45D0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Presumption of detention</header><text>For purposes of the hearing required under subparagraph (A), the alien shall be detained during the removal period unless the alien demonstrates by the preponderance of the evidence that—</text><clause id="id0B13F26E78D84FF699B941C55F97605C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alien’s removal is not reasonably foreseeable; or</text></clause><clause id="id40C680E9C17D413792CFC78A6D60F677"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alien does not pose a risk to the safety of any individual or the community.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BEA60DD8853481DA6ABB77B8894C324"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><clause id="HF546EC3634534616AAC937DC5DABF981"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">90-day</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">60-day</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HB907E44D2E724A14A1D564AEFD5EBA11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>the alien, pending removal, shall be subject to supervision under</quote> and inserting <quote>except as provided in paragraph (6), any alien who has been detained during the removal period shall be released from custody, pending removal, subject to individualized supervision requirements in accordance with</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8474CD09C2A4457AA5BF58459805928"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (6) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC043EB7285FA40D888748C49F3EFB804"><paragraph id="HAF1AE1EE93ED4C3D810D013152358501"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Subsequent custody redetermination hearings</header><subparagraph id="H76372E78283546A6880EE7A2F1099A1E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may request a subsequent redetermination hearing before an immigration judge seeking continued detention for an alien ordered to be detained pursuant to paragraph (2) who was not removed during the removal period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97F17B3F809945A98B278FC914489677"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Standard</header><text>An alien may only be detained after the removal period upon a showing by the Secretary of Homeland Security that—</text><clause id="H1FEC302A59AC43BABE4DDBFC7D992017"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the alien’s removal is reasonably foreseeable; or</text></clause><clause id="H6B8F2944496F4147AA3486950202F6EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alien poses a risk to the safety of an individual or the community, which—</text><subclause id="id8C16B803E8684C26BB31578C6DAE3AF7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>may only be established based on credible and individualized information; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idEEBEF10527A943CDB3FB9DB899E7CF61"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may not be established based solely on the fact that the alien has been charged with, or is suspected of, a crime.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AEDAF5CEFA741048FC05542CD836F6D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Period of detention</header><clause id="id58BB053F40DD44308978F8949CC1043A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien may not be detained pursuant to an order under this paragraph for longer than 60 days. </text></clause><clause id="idFD94743A75004A379941682D45376B6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent redetermination hearing</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may seek subsequent redetermination hearings under this paragraph in order to continue detaining an alien beyond each such 60-day period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H101E6B4131FD4CB9BE3E3E1DC6B1BC2F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (7).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE234836DCC5246D0A1F03BF95FE704D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="id0E73FF657F8C415A876E149FA3574B37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 238 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1228">8 U.S.C. 1228</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="idF5A5238B86CF42D091FD330628FA165E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8BA31A521DA148218155D2EB78117788"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ID03BA43CF81E5401D823B9BDE0978FF32"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall provide for the availability of special removal proceedings at certain Federal, State, and local correctional facilities for aliens convicted of any criminal offense described in subparagraphs (A)(iii), (B), (C), or (D), of section 237(a)(2), or any offense described in section 237(a)(2)(A)(ii) for which both predicate offenses are, without regard to the date of their commission, otherwise described in section 237(a)(2)(A)(i). Such proceedings shall be conducted in conformity with section 240 (except as otherwise provided under this section), and in a manner which eliminates the need for additional detention at any processing center of the Department of Homeland Security and in a manner that ensures expeditious removal following the end of the alien's incarceration for the underlying sentence. Nothing in this section may be construed to create any substantive or procedural right or benefit that is legally enforceable by any party against the United States or its agencies or officers or any other person.</text>
 </paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="idEC6E8FABC7AF4BB7930B5969A18AC58D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating the second subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc73efdb6d1324d0893b8d6bbb968d0f3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as redesignated—</text><subclause id="id19FC041472B94E90AA02E0A94E878FD8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by striking <quote>section 241(a)(2)(A)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 237(a)(2)(A)</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idC18161646400443F8DD2034F93D27469"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>section 241(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 237(a)</quote>;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5CF561E615F34ADD9588C0F239C5B0B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 276(b)(4) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1326">8 U.S.C. 1326(b)(4)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 241(a)(4)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 237(a)(4)(B)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E8A9D5EB129419CB33E12DACDC8524C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 501(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1531">8 U.S.C. 1531(1)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 241(a)(4)(B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 237(a)(4)(B)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id6AB378316F884D7F9E959D5062EADB11"><enum>10.</enum><header>Prohibition on solitary confinement</header><subsection id="id545D7B11091844F8971AA2AE86429C17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual in the custody of the Department may not be placed in solitary confinement.</text></subsection><subsection id="id301603CA988747FDB34308628BB17188"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this section, the term <term>solitary confinement</term>—</text><paragraph id="id5CF0BCB780E44CBD8E43DDC925BA74D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means the confinement of an individual to the individual’s cell, alone or with a cellmate, whether pursuant to disciplinary, administrative, or classification action; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA1F3DF2DCEF64739A0E315FE4927A0DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include the confinement of an individual to such individual's assigned cell during designated sleeping time.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc082fb6d05949a6a85b10a60dcca148"><enum>11.</enum><header>Legal orientation</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfb600f5033434843b1213a11bff4ee4b"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Program</header> <text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that each facility used to detain aliens provides each alien detained in such facility with access to the Legal Orientation Program (or any successor program), whether or not such facility is owned by the Department. Such program shall be operated by a nonprofit, nongovernmental organization with demonstrated immigration law expertise.</text>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0532a505e16421fabd172a1ad2d760b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Orientation</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that each alien described in subsection (a) receives the legal orientation required under such subsection, which may be provided in a group setting, as soon as practicable after entering the detention facility, which orientation may not be delayed until after the initial hearing before an immigration judge.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd5a21d9061fd420c96bdcf047b7a5626"><enum>12.</enum><header>Access to counsel</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall permit an alien who has obtained counsel in accordance with section 292 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1362">8 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>) to access such counsel, including through confidential contact with such counsel through in person, telephonic, or televideo meetings.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idf4080d71f4424906b6653f5de778a8d5"><enum>13.</enum><header>Congressional oversight</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b18c57b02674647a960a8722da551d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Defined term</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered person</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d12d6c004e945a8a53d5d4bf6ca872a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Member of Congress; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf92c151b10ee471f87013ce1b4c54235"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an employee of the Senate or the House of Representatives designated by a Member of Congress for the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bb005eda85444a084a96ebe0357d882"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68e1b878f1a24d788cd2b64d75b345a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall permit a covered person to enter, for the purpose of conducting oversight, any facility operated by or for the Department to detain or otherwise house aliens for any period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idba16017b1f764044b5237bed1f0b033f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not make any temporary modification at any such facility that alters what is observed by a visiting covered person, compared to what would be observed in the absence of such modification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e463c7fdd904ae1a2c10696c874f874"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No advance notice for covered persons</header><text>A Member of Congress may not be required to provide advance notice of his or her intent to enter a facility described in subsection (b)(1) for the purpose of conducting oversight.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc6035f8c2ea4a6b9354cc1c2294729e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice for employees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id856ed3a93a9e4593b17eaeb6e8cb7c15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employees not accompanying a covered person</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Homeland Security may require a covered person described in subsection (a)(2) to provide notice to the operator of a facility described in subsection (b)(1) at least 24 hours in advance of the entry of such covered person if he or she is not accompanied by a Member of Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85df7337b4cb471680256afb35c9037b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employees accompanying a covered person</header><text>The notice required under paragraph (1) shall not be required for a covered person described in subsection (a)(2) who is accompanied by a Member of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

