<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL25859-8M6-34-P2D"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3425 IS: Ranked Choice Voting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3425</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the use of ranked choice voting in elections for the offices of Senator and Representative in Congress, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260"><section section-type="section-one" id="H7ED262116170452F8085E6F6F5B355F7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; finding of constitutional authority</header><subsection id="H400555DC05C7457C96A5527E5CC4269D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ranked Choice Voting Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H35C91814A55E493EB0371274E596799B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Finding of constitutional authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that it has the authority to establish the terms and conditions States must follow in administering elections for the offices of Senators and Representatives in Congress because the authority granted to Congress under section 4 of article I of the Constitution of the United States gives Congress the power to enact laws governing the time, place, and manner of elections for such offices.</text></subsection></section><section id="H46010F5BE07F4DEAA60CF15BBFA45CD3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring ranked choice voting for election of Senators and Representatives</header><subsection id="H2F76B4A5CD594C30BF63C6075E26547A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title III of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21081">52 U.S.C. 21081 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H120717AABA8F4C41A18BF7F7125F77F8"><subtitle id="H559E266FD2A940CEB865598199AF3F2B"><enum>C</enum><header>Ranked Choice Voting</header><part id="H68E77FED26C748AC86D08513745FD371"><enum>1</enum><header>Requiring Ranked Choice Voting for Election of Senators and Representatives</header><section id="H5592BD1020404FD994CA964DDCD34C3E"><enum>321.</enum><header>Requiring ranked choice voting for election of Senators and Representatives</header><subsection id="HAA54A6291048415FB5A197A9100A9077"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ranked choice voting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State shall carry out elections for the office of Senator and the office of Representative in Congress, including primary, special, and general elections for such office, using ranked choice voting, a system under which each voter may rank the candidates for the office in the order of the voter’s preference, and ballots are tabulated, in accordance with this title.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF03F8BA9E7DE4BEFA072DC9140FC7A34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ballot design</header><paragraph id="H65B5195C6B854B9A8132310AA697DA93"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State shall ensure that the ballot used in a ranked choice voting election under this subtitle meets each of the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H2299EE0CA9BE4DBBBA1417D5D5C15636"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The ballot shall allow voters to rank candidates in order of choice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AD89BF824144388875CFF55A7F9CD19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of candidates whom a voter may rank in the election, as determined under paragraph (2), shall be uniform for all voters in the election within the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF2BF041591D46A28F23A9A2EA714BD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The ballot shall include all qualified candidates for the election and (to the extent permitted under State law) options for voters to select write-in candidates.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDED3CFEBDEB7438FB46C573C82B5F345"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ballot shall include such instructions as necessary to accurately inform the voter how to properly rank candidates and successfully cast the ballot under the system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D620321B791418FAF7F1F177AC136DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of number of candidates voter may rank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ballot shall permit voters to rank at least five candidates or the number of candidates in the election, including write-in candidates (to the extent permitted under State law), whichever is fewer.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5157FAD1656149189357628C63B6E86B"><enum>322.</enum><header>Prohibiting additional runoff elections</header><subsection id="H1C77EF75BB18428D9B7ED45C23143757"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Primary elections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State may hold a separate runoff primary election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress after the date established under State law for the primary election for such office.</text></subsection><subsection id="H64C47338097A4E30A87AE5A6CA23FB1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>General elections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State may hold a separate runoff general election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress after the date established under section 25 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/7">2 U.S.C. 7</external-xref>) for the regularly scheduled general election for such office.</text></subsection><subsection id="H50AB2F30BD724085BDAE7D8416F9DE7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special elections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State may hold a separate runoff special election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress after the date established under State law for such special election for such office.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF87AF672ED1045158D8330E50E3536A1"><enum>323.</enum><header>Treatment of primary elections</header><subsection id="HB86B4BB7EEF94665BE1DD311706871A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditions for holding nonpartisan blanket primary elections</header><text>A State may hold a nonpartisan blanket primary election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress only if State law provides that at least 3 candidates advance to the subsequent general election.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE59DADAFB6C846E581704BAD6A6E9B98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall be construed to require a State to hold a primary election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress prior to the date established under section 25 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/7">2 U.S.C. 7</external-xref>) for the regularly scheduled general election for such office, so long as the determination of the candidates who are elected to such office is based solely on the votes cast with respect to the election held on such date, as determined in accordance with the system of ranked choice voting under this title.</text></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H8158797A2516466999BA6FA1C9DEA5B3"><enum>324.</enum><header>Application to District of Columbia and territories</header><subsection id="H8F81C5045C5D45A091D718B7541F50AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Election of delegates and resident commissioner</header><text>In this subtitle, the term <term>Representative</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H57629B1B322840FFB18B4B0874ABC2FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to Northern Mariana Islands</header><text>This subtitle shall apply with respect to the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in the same manner as this subtitle applies to a State.</text></subsection></section></part><part id="HD8E2917F582948FE8880979193E92BC4"><enum>2</enum><header>Tabulation Process</header><section id="HBF98818D294041F8ABBE4A8A737A9BB5"><enum>331.</enum><header>Tabulation process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 332, tabulation shall proceed in the following manner:</text><paragraph id="H5C01A60F01C6429281952C9EE0BF1E8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Process for tabulation</header><text>Each ballot cast in the election shall count as one vote for the highest-ranked active candidate on the ballot. Tabulation shall proceed in rounds as described in paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37E2EBE028DA4DCA8F4E8B9FF841EA13"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elimination of candidates during tabulation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there are more than 2 active candidates in a round of tabulation, the active candidate with the fewest votes is eliminated, each vote cast on a ballot for the eliminated candidate shall be counted for the next-ranked active candidate on the ballot, and a new round shall begin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F80A99C02BD4A26937F02A699EED956"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Completion of tabulation; election of candidate</header><text>When there are two or fewer active candidates—</text><subparagraph id="H7D5A4068E7834B79BB399970F21D23E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tabulation is complete; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF726D1E3264D4104A7DE1999B2565B72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the candidate receiving the greatest number of votes shall be elected to the office of Senator or Representative in Congress (or, in the case of a primary election, shall advance to the general election for such office as provided under the law of the State involved).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34D27A8023264EC39A15404167D1CD66"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of certain ballots</header><subparagraph id="H3B4C4EE250C148F98F724B94EFC558D2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Treatment of undervotes</header><clause id="HC75A36D2C5F44DE1BF0797B7B46BFD3F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A ballot which is an undervote shall not be counted in any round of tabulation of ballots in an election under this section.</text></clause><clause id="H45DD0E95BC7B40E88B710EBA27850E3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Undervote defined</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, an <quote>undervote</quote> is a ballot for which the voter does not rank any of the candidates in the election.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F069AB6688D4CF2A92748FBDD6A359C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of inactive ballots</header><clause id="HF8FADB33020B469E9B83BAC66A47A8C8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A ballot which becomes an inactive ballot shall no longer count for any candidate for the remainder of the tabulation of ballots in an election under this section after the ballot becomes inactive.</text></clause><clause id="HBD7CF2590FF7468F8B92FBB075BE881F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inactive ballot defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, an <quote>inactive ballot</quote> is a ballot on which—</text><subclause id="H03E8AAE3E4934820A6CA7ACDDE9EB34A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all of the ranked candidates on the ballot have become inactive; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1FE80C1BD6AE4983B00836A4C0F938A9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the voter ranks more than one candidate at the same ranking and all candidates at a higher ranking have become inactive.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CC779A5E2C545E78B858CE0498D49C4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of skipped or repeated rankings</header><clause id="H2C50915C803A482E924866A241626537"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A ballot which includes any skipped or repeated ranking shall remain active and continue to be counted for the highest ranked active candidate in an election under this section.</text></clause><clause id="HBE30F4175E8E466FAFE929EDBDAF09F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Skipped and repeated rankings defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text><subclause id="HEC6E9BF93AF645E3B727C22A561C6580"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a <quote>skipped ranking</quote> is a ranking a voter does not assign to any candidate while assigning a subsequent ranking to a candidate; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H940F98F9177D401FA4FC8E35F5208412"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a <quote>repeated ranking</quote> is a ranking for which the voter has assigned the same candidate that the voter assigned to another ranking.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HB40D39D5FB1D49F9B56CA87FF90B4165"><enum>332.</enum><header>Special rules for nonpartisan blanket primary elections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of a nonpartisan blanket primary election, tabulation shall proceed in the following manner:</text><paragraph id="H80D98CCFB7FA4F109981635BAE0979F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Process for tabulation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a nonpartisan primary election—</text><subparagraph id="H4DC50AF76A93467EB970452B92C06EBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each ballot cast in the election shall count as one vote for the highest ranked active candidate on that ballot; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AF9F2B58E154F0CA1E05DB7BBCA22CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tabulation shall proceed in rounds as described in paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8606E3D5A4184F2CA0F9DA4254D430A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elimination of candidates during tabulation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the number of active candidates is greater than the number of candidates to be advanced to the general election, as provided under the law of the State involved, the active candidate with the fewest votes is eliminated, and votes for the eliminated candidate are counted for each ballot’s next-ranked active candidate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E3B54AC01804714BF3FAA287C0A385C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Completion of tabulation; advancing of candidates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the total number of active candidates is equal to or less than the number of candidates to be advanced to the general election, as provided under the law of the State involved—</text><subparagraph id="H84393ED02B2643D09411BA56F781E05B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tabulation is complete; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B1F984C5BD3408BAC604F45B30B89CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all active candidates shall advance to the general election for such office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H5E03423E46B7444CBFA94B2CEE45036E"><enum>333.</enum><header>Treatment of ties between candidates</header><subsection id="H9543D5E38D3E40BE97F5D8F400403A70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Resolution by lot</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a tie occurs between candidates with the greatest number of votes or the fewest number of votes at any point in the tabulation of ballots under this part and the tabulation cannot proceed until the tie is resolved, the tie shall be resolved by lot or by such other method as may be provided under State law, provided that any tie between candidates with the fewest number of votes shall be resolved on the same day as tabulation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2EF6B05EECB644CBA3BB20214BEC4855"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Resolution prior to tabulation</header><text>Prior to tabulation, the chief election official of the State may resolve prospective ties between candidates by lot or according to the method provided under State law, as described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCD26143A1E3C4F5387EE71FA3EE62F12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use during recount</header><text>The result of the resolution of any tie shall be recorded and reused for purposes of any recount under State law.</text></subsection></section><section id="H47FFCCC41C1548E5BC1D892F2671C4FF"><enum>334.</enum><header>Determination of votes cast for candidates of political parties for purposes of access to ballot in Federal elections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the extent that a State takes into account the number of votes cast in an election for candidates of a political party in determining the right of candidates of the party to appear on the ballot in subsequent elections for Federal office in the State, the State shall determine the number of votes cast for a candidate on the basis of whichever round of tabulation of ballots in the election under section 331 or section 332 contained the highest number of votes for that candidate.</text></section></part><part id="HD36DB7D3EFE7429B8F04023483FE6CBC"><enum>3</enum><header>Payments to States To Implement Ranked Choice Voting</header><section id="HEAB22A2E87F4414CBD492DC125F4D4C0"><enum>341.</enum><header>Payments to States to implement ranked choice voting</header><subsection id="H0A577C82C9CB44A3A897368BBE22F88D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payments described</header><paragraph id="H35751D4B80DA4B85B985D03DA299892F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 1, 2026, the Commission shall make a payment to each State in the amount determined with respect to the State under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F747644905D471C842DD31D592ED941"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount determined on basis of number of registered voters</header><subparagraph id="HFE6B7A3697E3471F8F607D870CEDC6AA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount determined under this paragraph is the product of—</text><clause id="H665EE2F4D86542079BAF496DC3284D67"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals registered to vote in elections for Federal office in the State, based on the most recently available information on voter registration in the State, as provided to the Commission by the State; and</text></clause><clause id="HAB9109D39E074CA59967A82EDFCD3236"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the per capita amount established by the Commission under subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F5AB6F3CD044F629E7845D3C935C804"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Per capita amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the Commission shall establish a separate, appropriate per capita payment amount for each State that may be not less than $4 and not more than $8, taking into account any reasonable demonstrated or estimated costs associated with the use of ranked choice voting, including costs related to—</text><clause id="H7CD7FB80FE6F41D6A07EE0607B0FDC70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>voting equipment updates;</text></clause><clause id="H629754B27D254AB99737E37CDA6293EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>election software updates or licenses;</text></clause><clause id="H5DFCCD8A111649EE83FFA4C7FA748F28"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>voting system programming;</text></clause><clause id="HD8091DF58EE048DD8A63298F13D7F33F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>ballot design and printing;</text></clause><clause id="H1EC4A42550804C5193616257C4575C21"><enum>(v)</enum><text>election official and poll worker training;</text></clause><clause id="H35C8A4303199423DB5A3329FAAC5868A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>processing, canvassing, centralization, and tabulation;</text></clause><clause id="H0479DF8669ED4F82BF8E0CBA70E09FEC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>reporting and displaying preliminary and final election results;</text></clause><clause id="H7B51754CB05E41A7B3F7C7843FEBFD7D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>post-election audits and recounts; and</text></clause><clause id="HD0EA89D7289241F59AEAE612CC6E72AB"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>voter information, education, and engagement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB771D623012646BDB631F8170198F188"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State shall use the payment made under subsection (a) to implement ranked choice voting under this subtitle, including educating voters about ranked choice voting.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD890365BB4534A5E901D1A82041F2844"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for payments under this section.</text></subsection></section></part><part id="HD0862B4D74E74A4BA6F974C0FD90AA5D"><enum>4</enum><header>Civil enforcement</header><section id="H195E5E65035246B0ADAD8A5365DAF084"><enum>351.</enum><header>Civil enforcement</header><subsection id="H51302908744F4028A27E017937A38BFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil Enforcement</header><paragraph id="HAAFDDC1EE68F4B22921AD5EBD371CC8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions by Attorney General</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action for such relief as may be appropriate to carry out this subtitle.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DDE71FDD6914C0DA9C45F9D961885C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of private right of action</header><subparagraph id="H9513E57B80E94834BB7B47F3B235D42E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any person residing or domiciled in a State who is aggrieved by the failure of the State to meet the requirements of this subtitle may bring a civil action in the United States district court for the applicable venue for such relief as may be appropriate to remedy the failure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EE6B552319E40CBA5BDFAC62F7E24A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No awarding of damages to prevailing party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except for an award of attorney’s fees under subsection (d), a court in a civil action under this subtitle shall not award the prevailing party any monetary damages, compensatory, punitive, or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53AB000009FA4364B467D7FFB6028858"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Delivery of complaint to House and Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action brought under this subtitle, a copy of the complaint shall be delivered promptly to the Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FCDD456CB2E429780F3B68CED6CC4C4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusive jurisdiction and applicable venue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction to hear and determine claims arising under this subtitle. The applicable venue for such an action shall be the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or the judicial district in which the capital of the State is located, as selected by the person bringing the action. In a civil action that includes a claim under this subtitle, with respect to an election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress held in a State, the United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall have jurisdiction over any defendant who has been served in any United States judicial district in which the defendant resides, is found, or has an agent, or in the United States judicial district in which the capital of the State is located. Process may be served in any United States judicial district where a defendant resides, is found, or has an agent, or in the United States judicial district in which the capital of the State is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C5A61C6E1E9427EB0C4551EA0D52D20"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of 3-judge court</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any action arising under this subtitle shall be heard by a 3-judge district court convened pursuant to section 2284 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2879AB9FE944AEDB6A343F503A0B505"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Review of final decision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A final decision in an action brought under this section shall be reviewable on appeal by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, which shall hear the matter sitting en banc. There shall be no right of appeal in such proceedings to any other court of appeals. Such appeal shall be taken by the filing of a notice of appeal within 10 days of the entry of the final decision. A final decision by the Court of Appeals may be reviewed by the Supreme Court of the United States by writ of certiorari.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H453EFB3A91994681AAC65A815A0D04CC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expedited Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action brought under this section, it shall be the duty of the district court, the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, and the Supreme Court of the United States (if it chooses to hear the action) to advance on the docket and to expedite to the greatest possible extent the disposition of the action and appeal.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4E1D216C0B4041DD81B29454EED189CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule in case final adjudication not expected within 3 months of election</header><paragraph id="HA15C82232F5A423FA34D69E261E523C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duty of court</header><text>If final adjudication of an action under this subtitle is not reasonably expected to be completed at least 3 months prior to the next regularly scheduled primary election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress in the State, the district court shall order adjustments to the timing of the primary election and other related deadlines, as needed, to allow sufficient opportunity for adjudication of the matter in time for the next regularly scheduled general election for such office in the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D014692CA4F4CCDA8D3DEC9FECECF0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibiting failure to act on grounds of pendency of election</header><text>The court may not refuse to take any action described in paragraph (1) on the grounds of the pendency of the next election held in the State or the potential for disruption, confusion, or additional burdens with respect to the administration of the election in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34DECFB993BA49D394061D6B98BB846D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Attorney’s Fees</header><text>In a civil action under this section, the court may allow the prevailing party (other than the United States) reasonable attorney fees, including litigation expenses, and costs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H19D3E158DF384A288A22BBBBF442B519"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relation to other laws</header><paragraph id="H21DAB852EE0F4D4C92D58F8032D48DFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rights and remedies additional to other rights and remedies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rights and remedies established by this section are in addition to all other rights and remedies provided by law, and neither the rights and remedies established by this section nor any other provision of this title shall supersede, restrict, or limit the application of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3D85B02ABDB4406AFD65698E7D0A967"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Voting Rights Act of 1965</header><text>Nothing in this title authorizes or requires conduct that is prohibited by the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34F196B6B19C488F8CAF245D10458912"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Legislative privilege</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person, legislature, or State may claim legislative privilege under either State or Federal law in a civil action brought under this section or in any other legal challenge, under either State or Federal law, to laws and procedures enacted under this subtitle.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFDB12E20A7E14061AFAE73DB5AD70E14"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Removal</header><paragraph id="H1195AE90B60E469FA77A67FBDB1FB09B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At any time, a civil action brought in a State court which asserts a claim for which the district courts of the United States have exclusive jurisdiction under this subtitle may be removed by any party in the case, including an intervenor, by filing, in the district court for an applicable venue under this section, a notice of removal signed pursuant to Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure containing a short and plain statement of the grounds for removal. Consent of parties shall not be required for removal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB26B2915F69344D391EE8BB08B97726F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Claims not within the original or supplemental jurisdiction</header><text>If a civil action removed in accordance with paragraph (1) contains claims not within the original or supplemental jurisdiction of the district court, the district court shall sever all such claims and remand them to the State court from which the action was removed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></part><part id="HA3A539087B864322B4AB67D671804382"><enum>5</enum><header>Definitions</header><section id="HEA89F19543A340C08F56D6411E5489F8"><enum>361.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subtitle, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H53B59D716301401B9A59366268E93AE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active candidate</header><text>The term <term>active candidate</term> means, with respect to any round of tabulation under this subtitle, a candidate who has not been eliminated, and who is not a withdrawn candidate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H157839C571D4496AB9EF9AC45D1DA39B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Highest-ranked active candidate</header><text>The term <term>highest-ranked active candidate</term> means the active candidate assigned to a higher ranking than any other active candidate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCA55AB560DE4509932D8081FFE213F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonpartisan blanket primary election</header><text>The term <term>nonpartisan blanket primary election</term> means a single, open primary election for the office of Senator or the office of Representative in Congress in which all candidates for the office are listed on the same primary election ballot, regardless of political party affiliation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H592E4A88AC564586B0A5F1761C3AF4A8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ranking</header><text>The term <term>ranking</term> means the number available to be assigned by a voter to a candidate to express the voter’s choice for that candidate, with <quote>1</quote> as the highest ranking and each succeeding positive number as the next highest ranking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01D448E990C34E96A11E7C4384DDC92F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Withdrawn candidate</header><text>The term <term>withdrawn candidate</term> means a candidate who, prior to the date of the election, files or has an authorized designee file a signed letter of withdrawal from the election, in accordance with such rules as the chief election official of the State may establish.</text></paragraph></section></part></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H56E0FFFB570345D1BC99C4ED1C6F1353"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to applicability of enforcement provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>sections 301, 302, 303, and 304</quote> and inserting <quote>title III</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE18FF46E4A4A4169A77D88D4F7503277"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end of the item relating to title III the following:</text><toc container-level="title-container" quoted-block="yes-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-quoted-entry style="OLC"><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="subtitle">Subtitle C—Ranked Choice Voting</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="part">Part 1—Requiring Ranked Choice Voting for Election of Senators and Representatives</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 321. Requiring ranked choice voting for election of Senators and Representatives.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 322. Providing additional runoff elections.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 323. Treatment of primary elections.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 324. Application to District of Columbia and territories.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="part">Part 2—Tabulation Process</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 331. Tabulation process.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 332. Special rules for nonpartisan blanket primary elections.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 333. Treatment of ties between candidates.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 334. Determination of votes cast for candidates of political parties for purposes of access to ballot in Federal elections.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="part">Part 3—Payments to States To Implement Ranked Choice Voting</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 341. Payments to States to implement ranked choice voting.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="part">Part 4—Civil Enforcement</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 351. Civil enforcement.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="part">Part 5—Definitions</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5505E5D2DFD043048901E322D31A7260" level="section">Sec. 361. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc-quoted-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H7964A9474007491ABACF88E5AED059CB"><enum>3.</enum><header>No effect on elections for State and local office</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or in any amendment made by this Act may be construed to affect the manner in which a State carries out elections for State or local office.</text></section><section id="H8C0E5099DDB64DD5B18C1C7466431992"><enum>4.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act or any amendment made by this Act, or the application of a provision of this Act or an amendment made by this Act to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provisions to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected by the holding.</text></section><section id="H38A4F4FA80794A7C8A0A6B8CBEECCFF8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to elections for Federal office held on or after January 1, 2030.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

