<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26705-708-42-4C4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4696 IS: Right to Record Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish an express cause of action for violations of the right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Right to Record Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd69fa60655e148408499735de0f4d60c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress regarding first amendment and right to record, observe, or peacefully protest</header><subsection id="id35e019321be240e5879a7fed6e8d3833"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="idec0f73c4b9f74ed38903b0e680417e5d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States protects, among other things, the right to record law enforcement officers and other public officials in public view, observe the actions of law enforcement officers and other public officials in public view, protest peacefully, and engage in other expressive activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id709dbdb1a5cf43e38d6fb8553ec537c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>while the First Amendment already protects the right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement, Congress can enhance the remedies available to individuals who are deprived of this right by establishing an express statutory cause of action for such rights violations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2b145c3739af4c1db3bfea4f1c24e19c"> <enum>3.</enum> <header>Right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities</header> <subsection id="id3a6c49634fcd4e48a0e25cef40247626"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Right To record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities</header> <text>A person has the right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities, except in cases described under subsection (c).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id6cb571ccd94a473cad730676ca65c572">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Cause of action</header>
                <paragraph id="id311c97e55cb248af81717b412314ff7c">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>Liability of officers</header>
 <text>Any Federal law enforcement officer who, while acting under color of law, violates a person’s right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities shall be liable to the party injured in a civil action with respect to such violation in the appropriate district court for redress, including an award of the greater of actual damages or statutory damages in the amount of $25,000 for each violation, and punitive damages up to $100,000 for each violation engaged in with malice or reckless disregard for the federally protected rights of the party injured.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idd533ebd9b251466c9fbb68328fabea0d">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Liability of the united states</header>
 <text>If, while acting under color of law, any Federal law enforcement officer violates a person’s right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities, the United States shall be liable to the party injured for the conduct of the officer in a civil action with respect to such violation in the appropriate district court for redress, including the greater of an award of actual damages or statutory damages in the amount of $25,000 for each violation, and punitive damages up to $100,000 for each violation engaged in with malice or reckless disregard for the federally protected rights of the party injured, regardless of whether a policy or custom of the Federal law enforcement agency that employs or contracts with the officer caused the violation, and regardless of whether the officer has any defense or immunity from suit or liability. This paragraph shall constitute a waiver of sovereign immunity with respect to Federal law enforcement agencies for any claim brought under this Act. Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit or preclude any legal, equitable, or other remedy that is available, under this section or under any other source of law, against an individual officer.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="iddf698056bf8f4ae0a3c04c129664dd19">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Violations</header>
 <text>A violation of the right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities includes the following:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id81dac14b5568444f9cf4f5377492b584">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Preventing or attempting to prevent a person from recording, observing, or peacefully protesting law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id15154df8fa7c42b4a20f0ddf2b95c60e">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Threatening, intimidating, or coercing a person with any negative consequences, including the addition of the personal information or biometric characteristics of the person into any database, in response to the person’s recording, observing, or peacefully protesting law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idf9b2ef3103c048fa8cf68cb2a7fcd001">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>Pursuing a person to a different location because the person recorded, observed, or peacefully protested law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idc4c6d554759d41579d4b22945ffc4e6b">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>Attempting to surveil or use surveillance powers to attempt to identify a person in order to intimidate or take other retaliatory action against that person because the person recorded, observed, or peacefully protested law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idb270fe65100d47d7a1b9246a441b1eff">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Commanding that a person cease recording, observing, or peacefully protesting law enforcement activities when the person was not prohibited by law or court order to engage in such activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id055a00b403a748ae9ecd1e244f77d222">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>Stopping, seizing, searching, ticketing, or arresting a person because the person recorded, observed, or peacefully protested law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id5f7b7cbebc764d098578668d1c021f19">
                        <enum>(G)</enum>
 <text>Demanding to see the identification of a person or interrogating or otherwise harassing a person because the person recorded, observed, or peacefully protested law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id10e82d54ecdf4e63aeddd20fdd306f1e">
                        <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>Unlawfully seizing property or instruments used by a person to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="idda016bb4b4f2425baf053341669dd253">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>Unlawfully destroying or seizing a recorded image or recorded images of law enforcement activities, or copying such a recording of law enforcement activities, without the consent of the person who recorded it or without approval from an appropriate court.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id22c2433d46554e68a90450cfe1ef7965">
                        <enum>(J)</enum>
 <text>Otherwise retaliating against a person because the person recorded, observed, or peacefully protested law enforcement activities.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="idfb58fcf89b2147cfa8c0344a5b2b7a7f">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Limitation</header>
                <paragraph id="idedee6d4767f943c7ba48a0a8900be4ca">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a person has no right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities pursuant to subsection (a) if the person physically restricts or restrains an officer taking official actions while acting under color of law.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idabc287154ca645a1901f296bb80a756b">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Exception</header>
 <text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the mere act of recording, observing, or peacefully protesting law enforcement activities, or positioning oneself to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities, even if such action is taken close to, in front of, or near the expected path of an officer acting under color of law.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id3d93648a56ca46cca7ebdd33bac11a6d">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Attorney’s fees and costs</header>
 <text>The court shall award reasonable attorney’s fees and costs to a prevailing plaintiff.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id792e5869d15c4d6a89afa03992d7de68">
                <enum>(e)</enum>
                <header>Training</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the head of each Federal law enforcement agency shall provide to every Federal law enforcement officer training on how to enforce the law while respecting the right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id30dcf26597c344f280ed851c7f0f14c0">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Definitions</header>
 <text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="id18d4a49b291845d4b30c1a0eb0317a7f"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Federal law enforcement agency</header> <text>The term <term>Federal law enforcement agency</term> means any agency of the United States authorized to enforce Federal criminal law or Federal immigration law.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idc23d42a48a9948088e617fe7f45e39f0">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Federal law enforcement officer</header>
 <text>The term <term>Federal law enforcement officer</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="id81931c69c49d4ad79d725c7c99d7def2"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>has the meaning given the term in section 115 of title 18, United States Code; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id8d9a4e6d461c4c779ccde453b10181b7" commented="no"
                        display-inline="no-display-inline">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>includes an immigration officer.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ide0e16f38852445f8bb046a5bdda062a9"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Immigration officer</header> <text>The term <term>immigration officer</term> has the meaning given the term <term>immigration officer</term> in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idd9a990306b1242c4ada3a878d6f56136">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
                    <header>Law enforcement activities</header>
 <text>The term <term>law enforcement activities</term> means the official actions taken in public view by an officer acting under color of law.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="ida58c4717d635483bb28ab4e7638be0a1">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
                    <header>Observe</header>
 <text>The term <term>observe</term> means to watch or otherwise perceive.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="id3bd7f394742e4cf5a84d178e98a7dcc9"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Peacefully protest</header> <text>The term <term>peacefully protest</term> means to engage in constitutionally protected expression or assembly.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id7611bb8bf26e4fcb9a1da9fb90f177e5">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
                    <header>Public view</header>
 <text>The term <term>public view</term> means anything that can be seen from any place where an individual cannot be deemed to be trespassing, including parks, sidewalks, and roads, or a privately owned place where the individual is lawfully present.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id9485f884d3a942a7892d7cf7327667c7">
                    <enum>(8)</enum>
                    <header>Record</header>
 <text>The term <term>record</term> means creating a written, visual, or audio record.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
 </section><section id="id395075982de345288ed922a5850b3b0c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subsection id="id08bbe6976564487c990fd358f397c9a4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Broad construction</header><text>This Act shall be construed in favor of a broad protection of the right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities and the right to access and document information about matters of public interest, to the maximum extent permitted by the terms of this Act and the Constitution of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf28bbcb4e65a4d5eb7cf71babd500aa9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No diminishment of other first amendment rights and remedies</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="idb8cf948440334f1e9589c552adcb55dc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>diminish constitutional and statutory protections for any activity outside the scope of this Act that is otherwise covered by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63903b89377f47d681573fe1c022448c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preclude any cause of action that may arise under the laws of the United States, a State, or a unit of local government for any violation of such First Amendment rights; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89c97c605b0343768dc9d8d16bd07158"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limit or preclude any legal, equitable, or other remedy that is available in any action for any violation of such First Amendment rights.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide7e80daa95dc4a66a68c55c8964d7ffa"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No preclusion of other causes of action</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preclude any other cause of action that may arise under the laws of the United States, a State, or a unit of local government for any violation by an officer acting under color of law of the right to record, observe, or peacefully protest law enforcement activities.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

