<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA6261CC7419246839486AED4CD28FE98" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5830 IH: Guaranteed Income Pilot Program Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5830</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251024">October 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a pilot program providing certain individuals with a guaranteed monthly income, to study the effect of a guaranteed monthly income on such individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H548F1FE85D224335BC28E329CB2553E7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4C210C0C4CAC44569E2D87CE10F69F28" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteed Income Pilot Program Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8F576AD34F044EA4B225210C7E6945AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H6446751B4450413782FB1DE6FC1587B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Too many Americans cannot achieve financial stability due to income volatility, the rising cost of living, wage stagnation, and a lack of affordable housing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A36CDAFCA0144E79CEBDEE7B9182B67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Real wages have failed to keep pace with inflation, meaning the purchasing power of American households has not changed in decades.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEC46C4E51FE74050AF4F831AB156E48A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Income volatility, defined as an annual income fluctuation of 25 percent or more, impacts millions of American households.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF59258F50D4540CC94598620E097C581"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two-thirds of Americans are worried they wouldn’t be able to cover their living expenses for just 1 month if they lose their primary source of income, while 57 percent of American adults are currently unable to cover a $1,000 emergency expense. That percentage is higher for millennials at 79 percent, and Generation Z at 85 percent, unable to cover an emergency expense.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H45160FCF312841978BC4F126487D6EA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Full-time minimum wage earners cannot afford an average 2-bedroom apartment anywhere in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H769A73F0ADFD4708982F4709ADEC429E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The changing nature of the economy, including the rise of the gig economy, unemployment risks posed by automation, and the fluctuating nature of waged labor, will result in increased income volatility and prohibit upward economic mobility.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9EFD3B36A7BA4FBE8AC25AE9FA1FD087"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the height of COVID–19, the Federal Government provided stimulus checks to the American people in response to the economic hardship of the pandemic. The Census Bureau complied an analysis that showed that material hardship in United States households fell sharply following the passage of the COVID–19 relief bill in late December 2020, and the American Rescue Plan in March 2021. From December 2020 to April 2021, food insufficiently fell by over 40 percent, financial instability fell by 45 percent, and reported adverse mental health symptoms fell by 20 percent.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H50DE7A8793154C198D5EB58D22D63D80"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guaranteed income pilot program</header> <subsection id="H6EE59323422D4C6C9850CCA705EC416B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner of Internal Revenue, shall establish and implement a 3-year pilot program (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>program</quote>) to provide a guaranteed monthly income to certain eligible individuals in accordance with this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDBB8C6B2DC08408EA7C29D8B2E0E87D0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Income subsidy</header>
<paragraph id="HC398FBBAC6824DB0B4F43176076AB01C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection of participating eligible individuals</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner and the external partner selected pursuant to subsection (d), shall develop selection criteria that the Secretary will use to select 20,000 total eligible individuals for participation in the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4BEC230C8984F67A983D9FBE41523D7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of income subsidy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the eligible individuals participating in the program, 10,000 shall receive a cash payment each month equal to the fair market rent for a 2-bedroom home in the ZIP Code in which the eligible individual resides, or a substantially similar amount as determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner and the external partner.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H074AEE5249534154A96EC43D72F674D2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monthly distribution of income subsidy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each participating eligible individual shall receive the cash payment on the 15th day of each month.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6CBE32D380E74D74BCD2EB23DEED6CF7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Commissioner of Internal Revenue</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of Internal Revenue shall be responsible for—</text>
<paragraph id="HC5A9E272E02B4B5494C6C5D9C303C97E">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing the Secretary access to tax records to administer and study the program under this section; and</text>
        </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0D5DB111DA1A4F6D9A812E6C67C7A702"><enum>(2)</enum><text>updating the Secretary and the external partner on changes to the taxable income of a participating eligible individual.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEA0A8D5D8D1A437FA3B33975AA69BBED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>External partner</header> <paragraph id="H4B6BFBB6890F4896921630D7A5A7A31D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select an external partner to provide assistance with the design, administration, and evaluation of the program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31DF7124C07D4386BB4F99BC23F6D5A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>An organization selected to be the external partner shall have demonstrated experience in—</text> <subparagraph id="H719D176AA8FC4585865B0EB3DDE5CC0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mixed-methods experimental design; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD9B085D71A874BD3A3AC74702519E979"><enum>(B)</enum><text>implementing cash-transfer programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DBA7E026A054235848BF82D37E43130"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The external partner, and any employee of the external partner, shall be treated as a Federal employee for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8605A1A6E90643C28C8EA38E74841CD9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The external partner shall collect data from participating eligible individuals as necessary to complete the study and reports required under section 4, and to conduct any additional research as the Secretary determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7CA0A520BBDB4CA9A686EF646F2728A6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Disregard of cash payments for purposes of all Federal and Federally assisted programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any payment made to participating eligible individuals under this section shall not be taken into account as income, and shall not be taken into account as resources for a period of 12 months from receipt, for purposes of determining the eligibility of such eligible individual (or any other individual) for benefits or assistance (or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance) under any Federal program or any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H20666285A2D148CD89B17AE32980AD92"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study and report</header>
<subsection id="HDFF75CC2E65545D5812289B99A246DB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study on pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in collaboration with the Commissioner and the external partner, shall conduct a study on outcomes of the program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7F6AA16045754761BACF82E6F18F6FAA" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after participating eligible individuals have been begun participating in the program, the Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner of Internal Revenue and the external partner, shall provide an interim report on the program under section 3 to the Congress.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H9AEEFD2A2D8F451ABDA1473EB519B39E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the conclusion of the program under section 3, the Secretary, in consultation with the Commissioner of Internal Revenue and the external partner, shall provide a final report on the program to the Congress, including—</text> <paragraph id="HA3281161637B49DCB0B097016282BDB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6AE23A3005D440E3AB487A43DC7291AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effect of the monthly income subsidy provided in section 3 on—</text> <clause id="HFCA679DC5B854BC4BC2D19D6A714C4E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>micro-economic outcomes of participating eligible individuals;</text></clause>
<clause id="H45D69FF6BA0B45549D818FEAB9283C5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the health of participating eligible individuals; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3F6B1283F78E4BEC84D331BC8441AFB9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the social costs of income volatility, including connections with income fluctuation and health, housing, education, employment, childcare, and other outcomes as determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFBDE1383502E4FA0AEEF3A0261682BD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the feasibility of expanding the program under section 3 to include a larger number of participants; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D06158E35BA4439BB4F4FC511D74262"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the results of interviews and focus groups conducted with consenting participants of the program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HD3779C2D6FB947DBA3A812ED64C71774" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H6F98A68C38454C85A29776D37A91CBC2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner of the Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65E2B42022A84CFDA52D060E178B424B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual taxpayer between the ages of 18–65.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H347EC68C6DF84B1BA4A5768116845554" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>External partner</header><text>The term <term>external partner</term> means a non-partisan research agency or a non-profit academic institution with expertise in social science experimentation.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC41B74E05D59489881B8F369DE92605B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fair market rent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fair market rent</term> means the applicable fair market rent established under section 8(c) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC14E08FD4B146E1A428DF7EDFBCFEEE" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H8663A94DABCD4693A0BCF2F9A3C22225"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $495,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

