<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4463C3BA272B4820A629FD3B5C19D13E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7380 IH: Internet Reach and Access Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7380</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make certain improvements relating to the coordination of efforts to promote internet freedom and access to information in Iran, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0FC53FB884644151BF8D886E500A2A10" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4C7C95EF8C974D949F70BA80D2CF9DFD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Internet Reach and Access Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IRAN Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H3B4CBC53AFCA4100A9478542585A008B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H50A92FC023624052A4D82A7DFE77E37A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the followings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA0DAD086516349BFBD00D2699BCA8C66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Government of Iran has repeatedly disrupted, throttled, or shut down internet connectivity, impeding the ability of the Iranian people to communicate during emergencies and to exercise internationally recognized human rights.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H810B2762776A4431B7924BC6A6130356"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Satellite-based residential and Direct-to-Cell (DTC) communications, Virtual Private Networks (VPNs), embedded-SIM (eSIM) technology, and other circumvention tools can mitigate those shutdowns, but Iranian users face high costs, sanctions-related equipment barriers, and pervasive digital surveillance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4008C83F07AF4613BA10E98E8342C343"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Clarifying United States policy and supporting secure connectivity tools will materially enhance internet resilience for the people of Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8038E658F0CF47DEB1FBAF6152C3B9FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that United States policy should—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE69303D3F3A641A8BF227C17128198C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote the deployment of DTC communications, VPNs, eSIM technology, and other secure communications tools that enhance open access to the internet in Iran; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC2EB1EB84D249B19B20E36C475B676C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that sanctions and export-control regulations are implemented in a manner that does not unintentionally hinder access to such tools by the Iranian people.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1F29C5F2C5B241518D9A8770385926D8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improved coordination of efforts to promote internet freedom in Iran</header> 
<subsection id="HC0CD6234EA0A4A1CB6EB7DC963646905"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties of the secretary of state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall be the Federal official with primary responsibility for—</text> <paragraph id="HFCBB1602AA4D4C9A923555D570119D71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting widespread internet freedom in Iran and expanding access to information for Iranian citizens;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC82B76CB4434A7B9BE5A9331A24FF7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinating all efforts carried out by Federal departments and agencies that relate to digital‑freedom initiatives in Iran; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE36A9BB69E9842E7BC8AE8CBB30798F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serving as the principal official responsible for updating and carrying out the strategy required under section 414 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97E5281E9F934B7DA16817C3F7A3D239" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates to comprehensive strategy To promote Internet freedom and access to information in Iran</header> 
<paragraph id="HF5BF73ABE50E403B9D17A554E0BD85F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 414 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H0578905861324DDD92AF41B9D3CD8D3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Not later than</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">(<enum-in-header>a</enum-in-header>) Initial strategy.</header-in-text>—Not later than</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4979FF8C8164FB79666E54E7C7A1CEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (11) and (12) as paragraphs (14) and (15), respectively;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA044F53424914DE681DAA1F70BF6E32F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (10) the following new paragraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1FD61DB55D404DAF9D205AE6B017D1B4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H916375DD3CA043CC855FF5DAD304BE52"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the use of virtual private networks and direct-to-cell satellite technologies by civil society and human rights activists in Iran and develop strategies for increasing the accessibility of such networks and technologies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E17A365B5BC483AA39009209ECD6AC4"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Commerce to ensure enforcement of sanctions does not impede companies providing to Iranian civilians the technology and other tools necessary to access the open internet;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EE894FFCAF34AF1A3429AE90A1F08A6"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the ability of the Iranian regime to cut off all access to the internet and develop a strategy to circumvent internet blackouts for Iranian civil society;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D1DB85710F745A7B5A984285CBFBD70"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB929F28CBBB04B4284DEC8DE9D7BD022" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H67F56B8B50A04EA4ACF134A0C78E8A6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies as appropriate shall review the strategy under subsection (a) on an ongoing basis and update the strategy as appropriate, taking into account the results of such review.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4265B88809174B1F8A9D9C6E2430227D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of first updates</header> <subparagraph id="HCC0545A427074875896C1DE96DBE7A73"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall—</text> 
<clause id="H133AE21BED5D4C11A9CF1485A75ADDD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review and update the strategy pursuant to section 414(b) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>), as amended by paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="HD831A8529F2A4F8998D2853B0C0FE1AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit such updated strategy to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB5761361D6B8495ABB966668B27ED87E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H9ABB3D13AD8A4C229E4A8EC30CE255BE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Satellite and Direct‑To‑Cell (DTC) coverage safeguards</header> <subsection id="HFF4BF78755E84BB7AF8CFB0EA493B890"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Non‑Exclusion condition for new licenses</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) shall, as a condition of any license, license modification, or market‑access grant issued on or after the date of enactment of this Act, require that the licensee shall refrain from intentionally disabling, degrading, or geo‑blocking satellite or DTC coverage over the land territory of Iran, except—</text>
                <paragraph id="H754ACC0402C74212863E9CC73EDF805B">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent specifically required by Federal law, an order of the FCC, or an international coordination agreement designed solely to prevent harmful interference; or</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HE2316231948B47E28C1FD94F01AAB463">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for limited periods necessary to mitigate an imminent threat to the integrity or security of the licensee’s network, provided that normal coverage is restored as soon as practicable.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD24858BD743416290762CAB3A671540"><enum>(b)</enum><header>International advocacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce and the FCC, shall oppose at the International Telecommunication Union (ITU) or any successor body any proposal that would compel or encourage geographic exclusion of Iran specifically from satellite or DTC coverage provided by United States–licensed operators.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0BD4D4276E08423E9DC39A93DE3E2397"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H797A0B024B3644679B3039AB3F2F1291"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actions taken pursuant to subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6474E7C6E92B4CB4A8E5D9E3C25C74AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any instances in which a satellite or DTC operator intentionally excluded coverage of Iran and the basis for such exclusion.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4DFAA2DF627E449E81E83291528C15B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Saving clause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="HF78FB1572AE64706831CD29324FCF27F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorize any transaction or service that is prohibited under United States sanctions laws or regulations, including those administered by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C32F45F849B4F088BD297C94BA2DD5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require a licensee to market, sell, activate, or collect payment for services in Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H450183464DFF44F39592A68076161036"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cybersecurity capacity for civil society in Iran</header> <subsection id="H64C5CC4F6960400A889D40E2CE2C39E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training and tools</header><text>The Secretary of State, acting through the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor, shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, establish programs to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H187478A44E3E4B629D093D71291686F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deliver remote or in‑person cybersecurity training to journalists, human‑rights defenders, and civil‑society actors in Iran;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84764B7925CB4CABB90745A93DBD4055"><enum>(2)</enum><text>furnish vetted open‑source or commercially available digital‑safety tools, including VPN services and end‑to‑end encrypted messaging applications; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9712EAFDF2F40B6B947F085104FFB13"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide multilingual educational materials that warn Iranian users about regime‑controlled applications and phishing campaigns.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H62FCE82C252A405F8339DED3CE8AC9B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting and evaluation</header> <paragraph id="HB5786A000FD7475FB3E8AABA19A0C77C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quarterly metrics</header><text>The Secretary of State shall track and, on a quarterly basis, make available to the appropriate congressional committees aggregate metrics on the number of trainees, incident‑response cases, and unique users of supported digital‑safety tools.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1150771C39664D49BFDAA9C4D9B3EDA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independent evaluation</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an evaluation of the effectiveness of the programs carried out under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3CB901128B2C4819BAAE30C5D86E89D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to supersede or limit existing authority under section 404 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>) or any other provision of law related to internet freedom programming in Iran.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1C244B91D340490381EA73476A2EC2AC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="H5F5A76E174B64EB4AD7EE5AAB3698080">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of State $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028 to carry out sections 5 and 6 of this Act, including programs that expand access to secure VPN services for individuals in Iran.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF0BF8C6A6C004E4298E745B932CF0D70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HE9D39E40CCE740EDAFE8B727ED48514F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF6639BAA416E47C1A2A42423AB89F913"><enum>(1)</enum><text>limit the authority of the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EE99858B85A40F98B9EEDC44E3839C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>authorize any transaction prohibited under United States sanctions or export‑control laws; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE41A7276ED6F40F3A14C9938D15E0A7A">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>require any United States person to provide goods, services, or technology in violation of such laws.</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA7F5018556694C3894447C7BE1CBFE6B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H3518116CE07044DBB744D8E52C95E47A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H61CC5386A6F5470C89E3D1E4C01938A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08F01A068E1541E680C73008CEA855B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H691B8FB42E4046818126BEB77BDF4EC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>eSIM technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eSIM technology</term> means embedded subscriber‑identity‑module technology that allows a user to remotely activate cellular service on a compatible device without a physical SIM card.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB5E9D2110BE4307890288AB28ED3F6D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>VPN services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>VPN services</term> means encrypted internet connections designed to bypass a government’s censorship and surveillance, enabling secure and unrestricted access to the open internet.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

