<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI26420-T7K-LK-X2C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4907 IS: Technical Reinvestment and Apprenticeship Development through Endowment Sharing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4907</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the excise tax on investment income of private colleges and universities and provide greater funding to career and technical education.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Technical Reinvestment and Apprenticeship Development through Endowment Sharing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TRADES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id07f6b24661cd483fa9dbffb0d847514e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supporting career and technical education for Americans</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3fd41ff0622e414d9d49f742b8e0c57c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4968">Section 4968(b)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>8 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>15 percent</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida165a1bf57ab4612b5815ec387b54be2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding for Career and Technical Education</header><text>In addition to any other amounts made available to provide assistance to States under title I of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2321">20 U.S.C. 2321 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall, on an annual basis, transfer to such program, from amounts in the general fund of the Treasury of the United States, an amount determined by the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) to be equal to the increase in revenue for the preceding 12-month period by reason of the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd9203a4585549aab16269b935a0810f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date which is 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

