<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8517B4465B044485870688A3B5C06228" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1020 IH: Honoring President Donald J. Trump for securing a historic strategic agreement establishing permanent United States sovereignty and control over critical military installations in Greenland, strengthening Arctic security, and countering malign Russian and Chinese influence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1020</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring President Donald J. Trump for securing a historic strategic agreement establishing permanent United States sovereignty and control over critical military installations in Greenland, strengthening Arctic security, and countering malign Russian and Chinese influence.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Arctic region has emerged as a central theater of great power competition, with Russia and the People’s Republic of China seeking to expand their military, economic, and strategic footprint in the High North;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Greenland occupies one of the most strategically significant geographic positions in the world, serving as a gateway between North America and Europe and a critical node for early-warning systems, missile defense, and Arctic power projection;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas previous administrations failed to adequately address the growing security risks posed by foreign adversaries operating in and around Greenland, leaving the United States and its allies vulnerable to emerging threats in the Arctic domain;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Donald J. Trump demonstrated decisive leadership by pursuing a bold diplomatic strategy to secure permanent United States sovereignty and control over key military bases and defense installations in Greenland, ensuring uninterrupted American operational authority and readiness in the region;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, under the leadership of President Trump, the United States reached a long-term strategic framework with Denmark, Greenland, and North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) allies that respects existing political arrangements while guaranteeing exclusive United States military control over critical installations necessary for national and allied defense;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this historic agreement enhances the ability of the United States to deploy advanced missile defense systems, safeguard Arctic sealanes, and prevent Russia and China from gaining any economic or military foothold in Greenland;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the agreement strengthens NATO’s collective security posture, reinforces transatlantic unity, and ensures that the Arctic remains secure, stable, and free from authoritarian influence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Trump’s leadership avoided armed conflict, preserved alliance cohesion, and delivered lasting security gains through strength-based diplomacy rather than concession or delay; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this achievement represents one of the most significant advancements in United States Arctic and hemispheric defense policy in modern history: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H400322DE5E114044AF484051B0064149"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0108A1AA65B2460CAB2E4E5216596762"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HE66914084BF340219A33A5D83708864F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors President Donald J. Trump for his historic leadership in securing permanent United States sovereignty and control over critical military bases and defense installations in Greenland;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43BAFB4522E74BCD834824A359AF1307"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the strategic importance of Greenland to the national security of the United States and its allies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA43828E0F37644238E237F92E3D49991"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affirms the necessity of maintaining robust American military presence and operational authority in the Arctic to deter aggression by foreign adversaries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C3DF702CE634C7FB09AB7961811793A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends the use of strength, diplomacy, and resolve in advancing United States security interests without the use of force.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

