<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEE38989CB0AA478B838EA5A657304F54" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6234 IH: Baby Bonus Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a baby bonus program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F023536F697427996042BB7DBF4818B" style="OLC"><section id="HFA5A28B2A0094A098965755F2A5575AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Baby Bonus Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1448368F2B6D49EEB3EE96F000EEC3BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the office of baby assistance</header><subsection id="H68AF4B0A6983479DA2A11C44339AD453"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Social Security Administration an office to be known as the Office of Baby Assistance. The Office shall be headed by a Deputy Commissioner appointed by the Commissioner of Social Security.</text></subsection><subsection id="H43602BBBD3CF441CB9A3EAB76D2A9294"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities of deputy commissioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner, acting through the Deputy Commissioner, shall—</text><paragraph id="H75D5DA83F9F94E9299A2469A79D73934"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hire such personnel as are necessary for the Office of Baby Assistance and make employment decisions with regard to such personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8125322FAF794B0B882882E8A172F4D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have the authority to enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with other agencies and departments as are necessary to ensure the efficiency of the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0873367474749ADA5EBF078FB3948CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make baby bonus payments to eligible parents pursuant to <internal-xref idref="HC4A4589764484A76A02C47CFFB9DE8B8" legis-path="3.">section 3</internal-xref>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9225CD2E8A2B4D86B9FCE643415C7DB9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review applications for baby bonus payments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9FF6DC565CA4601AD5BF97DE992975A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish and maintain a system of records relating to the administration of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8598DCF6A524FD1AAFF335EA1E66960"><enum>(6)</enum><text>prevent fraud and abuse relating to baby bonus payments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A6260E15DD34ED79405590EBEF5389E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide information to the public in relation to baby bonus payments, including eligibility requirements, the application process, payment amounts, and limitations on payments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A1BEF65926D45DAA09DB97E4A8FCAAE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>tailor culturally and linguistically competent education and outreach toward increasing utilization rates of baby bonus payments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA7ED12CB6C42799BA3F02BD73E917A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue an annual report to Congress detailing the effect of baby bonus payments, including—</text><subparagraph id="H93328D5FC83541B19AB73607861E05BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of individuals receiving payments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1D988D6AD9C4DDE91B0F915CF69966D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount of funds disbursed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91C4169A24DF48ADA1681C7154A36F6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demographic data of individuals receiving payments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68952F76E34D4EB39DEFE8EFD881246D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other information as the Deputy Commissioner determines is necessary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CA454DA711A4E82A3CEE7D2064B270D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1BAFB89D77946EEA2E198D653B5D60E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of data</header><text>The Commissioner shall make available to the Deputy Commissioner such data as the Commissioner determines necessary to enable the Deputy Commissioner to effectively carry out the responsibilities described in <internal-xref idref="H43602BBBD3CF441CB9A3EAB76D2A9294" legis-path="2.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC4A4589764484A76A02C47CFFB9DE8B8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Baby bonus payments</header><subsection id="H0EEFF80E65FF468585A70B0CF0ADD865"><enum>(a)</enum><header> Baby bonus</header><paragraph id="H55ECBD6A3AD1487F9417D371C141E2FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1st, 2026, and subject to paragraph (2), the Commissioner shall pay, in relation to each qualifying child, a baby bonus to one or more eligible parents of such child in accordance with this section. In the case of multiple qualifying children from a single pregnancy, a separate payment shall be made for each qualifying child.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67F8EA55E6DF4B21827BF0E0A5830594"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application required</header><text>In order to receive a payment under this section, an eligible parent (or an authorized representative described in <internal-xref idref="H38618AF28BCD446E8B9E1158D4DB4501" legis-path="3.(c)(5)">subsection (c)(5)</internal-xref>) of a qualifying child shall submit an application in accordance with <internal-xref idref="HBA363EB10D3F493EB008A4392124C415" legis-path="3.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>. Such application shall be submitted not later than 1 year after—</text><subparagraph id="HB7CC541385104F42B54EB688FAC95967"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the birth of the qualifying child in relation to which such application is submitted; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BE5D1667EE447A1B16F53DC5D637879"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of the death of a fetus or qualifying child as described in subsection (e), the date of such death.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8B990B553364CB1BFDC488738230DCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount</header><subparagraph id="HD6BBD79D7D694E8DA1FD7BBEFB0B95EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of a baby bonus shall be—</text><clause id="HB14DDCE1FFE14B64910B493B593E97CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for calendar year 2026, $2,000; and</text></clause><clause id="HA0F03A1ECA38433C934A52186A1295E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for any calendar year after such year—</text><subclause id="H943051B12A24412FB9D24373C3939D9D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount in <internal-xref idref="HB14DDCE1FFE14B64910B493B593E97CF" legis-path="3.(a)(3)(A)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>, multiplied by</text></subclause><subclause id="H2BAA331357DF4635B570B45FE301046F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1">section 1(f)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>2026</quote> for <quote>2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A5FA7E774D44B3CA7AC264155E884D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>If any amount determined under <internal-xref idref="HD6BBD79D7D694E8DA1FD7BBEFB0B95EC" legis-path="3.(a)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> is not a multiple of $1, such increase shall be rounded to the next lower multiple of $1.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H682D0DC875044075BC7DE6628A94EE64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment</header><paragraph id="H1E176A10551E42BEBBDFEFB15EFD8322"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Date of payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payment shall be made—</text><subparagraph id="HA01EF9107E56425386A065617A9C73E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if no objection is made as described in <internal-xref idref="HBD74798C02DB435D99BCD707F7833A6A" legis-path="3.(b)(3)(A)">paragraph (3)(A)</internal-xref>, during the 6-business day period immediately following the 21-day period beginning on the date on which notice is provided pursuant to such paragraph;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8E28C5587BB4412A0921BC3E00DDD99" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such an objection is raised, during the 6-business day period following the date on which the Commissioner determines which eligible parent is entitled to such money; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EC31E29E98B4A4E9C2D3F106E1535DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the Commissioner determines pursuant to <internal-xref idref="HBD74798C02DB435D99BCD707F7833A6A" legis-path="3.(b)(3)(A)">paragraph (3)(A)</internal-xref> that notice is not necessary, during the 10-business day period beginning on the date on which the application is approved under <internal-xref idref="H25168E4768EF4A408AE94B1D1BE402C0" legis-path="3.(c)(1)">subsection (c)(1).</internal-xref></text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64C60E18D4C0403E8ED7764661218DF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advanced payment</header><text>An eligible parent who has an approved application under <internal-xref idref="H7D52CE8FBAE343E38002875CEA5D1314" legis-path="3.(c)(2)">subsection (c)(2)</internal-xref> is eligible to receive a baby bonus up to 60 days before the expected due date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCB5B21E56F54CF0902EE7DDEF02029C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration of custody</header><subparagraph id="HBD74798C02DB435D99BCD707F7833A6A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice requirement</header><text>The Commissioner shall provide notice to all known eligible parents when an application for child payments is approved under <internal-xref idref="H25168E4768EF4A408AE94B1D1BE402C0" legis-path="3.(c)(1)">subsection (c)(1)</internal-xref> providing 21 days for any objections before payment is made. Notwithstanding the prior sentence, the Commissioner may elect not to provide such notice if the Commissioner determines that the applicant has produced clear evidence that providing such notice will not result in an individual other than the eligible parent receiving the baby bonus payment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BBA9678F8BB4D768CBAA30F55BDE544"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Child payments</header><text>Where multiple eligible parents submit applications for the same qualifying child, payment shall be made to the eligible parent who—</text><clause id="H07D88404718E45F889F088D9DA725B9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has primary or sole physical custody, as evidenced by a court order;</text></clause><clause id="HDE3E3E38DD2B4A8EBD30111B2C9F0335"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the child primarily resides with, in the absence of such a court order; or</text></clause><clause id="H498A822541A943889E97A7B0A1876E03"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if neither clause (i) or (ii) can be determined, the first approved applicant.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD74C1FDA2E3346CCABD406B00B5B959A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Joint custody exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <internal-xref idref="H2BBA9678F8BB4D768CBAA30F55BDE544" legis-path="3.(b)(3)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>, where parents have a court order establishing equal shared physical custody, either parent may request that the payment be divided equally. The Commissioner shall so divide the payment unless the other parent declines, in writing, their share of the payment within 21 days of notification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC495E8D6AB364442B4DA3038CE1EACCB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Dispute resolution</header><text>In cases in which a dispute exists as to which eligible parent should receive the payment pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H2BBA9678F8BB4D768CBAA30F55BDE544" legis-path="3.(b)(3)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> and there is no applicable court order, the Commissioner may require submission of such additional documentation as the Commissioner determines appropriate before making payment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B4FD63AD16847509250FC11E65A8DC2"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Changed circumstances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <internal-xref idref="H55ECBD6A3AD1487F9417D371C141E2FE" legis-path="3.(a)(1)">subsection (a)(1)</internal-xref>, the Commissioner may transfer payment to a different eligible parent (or if payment has already been made, may issue payment to a different eligible parent and attempt to recover the original payment in accordance with <internal-xref idref="HAE0AD755E1E14EA3A8B024848C422370" legis-path="3.(e)">subsection (e)</internal-xref>) upon receiving documentation showing that—</text><clause id="H7141583721524C4DB4D8123EDBDC1B1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the 1-year period beginning on the date on which the child is born—</text><subclause id="H044D0B26BBD14A56AF5FA4062E231F68"><enum>(I)</enum><text>custody arrangements were modified by court order subsequent to the initial application; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD3A42D70FB334456AA794CEE9ECA216B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the original recipient died or became legally incapacitated;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1836C581A4FB462EA295326A195D4701"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the original application contained fraudulent information; and</text></clause><clause id="H91BE3E39F35D473DB32618926AC3E0D9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of payment made to a prospective adoptive parent described in <internal-xref idref="HDFEB3C214D904351A3BFBF1D343A219F" legis-path="4.(4)(C)(ii)(II)">section 4(4)(C)(ii)(II)</internal-xref>, the adoption is not completed within 60 days of the birth of the qualifying child.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA363EB10D3F493EB008A4392124C415"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H25168E4768EF4A408AE94B1D1BE402C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approval process</header><text>Not later than 14 days after the receipt of an application, the Commissioner shall verify that the applicant meets the requirements established under this section. The application of any applicant so verified shall be considered approved.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D52CE8FBAE343E38002875CEA5D1314"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Subject to <internal-xref idref="H6A3B520621CC4422BF6D05BEB6D21AE2" legis-path="3.(c)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref>, an eligible parent (or an authorized representative described in <internal-xref idref="H38618AF28BCD446E8B9E1158D4DB4501" legis-path="3.(c)(5)">paragraph (5)</internal-xref>) applying for a baby bonus payment shall provide the Commissioner with an application in such form and manner as the Commissioner may require. The application shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HC0A64EE2BA1F497B920210A1F6773755"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and social security account number or taxpayer identification number of the eligible parent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF698D0B00BB44DEE8F0BBEDA4FE02825"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0977B7AA36634518A6384A0C3BE096EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the eligible parent is applying before birth of the child, verification of gestational age obtained under <internal-xref idref="HD75C0E0FC0874318865806732316140D" legis-path="3.(c)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref>; or</text></clause><clause id="H6C7EEC5AC2C1423E96589A0752B4E3B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the eligible parent is applying after the birth of the child, documentation determined appropriate by the Commissioner to prove the age and identity of the child;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE19772514FED4BD58494AB29D3685DAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a written statement from the gestational parent stating, under penalty of perjury pursuant to section 1746 of title 28, United States Code—</text><clause id="HF923EA5528394B4AAD7BD05D2CDDB8DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether such person is the biological parent of such fetus; and</text></clause><clause id="H7C665D8CCBE043F1B0C4DEC048AF8A8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether such person—</text><subclause id="H3EF75C82BDC54B2B8384C1850E7B7B3E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>intends to retain custody of and parental rights to such child once born;</text></subclause><subclause id="H667775041C77464A891C07779CE66E3D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is acting as a gestational surrogate pursuant to a written surrogacy agreement and consents to the intended parent receiving the baby bonus payment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H394FC4BDFFB34811A197FEB66CD9CD64"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has entered into a pre-birth adoption agreement and consents to the prospective adoptive parent receiving the baby bonus payment;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4F1E2A7903D4439A072893B806F47C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the contact information of any other eligible parent known to the applicant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B77A52905AE445DAB90F480A332E3B3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the Commissioner determines necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A3B520621CC4422BF6D05BEB6D21AE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Simultaneous application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an eligible parent has not received a baby bonus and does not have an application under <internal-xref idref="H7D52CE8FBAE343E38002875CEA5D1314" legis-path="3.(c)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>, the Commissioner shall treat an application for a social security account number for a qualifying child as an application for a baby bonus payment under this section unless the eligible parent affirmatively indicates on such social security account number application an intent to opt out of receiving a baby bonus. The Commissioner may require, as a condition of receiving a payment under <internal-xref idref="H0EEFF80E65FF468585A70B0CF0ADD865" legis-path="3.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, that the eligible parent submit information required under <internal-xref idref="H7D52CE8FBAE343E38002875CEA5D1314" legis-path="3.(c)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref> in addition to the application for a social security account number.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD75C0E0FC0874318865806732316140D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Verification of gestational age</header><subparagraph id="HFF7E07F18C2C4FB1927F7E343BFC322A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the request of a gestational parent, a physician may make a determination with respect to the gestational age and expected due date of the fetus. Any determination made under this paragraph shall be based on the reasonable medical judgment of the physician following such inquiries, examinations, and tests as a reasonably prudent physician would deem necessary for purposes of making such determination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DFCDC8388644D9A9A1974EA6E452C14"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the physician has made a determination pursuant to <internal-xref idref="HFF7E07F18C2C4FB1927F7E343BFC322A" legis-path="3.(c)(4)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> that the gestational age of the fetus is 20 weeks or greater and the expected due date is on or after January 1st, 2026, such physician shall, upon the request of the gestational parent, provide the gestational parent with a form which includes the following:</text><clause id="HB446D37D5CD142A5AD5687649EA4565E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The gestational age and the expected due date of the fetus.</text></clause><clause id="H4B7FEC7FB589485AA582FC9F65CFF55A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The name and social security account number or taxpayer identification number of the gestational parent.</text></clause><clause id="HA63B4C4DBA3C4FBBBA97E71DD0CB039C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the application is being submitted by a spouse or domestic partner of a gestational parent, the name and social security account number or taxpayer identification number of such spouse or domestic partner.</text></clause><clause id="HFB80DD062E834BD781F4CE4E82FE1673"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The name and contact information of the physician.</text></clause><clause id="HAD48BABB896F491B9C908195F1F957AF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A written documentation from such physician stating, under penalty of perjury pursuant to section 1746 of title 28, United States Code, that—</text><subclause id="H53C4A6716E13427498974AB77FDCAC93"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the gestational parent was determined to be pregnant with the fetus, according to standard medical practice, by such physician; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H825E9690B8794857ABE97FF0A4FD013F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such physician has determined that, in their reasonable medical judgment, the gestational age of the fetus is 20 weeks or greater and the expected due date is on or after January 1st, 2026.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38618AF28BCD446E8B9E1158D4DB4501"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorized representatives</header><subparagraph id="H2D2095C8C8A3464A93583A8BE141157E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An application may be submitted on behalf of an eligible parent by—</text><clause id="H16ED49843B0C455EA8467159A7774ED8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a spouse or domestic partner;</text></clause><clause id="HEA899E823FA84EE2B55A30C5D22AED38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a legal representative;</text></clause><clause id="HD9059BD3CC1049B19C15C8C2DB17EFB7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a healthcare provider involved in providing prenatal or postnatal care to the eligible parent; or</text></clause><clause id="H2A8041419D374F1AB84DF3C2D6D002AE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an social service agency determined appropriate by the Commissioner to submit such applications.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7ED890037824D5B9FAC24C06E6EAE99"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text>The Commissioner may require that a person submitting a request in accordance with <internal-xref idref="H2D2095C8C8A3464A93583A8BE141157E" legis-path="3.(c)(5)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> provide such documentation as the Commissioner determines appropriate to prevent fraud or abuse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BA7E46A0C7D4698A4B19C5A084C7535" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effect of death or loss of qualifying child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the involuntary death of a fetus or qualifying child, or the death of a fetus or qualifying child as a result of any treatment intended to save the life of the gestational parent or any treatment of an ectopic pregnancy, occurring after 20 weeks gestation, such death shall have no effect with respect to whether the payment is allowed under this section to an eligible parent, provided that such person otherwise satisfies the applicable requirements under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE0AD755E1E14EA3A8B024848C422370"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Payment recovery; penalties</header><paragraph id="HFBD45368D2C645E98FDAD0DBFA0178EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Overpayments and underpayment</header><subparagraph id="H8F571DF92845421EA8DF91CCBE6C70CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever the Commissioner determines that more or less than the correct amount of payment has been made to a person, proper adjustment or recovery shall be made in the same manner as adjustment or recovery is made under section 204 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/404">42 U.S.C. 404</external-xref>) with respect to overpayments or underpayments under title II of such Act. Notwithstanding the previous sentence, payments under such title may not be adjusted for the purpose of recovering a payment under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FCF374019C9455E908E003C59B82E72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other recovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an overpayment to an individual who later becomes entitled to a benefit under this section, the Commissioner may decrease such benefit in order to recover such overpayment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H822C546FB34A4C129F1563ACC279A7F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Section 208 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/408">42 U.S.C. 408</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to baby bonus payments under this section in the same manner as such section applies with respect to monthly insurance benefits under title II of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA1496CEAC8F4E83B9E1FB929B6B1198"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Income disregard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A baby bonus payment made under this section shall not be taken into account as income for purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and shall not be taken into account as income or resources for purposes of determining the eligibility of such individual or any other individual for benefits or assistance, or the amount or extent of benefits or assistance, under any Federal program or under any State or local program financed in whole or in part with Federal funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3B684B0427604280B442B6747279D63F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, information submitted pursuant to subsection (c) may not be used for any purpose other than to determine eligibility for a baby bonus payment under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5C654844B9F34C60A39D1A44F03E3729"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4D4A59A63C6C43E393043539AD75B83F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business day</header><text>The term <term>business day</term> means any day other than Saturday, Sunday, or a legal public holiday described in section 6103 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA74AD68269004AA0B3F5CE881B360D61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner of Social Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2320045DE95C41B1A9959D21EBADA7D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deputy commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Deputy Commissioner</term> means the Deputy Commissioner of the Office of Baby Assistance established under <internal-xref idref="H68AF4B0A6983479DA2A11C44339AD453" legis-path="2.(a)">section 2(a)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB4EA6B662F449BB83865C4EA902E49A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible parent</header><text>The term <term>eligible parent</term> means an individual (other than an ineligible person) who—</text><subparagraph id="H5721DF7D011C42CDB8352548DC88378B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resides in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F4C227734FF4DED87BEB49CD181B6E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text><clause id="HD1754A92C7704D9296D4DE8D16F82FAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a citizen or national of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="H5C4F74C9168542C7BA067942F4C247F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a qualified alien (as defined in section 431 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1641">8 U.S.C. 1641</external-xref>)); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EBC1FEC0A2F428C97E2CDD9433F22BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is—</text><clause id="H17E960E3F55540939F8533D7AE86423D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the parent (other than an ineligible person) or legal guardian of a qualifying child; or</text></clause><clause id="H99ACB13C4C4E4D6C9E638959E13DCA23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the parent is an ineligible person—</text><subclause id="HC1C653B5901E4506AFB24FCA45F4FB8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an intended parent in a surrogacy arrangement; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HDFEB3C214D904351A3BFBF1D343A219F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a prospective adoptive parent with a court-approved pre-birth adoption agreement</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2FD733077354B53B3667750C5592B34"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fetus</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fetus</term> means a human fetus and includes an embryo.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E081B3B86554180A38F86BCBF97E626"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Gestational age</header><text>The term <term>gestational age</term> means the age of a fetus, as calculated from the first day of the pregnant person’s last menstrual period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5833D59EF82C435E90C8E66A8139066E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Gestational parent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gestational parent</term> means an individual who is or was pregnant with a qualifying child, including an individual who is an ineligible person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD70127704F574F8BB19E1134F8C49A6D" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Ineligible person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ineligible person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H555B8E8688D6400FA3EA84D111346623" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a gestational parent who—</text><clause id="H5032F50C8F2D436C829595BCCA1123ED" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enters into a court-approved pre-birth adoption agreement with an adoptive parent; and</text></clause><clause id="H5D88BF900650436BAF0C3645DC6FECD9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>completes the adoption process for the child within 60 days of birth; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99A734F5090E4E8894DD4C04E996A003" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a surrogate who has a surrogacy arrangement in a State that recognizes the intended parent’s legal rights to the qualifying child upon birth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BBB9BC59D134DB684F2DE5435ECBA60"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Physician</header><text>The term <term>physician</term> means an individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="H05E421101CC84C85AB905DD753EC62DB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>licensed by a State or territory of the United States to practice—</text><clause id="HABD734D80B814945B811FF1FC84AA09D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>medicine and surgery;</text></clause><clause id="HBA11F9EAEDA2419691CA8DE089247C14" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>osteopathic medicine and surgery; or</text></clause><clause id="H2FC64A9863F348BD9E48C296CA6CE3CD" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>midwifery; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD70388C253974DA496C2356EABAE0EE8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise legally authorized to—</text><clause id="HEB07A9D82DA94ABAB793D78B076852EF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>perform births and to diagnose and attend miscarriages or stillbirths; and</text></clause><clause id="HDE11A3A8856E4D67AE927C94E23844CA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>perform examinations to determine the gestational age of a fetus by the State in which such practice is performed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78274CC62B1A470DAE693BE6641F1702"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Qualifying child</header><text>The term <term>qualifying child</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD61DCD81511C4B37BC80F1505EED43FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a child born on or after January 1st, 2026; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A1A76642380482AB84516AAB21E97FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a fetus with a gestational age of at least 20 weeks and an expected due date on or after January 1st, 2026, as certified by a physician.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7836B0581264EA89D2A9FE02534E67A" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Surrogate</header><text>The term <term>surrogate</term> means an individual who carries a fetus conceived through assisted reproductive technology and who has entered into a surrogacy arrangement.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

