<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H74FF448547EE49209B1B8FDF06AB7484" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1736 : Generative AI Terrorism Risk Assessment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1736</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc> Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to conduct annual assessments on threats to the United States posed by the use of generative artificial intelligence for terrorism, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HC3C5DFBF766F4444ADEF3B590CD05B42"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H42A63C24342E4D4EAB3EB27734B32010" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Generative AI Terrorism Risk Assessment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCA9844F7F6CA463C906B9B108C55BC7E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding the use of generative artificial intelligence applications for terrorist activity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H7D8EFEBE22B54AB5B1576654BA51EB58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the heightened terrorism threat landscape and the increasing utilization of generative artificial intelligence by foreign terrorist organizations represent a national security threat, and the challenges posed by such threat are not well understood; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F167FCFF9A14B1FAB6886418DB6976D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, must take steps to recognize, assess, and address such threat, thereby reducing risks to the people of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEAFF7F1250054BFC9EA3C15C587EBC5D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual assessments on terrorism threats to the United States posed by the use of generative artificial intelligence for terrorism</header><subsection id="H4FFC6EC26E12450390DF5D71228B7F9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessments</header><paragraph id="H10750B92089A474791D1DA9C7733BA8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for five years, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an assessment of terrorism threats to the United States posed by the use of generative artificial intelligence for terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H696037B3601C46D2B48275DC990FB2D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each terrorism threat assessment under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HE7EAC96DF10E4B53A7E1AE96FE91B37B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of incidents during the immediately preceding calendar year in which a foreign terrorist organization or individual has used or attempted to use generative artificial intelligence to carry out the following:</text><clause id="H675402353B004239B5ED1398F549D8CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Spread violent extremist messaging and facilitate the ability to radicalize and recruit individuals to violence.</text></clause><clause id="H18463AAE058A4B1E9C66F5DFA6984E03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhance their ability to develop or deploy chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear weapons.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF8C5F86EA0D4BB493860CC0225B4006"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations on appropriate measures to counter terrorism threats to the United States posed by such terrorist organization or individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H571C3B6049C445C6A25E43338B04703B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>Each terrorism threat assessment under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H9DFFBC1642274B798140537906B7403F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be coordinated by the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure compliance with applicable law and protections relating to individuals’ privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB60101FF1AF54A9CBAC6873DDFA53BAC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be informed by existing products of the Department of Homeland Security, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7E1FDA10D24D28BB8670112A8BAC01"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each terrorism threat assessment under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex. The Secretary of Homeland Security shall post on a publicly available website of the Department of Homeland Security the unclassified portion of each such assessment. Each such unclassified portion shall not contain information that is designated as For Official Use Only, or otherwise would not be publicly available pursuant to section 552 of title 5, United States Code (popularly referred to as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote> (FOIA)), or other applicable law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DAEA6ED2AF14D1FB7F4118B8A65FA5C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the submission of each terrorism threat assessment under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall brief the appropriate congressional committees regarding each such assessment. The head of any other relevant Federal department or agency shall join the Secretary for any such briefing if any such committee, in consultation with the Secretary, determines such is appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB893CF00622E46DDA2184D0262864DF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><paragraph id="H673A6AAE497045CD871128B6C17F5AC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall review information relating to terrorism threats to the United States posed by the use of generative artificial intelligence for terrorism that is gathered by State and major urban area fusion centers and the National Network of Fusion Centers, and incorporate such information, as appropriate, into the Department of Homeland Security’s own information relating to such. The Secretary shall ensure the dissemination to State and major urban area fusion centers and the National Network of Fusion Centers of such information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE733CE9A4318404A87F05A77C12B26D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the entities specified in paragraph (3) shall share with the Secretary of Homeland Security information regarding terrorism threats to the United States posed by the use of generative artificial intelligence for terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCF0902B54A34D20B1FBD0561DC0106D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entitles specified</header><text>The entities specified in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="H71C1E3F58FD248CD82ECF7DE0804B573"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of the Director of National Intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4545724B766248619F736D7CAD99F176"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61AB0C87FB2C4FA391316844075A6295"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Members of the intelligence community.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F149A7A67D24275B6B2C928377710D7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other relevant Federal department or agency the Secretary of Homeland Security determines necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB60938E5F60D4B308528F6462E842AF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H44A082EC6DE740668DB89F75BC40CA2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Homeland Security, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CAC109828184C1ABB66E020E99B7701" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H794383EDEEFC49929D37AF07F7313054"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Generative artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>generative artificial intelligence</quote> means the class of artificial intelligence models that emulate the structure and characteristics of input data in order to generate derived synthetic content, including images, videos, audio, text, and other digital content.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H642346A2E9EB445F8775EB43F7BAF4F0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign terrorist organization</header><text>The term <quote>terrorist organization</quote> means any entity designated as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6994369BB10B4DF4A3B3396999B4B573"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fusion center</header><text>The term <quote>fusion center</quote> has the meaning given such term in subsection (k) of section 210A of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124h">6 U.S.C. 124h</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63168564B4E043FA948668B83B6C2EA3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0603BD33CF23441E9AABC395ACEF17AB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>National Network of Fusion Centers</header><text>The term <quote>National Network of Fusion Centers</quote> means a decentralized arrangement of fusion centers intended to enhance the ability of individual State and local fusion centers to leverage the capabilities and expertise of all such fusion centers for the purpose of enhancing analysis and homeland security information sharing nationally.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5524C89AD78A4A53AD93E08BC067F048"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Terrorism</header><text>The term <quote>terrorism</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20251119" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 19, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

