<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-KAT25862-P20-TH-0W7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 SRES 501 ATS: Recognizing National Native American Heritage Month and celebrating the heritages and cultures of Native Americans and the contributions of Native Americans to the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 501</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date>November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing National Native American Heritage Month and celebrating the heritages and cultures of Native Americans and the contributions of Native Americans to the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, from November 1, 2025, through November 30, 2025, the United States celebrates National Native American Heritage Month;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Native American Heritage Month is an opportunity to consider and recognize the contributions of Native Americans to the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native Americans are descendants of the original, Indigenous inhabitants of what is now the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Bureau of the Census estimates that—</text><paragraph id="idF79AEA9033964109A8CDC7A5845ABBCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in 2020, there were 9,666,058 individuals of American Indian and Alaska Native descent in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id431F837AC4B0470584FA9AA378D61D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in 2020, there were 680,442 individuals of Native Hawaiian descent in the United States; </text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native Americans maintain vibrant cultures and traditions and hold a deeply rooted sense of community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native Americans have moving stories of tragedy, triumph, and perseverance that need to be shared with future generations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native Americans speak and write in their Indigenous languages, which have influenced and contributed in a variety of ways to the United States, including the naming of places and sites throughout the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has consistently reaffirmed support for self-governance and self-determination policies for Native American communities and the commitment of the United States to improving the lives of all Native Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is committed to—</text><paragraph id="id34096a00b5134d8694775d1daeb96f41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthening the government-to-government relationship with Indian Tribes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idca8a199d32c64e0b8186781cb16a2c03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>upholding the Federal trust responsibility to Native American communities;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress has recognized the contributions of the Haudenosaunee Confederacy and the influence of the Haudenosaunee Confederacy on the Founding Fathers in the drafting of the Constitution of the United States with the concepts of— </text><paragraph id="id844f4cac5a15456fa69d6e2fdf4f251b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>freedom of speech;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9e08c71a5404110b696216eb39a1b88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the separation of governmental powers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1404e9fbddfa4c00a6076674108c27e1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the system of checks and balances between the branches of government;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with the enactment of the Native American Heritage Day Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/33">Public Law 111–33</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1922), Congress—</text><paragraph id="id0bc683a987314c5e92a49b448cf8c3f7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirmed the government-to-government relationship between the United States and Native American governments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4037d7b11644a348c2c3ca01ecb251c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognized the important contributions of Native Americans to the culture of the United States;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native Americans have made distinct and important contributions to the United States and the world in many fields, including agriculture, environmental stewardship, wayfinding, medicine, music, dance, language, and art;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas contemporary applications of traditional knowledge systems of Native Americans have expanded scientific, environmental, and intercultural understanding;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native Americans have distinguished themselves as inventors, entrepreneurs, spiritual leaders, and scholars;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Native Americans have served with honor and distinction in the Armed Forces of the United States for centuries and have the highest per capita involvement of any population currently serving in the Armed Forces of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has recognized the contribution of the Native American code talkers in World War I and World War II, who used Indigenous languages to communicate an unbreakable military code, saving countless lives in both conflicts; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States have reason to honor the great achievements and contributions of Native Americans and their ancestors: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id586cbe7ac3744a35b6abf23ece65ed00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the month of November 2025 as <quote>National Native American Heritage Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb3863f39c7084d7f82930cfc696b4b12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the Friday after Thanksgiving as <quote>Native American Heritage Day</quote> in accordance with section 2(10) of the Native American Heritage Day Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/33">Public Law 111–33</external-xref>; 123 Stat. 1923); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id265d7be6df9349d4b2d92a0c044db6ef"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to observe National Native American Heritage Month and Native American Heritage Day with appropriate programs and activities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

