<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H27DD023874784BB0AA1864C6118F7778" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6475 IH: Preventing Child Trafficking Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6475</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Office for Victims of Crime of the Department of Justice to continue implementing the anti-trafficking recommendations of the Government Accountability Office and to report to Congress regarding such implementation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86D5925270604FA480D572CE24E8D16B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8A140DAF2CBF4452B205A4A527771B08"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Child Trafficking Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H64084843DA2941A480E9F70E7EB42AE2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>anti-trafficking recommendations</term> means the recommendations set forth in the report of the Government Accountability Office entitled <quote>Child Trafficking: Addressing Challenges to Public Awareness and Survivor Support</quote>, which was published on December 11, 2023.</text></section> 
<section id="HFBD88A5EC8AB491F968E5FBA00F140D5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Continued implementation of anti-trafficking programs for children</header> 
<subsection id="HCD144FA5DDB24722921FDA7B3FEE0641"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Office for Victims of Crime of the Department of Justice, in coordination with the Office on Trafficking in Persons of the Administration for Children and Families, shall continue implementing the anti-trafficking recommendations by—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56F9A39A2DA343518A99FA8ABFEDA7A1"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">working together, in accordance with the leading collaboration practices referenced in GAO–24–106038, to develop and implement strategies to prevent child trafficking and support child trafficking survivors; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4F315B5D0964783B7821D877EBAB7D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing achievable performance goals and targets for anti-trafficking programs for children that reflect leading practices, such as being objective, measurable, and quantifiable, using baseline data from program grantees. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H91D859365B4C4C6E885087B3BBDB38FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office for Victims of Crime shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that explicitly describes the steps taken pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

