<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL25A28-1S8-JF-6F0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3387 IS: One Fair Price Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3387</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251208" legis-day="20251204">December 8 (legislative day, December 4), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit certain uses of automated decision systems to inform individualized prices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC063CB9DC9D4442CB60312CFCDD4AA37"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF64CE1DF4A434977A8CBFC489CC081F2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>One Fair Price Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD86CAD80ADEC46BE97B15EF6F61ADC85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on surveillance-based price setting</header><subsection id="id3b5c182273e64b9f956e4f3baf23fcab"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Surveillance-Based price setting</header> <paragraph id="id1f6cfd830f394d84b2e6d0d627cc4022"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), it shall be unlawful for a person to offer or charge different prices to different consumers for the same, or a substantially similar, product or service using, informed by, or based on, in whole or in part, surveillance data.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id93f636e1b8c74d3eb4f190ae33d5e11e">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Safe harbor</header>
          <subparagraph id="id5d4af2cbbffe4218bfff73e35e0f10bf">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>In general</header>
 <text>The following shall not be considered surveillance-based price setting for purposes of paragraph (1) if the conditions of subparagraph (B) are met:</text>
            <clause id="idbd8a3f9916e048ca8d603d26ae746fe6">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>A difference in price that is based solely on reasonable costs associated with providing the product or service to different consumers.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="idbe5cdf8e2535469badde73e798ae323f">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>A bona fide discount that is offered to any member of a broadly defined group, including teachers, active duty personnel, veterans, senior citizens, or students.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id76bb036f1d41427db077028805e1ec46">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>A bona fide discount that is offered to any consumer who affirmatively and knowingly enrolls in a loyalty program.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id5fa7cc92394e4e76806bda69a40682aa">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Conditions for exception</header>
 <text>The conditions described in this subparagraph are the following:</text> <clause id="ide96303b1eca54ddcac0225600df8fad3"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>Any basis for a difference in reasonable costs associated with providing a product or service to different consumers is disclosed to the consumer prior to purchase.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id693ed23f9d204a82a29d55ab6ccb62be">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>Any eligibility condition or criteria for receiving or earning a bona fide discount is clearly and conspicuously disclosed.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id001521235286418a980e7ce1d2f97466">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>Any bona fide discount is offered uniformly to any consumer who meets the disclosed eligibility conditions or criteria.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id281263e458a542a4a1856489b358e4fb">
              <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Any surveillance data used solely to offer or administer a bona fide discount is not used for any other purpose, including profiling, targeted advertising, or individualized price setting.</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="id7207bd0047a34a5993d95fadf3022017">
              <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>Any loyalty program that allows a user to accrue and exchange points, credits, or any similar nonmonetary system of value for a product or service does not charge a different price for those points, credits, or similar nonmonetary system of value to different consumers for the same or substantially similar product or service.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="id2c8477af0bc34229bdb9538b726fb29d">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
          <header>Inapplicability to insurance or credit products</header>
 <text>The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply to the business of insurance or any credit product.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="H13F6FC99CBE040DE9EE65F02757FA697"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Commission</header><paragraph id="H6D4643E70B5742B0AB80FCDAF4043E0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices; Unfair methods of competition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) and as a violation of section 5(a) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)</external-xref>) regarding unfair methods of competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10E2F7FE5EBB41C4AA32D29B869B2E58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5eea5cf3ba5747ffa6095066e1f376af"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), the Commission shall enforce subsection (a) and any regulation promulgated under such subsection in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94b02c9df17743e3b4563dce4544feea"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), any person who violates such subsection or a regulation promulgated under such subsection shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B3A7AFF3EA64BA9846A20E208F08B24"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Common carriers, nonprofit organizations, and air carriers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 4, 5(a)(2), or 6 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>, 45(a)(2), 46) or any jurisdictional limitation of the Commission, the Commission shall also enforce subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under subsection (a), in the same manner provided in subparagraphs (A) and (B), with respect to—</text><clause commented="no" id="H169107012B9845348A58DEFB044DA1FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>common carriers subject to the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) and all Acts amendatory thereof and supplementary thereto;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H9048003B1BC84E5095C8D2CC7FA11FEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>organizations not organized to carry on business for their own profit or that of their members; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc083ed116fcf4476830c767f8ebdaeca"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>air carriers and foreign air carriers subject to the Federal Aviation Act of 1958.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b0f265c81844e6f9fe088d2b02a91b7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida2ec9beacb2c4c2881cc8ea48e495b94"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Commission may promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules as may be necessary to carry out this section, including guidance regarding how to comply with subsection (a).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7dcb3c9395c4020aeed708cfc5c9426"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Small business concerns</header><text>The Commission shall consider rules necessary to carry out this Act as having a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Regulatory Flexibility Act</quote>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CCB10A9E91649A59FF6EE575D9E37CF"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8B7ABA5948364913A5A0ED2E77084BC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions by States</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HBCC21E9A861340089143C2A249579BC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of such State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by the engagement of any person in an act or practice in violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under such subsection, the attorney general of the State, may as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1BC8F284589C4CDCB5E73A68C62A89B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE04CBD2783E84700A53A1E35372CB5A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such subsection or such regulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01FE372079E6478582C00DFE3CBF1CF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain, for each violation, the greater of—</text><clause id="HE1893A7CEE3A49258779B99C6EA26876"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the actual monetary damages incurred from the violation; or</text></clause><clause id="H14B0F321174E497BAF97FF7886B86A56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$3,000; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9768283E6A84844B06CA49BB5C34377"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain, for each violation, any other restitution, penalties, and other legal or equitable relief as the court may deem appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4DB5139EC29E4D28B93959FD0B1AF041"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing a civil action under this subsection, nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent an attorney general, official, or agency of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, official, or agency by the laws of such State to conduct investigations, administer oaths and affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4FC8B042E4CD4A7D9D221587F2408DCE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H0292E876739E4655BEEFA3E4CA753FBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who has been injured by a person in violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated under such subsection may bring a civil action against such person in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2C81AC03427F43E891BCF1833F4C4E9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin the violation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E5856ABDB614A9E94E9EE407822EEF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain, for each violation, the greater of—</text><clause id="HCB3F6727E63F4A07A7BB37A26068D62D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the actual monetary damages incurred from the violation; or</text></clause><clause id="HB25D3FEFD8144A3297950FD3F4194EA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$3,000; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD007577FF25D45C69B3278E19734A7D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtain, for each violation, any other restitution, penalties, and other legal or equitable relief as the court may deem appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H652DC5032B1F4588A32885CE63395516"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Willful violations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the court finds that the defendant acted willfully in committing a violation described in paragraph (1), the court may, in its discretion, increase the amount of the award to an amount equal to not more than 3 times the amount available under paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8fc9f3f78c134145b6cbe89c3c5c2037"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prima facie case; rebuttal</header><subparagraph id="ide9e62bb886874a5aac0666d5236c5bf9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prima facie case</header><text>In any proceeding commenced pursuant to paragraph (1), the defendant shall be presumed to be in violation of subsection (a) if the plaintiff can demonstrate that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd10e2c9fddf54e1ebdcf153e96354e9d"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">two or more individuals were offered different prices by the defendant for the same, or a substantially similar, product or service during the same, or a substantially similar, period of time; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ad9a051fb2548018dce92a463436bc5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one individual was offered different prices by the defendant for the same, or a substantially similar, product or service during the same, or a substantially similar, period of time while using different means of viewing the price.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97c8cbf3fec14904a7b06358bcf472a4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Burden of rebutting prima facie case</header><text>The defendant may rebut the presumption described in subparagraph (A) by demonstrating that the alleged difference in price was—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8b4bbd1c1b54c2892c7d5a7c7fca7d6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not informed, in whole or in part, by surveillance data; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18fc566b8f034ea5ab1b3d5e1101ebc8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fully explained by the safe harbors described in subsection (a)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H99F53AA9EE8D408E9B0C48E9420F5FB9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Costs and attorney’s fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall award to a prevailing plaintiff in an action under this subsection the litigation costs of such action and reasonable attorney’s fees, as determined by the court.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCF4DE2D200B44DC68FE82A44CD573559"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An action may be commenced under this subsection not later than 5 years after the date on which the individual first discovered or had a reasonable opportunity to discover the violation.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE0D472AA35AF4B4BB3D57BF731DD8E77"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nonexclusive remedy</header><text>Bringing a civil action under this subsection shall be in addition to any other remedy available to the individual bringing such civil action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E671CFCC1424E56957E3A49DDBEF8B7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Invalidity of pre-dispute arbitration and joint action waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/9/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 9, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Arbitration Act</quote>), or any other provision of law, a pre-dispute arbitration agreement or pre-dispute joint action waiver between a person in violation of subsection (a) and an individual is not valid or enforceable for purposes of the individual bringing a civil action against such person under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd68366fd2544b00b1dac7ff5a1b02ba"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Joint study and report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72b2e19750394f0d8f5cb146a89df347"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Office of Advocacy</quote>), in consultation with the Commission, shall conduct a joint study to evaluate the impact of this Act on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37256024d9aa4a5b8c818a4759293218"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">small business concerns; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a72f27e5303465cb42317c611fe4bee"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promoting competition between large and small business enterprises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c032a7d5bd94671904ed8eb8f90374e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Office of Advocacy completes the study under paragraph (1), the Commission and the Office of Advocacy shall submit to Congress a report on such study, including any relevant findings and recommendations resulting from such study.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE27261C98F864E93B231867EC2544714"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idb541e0ca2a7e456e8d5c344ac691482b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bona fide discount</header><text>The term <term>bona fide discount</term> means an offered price that is lower than the genuine price at which a product or service is widely offered to the public on a regular basis for a reasonably substantial period of time and not for the purpose of establishing a fictitious price to enable the subsequent offer of a reduction.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd453a0dd92094d91995329db33f167f5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business of insurance; credit</header><text>The terms <term>business of insurance</term> and <term>credit</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 1002 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA8B69C593EF416888C4DC4E9BD5C1FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id197f605e98454098bc107a2f8a3425ed"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Genetic information</header><text>The term <term>genetic information</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2791(d) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2EA044773044C448D8EAE96530B1384"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Personal information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal information</term> means any quality, feature, attribute, or trait of an individual, including any immutable characteristic (such as race and eye color), mutable characteristic (such as address, weight, citizenship, family, or parenthood status), genetic information, and any other information that could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular individual or household.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H887EBD176801449D9D876745245781F4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pre-dispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <term>pre-dispute arbitration agreement</term> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not arisen at the time of making the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D6BC8124A30412AAA24D40389FB1086"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Pre-dispute joint action waiver</header><text>The term <term>pre-dispute joint action waiver</term> means an agreement, including as part of a pre-dispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not arisen at the time of making the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07BBB108C8FE4020AC713BF1ED4025A3"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Price</header><text>The term <term>price</term> means the amount charged or offered to a consumer in relation to a transaction, including any related cost and fee and any other material term of the transaction that has direct bearing on the amount paid by the consumer or the value of the product or service offered or provided to the consumer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3dcc5d50bda141f698a9f8170a9d5b1e"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text>The term <term>small business concern</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f3135d55ab74e82bc4f022da1d16c69"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida91f42a01eb7456a8ca1a8317ac24f62"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not include a small business concern involved in developing, training, or selling a product or service for the primary purpose of aiding a business to determine a price.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403971857806472F9018E08CAF609A27"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Surveillance data</header><text>The term <term>surveillance data</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HC3424E1B77C24491B87D9834BD451052"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means data that is related to the personal information, behavior, or biometrics of an individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H231F47E85D584DF0AED217D18EFE70C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes data gathered, purchased, or otherwise acquired.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ida6e70af67d1f4be9862db1a26ce60698"><enum>3.</enum><header>Application of prohibition on surveillance-based price setting to air carriers and ticket agents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc18319f81dc4e76af43b64bc540fea8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 41712 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc56d3f50e7a64cb0b4fa838e7ebdcf1c"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a9f735382444d57a6b1da5502fd976e"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Prohibition on surveillance-Based price setting</header> <text>It shall be an unfair or deceptive practice under subsection (a) for an air carrier, foreign air carrier, or ticket agent to engage in surveillance-based price setting, as described in section 2(a) of the <short-title>One Fair Price Act of 2025</short-title>.</text>
 </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id990a87fa176c4c1290badebeae4ba27c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No preemption of consumer protection claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 41713(b)(4) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="id4B9AE6E47A354AABBC609A3577AC1E0D" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="USC"><subparagraph id="id7c7f977dbfce4c8da5ff995aba3b8791"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No preemption of surveillance-based price setting claims</header><text>Nothing in subparagraphs (A) through (C) may be construed—</text><clause id="id824C2B74318C4021BD065029EFCA8805"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to preempt, displace, or supplant any action for civil damages or injunctive relief based on a violation of section 2(a) of the <short-title>One Fair Price Act of 2025</short-title>; or</text></clause><clause id="id0449701E502142CEBDBE2E0C766F36BA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to restrict the authority of any government entity, including an attorney general of a State, from bringing a legal claim on behalf of the citizens of the State with respect to any such violation.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

