<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEA489481F05C49D6948741066DFFE9A7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7007 IH: Governing for the People Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7007</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260112">January 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Ethics</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To govern on behalf of the American people.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H618F86CE79114D20B486233B189AF1C5" style="OLC"><section id="H83F33D7103054A1D9C0A3E400BD8AB4E" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Governing for the People Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><title id="H852C002E44A34F868D01D411E09E8E0D"><enum>I</enum><section id="H0196712F342D46E1AC87D02ECBDD4AFC" section-type="section-one"><enum>101.</enum><header>Film and television production deduction amendments</header><subsection id="H971C14695D1E4B1C911229EB87449E31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/181">Section 181(g)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>December 31, 2025</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2030</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF58D96038F4A425BA5CFC23DCA9D6D3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increase in dollar limitation</header><text>Section 181(a)(2)(A) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF0DF96DCB3B3483B8078424726D70D5F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HAC638FD671954CD681961283C1A35858"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to so much of the aggregate cost of any qualified film or television production or any qualified live theatrical production as exceeds $30,000,000.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HAE34EDDC501E4533A749EDBFF28E1279"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Higher dollar limitation for productions in certain areas</header><text>Section 181(a)(2)(B) of such Code is amended in the matter following clause (ii) by striking <quote>substituting <quote>$20,000,000</quote> for <quote>$15,000,000</quote></quote> and inserting <quote>substituting <quote>$40,000,000</quote> for <quote>$30,000,000</quote></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H99EF13D28580476781D4F1C07E7E6342"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>Section 181(a)(2) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7D4EF80A4C33436697B87DDF18BA1E4C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HF5F11540312A412ABF04BFBEBABA73EB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><clause id="HF12F5693AB7E435F955F00620F14A937"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2026, each dollar amount in subparagraph (A) or (B) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subclause id="H563D2312168D47F98A4D479A2D293BB0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subclause><subclause id="H6A2DF38367CE4CD6A8A409B9DDF18ED6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H449EE1F1B5404D1EA9C0F5B5941D0A7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Rounding.—Any increase determined under clause (i) shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H614B1CCA3190444090D91772C96BA012"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to productions commencing after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H82FC46ED001A4F679300702C37F34D66"><enum>II</enum><section id="HC554B1F136404E5FBAE099DE4D185BEB"><enum>201.</enum><header>Additional tool to prevent certain frauds against veterans</header><subsection id="H4DB8D8F70DF84399836E1EC1CEE99C78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/63">Chapter 63</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CCE4096308942E0A8BD1822773223AE"><section id="H3E199F5FBA5D455F91ECEB3B3B11D91D"><enum>1352.</enum><header>Fraud regarding veterans’ benefits</header><subsection id="HF9F1A0DAFADE433384A425CBE058B4C5"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever knowingly executes, or attempts to execute, any scheme or artifice to defraud an individual of veterans’ benefits, or in connection with obtaining veteran’s benefits for that individual, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C1EF9DD9C904145881B5238EBB0A491"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text><paragraph id="H65395D21980846EA935C29D8F98C8F61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H803B7A8370894079A77CA404BCEE3FED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>veterans’ benefits</term> means any benefit provided by Federal law for a veteran or a dependent or survivor of a veteran.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H45F42D9CE2A74EE1BBACFEB9218ECCEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0739C8A24D8448BA900FFB0C00A0595"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1352. Fraud regarding veterans’ benefits.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title><title id="H5C88A8A9624D44A2B1E4B92457323776"><enum>III</enum><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84F8BA40A04E4834A4A552C3B025EE72"><enum>301.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this title is to ensure that parties affected by wildland fires resulting from management activities conducted by the Department of Agriculture on National Forest System land are eligible to receive 100 percent funding for the cost of remediating direct and indirect damages under authorized Federal recovery programs.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA6974F61649843AF9FBE8977FB3B2A39"><enum>302.</enum><header>Cost-share waiver for rehabilitation from wildland fires</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45972D1FBA5C4A38AC809B788634A1B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6639AD9E956F42F69CADB8057C40AAB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered matching requirement</header><text>The term <term>covered matching requirement</term> means a requirement under a program of the Secretary for wildland fire recovery for a State, Indian Tribe, locality, or individual to provide matching funds, in cash, for a project.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA0E4C9970D54F8B9861BD5C5E99D11E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered wildland fire</header><text>The term <term>covered wildland fire</term> means a wildland fire that the Secretary determines to be a result of management activities conducted by the Secretary on National Forest System land.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H087C7F467B4E47508BB2FEB2BDA386F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3D518901DAB4029914282ECDAB58220"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wildland fire</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA751848510C64D69A060077DA70A4029"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>wildland fire</term> means any non-structure fire that occurs in vegetation or natural fuels.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10AD56A8021241D8BAD6A64AE1778AFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>wildland fire</term> includes wildfire, prescribed fire, and any direct or indirect damage resulting in watershed impairment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECF1A44042C54912AA4E7A244997C8F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may waive any covered matching requirement for a project in response to a covered wildland fire that is in an area affected by that covered wildland fire.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H33A29652AA3146EFA188F2DAF896E03C"><enum>IV</enum><section id="H0334767D690C47DA819814F93EFADCD9"><enum>401.</enum><header>Awards for artificial intelligence literacy programs</header><subsection id="H04AC77FCE50F484A95CE9CB40B2DFFC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Awards</header><paragraph id="H1CF94F4065E14A04B75959F7CAE1A1F3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) may make awards to eligible entities, including nonprofit organizations, educational institutions, or consortiums of such entities, to develop, implement, and evaluate programs that promote AI literacy at the local level allowing communities to learn about AI from local, trusted sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H719FE98CE1994A14A37098331D27BAC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Awards made under this subsection may be used for the following:</text><subparagraph id="HDC40170DEB3E4169B506745D6A0C5625"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To develop curricula, educational materials, and resources focused on AI literacy, including relating to understanding the basics of AI, its applications, ethical considerations, and the societal impacts of AI.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35CB85A8276544E1BF030DB69211B225"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To provide AI literacy education and training to marginalized communities, with priority given to communities of color, low-income populations, rural areas, senior citizens, people with disabilities, and other underserved groups.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F8BA5B56E1047209176C6317CC734D2" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To conduct outreach and engagement activities to raise awareness of AI literacy and encourage participation in AI literacy programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB547955F7050491E8D214DA2D925132D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To evaluate the effectiveness of AI literacy programs and share best practices and lessons learned with other organizations and institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3AF283EAAC48C9A005B9EC68DCEE9C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making awards under this subsection, the Director of the NSF may encourage applications that—</text><subparagraph id="H18DFFEFF24014777813D4D398B43D55A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate a strong commitment to serving marginalized communities, including senior citizens;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EABB4350E644BE78277AE96465B921C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have experience launching technology education local programs working with target populations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD30D42F40EEE469092144D1A337DCABA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>propose innovative and scalable approaches to AI literacy education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F1551EB76A34C9C90B511E10916AD11"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Each recipient of an award made under this subsection shall submit to the Director of the NSF an annual report that may include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HCBBB3C64CBB041F380E6E1EDA7EEF2C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the AI literacy programs funded by the award.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F59971FBC024159BC3F63C5FBFE7966"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information relating to the number and demographics of individuals served by the award.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC5CADBDA81C455DBAC6B099730D7709"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact of the award on participants’ understanding of AI and its implications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8AB73E7533141A398DB9E2FA3005DB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency coordination, reporting, and award identification</header><paragraph id="HFE7370C75C23489593D27A16E562C4A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the heads of the following Federal agencies shall each submit to Congress a report detailing how the respective agency can more effectively advance AI literacy:</text><subparagraph id="HD556CEF051EE46E1A46A3EAF2B97E098"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor shall assess how AI literacy can be integrated into workforce development programs, with a focus on preparing workers for the jobs of the future and maintaining the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC93E03AB75FD49CCB1D7C07D2C9C61E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall evaluate how AI literacy can enhance the competitiveness of United States businesses, particularly small and medium-sized enterprises, in the global AI economy, and contribute to maintaining the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA33077443254C44B752ED0A8AF1E4C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall evaluate opportunities to support AI literacy among small business owners and entrepreneurs, with an emphasis on underserved communities, to maintain the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DD703D4A2B64D0B91751D7296A80F3B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Education shall identify strategies for incorporating AI literacy into K–12 and higher education curricula, ensuring that all students have access to quality AI education, and that AI literacy contributes to maintaining the United States competitive advantage and national security through artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C3489255AE545EDAB9E253745992DC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Award identification and modification</header><text>The head of each agency specified in paragraph (1) shall also include in the respective reports required under such paragraph the following:</text><subparagraph id="H0F4CE159C521418CA7516F1D18EC2440"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of existing awards under the jurisdiction of the respective agency that can be modified to include AI literacy as an eligible use of funds.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1BD6189016C4460B6D09D4F62AE4A53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recommendations on how such awards can be adapted to support AI literacy initiatives, particularly in the context of workforce development, business competitiveness, education, and national security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF6AB2EBDD9C47CCA5240BC0FEA23BFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Specific examples of award programs that could be modified and the potential impact of such modifications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66636A257F4444CB8E645087F7A68ECE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the reports and recommendations required under this subsection, the head of each agency shall consult with relevant stakeholders, including educators, industry representatives, community organizations, and AI experts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E3C3D9A8E11418C92CBE905FC319695"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The reports required under this subsection shall be made publicly available on the websites of the respective agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F15C15FC21F4687B7B0B61DC77369EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2954F139BCAA447496FB6EFF445FB33B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>AI</header><text>The term <term>AI</term> means artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40A2B08BF7FF4D81B63A3559B7E19FC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> means an engineered system that can generate output for a given set of human-defined objectives, such as content, predictions, recommendations, or decisions that influence people or environments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B79E53823664CAA95809D86B5B848A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence literacy; AI literacy</header><text>The terms <term>artificial intelligence literacy</term> and <term>AI literacy</term> mean the ability for humans to understand, evaluate, and effectively use artificial intelligence technologies, including understanding artificial intelligence basics and knowing what artificial intelligence can do, how artificial intelligence works, and being aware of the effects on society of artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BF7F3AB492A46AFA9D7DCB4BCF41965"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ethical artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ethical artificial intelligence</term> means the practice of designing, developing, deploying, and using artificial intelligence systems to align with ethical principles and human values, considering the potential impact on society of such systems.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H720742D7A8054C01B5C4F020FE1137B8"><enum>V</enum><section id="HDCA893B86BBF460A9C1739E02E1013E0"><enum>501.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><subsection id="HBF8F8D60FC384412A13050C03A2EE246"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and Secretary of the Treasury a report analyzing oil and ballistic missile-related transactions between the People’s Republic of China and the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDDCA56C0E1BE4FBAA58A4F9490806CDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H63FAB476E8CF468F9A3C316442FD3369"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the purchases of Iranian oil by the People’s Republic of China since 2020, including an assessment of the use of transshipment points and shell companies as methods to insulate the People’s Republic of China from sanctions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5015860E6EF44808EC2674AD5081728"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of significant financial transactions by entities in the People’s Republic of China related to the sale, supply, or transfer to Iran of chemical precursors and other materials that may support the ballistic missile program of Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AFDE860800541E4A89256D149300990"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H99B03A04A3ED47768619000D20387073"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A341EA7EA8549359A8B13097D55BA00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB66E4122483A443EB4B0DD1E67FD1B78"><enum>502.</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the submission of the report required by section 2, the Secretary of the Treasury shall determine whether the People’s Republic of China is conducting any sanctionable activities and report such determination to Congress.</text></section></title><title id="H8DC439B5F3064323896F4058B4795EB7"><enum>VI</enum><section id="H82735B181BB049EA8FE14D0705D17546"><enum>601.</enum><header>Coverage requirement</header><subsection id="H9A3C1870C3D84B5EA84EDAAF48A575BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All health insurers—including a group health plan, a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, and all applicable Federal health programs—shall provide full coverage, without cost-sharing, for annual low-dose computed tomography (LDCT) or other appropriate lung cancer screening technologies for eligible individuals described in section (3).</text></subsection><subsection id="H03F75BA91E5848529A09D7D79E4FF3AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited barriers</header><text>Coverage under this title may not be subject to—</text><paragraph id="H45E0E3C495E3499E89CC28554D262DE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prior authorization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF8CA8C720D34755AE536BA8CC29A975"><enum>(2)</enum><text>step-therapy or other utilization controls;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD09743DB54604B62A42A47A1EE78107B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>frequency limits more restrictive than one screening annually; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58361402387848348B830F32A902BB72"><enum>(4)</enum><text>documentation requirements beyond those included in recent evidence-based clinical guidelines.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9A541982B55349E0A4A0D20CD490FF0E"><enum>602.</enum><header>Eligible individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An eligible individual is an adult who—</text><paragraph id="H79A577381D584101AF4ED7F2B8A3C8F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is 50 to 80 years old; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H680316416F8B4A21BD25B06460AE50FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is determined by a treating health care professional to be at increased risk for lung cancer based on personal, environmental, or familial risk factors.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF39E262E5C744BABA338CD10E63EF989"><enum>603.</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall issue implementing regulations within 180 days of enactment and ensure program-wide compliance.</text></section></title><title id="H1EE4CF489A6F47B89574117465B72C70"><enum>VII</enum><section id="HAE90DFFFABCA4309A6D4B23C60B28BB4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>701.</enum><header>Implementation of GAO recommendations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall take such actions as may be necessary to implement the priority recommendations of the Comptroller General of the United States contained in the report published on November 15, 2022, and titled <quote>Disaster Recovery: Actions Needed to Improve the Federal Approach</quote> (GAO–23–104956).</text></section></title><title id="H4C0A87E660BB4C3F8375A3DB7B409092"><enum>VIII</enum><section id="H57B158988DBF484B83470D7E534B8349"><enum>801.</enum><header>Updating the process for paying salaries of the House of Representatives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 116(a) of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4551">2 U.S.C. 4551</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD80D055C4F6440358FCF58AFA95CAB6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The usual day</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the usual day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC5ECA97C59D446883E35540F2431ECA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2F8288E938784A70A0FCD7EC0768DAEE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HC819621FC43547F088D83AE89C093D08" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the House of Representatives next upgrades its payroll system, if directed by the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer may pay salaries in or under the House of Representatives twice per month, or on the basis of such other schedule, as such Committee may promulgate by regulation.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title><title id="HA1AC43E1CC9048C7B068D602C7A06091"><enum>IX</enum><section id="H4641E40B66BF471D8114BA4CA5C3FD10" section-type="section-one"><enum>901.</enum><header>Administration of Next Generation Warning System grant program</header><subsection id="H2A443C7915A84043B25B2542FEF41870"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall take such actions as may be necessary to—</text><paragraph id="HFDC0D9CD29D04E0E8EE65011D621BC17"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assume responsibility for administering the Next Generation Warning System grant program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09AD991FD19A4962A91E8083FDE31ED3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, disburse all funds made available for fiscal year 2022 to carry out such program under the heading <quote>Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery—Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote> of title III of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>) that are obligated as of the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB96DC8903F64AE6B80AD84B6B5F17D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begin the process of awarding grants under the Next Generation Warning System grant program with funds made available to carry out such program—</text><subparagraph id="H9B5BBBC04C964713BB3FE6C21503F45B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2023 under the heading <quote>Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery—Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote> of title III of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/328">Public Law 117–328</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D966FBA4B1D455F88B812A3E6984E80"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for fiscal year 2024 under the heading <quote>Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery—Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote> of title III of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2024 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80388E0D42274DE183FF8764A8CD7BF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Communications research and development</header><paragraph id="HE515D216211546FDB55FD2B61373AFFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with other relevant Federal agencies and departments, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, and relevant owners and operators of critical infrastructure, as appropriate, shall, to the extent practicable, carry out research and development to support and improve the—</text><subparagraph id="HA34325F439BC43578D06C67A51FDEF62"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accessibility of emergency warning systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C8C131829DF41A293C9B4EF6F326B78"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resiliency and security of emergency warning systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4667BB4C6D6F41F0A1A28A4D95DB9018"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other matters as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B9B3E0BFEE1447187757C71ABDB5ADA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Research and development report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the research and development activities carried out pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA198F3AC358348BD82D7E923C06E667B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0E3DBA45CA074D23849E7A576499A841"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Next Generation Warning System grant program defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Next Generation Warning System grant program</term> means the grant program authorized pursuant to title III of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>) under the heading <quote>Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery—Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4334A8FE3B964994B45AC6FFB161107E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H54F8B9C9C5A0453DBE303A70228F814B"><enum>X</enum><section id="H0B7EF59643B342FFBDC33CD67370D702"><enum>1001.</enum><header>Hearings</header><subsection id="HFD7ACA8A7D1E48BF9C80DC2F8C5B5793"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each standing committee of the House of Representatives shall hold a hearing on the implementation of this Act within one year of enactment.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE5F208121A1C4E0C9B0336547DCA0D78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exercise of rulemaking authority</header><text>Subsection (a) is enacted—</text><paragraph id="HBC0D0FDE98BD4BF4AEE8B3289D7361B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of rulemaking power of the House of Representatives, and, as such, shall be considered as part of the rules of the House, and such rules shall supersede any other rule of the House only to the extent that rule is inconsistent therewith; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB75D600AFDE44FEEB18E6976430F7A50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change such rules (so far as relating to the procedure in such House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of the House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H69AE5ACCA2344F4D808B5C591CBEC016"><enum>XI</enum><section id="H315C0DE44C0F41F8860008F742B4FAEA"><enum>1101.</enum><header>Code of official conduct</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives, strike clause 18 and insert the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3EB801A732ED4B90BDF4CF41158C46F0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><rules-clause id="H9FB124DE76EA41A6B8D15635B9EE889D"><enum>18.</enum><rules-paragraph id="H7A1D138C3771452096DA7FCBCA1F16F6" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner may not engage in a sexual relationship with any employee of the House who works under the supervision of the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner, or who is an employee of a committee on which the Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner serves. This paragraph does not apply with respect to any relationship between two people who are married to each other.</text></rules-paragraph><rules-paragraph id="H22B60992876F4018BCC69DA25B4D1945" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House may not engage in unwelcome sexual advances or conduct towards another Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House.</text></rules-paragraph><rules-paragraph id="H1D4FDA60E00F4513B7243D0413947D7F" indent="up1"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this clause, the term <term>employee</term> includes an applicant for employment, a paid or unpaid intern (including an applicant for an internship), a detailee, and an individual participating in a fellowship program.</text></rules-paragraph></rules-clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title><title id="HD2D351B835494483B979AADCF8C173F5"><enum>XII</enum><section id="H80EF150EBACC45A8A413BAB67B0E26AC"><enum>1201.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go-Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></title><title id="H9843F290023E4E2D9F398CA79A0553E5"><enum>XIII</enum><section id="HA42884B1A3BF4C94AAF0DCCD01C3D07B"><enum>1301.</enum><header>Appropriations</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The following sums are hereby appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2027, and for other purposes, namely:</text></section><appropriations-major id="HD482E5496845461C84A193E7BBEFF6DD"><header>DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HA5F55913AF48476D8BC52122A1EF66E4"><header>NATIONAL INSTITUTES OF HEALTH</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H02DB1B38B8EC46F5B3EE9960C4355E73"><header>NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF DENTAL AND CRANIOFACIAL RESEARCH</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for necessary expenses for carrying out section 301 and title IV of the Public Health Service Act with respect to dental and craniofacial diseases, $1,000,000.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H113383D8663245D590809E58613AEE54"><header>ANIMAL AND PLANT HEALTH INSPECTION SERVICE</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HA68E02D137C84D52B5F10EC87C54F150"><header>SALARIES AND EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service salaries and expenses, $1,000,000.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H7724D40BD3674EC5BEA07C515748D17D"><header>UNITED STATES TAX COURT</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H557382ABA6DA41F98EC24B7C544061D1"><header>SALARIES AND EXPENSES</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount for necessary expenses, $1,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="HEF2CDB41D18D49EB9F8DD2D7ADA5B62C"><header>DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="HE49556507043423BAEAA5C7C97ED0B25"><header>OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE, SPACE FORCE</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount of expenses, not otherwise provided for, necessary for the operations and maintenance of the Space Force, as authorized by law, $1,000,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-major id="H4EB7D49070854D13AB83662BF6F17F28"><header>DEPARTMENT OF THE INTERIOR</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-small id="HD2C42AB88D534646864C721EAB43711B"><header>NORTH AMERICAN WETLANDS CONSERVATION FUND</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount of expenses necessary to carry out the provisions of the North American Wetlands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4401">16 U.S.C. 4401 et seq.</external-xref>), $1,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-major id="H548B91DBC9FB4725934A88077B83F82D"><header>FEDERAL RAILROAD ADMINISTRATION</header></appropriations-major><appropriations-intermediate id="H2FF378C29AF04DFD89D3B8326F27FCC3"><header>SAFETY AND OPERATIONS</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For an additional amount of expenses necessary of the Federal Railroad Administration, $1,000,000.</text></appropriations-intermediate></title></legis-body></bill>

