<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H0E196ECE800243B7A30E87ABD63EC8EB" key="H" resolution-type="house-resolution"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1313 IH: Original Resolution Condemning the Hateful Comments of Texas Congressional Candidate Maureen Galindo</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1313</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Condemning the hateful comments of Texas congressional candidate Maureen Galindo.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body display-resolving-clause="no-display-resolving-clause" id="HE4ABA8FF8C57473DB5D48B398651CDD9"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0E196ECE800243B7A30E87ABD63EC8EA"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header></section> 
<section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0E196ECE800243B7A30E87ABD63EC8EC"><text>This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Original Resolution Condemning the Hateful Comments of Texas Congressional Candidate Maureen Galindo</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="s1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The House of Representatives finds the following:</text>
<subsection id="ss1"><enum/><text>Whereas, on May 13, 2026, referring to herself, Texas congressional candidate Maureen Galindo posted on Instagram, <quote>When Maureen gets into Congress, she'll write legislation so that all Zionism is undoubtedly Anti-semitic, since it's Zionists harming the Semites. She'll turn Karnes ICE Detention Center into a prison for American Zionists and former ICE officers for human trafficking. (It will also be a castration processing center for pedophiles which will probably be most of the Zionists)</quote>;</text></subsection> <subsection id="ss2"><enum/><text>Whereas Ms. Galindo's comments advocate the imprisonment of Americans based on their ideologies and associations and endorse the use of detention facilities as institutions for political punishment;</text></subsection>
<subsection id="ss3"><enum/><text>Whereas, throughout history, some governments have used detention camps and prisons to persecute individuals because of their race, religion, ethnicity, political beliefs, or perceived affiliations;</text></subsection> <subsection id="ss4"><enum/><text>Whereas, during World War II, Nazi Germany established concentration camps that imprisoned and murdered millions of people, including six million Jews, who suffered the horrors of the Holocaust;</text></subsection>
<subsection id="ss5"><enum/><text>Whereas among the lessons of the Holocaust is the demonstration of the dangerous consequences of targeting individuals or groups for detention based on identity, beliefs, or associations;</text></subsection> <subsection id="ss6"><enum/><text>Whereas calls for the imprisonment of persons possibly associated with Jewish identity evoke some of the darkest chapters in human history and are deeply offensive to Holocaust survivors, their descendants, and the families of those who suffered religious persecution;</text></subsection>
<subsection id="ss7"><enum/><text>Whereas the First Amendment to the Constitution protects freedom of speech, freedom of religion, and freedom of association for all people in the United States; it does not, however, protect persons from the condemnation of their hate speech; and</text></subsection> <subsection id="ss8"><enum/><text>Whereas calls to imprison and castrate Americans because of their ideologies or affiliations are contrary to the idealized principles of liberty and justice enshrined in the Constitution: Now, therefore, be it</text></subsection></section>
</resolution-body> 
<resolution-body id="HC04FAD4D9EB14A4FB4C00BEEF7B02BD2"> 
<section section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1C4A72EE19234F08AB7176835100B2D0"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H32CABAE44BDC4788B4A1E46AE3541593"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemns the hateful comments of Texas congressional candidate Maureen Galindo, advocating the imprisonment and castration of Americans based on their ideologies or associations.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body>
</resolution>

