<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-RIL25A06-5YD-66-2HY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 441 ATS:  Designating the week of October 5, 2025, through October 11, 2025, as “National Community Policing Week”. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 441</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251007">October 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes"> Designating the week of October 5, 2025, through October 11, 2025, as <quote>National Community Policing Week</quote>. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas police officers are indispensable members of the community who put their lives on the line to protect others;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas promoting strong relationships, founded in trust and mutual respect, between law enforcement officers and the communities they serve helps ensure the safe and effective execution of the law;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas relationships developed through community policing help protect both law enforcement officers and civilians; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas law enforcement officers and communities that work together to address public safety concerns can create lasting solutions to difficult challenges; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community policing has helped produce reductions in both violent and property crime; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas events in recent years have sparked a nationwide call to improve the interactions between law enforcement officers and the communities they serve;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community policing facilitates peaceful dialogue, capable of fostering understanding and trust, between law enforcement officers and civilians;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community policing informs the public about the challenges that law enforcement officers face in executing their duties and provides law enforcement officers insight into the concerns of community members;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a long-term commitment to community policing is necessary to eliminate the underlying causes of crime;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the advancement of community policing should be supported to ensure that State and local law enforcement agencies have necessary resources; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas community policing has been recognized as an important tool for improving the relationship between law enforcement officers and the communities they serve: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idA115DE2D3F1D4A79811E94A203008C96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week of October 5, 2025, through October 11, 2025, as <quote>National Community Policing Week</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1941FE2EA2864C05BE5F9CBDF6E64D0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports community policing and encourages the people of the United States, law enforcement agencies, and elected officials to identify ways in which communities can improve public safety, strengthen relationships, and build trust.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

