<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY26105-6F3-30-CFW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3999 IS: Women Veterans Specialty Care Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3999</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that women veterans may schedule appointments for women’s specialty care under the laws administered by the Secretary without requiring a referral, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women Veterans Specialty Care Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9022f2aa264f496bad5e5cefb5fd9e22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Direct scheduling of women’s specialty care for women veterans</header><subsection id="id15e37dc20334471ca608a73eb70b3b58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that any covered veteran may directly schedule an appointment for women’s specialty care, including through the Veterans Community Care Program under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, without requiring a referral from a primary care provider of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4979452e51a94cc9a9c7fe44696e04d6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that direct scheduling under subsection (a) is available—</text><paragraph id="iddc29a4cfe3c041fabe881f7c5dbe75e2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>through each medical center or clinic of the Department that offers women’s specialty care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id641e27c877bd4451a48759185c1bf5d6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>via telephone, online scheduling tools, and any other modality used by the Department for scheduling of specialty care.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id892a98134b4b4c059bf2c272746ee252"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on additional administrative barriers</header><text>The Secretary may not require any additional approval, referral, or screening step as a condition of a covered veteran accessing women’s specialty care.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3c3132b422764345845e0f8c68928cbf"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter or waive eligibility or access standards for the receipt of care or services under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="id59c4c181b94c48dbaabfefa2accf0550"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ab02289f4f24831b579fbd9bf5275db"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered veteran</header><text>The term <term>covered veteran</term> means a woman veteran enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment of the Department of Veterans Affairs established and operated under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code, who is eligible for the receipt of women’s specialty care under the laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32cfc53e8b854ec5981d4576f45a69d8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Women’s specialty care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>women’s specialty care</term> means gynecology care, obstetrics care, maternity care, and postpartum care.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

