<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H386CDD9781464B70A7E3A4FDB21B6E71" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8093 IH: Privacy Protection Updates Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8093</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Privacy Protection Act of 1980 to update and strengthen protections for newsgathering records, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBE5C089FE0B643ADBAD87C9B91E607B4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8CEB291A70FF42BF8A8F60204825BD52" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Privacy Protection Updates Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H45D22848F6F4476C965095820103D754"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusionary rule for violations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106 of the Privacy Protection Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000aa-6">42 U.S.C. 2000aa–6</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (e) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H02C93E454DE64AB697DE25A9869197E8"> 
<subsection id="H01328681737A48A39A0CB56B2919B516"><enum>(e)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H44CEF9A8F37E4EC38508BD8974A6D8C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except in a civil action described in subsection (a), materials described in subsections (a) and (b) of section 101 searched for or seized in violation of this Act, and evidence derived therefrom, may not be used, received in evidence, or otherwise disseminated in any investigation, trial, hearing, or other proceeding in or before any court, grand jury, department, office, agency, regulatory body, legislative committee, or other authority of the United States, a State, or political subdivision thereof.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BDFB4FF0A6C40428B1452A3C1CCA8A7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0754D297F0954C07BCC5C16606F89A92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any aggrieved person in any trial, hearing, or proceeding in or before any court, department, office, agency, regulatory body, or other authority of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof, may move to suppress materials described in subsections (a) and (b) of section 101 searched for or seized pursuant to this Act, or evidence derived therefrom, on the grounds that—</text> 
<clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF20CFB0D305F454BBF415A92F89E30BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the materials were unlawfully searched for or seized;</text></clause> <clause id="H1BC34AA55E80426E930C3FFD49D4F147" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the warrant or order permitting the search or seizure of the materials is insufficient on its face under the requirements of this Act; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3C05853ECCA446139329815DA2654983" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the search or seizure was not made in conformity with the warrant or order.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59C389B1FC1D40B0AF15203FFF2B8A08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the motion is granted, the materials, and evidence derived therefrom, shall be treated as having been obtained in violation of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HBAC4B8FCBA8244818AFA7323079D34C9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Other remedies permitted</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106 of the Privacy Protection Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000aa-6">42 U.S.C. 2000aa–6</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H4BE057013DE54883AD170AF8DA9F46BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (d); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C996E639F424A2590BD72EEE2BC50A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) through (h) as subsections (d) through (g), respectively.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H72592923D80B4B5E8DF67630B68BD129"><enum>4.</enum><header>Required disclosures in warrant application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101 of the Privacy Protection Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000aa">42 U.S.C. 2000aa</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB2B3A393EF54A42A7D16D3FD588EE67"> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD516AC4AF0A247E6B66AD907A939621F"><enum>(d)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H583963ECA8974C3DB78D891515244516"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>covered materials</term> means materials described in subsection (a) or (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2305153740FA41A4884E3082030F0CEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), a government officer or employee may only search for or seize covered materials, pursuant to an exception described in subsection (a) or (b), if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC30D2A7865CC4768AECF82C7FF529D4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the officer or employee obtains a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures) by a court of competent jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H120403E1174D4BA6BAD5739A2BB575C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the application for a warrant described in paragraph (1), the officer or employee discloses—</text> 
<clause id="H754682CF49494C1ABAEB7871FC995680"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the factual basis justifying the applicability of an exception described in subsection (a) or (b), including all information that—</text> <subclause id="H719403EEAA5442089236DC9FA74B06C7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>might reasonably call into question the accuracy of the information or the reasonableness of any assessment in the application, including how the materials qualify as covered materials if no exception is satisfied; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H07D6BC373E96408682932D65FF013641"><enum>(II)</enum><text>otherwise raises doubts that an exception applies; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H979087C1A4A34016926070A5683CAD6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all persons who are the targets of the investigation or prosecution of the criminal offense;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDFB5544F9BD8407AADDCB33CF4873F16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the court finds that—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A3A884C65E04113932E30D6D6E7FE7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an exception permits the search for or seizure of the covered materials; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54A95DEB5EC8491BBB32BF4C4681DD61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the officer or employee argues that an exception described in subsection (a)(1) or (b)(1) applies, that a prosecution for the alleged offense under the facts is consistent with the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D3D8227D11F4B15B461F0913A4C0C0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the court includes such limitations as the court deems necessary to protect against—</text> 
<clause id="H1CFF56B59E594DDABAB9B3BD8207F020"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the search for or seizure of covered materials that are not justified by an exception; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF43A6F149F424FCC9198C4CF40C14ECC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the harms that might follow from a search or seizure described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74F7591751E8498EB630AACBFE1550A9" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A government officer or employee may search for or seize covered materials pursuant to the exceptions described in subsections (a)(2) and (b)(2), without following the procedures described in paragraph (2), if the officer or employee—</text> <subparagraph id="H03C558946DFE4A0398953033E128E0A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>takes reasonable measures to limit any search or seizure to only those covered materials that are necessary to address the harms giving rise to the exception; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2DA90F7B17A14B3CBA294C941EDAC24C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 48 hours after such search or seizure, submits to a court of competent jurisdiction an application that discloses—</text> <clause id="HDC68E6E657784F0D8F83635B1BF7A0DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered materials searched for or seized;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDAE82A7F2BBD4E89A565B93603233B67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the measures described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause> <clause id="H8556926802BA45849531089073BBD2D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the information described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18459DEADF1E4F00960A293C48D62B7E" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H47E6902AD41B48318DCF1D51CF75012E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Upon receipt of an application under paragraph (3)(B), the court shall review the application and issue an order determining whether the search or seizure was justified by an exception described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC41A20031ACF47C0B0BF0ED52DDE915B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the court issues an order described in subparagraph (A) that the search for or seizure of covered materials was not justified by an exception described in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<clause id="H5B483B5D7651422F9E9F3A8B3D45CE73"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the covered materials shall be treated as if they were searched for or seized, as applicable, in violation of this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB8A480F6C4384D198040D550E61979DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the court shall order the government officer or employee to—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H158E72294BD14E06ABE6575356BC29AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">immediately return all covered materials seized; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE234B57846234568B2D8BB5423CB88BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">destroy any copies of the covered materials seized.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H42211E4476D241B48791DC5409EB1CBE" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the court issues an order described in subparagraph (A) that the search for or seizure of covered materials was justified by an exception described in paragraph (3), the court may order the government officer or employee to take any measures that the court determines are reasonable to appropriately balance the continued need for the covered materials of the government officer or employee against the harms flowing from the continued access to covered materials by the government officer or employee, including by ordering the return of any portions of the covered materials, the destruction of any copies of any portions of the covered materials, or by limiting the use or dissemination of any portion of the covered materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H67AC43044BB34EC2B3B2026A47AB3475"><enum>5.</enum><header>Clarifying possession of materials on the cloud</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101 of the Privacy Protection Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000aa">42 U.S.C. 2000aa</external-xref>), as amended by section 4 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end of the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50F321E3B9A94118BD7FD6060C066EDF"> 
<subsection id="HB7F3E4955BFF4F3D9A872AF773204A57"><enum>(e)</enum><text>For purposes of subsections (a) and (b), if the materials described in such subsections are stored, held, or maintained on an electronic communication service (as defined in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code) or remote computing service (as defined in section 2711 of title 18, United States Code) by or on behalf of a customer or subscriber, the customer or subscriber shall be the person deemed to possess such materials.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

