<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H326CDD74B1A942AB9A083E82C33A9388" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9420 IH: Reproductive Health Care Training Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9420</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of an education program to expand abortion care training and access.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9FEE3D50A97740CFB3A14A5D4D930E2A" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H49CA4BB427CE4F0298EB73596B9F895E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reproductive Health Care Training Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8AABFA83DDAA4E548DEC302D176E7999"><enum>2.</enum><header>Education program to expand abortion care training and access</header> <subsection id="H24ADC558334C447AA849F8E6E4B9767D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall establish a program to award grants or contracts to eligible entities to carry out the activities described in subsection (e) for the purposes of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H114E049C2EFA4B918B9590F785BAD962"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expanding and supporting education for students, residents, or advanced practice clinicians in a covered State that permits comprehensive training in abortion care; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6BF9FD28FB54575975A674C177F7890"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preparing and encouraging each such student, resident, and advanced practice clinician training in a covered State to serve as an abortion provider after completing such training.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H283EFDEA2D5A4CBA9623824B29B93DDA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive an award under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H4F726A7EC2FD4A24B46798034F0D8EE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a certification that such eligible entity will use amounts provided to the entity to carry out the activities described in subsection (e); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98D2337725AC42CFB0F119ED97FADE74"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how such eligible entity will carry out such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H032BE6A574C6474E81F6A7B6DA3CCF90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> includes accredited health professions schools, academic health centers or other appropriate public or private nonprofit health care safety net providers, including sexual and reproductive health providers, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H138E5B365DAF46EFBEADA3AD440481FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making awards under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <paragraph id="H540160C3B6E2407B97283F8F2A692D8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are located in a covered State in which clinical training for heath care students, residents, and advanced practice clinicians in abortion care is permitted or comprehensively taught;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22B1037C82BD4D28A43038B6900EF6F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support clinical training in abortion care for health care students, residents, and advanced practice clinicians from States where such training is otherwise limited; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53D8E4012C70499992B4B2F471B57136"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are minority serving institutions or institutions that provide training to increase underrepresented minority health professions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBE6E1FF4BEA4434BA717345BC2AEC698"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity shall use funds made available under an award under this section to carry out the following activities:</text> <paragraph id="H7B63310CFBEC4B8FB4D9A5777311A11E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Support or expand clinical training for health care students, residents, and advanced practice clinicians in abortion care.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF767190933E046D4B42DBB595D18D8DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop and operate programs to train health care students, residents, and advanced practice clinicians in abortion care by—</text> <subparagraph id="H3ABD21D2DE134DCAB46DBFD481793B38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>defining a set of clinical training activities related to abortion care, including those that include care for racial and ethnic minority groups, people with disabilities, Tribal, and medically underserved communities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89B165D557DD4D0D809CC0E7E7709547"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifying and addressing challenges to accessing abortion care, including the needs of racial and ethnic minority groups, people with disabilities, Tribal, and medically underserved communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6186A5DD0FB94C0FB954484B9F8C3764"><enum>(C)</enum><text>supporting the use of telehealth technologies and practices related to abortion care;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H50089357425C481DB7713231EF3E59F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>integrating abortion training into health care education; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBF3504F764D4BCF8194604CC5F29AFB"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>promoting interprofessional training that includes non-obstetrician–gynecologist abortion providers.</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE28FD5915F140C5B51E5676788E32F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Develop or expand strategic partnerships with community health organizations or other eligible entities to enhance access to abortion care and improve health outcomes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5AE67843F9CC4305B1A6CDB8899D3E0A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Develop, implement, and evaluate methods to improve recruitment and retention of health care students and advanced practice clinicians from medically underserved communities to increase access to abortion care.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95A38E684FB445DAA14F202273ABDEA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Train and support instructors to serve medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC45745E3924C4CC8A6A68FAB244C3447"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Prepare health care students, residents, or advanced practice clinicians for transition into clinical practice that includes abortion care, with a focus on medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF485E9AB65CA4682859FCBD61284AC73"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Provide scholarships or stipends to health care students, residents, or advanced practice clinicians that are pursing training in abortion care, with a focus on medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF99123F991734FB0B2BBB2A1CF2638DD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Federal funds appropriated to carry out this section shall supplement not supplant funds otherwise made available to carry out title VII and title VIII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref> and 296 et seq.).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8B53BED91B43475EABC13ABFBCE8A315"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting</header> 
<paragraph id="HD47A51BA71224C38AD45C55562EBEC15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports from entities</header><text>Each entity that receives an award under this section shall submit an annual report to the Secretary on the financial and programmatic performance under such award, which may include factors such as the number of trainees, the number of professions and disciplines, the number of partnerships with health care delivery sites, the number of faculty and practicing health care professionals who participated in continuing education programs, and other factors, as the Secretary may require, in a manner that does not allow for identification of patients, individual providers, or other participants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0975A33FB5664A178F400B77B196169B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>At the end of each year in which the Secretary makes awards under this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that provides a summary of the financial and programmatic performance of such awards, which may include factors such as the number trainees, the number of professions and disciplines, the number of partnerships with health care delivery sites, the number of faculty and practicing health care professionals who participated in continuing education programs, and other factors that assess the impact of the program on the expansion of access to abortion services, in a manner that does not disclose any identifiable information of patients, individual providers, or other participants.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H41A0E8255CEF46A0A5D68E95B3760A09"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB44C001139D24867AB5AED979748CEEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered State</header><text>The term <term>covered State</term> means a State, Puerto Rico, and a territory or possession of the United States in which comprehensive training for abortion care is permissible.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6197AEC93CCA4D6EB21EC148317C2C85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medically underserved community</header><text>The term <term>medically underserved community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 799B of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/295p">42 U.S.C. 295p</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H64D6BB61840049EB9BCCF0EE0741C6A4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

