<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC25E31-WL0-XX-X1K">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3163 IS: To require the Secretary of Defense to seek to engage appropriate officials of Taiwan in a joint program with Taiwan to enable the fielding of uncrewed systems and counter-uncrewed systems capabilities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3163</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on
                    Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to seek to engage appropriate officials
            of Taiwan in a joint program with Taiwan to enable the fielding of uncrewed systems and
            counter-uncrewed systems capabilities.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body>
        <section id="idf7659906b4d8475b9ba3bf2d07e6c53e" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Joint program with Taiwan to enable fielding of uncrewed systems and
                counter-uncrewed systems capabilities</header>
            <subsection id="id8278613611684bd7a36676b64fdb0f9c">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than March 1, 2026, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall seek to engage with appropriate officials of Taiwan in a joint program for the purpose of enabling the fielding of uncrewed systems and counter-uncrewed systems capabilities, including co-development and co-production of such capabilities, for the Armed Forces of the United States and the military forces of Taiwan, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id4188bacec71d463bacf4752500567d31">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Use of authorities</header>
 <text>In carrying out a joint program under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may use the authorities under title 10, United States Code, and other applicable statutory authorities available to the Secretary.</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id5abd695d1a0d40ec8f13eeeb503cceeb">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Report</header>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4829c473709943fa9d3a795b1bd7cb44">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter through 2029, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the joint program under subsection (a).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id581fc291856a4d6a9f3f41f5183e25df">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Elements</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include, for the period covered by the report, the following:</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id363f0f6bdab44167af736756aeefb8dc">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>A summary of engagements under subsection (a).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id2b7f38e066c54d7a985b75cc45125ce1"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>A description of activities undertaken by the Secretary of Defense and appropriate officials of Taiwan to enable the fielding of uncrewed systems and counter-uncrewed systems capabilities described in subsection (a).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id3e689c405d114186987a2dd799f9cd26">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>A description of progress made in finalizing defense trade foundational agreements between the United States and Taiwan, including—</text>
                        <clause id="id2143d8a8cfee480ea095329f6ea3ae7c">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a memorandum of understanding on reciprocal defense procurement;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="ide71d5d3a113441c2834fad87f32fb97e">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a security of supply agreement;</text> </clause> <clause id="idd5b5ece664734c9683b01c730f023f9e"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>an acquisition and cross-servicing agreement;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id740aec0202e04aba90112deb8919c379">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>a general security of military information agreement; and</text> </clause> <clause id="idefb9aac5d51542248c63779688f46cd0"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>a cyber maturity model certification.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id6407b672e72d4f9fa0a738e810c1a3c1">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>An identification of the additional resources or authorities necessary to enable the fielding of uncrewed systems and counter-uncrewed systems capabilities described in subsection (a).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id99154e6657134d39a3c42d8c61c4dae9">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>Any other matter the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id06d8807c2f434f4884b1813d2814530a">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header>
 <text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide60f471c135949a6ba2021a00f6f0316">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idbd6bf20bdbc34027ac58a3a0f69ab560" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

