<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07C13D2380694FED8DB9C961F48B0285" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9474 IH: Local Foods for Healthy Schools Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9474</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish the Local Foods for Healthy Schools Program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC21EDB1C72A741DB90D86D2565D6FE3F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H051F950F600C4973A13FA77B251FA2B4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Foods for Healthy Schools Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1597221D97FF43F9A8D455D0864B4A14"><enum>2.</enum><header>Local foods for healthy schools program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle A of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1621">7 U.S.C. 1621 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAD3CE6D4A102491CB5D2D83785DD86C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H6DC78A0EC00C40B7B7F24778FB6A12AC"><enum>210B.</enum><header>Local foods for healthy schools program</header> 
<subsection id="HCBF4529F8D2B4E09A838D6E139571ECB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>Local Foods for Healthy Schools Program</quote>, (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) under which the Secretary shall enter into noncompetitive cooperative agreements with eligible units of government for the purpose of—</text> <paragraph id="H8B337F7F25C94C589F3E04B4DC81EEDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>purchasing local foods from covered producers; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0789BFCB4A4460B96570A9B5BCA557F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating the distribution of such foods to schools operating in the geographic boundaries of each such eligible unit of government.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H40D98B99F9904A6D8F24195D4E429CF3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Under a cooperative agreement entered into under this section, an eligible unit of government shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H11A3A78118934F26A88F8E7FFCB46F6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the use of any funds received under the Program—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE21AC39C4DB4885A6D5F3147B785409"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase only local foods from a covered producer and distribute such food to any school food authority that is interested in receiving such food; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6731ACD23F443FB8BA0513A0F3D08FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disburse such funds to any such school food authority to purchase only local foods from a covered producer; and</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0616F59EF8DA4E20955C5C0EE8B0A6EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reserve not more than 5 percent of any funds received under the Program to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF96A7EFD303143FB921DC946243CD94D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training and technical assistance to persons involved in carrying out the activities described under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H773C518E2A35490D82B60DC59346F2AC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to purchasing local foods from a covered producer, pay the cost such producer incurs in obtaining any required food safety certification;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE22D756094FC4F579ABA85CE79C1B665" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>conduct oversight and reporting in the State of such eligible unit of government; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34FDE4EFEACA498D8C7F857169DFD93A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>administer the activities described under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H093B8D34CBEB4DC5A014C2D60DB76816"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible unit of government seeking to enter into a cooperative agreement under the Program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text> <paragraph id="H865AC390A588473D95F4D5952911C7B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a plan that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA8C3129463D941669BA3538E010EC858"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies the lead agency responsible for carrying out such plan;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B19F4F1D5ED4ABA8038EE59BFECBB71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies any community partner, including an aggregator, that will contribute to implementation of such plan;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD97FE5FF06704C5294A1F054BD3DAC62"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the proposed use of any funds received under the Program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E613DD3ACC14A7084E363919D365893" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrates that, to the extent possible based on availability and local conditions, a wide variety of local foods will be purchased and distributed using funds received under the Program; and</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE07DD65ABE064E138902BEFF0ABAEF53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assurance that—</text> <subparagraph id="HCE42975E4CCE42FE8F63C2B9DDC93BE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the funds received under this section will supplement, and not supplant, funds provided by the State in support of providing local foods to school food authorities or for school meals; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H88F10E62C2B84E5A996999F4F48DE9EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the eligible unit of government has sufficient mechanisms in place to ensure the efficient and reliable transfer of funds received under the Program, or distribution of food, to school food authorities, schools, covered producers, and community partners in accordance with the plan required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7ABD845460E741C69C2A111D7246A019" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out any requirements of the Program, an eligible unit of government shall coordinate with any other applicable eligible unit of government in the State in which such unit of government operates.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBCCA626D408E4CCFAC41D5935BA25B6D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Noncompetitive allocation</header> 
<paragraph id="H27F107E0FD1D4B02B9405E2A29BBEFAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allocation formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts available to carry out the Program for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall develop an allocation formula that provides—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A94C1072B83478CA290CA108CBB7365" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State-based allocation that is equal for each State;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EF6998C1BEC4779902BE68C5938DCE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that any funds remaining after the allocation under subparagraph (A) are distributed such that the amount a State receives under this subparagraph bears the same proportion to such remaining funds as the number of students receiving meals under the programs described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (h)(4) in that State bears to the number of such students in all States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF458B5CF5CEF4953A4084781CCFB00C9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of funds allocated to an eligible unit of government that are not obligated by the end of the applicable performance period, for the rescission and reallocation, in the manner described in subparagraph (B), of such funds for purposes of carrying out the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07E5752BFC014CF6AC1C0719EA2D1C9E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the allocation formula under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall allot not more than 30 percent of the total funds available to carry out this section under subsection (g) to the State-based allocation under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6043864726E64A6BB21F437875ADD737" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From any funds that an eligible unit of government has not obligated by the end of the performance period for the cooperative agreement of such eligible unit of government, the Secretary may reallocate, in the manner described in paragraph (1)(B), such funds to 1 or more States in which an eligible unit of government has entered into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary, if such eligible unit of government in such a State has the capacity to expend additional funds.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6C28E61DE614D769246800FEDE0FFD3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H319CBBF001A4420DBD5AFDB26035EE2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary requires any funds received under the Program to be expended, each eligible unit of government that enters into a cooperative agreement under the Program shall submit to the Secretary a report containing data relating to the purchase and distribution of local foods described under subsection (b)(1), including the amount of any funds expended, the name of the covered producer receiving any such funds, and the local foods purchased from such producer.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0F289594A3249C699F48F2D640F28EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination by Secretary</header><text>In establishing any additional requirement related to the submission of a report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall minimize any administrative burden on eligible units of government, school food authorities, schools, and community partners involved in carrying out the activities described under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD29DF36C4DA42798A6403E6CC9D4F28" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible unit of government that submits a report under paragraph (1) shall make such report available to the public on the website of the State educational agency (as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) of the applicable State at the time of such submission.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H33C4822E7E7047BCB8CC1E2DA60D8A9C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="HEAD850696C0743EA915050BAD0E36C65" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2026, and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall use $200,000,000 of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5F0612503694AE491642C744CB4D0EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to other funds and authorities available to the Secretary, there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $200,000,000 for fiscal year 2026, and each fiscal year thereafter, to remain available until expended.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F0D8DDCF2DD47929EB1AFACDB063DBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may reserve not more than 0.50 percent of the total amount of funds made available under this subsection each fiscal year to support Federal administrative activities to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8635A0BC43243B68804E7BC945E587D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H02CEF88311D94371A0128630AC8016AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered producer</header><text>The term <term>covered producer</term> means a farmer, producer, rancher, processor, distributor, or other such business involved in food production or distribution that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0EF6379E16A249A085C92964C58346A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in the geographic boundaries of a State in which an eligible unit of government has entered into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary under this section;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H863AB33A5B594A5A875C08E56225F23C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in a 400-mile radius of the location of the school food authority receiving a distribution under the Program; or</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD975EE3B0A28436C81AB4E50804E2D63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meets such other requirement proposed by such eligible unit of government and approved by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF54B1FDB1771482EAC7E320FE46B3844"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible unit of government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible unit of government</term> means an agency, commission, or department of a State responsible for agriculture, child nutrition, procurement, food distribution, or such other similar activities, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, in such State.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B13FAE156EC4737AB90F70395A3B510"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local foods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local foods</term> means agricultural products that—</text> <subparagraph id="H76BB95856B9D4E36A0A468B868510A22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are minimally processed, including products that are whole, cut, pureed, fresh, frozen, canned, or dried; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H06CC4B132DB94062ABCF6EBF988A4403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are produced and distributed—</text> <clause id="H9BC0A1DEACCD4919AA4943424FA3BCD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the same State;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H22017CF805A54E138D82568C532B3C20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a 400-mile radius of the school food authority receiving or purchasing such products under the Program; or</text></clause> <clause id="H29DEE7D35FEE45868E284D535ABAA453"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a manner that meets any such other requirement proposed by such eligible unit of government and approved by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BE254ABB76C4367A72350B0558422E5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school</term> means a school (as defined in section 12(d) of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1760">42 U.S.C. 1760(d)</external-xref>)) that participates in—</text> <subparagraph id="H1E96749B65E643B3BF2FC1AC0828CE76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40FA085B9B9E4123952BEA7229B56F28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the school breakfast program established under section 4 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1773">42 U.S.C. 1773</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A24B862BED7403C8471FAA93DD206A0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School food authority</header><text>The term <term>school food authority</term> means the governing body that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6E1A3439579F4799B54E87D6B6D9E7B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is responsible for the administration of a program described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (4) in one or more schools; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDB3302FC98C45D0AD392DBAC02FA820"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has legal authority to receive from an eligible unit of government a distribution of local foods or disbursement of funds under the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FFE8637E81B4B179AF7F8CDB1D94C34"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35E13DC43FC84D51BD6EC9912FC8657F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any of the fifty States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

