<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E36174D3B5F45318A63DC73B8252760" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8394 IH: Higher Education Marijuana Research Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8394</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To streamline the process for institutions of higher education to research marijuana.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC253F248DF134B0C8A982D103DD62CB6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1E31BA8D4B93437E87825E6F163CCDC5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Higher Education Marijuana Research Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB1F9463DF0A14808AA90EB86FD6A3601"><enum>2.</enum><header>Marijuana for research purposes</header> <subsection id="HDCEC7E7C66594E41BFFFFFF6110DE5DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Priority factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 303(a) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H05CC8706DA82406AA951540408A64BA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B178BFEE37F4E5DA45CED5A0B46042B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86720DE0292E457DB54CD72306200A46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE983B1A9DED84ED6BDFDC2D8496FD880" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H4D49820C2FFC44E59AB2F703CA2C2FFD"><enum>(7) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the applicant is an institution of higher education or a State or local government entity.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H48908D3BAAB54FFB9C3CEF70910A211C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on certain licenses</header>
<paragraph id="H7EFCDB15E4C94457A679FE053A80D05E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, acting through the Drug Enforcement Administration, shall submit a report to Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H4CAE237FC4A34B5EB0C5662F2B628149"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of applications for licenses under section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) it has received for the previous year, disaggregated by whether the applicant was a private entity, an institution of higher education, or a State or local government entity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2396098E0C9E4C93B476487AA63DE2F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status of each application received in the previous year; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4586EC77CE424444A18DCF25A089581F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if applicable, the reason an application was denied.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70CF10DCF0694026A0A3BDFBDAAEAC1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Name with consent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With the consent of the applicant, the Attorney General, acting through the Drug Enforcement Administration, may submit in the report under subparagraph (A) the name of the applicant.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H978276E03F3E4F99A6EE3469711E13F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Obtaining marijuana for research purposes</header> <paragraph id="H14212D253ED146F5B36901D99A602F74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>), the Safe and Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law, an institution of higher education located in a State or on tribal land where marijuana sale or use is lawful may obtain or purchase marijuana from a State or tribal government marijuana regulatory body or obtain marijuana from a State or tribal law enforcement agency for the purpose of biological, chemical, agricultural, or public health research.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC15F85EEA0D848D691C4334D0F3661BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional research purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Marijuana obtained by an institution of higher education pursuant to paragraph (1) may be used to study the type of marijuana in a State’s marketplace, public health considerations of marijuana policies in the State, and any potential medical benefits of marijuana.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D75201ECD664F8898F0EE1719DEDDF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited research purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Marijuana obtained by an institution of higher education from a State or tribal law enforcement agency shall not be administered to individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H404B11437645476BAD9BF8B30C3F9F48"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Participation in research</header>
<paragraph id="H89B5E70C38FE4A03A763A8E3510F434D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Student participation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>), the Safe and Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law, a covered student or covered researcher shall not be ineligible or lose any Federal student aid or other Federal funding because of participation in covered research, conducted by an institution of higher education in a controlled setting, involving marijuana.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H422C20C38E2B49D2858AC5F1DAE3709E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>), the Safe and Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law, an institution of higher education shall not be ineligible or lose any Federal funds as a result of any sponsorship of research involving marijuana.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H381C5732B8134FA4AFA0BC67402424D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Impact on immigration status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The immigration status of a covered student or covered researcher who participates in covered research, conducted by an institution of higher education in a controlled setting, involving marijuana shall not be impacted by such participation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9C4FF06ED1B846D58059584CBEF6530B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H0ECBEA8B22954931BC40902E0258C026"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Controlled setting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>controlled setting</term> means a setting for which the research being conducted was approved by the institution of higher education’s internal authority for reviewing research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30226AC949FF435DBFC38053B17771DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered student</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered student</term> means an individual enrolled part-time or full-time at an institution of higher education for undergraduate, graduate, or post-graduate study.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H562B0A7B542E4C87AE9FEC3363661772"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered research</header><text>The term <term>covered research</term> includes the administration of any research involving marijuana, but does not include a covered student consuming marijuana in any manner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD403A6B2D6574BF48E1B56657E7DBACA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered researcher</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered researcher</term> means an individual employed by a institution of higher education to conduct or assist research approved by the institution of higher education’s internal authority for reviewing research.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB9A5E2D6CB6E41709800A5A5E7EE4235"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian tribe</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 4(e) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDA90B37D28D4638B1F7EABB0C449977"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State or Tribal government marijuana regulatory body</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State or tribal government marijuana regulatory body</term> means the entity approved by State or tribal law with overseeing marijuana licensing in such State or Indian tribe.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H28362A47074B498A8BD7B6652B821C42"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State or Tribal law enforcement agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State or tribal law enforcement agency</term> means an entity authorized by State or tribal law to enforce the laws within their jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H58FCDDCA92044B7F9A3A657C1558B173"><enum>3.</enum><header>Drug Enforcement Administration license process to study marijuana</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration shall establish an Office of University Relations to—</text>
<paragraph id="HDDAD7BFCFB7C4313976C48983B4991E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to a researcher or institution of higher education seeking to register for the manufacture, distribution, or dispensation of a controlled substance under part C of title II of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/821">21 U.S.C. 821 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22A3D843964C4A788D9C6A4BBE9E6206"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop any technology necessary to provide the opportunity for a researcher or institution of higher education to amend an application prior to submission.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HF24D6D5062EF42888C3A2D1751D0A163"><enum>4.</enum><header>Institution of higher education partnership</header>
<subsection id="H9269A5E83AF9423EA4ECBB2D6273A1B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Institution of higher education partnership</header>
<paragraph id="HCD5C9346F967441CBBB6450B9E012251"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall establish working group to produce recommendations on how to simplify and streamline the registration process for studying marijuana at institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93317CC4C2034A8393A1ED3CCF00C7E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participants</header><text>The working group established in paragraph (1) shall include:</text>
<subparagraph id="HF71B8652CA0A40D495401C635F5FBCF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2 appointees from the National Institutes of Health.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56C0A2CEB73B4D24AD3DF1B76EB03364"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 appointees from the Food and Drug Administration.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE2802EC2566D44F98E9B612E99CA08F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2 appointees from the Drug Enforcement Administration.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD460E0B6ABA245A7AA49DA13A14AAF46"><enum>(D)</enum><text>2 appointees from two different institution of higher education, appointed by the individuals under subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) based on their prior study of marijuana.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3942D3BE8B5947D8BA703BCB4DC7376E" commented="no">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Responsibilities</header>
 <text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the working group established under paragraph (1) shall submit a report to the Committee on Education and Workforce, Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate including—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HFAC089BD65F148C09AF9CFC2B4CDF429" commented="no">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the status of marijuana research at institutions of higher education in the United States; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H8796ECE9D24949C3A9D1E06528ECE206" commented="no">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a list of recommendations to improve the academic study of marijuana.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HCB7F9A7FABC64F689508A51239B73F22"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grant program for universities to study marijuana</header>
<subsection id="HFB4B47037942442880B9F70A621B8B97">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall establish a program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) within the National Institute of Drug Abuse to study marijuana for potential medical benefits.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H19FDC74E128C4DD68419A01F524139FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Director may award a grant on a competitive basis in accordance with this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEB3E362FF1424F48B4797CFCF1683382"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may award a grant under the Program to an institution of higher education determined by the Director to have the authority and capability to carry out a project described in subsection (d).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4446D1FDDB2A4D51A75E1A73CB4883F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds awarded under the Program may only be used to study marijuana for medical or public health purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H381EB3A3C0C64BBEAF3A4F27F757521E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an eligible recipient shall submit to the Director an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Director determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2AB8042FAB0E48D9BD7FA5420EB398B5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a grant under the Program, the Director shall give priority to an institution of higher education in a State or tribal land where use of marijuana for recreational or medical use is legal, accounting for geographic diversity and whether the institution of higher education is a minority institution.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H78576711E42D4CD295EAA303290838A5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Director to carry out this section, $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 to 2030.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HD3DBEA51F386494D8F05C97AB2C0C3D9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Grant program for universities to study marijuana for agriculture purposes</header>
<subsection id="H2E8BDAABE5FD40339738A7B15F0201D7">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Establishment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to study marijuana for agriculture purposes, including conservation and growth techniques, impacts on other crops, and the impact of different strains of marijuana on other crops.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="HC5557F6AE5BD4443B3F6BC37A45BD377"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may award a grant on a competitive basis in accordance with this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4F826B6F00A347B698568CB25149D28A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award a grant under the Program to an institution of higher education determined by the Secretary to have the authority and capability to carry out a project described in subsection (d).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H423E66293CD641F2A25AFB44E22B2A27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds awarded under the Program may only be used to study marijuana for agriculture purposes.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDD787015B12D492F86063EE1AEB4A7A0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an eligible recipient shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1D66DBE1D6764493B0522B7D8512E53F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a grant under the Program, the Secretary shall give priority to an institution of higher education in a State or tribal land where use of marijuana for recreational or medical use is legal, accounting for geographic diversity and whether the institution of higher education is a minority institution.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2E889C00A8054BE591B3B0B343194B8C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section, $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2026 to 2030.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HF27A1EDE60784E1B80809B2586A715CF" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Article 28 of single convention on narcotic drugs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Article 28 of the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs shall not be construed to prohibit, or impose additional restrictions upon, research involving marijuana, or the manufacture, distribution, or dispensing of marijuana, that is conducted in accordance with the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>), this Act, and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> <section id="HABBA8A5E104D437E9B12B57A7A086074"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HD57B407004F6451D91933917BA4DBB61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9FFA5E891A04CB39CF0E4AFFCFA076A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minority institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority institution</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 365 of the Higher Education act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067k">20 U.S.C. 1067k</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDA61216DF4214A4C830282DE2B586CAB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

