<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MIR26298-L68-7P-XYW">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3968 IS: Housing for America’s Middle Class Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code>
<congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session>
<legis-num>S. 3968</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title>To require the Government Accountability Office to study and recommend a definition for workforce housing.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H8AF85F81EE2E445A8D863BC3F14D25A6">
<section id="idf5c106dbe9174132bc1a4ca997f95eb1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id497e6df5b86044e9bec208008e9caa26"><enum/><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing for America’s Middle Class Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f60caaf6c2940868bf8de8f2d1e27e6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on workforce housing</header> <subsection id="id00832dfc8ded4407a9f89559d2b4a1d8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study and submit to the Congress a report that—</text>
<paragraph id="idfb7d6d23be5a424e9e83136aff6a1e2f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies obstacles middle-income households face when looking to secure affordable housing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id964adb4f07f445849912a7d7140243f2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifies geographic areas where housing is the most unaffordable and unavailable for middle-income households;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id16af5bb30a13444d9cb22ab6e91b96cc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes a list of Federal housing programs, including Federal tax credits, grants, and loan programs, that are not available to middle-income households due to their income status, including Federal housing programs designed to promote affordability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idef9eb26b0b35472e96b8ee52140ecd2b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommends income and other parameters to establish a clear and consistent Federal definition for the term <term>workforce housing</term> for use when describing the segment of housing that could be made available to such middle-income households in Federal housing programs if funding commensurate with the additional eligibility were to be made available; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idf031658148264d6cb65a4e672f91dcab"><enum>(5)</enum><text>analyzes how to modify or newly develop new Federal housing programs and incentives to include <quote>workforce housing</quote> if funding commensurate with the additional eligibility were to be made available.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="id5a574d9bedd44d6a9ca1e56f7ffe262e"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Middle-Income household defined</header> <text>In this section, the term <term>middle-income household</term> means a household with an income above 80 percent but that does not exceed 120 percent of the median family income of the area, as determined by the Secretary with adjustments for smaller and larger families.</text> </subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>


