<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22EAB43FA3F3490EAC588A200E6995C1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8221 IH: First-Time Homebuyer Savings Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8221</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish first-time homebuyer savings accounts.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2D85282B3D914E73854FEFA1F947D0AC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H93F05E843A564B09878E78359C932014" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First-Time Homebuyer Savings Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HDD4E58B4F9984E35AAEBD075965C4B2A"><enum>2.</enum><header>First-time homebuyer savings account</header> 
<subsection id="H3F25BEC0308A4B8BBB98AF63C29C1315"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle A of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 225 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HED2DD3A9991545B28D716657F0B3C553" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H51648BE857DC449580679A43DA56951F"><enum>225A.</enum><header>First-time homebuyer savings account</header> <subsection id="HEBE2A4A0132142D9AF26A2096D0DE337"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deduction allowed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed as a deduction for the taxable year an amount equal to the aggregate amount paid in cash during such taxable year by or on behalf of such individual to a first-time homebuyer savings account of such individual.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00D47989CBC441ED9B5F2A194DCCF7AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HD47FB39D9FC746C092A4910E6632C2E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First-time homebuyer savings account</header><text>The term <quote>first-time homebuyer savings account</quote> means a trust created or organized in the United States as a first-time homebuyer savings account exclusively for the purpose of paying qualified homebuyer expenses of the account beneficiary, but only if the written governing instrument creating the trust meets the following requirements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A9258E207D0456E87A5540BED009639">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>No contribution will be accepted—</text> <clause id="HB05773B4424345E3AAD9D483D949790E"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>unless it is in cash, or</text>
                                    </clause>
                                    <clause id="H3B81549BDA3C46B1901BF099DACA8D2B">
                                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>if such contribution would result in aggregate contributions to such account in excess of the contribution limit specified in subsection (c).</text>
                                    </clause>
                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0AA2BEFA04054451AE4FB12AC4F9665F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The trustee is a bank (as defined in section 408(n)), an insurance company (as defined in section 816), or another person who demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the manner in which such person will administer the trust will be consistent with the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F3A1BF14A234DC282DC8F766C09BCAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>No part of the trust assets will be invested in life insurance contracts.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC23718CBBADF4130B30A01CD42BC8487"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The assets of the trust will not be commingled with other property except in a common trust fund or common investment fund.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4633CEE7603A4804A5E9D1D2D22FE597"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The interest of an individual in the balance in his account is nonforfeitable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA9C753E7C4F4FF5B9B5847F06FC7FEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible individual</quote> means an individual if such individual (and, if married, such individual’s spouse) had no present ownership interest in a residential property during the 3-year period ending on the present date.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68B09AF221A44973A6616A386F2EC853"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified homebuyer expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>qualified homebuyer expenses</quote> means amounts paid or incurred by the account beneficiary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4CBB21D65A024307B11DC8930669401C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible individual, to purchase a principal residence, including any transaction costs relating to such purchase,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0955FAB5419479DB4C4E637FB216331"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible individual, to construct a principal residence, including purchasing land, site preparation, design costs, permitting costs, and other expenses incurred to carry out such construction, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H278B46F572B146EDA8E5F31BBFBE374F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for any expense relating to a principal residence of the account beneficiary acquired or constructed when such account beneficiary was an eligible individual during the 3-year period beginning on the date—</text> <clause id="H94843717441D45F7A5F9807D16DB0174"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of the acquisition of such principal residence, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAE3EB6BDA3B24499B9A98AA57F83AD71"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a principal residence constructed by the taxpayer, the date on which such construction was completed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CB8C8EA217C461F80F4BB9427B9E11E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Account beneficiary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>account beneficiary</quote> means the individual on whose behalf the first-time homebuyer savings account was established.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5C4D059AA14442FAE58E3131AE999A9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Principal residence</header><text>The term <quote>principle residence</quote> has the same meaning as when used in section 121.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H290739056F1440D5A5CAE91E31E711DB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Publication of national average single family home price</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall, not later than December 31 of each calendar year, publish the estimated national average price of a single family home for the following calendar year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2676A43F0F9F402C81DF93D8C8A57D0D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rollover contribution</header><text>The term <quote>rollover contribution</quote> means an amount paid or distributed from a first-time homebuyer savings account to the account beneficiary to the extent that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF64A83BF9C3D40CA9FCCB13BB4D9DB95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount received is paid into a first-time homebuyer savings account for the benefit of such beneficiary not later than the 60th day after the day on which the beneficiary receives the payment or distribution, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H21F68E01E2744FBEA2670D0336FD6F21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such account beneficiary did not receive any other amount described in subparagraph (A) from a first-time homebuyer savings account which was not includible in the individual’s gross income because of subsection (d)(2)(B) during the 1-year period ending on the date of such receipt.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H100822C6257A4D0DBA1730F510261901" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contribution limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate amount of contributions for any calendar year to all first-time homebuyer savings accounts maintained for the benefit of an individual shall not exceed $10,000.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC752BE3C986A4F8A83D908F83DBF3CA0" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on modified adjusted gross income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a taxpayer whose adjusted gross income for the taxable year exceeds $200,000 (twice such amount in the case of a joint return), no deduction shall be allowed under subsection (a) for such taxable year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HED53D51464174F0C8565243FF2B76AA8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of distributions</header> <paragraph id="HFC0326B0BFB7468C9A539F8008E42F77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts used for qualified homebuyer expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amount paid or distributed out of a first-time homebuyer savings account which is used exclusively to pay qualified homebuyer expenses shall not be includible in gross income.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4ACD9F254A6407B9F921B39BE356891"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of amounts not used for qualified homebuyer expenses</header><text>Any amount paid or distributed out of a first-time homebuyer savings account which is not—</text> <subparagraph id="H302D51D5B340448A877DD988DF3EA50D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used exclusively to pay the qualified homebuyer expenses of the account beneficiary,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B5C5B8D2D3B4A8EAEC52645312D4870"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a rollover contribution, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C2E188ECD9A4876833154AD5DD4E09A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a transfer made under subsection (g),</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall be included in the gross income of such beneficiary and the amount of any tax imposed by this chapter shall be increased by 10 percent on any amount so includible.</continuation-text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF1FE225CDD74DE6AF719B8C822E9D0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Excess contributions returns before due date of return</header> 
<subparagraph id="HBB8D2C962E644E71B0694F11A4DC0833"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any excess contribution is contributed for a taxable year to any first-time homebuyer savings account of an individual, paragraph (2) shall not apply to distributions from the first-time homebuyer savings accounts of such individual (to the extent such distributions do not exceed the aggregate excess contributions to all such accounts of such individual for such year) if—</text> <clause id="HCD12B0B5CFCF4D808143886B5532A6D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such distribution is received by the individual on or before the last day prescribed by law (including extensions of time) for filing such individual's return for such taxable year, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBB000386AD26453EAC7825EAD790AF6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such distribution is accompanied by the amount of net income attributable to such excess contribution.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any net income described in clause (ii) shall be included in the gross income of the individual for the taxable year in which it is received.</continuation-text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B6D0A0FEC284558B0B7E447E71F7619"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess contribution defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>excess contribution</quote> means any contribution (other than a rollover contribution) which is not excludable from gross income under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE67975ACB72942E080A7856ECBDF6DFF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Tax treatment of account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A first-time homebuyer savings account is exempt from taxation under this subtitle unless such account has ceased to be a first-time homebuyer savings account. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, any such account is subject to the taxes imposed by section 511 (relating to imposition of tax on unrelated business income of charitable, etc. organizations).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD0E6A0AFA63548FF97F0EDF55A614CC0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Treatment of account after acquisition of residential property</header> <paragraph id="H5236F4EEB3334526919BFEDF9B4E4458"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an account beneficiary who acquires (or whose spouse acquires) a present ownership interest in a residential property such individual may transfer amounts in the first-time homebuyer savings account of such individual or such individual’s spouse to an individual retirement account (as defined in section 408(a)) of such individual or such individual’s spouse during the 180 day period beginning on the date on which the 3-year period described in subsection (b)(3)(C) ends with respect to such acquisition.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDAAAC34863E424F960F6CF5B0A7CBC1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>A first-time homebuyer savings account shall cease to be a first-time homebuyer savings account on the first day after the 180 day period described in paragraph (1) and amounts in such account shall be treated as distributed to the account beneficiary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1E531483A4F94BAAA9F22B7494518508"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Payment to first-Time homebuyer savings account not treated as wages</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3121(a) of such Code is amended—</text>
                <paragraph id="H09BA9E48489C4A55A381DDFD34DCF842" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (22)(B), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a comma,</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H5AF30CBB71A74CB0B7B69980DBCDF4A3" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (23), by striking <quote>section section 139B(a).</quote> and inserting <quote>section 139B(a), or</quote>, and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4AD175EF8ABE4F81B39BDABE702CC879" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after paragraph (23) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD29EA93CEA71430685AB55A1D8198BB3"> <paragraph id="HBFBE3636048149B2A696C646A5C8FEED"> <enum>(24)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amount which is excludible from gross income of the employee under section 225A(a).</text>
                        </paragraph>
                        <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                    </quoted-block>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9BEA3B6B1609495C84E34F9C9FC588BD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tax on excess contributions</header> 
<paragraph id="HCCFE7E56A08044DDB1D336FA7812C9E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4973(a) of such Code is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HC48FD00E045842B0AAAA3F8584466B63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>or</quote>,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49EA51394B784DD88D14E2F07C328065"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the comma, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C2D7E9BE971475D9734562FD0C68830"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8F2B74E4209448C8B2081B257693ACCD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HDD129E8DC93E4467A1AFA7C61F493AFD"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a first-time homebuyer savings account (within the meaning of section 225A(b)(1)),</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C91998CAC4344C0BBD4C9DDB6794714"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of excess contribution in 4973</header><text>Section 4973 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBAB8F16CE69E408D9A20BCF25230D366" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H9AD2D95FB2A7489297BA2C03E7BDE64A">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
                            <header>Excess contributions to first-Time homebuyer savings
                                account</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, in the case of a first-time homebuyer savings account (within the meaning of section 225A(b)(1)), the term <quote>excess contribution</quote> means the amount by which the amount contributed for the taxable year to such account exceeds the contribution limit under 225A(c)(1).</text>
                        </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F9FE021AB314864A552AE6AF3C32952"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part VII of subchapter B of chapter 1 of subtitle A of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 225 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H447D7AD01D0A4B8BAE1DE968A49F97EC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="yes-regeneration"> <toc-entry idref="H51648BE857DC449580679A43DA56951F" level="section">Sec. 225A. First-time homebuyer savings account.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB287A28025154632A2C41568BBF03D51"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

