<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBDA2A7BF9C084069B6492841D90100CE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9193 IH: Powering the Future of American Space Dominance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9193</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance NASA’s use of nuclear propulsion and power systems for deep space exploration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H30930CFC1D5642F8BD5DE33CF19E1AC7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H25A46A7080E84B28ADE72A417A708BAF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Powering the Future of American Space Dominance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H99CDAF77ECF04982BFDF0080B03A8DDD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Space nuclear power and propulsion systems</header> <subsection id="H9791EB660A284A74B7BAA80E3B6779EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H80D3D0871A1848799560C159F9F3371C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>space nuclear systems are a key enabling technology for deep space human and robotic missions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H213F024400DE479C9BE6576DE4AF4A6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>development of space nuclear systems will require long-term commitment and investment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF63F31B05B064EF29090919A11466A1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advancing space nuclear systems could support the National Aeronautics and Space Administration’s (NASA’s) efforts to ensure technological readiness for Moon and Mars missions and other deep space exploration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H567AF4FB00E449569AADD412ED8255EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>radioisotope heater units and electric radioisotope power systems represent proven, near-term technologies capable of enabling lunar night survival and sustained surface operations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41620B7D95C14B2E89CF9F7045C64B12"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">NASA and the Department of Energy have a long history of collaboration on the development of space nuclear power and propulsion systems.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB39A034A194F42F78F5E7238E99ABB3F" commented="no"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Plans</header> <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate an update to each of the plans required under subsections (a)(3) and (b)(2) of section 10841 of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/51/20301">51 U.S.C. 20301</external-xref> note), which shall include information relating to the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H26F143F3E729467596A068833F29A966" commented="no">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The status of and progress made with respect to the space nuclear propulsion program under subsection (a)(2) of such section.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE96FE125B653489EB785B80E40677138" commented="no">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the potential near-term use cases of nuclear systems for NASA missions, including how such systems could be used on commercial lunar payload services missions for lunar night survival, and an estimate of associated costs.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HD6C2E95418154AEAB6446D5FD45B8E0E" commented="no">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>The status of the in-space demonstration of a nuclear propulsion system in the late 2020s, including remaining milestones and estimated dates for completion of each such milestone.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H344A798662654163AFD454575773C85B" commented="no">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposed phased program for use of radioisotope heater units and electric radioisotope power systems to further the goals of the Moon to Mars Program and the commercial lunar payload services program, including the following:</text>
          <subparagraph id="H05026C474FC44907BEEE579C0850A0AE" commented="no">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>Demonstrations of radioisotope heater units for lunar night survival by not later than December 31, 2028, and of radioisotope power systems by not later than December 31, 2030.</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H8000BD89304E427C817B0B6B478BE216" commented="no">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>Routine use of such systems for lunar night survival and operations by not later than December 31, 2032.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H855BEB66D075442CAE35AAA470638A53" commented="no">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of follow-on activities for the Harmonia Radioisotope Power System project for demonstration and deployments, including a timeline and plan for first deployment on the lunar surface.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H58B82F68AD924E8BB99E5C42467F9B63" commented="no">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>An assessment of the readiness to launch a derivative fission surface power system by December 31, 2030, for deployment on the surface of the Moon.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H84BF1553044140F7B43825853175CA99" commented="no">
          <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>A description of current and planned NASA efforts to engage with Federal departments and agencies and private sector entities on the development and demonstration of space nuclear systems and technologies.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HABF6ED14C0D940C5A52C559831241584" commented="no">
          <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>A plan for the use of previously developed NASA hardware, as appropriate.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H0D9828E6E1D141A48A62BC121E278C18" commented="no"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Lessons learned assessment</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a lessons learned assessment derived from the joint NASA–DARPA Demonstration Rocket for Agile Cislunar Operations program. Such assessment shall identify the following:</text>
        <paragraph id="H25D098E345E34BAF9F745420E8F58F5D" commented="no">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The technical, programmatic, governance, acquisition, and interagency coordination failures that contributed to the inability to execute a flight demonstration.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H6A807D84F74D48929453C3EB5BCACB18" commented="no">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The corrective actions the Administrator of NASA has taken or will take to prevent recurrence of such failures in future space nuclear power and propulsion programs.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="HB8204720C3D84658BCCD09E0D020D64C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Lunar surface power</header> 
<subsection id="H34E3B202060941B08BAA3AE8B7FF7D56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H512554FDC7D64AC6B4984E86BCC2740E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increased access to reliable power could further NASA goals of carrying out robust human and robotic exploration of the Moon and other deep space destinations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1A347655C20495597A6C60A7E4148A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commercial entities seek to deploy technologies such as solar arrays, nuclear reactors, and radioisotope power systems to the surface of the Moon for the purpose of providing power for lunar activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A4841368CF24C39A35DA8DA9AD2E557"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leveraging commercially developed power infrastructure to carry out Moon to Mars program activities could allow NASA to increase efficiency and reduce costs of such missions, and encourage commercial entities to accelerate the deployment of lunar power sources.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8F6544A1B8664005B710E27318754B45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on power demand</header> 
<paragraph id="H2C0D6351EDB64EA2BC40A7576390A97C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of NASA shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the non-governmental entity under subsection (c) a report that forecasts the demand for power, including heat and electricity, of NASA for operations on the lunar surface during the 10-year period beginning on such date of enactment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12B0F062B26E407C8AD3A86D1A1C1D2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9A41CAEE26E142E697A708D0122CBCB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the power demand of NASA for operations on the lunar surface for—</text> <clause id="HD67771BCB1A54A72A24F890AD2C25B16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>near-term exploration activities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5E2F9D348F0F4BA9A076784BD4DEB162"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>long-duration surface activities; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2959EF19897641A8A8488FFA0CE19F64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>activities intended to be conducted throughout the lunar night; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF425A145286C4C32ADAF5EF6FE68CBB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include an assessment of—</text> <clause id="H18C8C0DB2AA244E9BA96BC4D9BAF366B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the projected power needs for both human and robotic NASA operations on the lunar surface; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC04DB09ED7AE4CD5A512ACC7FBB08D27" commented="no">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the power needs of commercial entities engaged in activities to support NASA operations.</text>
                        </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2FE21F8EFB74FA2A489923417F2BCFF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA2A85F7D71924029BD10C590BF4D1FBC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Lunar power purchase agreement feasibility study</header> <paragraph id="H91326EEDABEC4A03A83EADDF3FAD533C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of NASA may enter into an arrangement with an non-governmental entity with appropriate expertise to conduct a study evaluating the feasibility of using power purchase agreements to facilitate the private sector development and deployment of lunar surface power capabilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D27EC3597E3449A8209ED74677D5F6D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall consider the results of the report required under subsection (b), and may include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H756955998BE649A585CBB115F0985947" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An identification of facilities and technical capabilities needed to support lunar surface power production.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75B7AC29975F4038ACA013FB0E2992C2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description and assessment of the types and technical readiness of technologies that could be used to provide the United States with access to lunar surface power, and an estimated timeline of availability of such technologies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E45EEADDD0945C19596667025F137B8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An identification of lessons learned from Federal Government experience with power purchase agreements, including a description of any relevant Federal Government use of such agreements, and a description of how such lessons learned could inform or be applied to future such agreements.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1278C315272342099A6ACA9E41261898" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Potential policy and legal issues associated with lunar power purchase agreements between providers and the Federal Government, international partners, and other private sector entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDC5B99D6B46455B909AA6124C7042F3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of NASA shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that describes the results of the study under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8043CCB94E2483FAAA1DEC5024DA8F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agreements</header> 
<paragraph id="HD8A88DA777EE4E809267428985195354"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on the results of the report under subsection (b), the study under subsection (c), and consultation under each of such subsections, the Administrator of NASA may, through an open and competitive solicitation process, enter into an agreement with not fewer than two private sector entities that utilize not fewer than two different energy technologies, for the purpose of procuring power systems or acquiring power on the lunar surface.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0012EF14591F425D8335C5B22E2A56DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of NASA shall ensure any agreement entered into under paragraph (1) satisfies the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC4544A22A04248BE86D29A9C539AE100"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Includes the right of the Administrator to terminate such agreement if the private sector entity concerned is unable to commence the delivery of power on the lunar surface by the date that is four years after the date on which such an agreement is entered into.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65891A4EFB074F2B88E84DBB1A965FBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Does not allow for payment in excess of ten percent of the contract value to be made before power is provided to NASA, or a NASA-sponsored entity, on the lunar surface.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BF312DC38404E3F80AE83AA26DD761B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sunset</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9FADD9C185FF4557989C8C829592BBB4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to enter into agreements under paragraph (1) shall terminate on October 1, 2030.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF8CDFB6316344BA9DF3564FA5C449F0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Saving provision</header><text>An agreement entered into under paragraph (1) that is entered into before the date of termination specified in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<clause id="H060745746DFC4173999C7F9AF6008E85"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not be affected by such termination; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA6C35BD0A4FE4C21B4F1D0E1D5E20CE4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall continue until the conclusion of such agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5950A80B155E4DCBA873656429319ADE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In preparing the report under subsection (b)(1) and conducting the study under subsection (c)(1), the Administrator of NASA may consult with the following:</text> <paragraph id="HE872E2DC9D564A2592B339E6B95291A8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Lunar Surface Innovation Consortium.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5751F59F7BEC484F8F20206A549768B9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other Federal departments or agencies, as determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D22CF5DA3D642D7A4CCC557909DBF1E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>International partners.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9A92ECFE65243969C1F9DFA173B65A9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Relevant private sector entities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE4FB30226A714D1682598798D3EA943E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report risk management approaches for commercial partners supporting NASA space nuclear activities</header> <subsection id="HE75EAF7B318841EB92B2D21764CCE812" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of NASA, in consultation with the head of any other appropriate Federal agency, shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report reviewing existing frameworks for, and proposing new frameworks for, indemnification of commercial partners supporting NASA space nuclear activities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H60E48001967A4210A360E8D233A169F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HB8C2CE0C15B14E2587F3C46C47417B52" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An evaluation of the existing statutory and regulatory authorities under which NASA or another appropriate Federal agency may provide indemnification or other liability protection related to the use of space nuclear systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59534909ADAA4AF987EE69B980C6E5EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of gaps, or areas lacking clarity on implementation, in the current indemnification framework for civil activities involving commercial partners, including relating to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H78B8258C0AFE40C3975FE6C32448C9CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Radioisotope power systems.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94AE6DA8639846A69CC3C910F2188880"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Fission surface power systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7536137C47C04D439F75E7AFF2A49235"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nuclear electric or thermal propulsion systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H744E25AB18E24B28B0C947ADEE9A588C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of potential solutions to address such gaps or areas, or otherwise enable use of existing authorities, including relating to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H929080D51B474BBC9DB1FF756AD2FC5B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Indemnification under section 20138 of title 51, United States Code, and <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/804">Public Law 85–804</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1431">50 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB54B41B3C34A422881D7738C20080F29" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The applicability of authorities under part 440 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, for nuclear systems launched on commercially procured launch vehicles.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H097447C44CC44BB0B46EA2D719859846" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Extension of coverage under section 170 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2210">42 U.S.C. 2210</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79F722D9513A49DF82215E34B27E7DEC" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for legislative or regulatory changes to ensure appropriate use of existing indemnification mechanisms, or for the development of new statutory authorities or risk-sharing mechanisms, for commercial partners supporting NASA space nuclear activities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8B9AC8F9E0C64D73876750C1BD6544EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall address indemnification considerations for the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H23C400741EFC415196F68FFAF0F43D58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States Government-sponsored missions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3C1228AAE684B2E9C7A569030CB2E0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Missions conducted through public-private partnerships and commercially procured services, including technology demonstrations and operational capability deployments in cislunar space, on the lunar surface, or beyond low-Earth orbit.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6936196B6CAE4D1989D0EA7F40D5C317"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

