<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD3E7480DDA2A4E0988CAA80225CF390E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 77 IH: Authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the lying in state of the remains of Army Major Jeffrey R. O’Brien, Captain Cody A. Khork, Chief Warrant Officer 3 Robert M. Marzan, Sergeant First Class Noah L. Tietjens, Sergeant First Class Nicole M. Amor, Sergeant Declan J. Coady, and Sergeant Benjamin N. Pennington.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 77</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>) submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Authorizing the use of the rotunda of the Capitol for the lying in state of the remains of Army Major Jeffrey R. O’Brien, Captain Cody A. Khork, Chief Warrant Officer 3 Robert M. Marzan, Sergeant First Class Noah L. Tietjens, Sergeant First Class Nicole M. Amor, Sergeant Declan J. Coady, and Sergeant Benjamin N. Pennington.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H29840800F8A84B0DB95B7C36AD9C01AE"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HEDDBFCC28D784A29A06C5DAD7007C5CE"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That in recognition of Army Major Jeffrey R. O’Brien, Captain Cody A. Khork, Chief Warrant Officer 3 Robert M. Marzan, Sergeant First Class Noah L. Tietjens, Sergeant First Class Nicole M. Amor, Sergeant Declan J. Coady, and Sergeant Benjamin N. Pennington, who served with distinction in support of Operation Epic Fury, whose remains shall be permitted to lie in state in the rotunda of the Capitol on a date to be determined by the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Architect of the Capitol, under the direction of the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives, shall take all necessary steps for the accomplishment of that purpose. </text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

