<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY26291-RX5-PN-S2Y" key="G" star-print="first-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4106 IS: Rx Access, Choice, Cost Equity, and Supply Stability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4106</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260317">March 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve access to certain medications under the TRICARE program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF2111B3DBA25464B8EC0089C6EB7FAC7"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEA3CFB2F547A44428423C00CAC727995"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rx Access, Choice, Cost Equity, and Supply Stability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Rx ACCESS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB970727F29714253948B87DCBB9B8171"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements relating to access, fairness, and transparency under TRICARE pharmacy benefits program</header><subsection id="H00EF7751CFBC4541BDD33AD6EA92BA12"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Beneficiary election of prescription refill means</header><text>Section 1074g(a)(9) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE8F8771A0999480DAD65A01CD71C318B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, and ending on October 1, 2026</quote> after <quote>Beginning on October 1, 2015</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4324AFC3012D4CE9986FB9E8B8EA0DDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69663B05386D41A991D12AA28ECE0100"><subparagraph id="HFCE4A092AE0E436FB0DB1E4AAC3F0057" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on October 1, 2026, an eligible covered beneficiary may elect to receive non-generic prescription maintenance medications through any means described in paragraph (2)(E).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7C03DC9CC3749E9B1C0ED79BD274FBF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefit manager reimbursement standards; independent audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1074g of title 10, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H187DAB2D8E864CA1A26B761513458F66"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (i) and (j) as subsections (j) and (k), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67767D96ABDF48F7AACAC73C835E1F92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (h) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75B73FB6F07746F097A35A8A7E7B6519"><subsection id="HF8561D085EE449B09A5E4B9756DF7BD5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefit manager reimbursement standards</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDEDE94AD69BC4E00AB920DB39651EED2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, as a condition of any contract entered into for the administration of the pharmacy benefits program, reimbursement to a retail pharmacy described in subsection (a)(2)(E)(ii) for a pharmaceutical agent provided under such program shall be an amount that is equal to not less than the sum of—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7973C30E96AD48558A16034680E15E4A" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either—</text><clause id="H16C9CE709DE746AEAEB210631D1C48E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the actual cost to the pharmacy of acquiring such pharmaceutical agent from a wholesaler, or</text></clause><clause id="H20308701757C435D99D470462CFEB14B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a pharmaceutical agent included on the national average drug acquisition cost index published by the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, a proxy amount calculated at a rate that is not lower than the national average acquisition cost for such pharmaceutical agent, as identified on such cost index as of the date of the adjudication of the claim for such reimbursement, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H241DF5D58FF7426887EBC0D80CBA8DD5" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a professional dispensing fee that is equal to the professional dispensing fee paid by the State in which the pharmacy is located under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) for dispensing a prescription drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F2DC3FAEFEC478088C8E59434DC32C2" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The contractor administering the pharmacy benefits program may not impose any fees on a retail pharmacy described in subsection (a)(2)(E)(ii), including point-of-sale fees, retroactive fees, or other indirect or hidden fees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D173F4993B7486C883AD75DD91AEF47" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H37DBB56638A542B1B80377CA7450CC82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not less frequently than annually, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><clause id="HDFB3932D9D3C4125B5542C0D98FE36C4" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an audit of—</text><subclause id="H049DF4A37F614D5A8FAEFF3522433EFC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>data reported by the contractor responsible for the administration of the pharmacy benefits program relating to the rates of reimbursement under paragraph (1) and any price concessions; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HFF68EB68BEB74850AFC1C7BC5ADDD29D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the adequacy of the retail pharmacy network under the TRICARE program and access by eligible covered beneficiaries to such network, including with respect to continuity of care, geographic accessibility (taking into account factors in addition to travel time to and from a pharmacy, with special consideration for rural and underserved areas), and the extent to which elections by such beneficiaries under subsection (a)(9) reflect personal preference; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB74B79D58B7F4FE0A03FD9CA4C619FD3" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit the results of such audit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7914438F645E47838D75527FF791992E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that, as a condition of any contract entered into for the administration of the pharmacy benefits program, the contractor provides the Comptroller General information required to conduct the audit under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35136938336E4342A581F78B2A298654"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code) a plan for the implementation of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

