<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-KAT26106-FP3-01-NDK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 625 IS: Designating February 2026 as “Hawaiian Language Month” or “‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 625</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating February 2026 as <quote>Hawaiian Language Month</quote> or <quote>‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Hawaiian language, or ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i—</text><paragraph id="idb19d8a28c24a4af6943039be4c6cbd3a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is the Native language of Native Hawaiians, the aboriginal, Indigenous people who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3bb8c83b780a4b4bab43f63f4d3b61a8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">settled the Hawaiian archipelago as early as 2,000 years ago, over which they exercised sovereignty; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id164342eacfba470dbdde7594824c440c"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">over time, founded the Kingdom of Hawai‘i; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b972fba17644d7bbfd6c06c37f4c26a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was once widely spoken by Native Hawaiians and non-Native Hawaiians throughout the Kingdom of Hawai‘i, which held one of the highest literacy rates in the world prior to the illegal overthrow of the Kingdom of Hawai‘i in 1893 and the establishment of the Republic of Hawai‘i;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of Hawai‘i enacted a law in 1896 effectively banning school instructional use of ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i, a law that continued in effect over the generations-long territorial period;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Republic of Hawai‘i banned the use of ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i to communicate and punished children for speaking ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i in schools and on the playground;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas parallel to the Federal efforts to eliminate Native American languages spoken by Indian Tribes, the ban on the use of ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i led to the near extinction of the Hawaiian language by the 1980s, when fewer than 50 fluent speakers under 18 years old remained;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the 1960s, Native Hawaiians have led a grassroots revitalization of their Native language, launching a number of historic initiatives, including—</text><paragraph id="id339b9990c2b94c71b2d1f49ecb8b5488"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Hawaiian language course and degree programs through the University of Hawai‘i system;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b857e6c7fb7414a90a4fb17b59c1d97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the statewide Hawaiian language immersion preschools created by the Native Hawaiian nonprofit ‘Aha Pūnana Leo, combining speakers and non-speakers in language nests;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5d97edeb3c584e0f9caa7cc0fc9c675c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Hawai‘i State Department of Education Hawaiian language immersion program developed from a base of ‘Aha Pūnana Leo graduates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fa5c71aafa54aa491b3c98a186a7266"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the research conducted by the Hawaiian language college at the University of Hawai‘i at Hilo relating to Indigenous language immersion teacher training, curriculum materials, and best practices, which allowed the State of Hawai‘i to develop an integrated preschool through doctorate Hawaiian immersion program;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Hawaiian language revitalization movement inspired systemic Native language policy reform, including—</text><paragraph id="idb2a91d229bc3456286fb14ba9d557510"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State of Hawai‘i recognizing ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i as an official language in the Constitution of the State of Hawai‘i through a majority vote of its Hawaiian and non-Hawaiian citizenry in 1978;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3485ea2baa94bac99bb5e24e9499d51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State of Hawai‘i removing the 90-year ban on teaching ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i in public and private schools in 1986;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id329b316f09654095ac5005cce80e84fa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the bipartisan enactment of the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2901">25 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.</external-xref>) in 1990, which established the policy of the United States to preserve, protect, and promote the rights and freedom of Native Americans to use, practice, and develop Native American languages, including the Native Hawaiian language; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id688f0bb712f84b6fa1ea17d41983c686"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the State of Hawai‘i designating the month of February as <quote>‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i Month</quote> to celebrate and encourage the use of the Hawaiian language;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the enactment of the Native American Language Resource Center Act of 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7457">20 U.S.C. 7457</external-xref>) in 2023—</text><paragraph id="ida55bc0ba8c5e4330bf30ce252af2028f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reconfirmed a Federal commitment to revitalizing Native American languages, including the Hawaiian language; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id33b1cb0e6c304b58a928caffc5b1bed0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">resulted in the Department of Education awarding the Hawaiian language college at the University of Hawai‘i at Hilo a 5-year grant to establish and lead the first National Native American Language Resource Center with State and Tribal college and university partners to support the revitalization of other Native American languages through expertise and best practices; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the enactment of numerous laws by Congress over many decades to promote education, Native American language revitalization, and cultural preservation recognizes and implements the special political and trust relationship with the Native Hawaiian Community: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idabf1205c84714b8bb63b4478f3f34648"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates February 2026 as <quote>Hawaiian Language Month</quote> or <quote>‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8063d9e496af48f6890f3bf5a89fc092"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commits to preserving, protecting, and promoting the use, practice, and development of ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i in alignment with the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2901">25 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13f864676f1e49bf97e91303261f18c0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the people of the United States and interested groups to celebrate ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i Month with appropriate activities and programs to demonstrate support for ‘Ōlelo Hawai‘i.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

