<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H0C7F1F825369473082AB117F47CE3C58" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6550 RH: American Financial Institution Regulatory Sovereignty and Transparency Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 454</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6550</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–529]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000583">Mr. Loudermilk</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on December 10, 2025</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require annual reporting on interactions between Federal banking supervisory agencies and global financial regulatory or supervisory forums, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H54A5751A35A94844B6ED597E8A49261F"><section id="H56E80B0815AF4B9BBE0E329709271D9C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Financial Institution Regulatory Sovereignty and Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>American FIRST Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB04BA204ACFE4CCD9430835AA878D757"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual reporting on interactions between Federal banking supervisory agencies and global financial regulatory or supervisory forums</header><subsection id="H84120C483BCB4F60A1CE4C078DFCD67E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The seventh undesignated paragraph of section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/247">12 U.S.C. 247</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA55DE0D273E340EE9C85875AA28CB8A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Board</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H917AC64038DE475692CC0CC3FEA70644" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><paragraph id="H255C3873D02E44E188BE5C8DB629A20F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Annual report</header><subparagraph id="H4B112029E2754AA5BD1634735E8E2078"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC08210F1779249A0A26CC7DE2736F4DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10D6DF705E2E4562BFD29A54F83F97B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7DEBC27D63484AD6972BD54C710AC230" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><subparagraph id="H0D886EE0092A4D4491C52C629EF97577"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interactions with global financial regulatory or supervisory forums</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include a description of the Board’s interactions with global financial regulatory or supervisory forums, including—</text><clause id="H4ECEB6529D4941FBBA60B1726E9EBEB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forums in which the Board maintained membership during the period covered by the report; and</text></clause><clause id="HB27D2335A9D34EEDBA2D7E338B51B513"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each such global financial regulatory or supervisory forum in the list provided pursuant to clause (i)—</text><subclause id="H8363CA8ACEF344CFAFCDB12CF312D17C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the general purposes of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including a list of the current members and observers of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum;</text></subclause><subclause id="H39968B4672674A30A65A5D15CF35B2A5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a discussion of how the general purposes of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum align with the purposes of this Act and the other Acts that the Board implements;</text></subclause><subclause id="H457C495BBEA449859D72B93C421667C0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an identification of the sources that provided a material amount of funding for the operations of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></subclause><subclause id="H61B55D77F71D45EE8C60DEE9C9F49F0C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a description of the organization the Board maintained during the period covered by the report to conduct interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including an organizational chart and an identification of the official staff of the Board with oversight responsibility for interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum;</text></subclause><subclause id="H46D5878DEA104043A62A9DF2ACC66A22"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a discussion of the financial regulatory or supervisory standard-setting issues under discussion at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1F94169AADB0416E8DB46A04B4F9FFEA"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a description of the positions taken by representatives of the Board at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report, including the rationale, objectives, and potential impacts of such positions;</text></subclause><subclause id="H47F206BCA4BA43E4B60048A16AB55882"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a summary of the meetings attended by representatives of the Board at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report, including a discussion of the key outcomes from such meetings;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8F41218AE6C943479CD3826CA227CF2A"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the text of any final policies, standards, or recommendations adopted by the global financial supervisory or regulatory forum during the period covered by the report, including any implementing material, annex, appendix, side letter, or similar document entered into contemporaneously or in conjunction with the underlying policy, standard, or recommendation, or an identification of a publicly available source for the text of such policy, standard, recommendation, or implementing material;</text></subclause><subclause id="H38EDF7CFF1B043299B8CDC2A97977784"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>a description of any amendments to Federal statutes, regulations of the Board, guidance of the Board, or changes to the Board’s supervisory practices the Board anticipates will be necessary to implement any final policies, standards, or recommendations adopted by the global financial supervisory or regulatory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF10F6D2703624DFAAB7F83AA419A1FCE"><enum>(X)</enum><text>a discussion of rules proposed, rules under consideration, final rules adopted, guidance proposed, guidance under consideration, final guidance adopted, or any other similar actions taken by the Board during the period covered by the report to implement agreements of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including an economic impact analysis and a justification for why the expected costs of implementing actions are at least offset by the expected benefits related to economic, national security, financial stability, or other national interests; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6CF33F9BE03A49EDAFD611EF80AED8A5"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>such other information relating to interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report separately requested in writing by the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate or the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC298D151DA9436F817AF68512F1FF2D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Global financial regulatory or supervisory forum defined</header><clause id="H7DFB34DCC8E14461BBFE16B4B6E1946B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>global financial regulatory or supervisory forum</quote> means any association or union of nations through or by which two or more foreign authorities engage in some aspect of their conduct of international affairs regarding financial supervision and regulation, including—</text><subclause id="H7BCFA7F3A2894BC1A8A06EF0D74E82D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Bank for International Settlements;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC2EF6401815A4FBBA702A1FADD39E744"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB156BF48BCF1436E9542CFEEFE4D067C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Financial Stability Board;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD6B180CF542F4A23AB86231B59491234"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the International Association of Insurance Supervisors; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HBA0F36EC673743549EFAA929E36CC25D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Network of Central Banks and Supervisors for Greening the Financial System.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H78C0B3CFD86649CABDE3869317C41B6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <quote>global financial regulatory or supervisory forum</quote> does not include—</text><subclause id="H32D85AC52DC4401E98756E16FC0694E3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>international financial institutions, as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)(2)</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD319F21CB0E94A5AA618405923E177B7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any international organization with respect to which the Board participates pursuant to a treaty to which the United States is a party.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7789958C949540D5A4B4FC4B5A8E5E7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of the Comptroller of the Currency</header><paragraph id="H0D3883AD614E4CFD8A7BD7CA0FCB60EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The second section 333 of the Revised Statutes of the United States (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/14">12 U.S.C. 14</external-xref>; relating to an annual report) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H35EC8519CB3D43A1A34EB8B4A2289238" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><section id="H956B8AE11E0F4A1C95323A5746BACD10"><enum>333.</enum><header>Report of Comptroller</header><subsection id="H87E01CD1663742C2B87ED962817BC007"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller of the Currency shall make an annual report to Congress.</text></subsection><subsection id="H960EC1D3829148688422DC13EF23EEAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interactions with global financial regulatory or supervisory forums</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (a) shall include a description of the Comptroller’s interactions with global financial regulatory or supervisory forums, including—</text><paragraph id="H7625E2E8709042469423B70675CEDB93"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forums in which the Comptroller maintained membership during the period covered by the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C468DA171554CBBA5D5420A62F7D398"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each such global financial regulatory or supervisory forum in the list provided pursuant to paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H254BD0414AC542219DBA4D0570856347"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the general purposes of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including a list of the current members and observers of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BB1A2C8B63545CFBC68F020A4B2C45A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a discussion of how the general purposes of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum align with the purposes of this chapter, title LXII, and the other Acts that the Comptroller implements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72440E28250142E6A693D260D8DCB4CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an identification of the sources that provided a material amount of funding for the operations of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35BB9A211A234C6C92B94EE51044C378"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the organization the Comptroller maintained during the period covered by the report to conduct interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including an organizational chart and an identification of the official staff of the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency with oversight responsibility for interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A139CAECAE641D69D2BEC27DC7015F3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a discussion of the financial regulatory or supervisory standard-setting issues under discussion at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68E74A32195F42AB96A9580E6A1A2369"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the positions taken by representatives of the Comptroller at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report, including the rationale, objectives, and potential impacts of such positions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11358CC79A8440D4A024ED859DB2A5A8"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the meetings attended by representatives of the Comptroller at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report, including a discussion of the key outcomes from such meetings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F5D4A681CF54DA3B07D446F20AB6CA6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the text of any final policies, standards, or recommendations adopted by the global financial supervisory or regulatory forum during the period covered by the report, including any implementing material, annex, appendix, side letter, or similar document entered into contemporaneously or in conjunction with the underlying policy, standard, or recommendation, or an identification of a publicly available source for the text of such policy, standard, recommendation, or implementing material;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFF5A4A4E5ED498BB49E7A860FACB8CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any amendments to Federal statutes, regulations of the Comptroller, guidance of the Comptroller, or changes to the Comptroller’s supervisory practices the Comptroller anticipates will be necessary to implement any final policies, standards, or recommendations adopted by the global financial supervisory or regulatory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09BD47B1E30C4C56BB7AAAC842FE7E16"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a discussion of rules proposed, rules under consideration, final rules adopted, guidance proposed, guidance under consideration, final guidance adopted, or any other similar actions taken by the Comptroller during the period covered by the report to implement agreements of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including an economic impact analysis and a justification for why the expected costs of implementing actions are at least offset by the expected benefits related to economic, national security, financial stability, or other national interests; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95B2D086BE7A43B4B5BF9AF38831BC9E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>such other information relating to interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report separately requested in writing by the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate or the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5ED504953954AA69BFE99368E96D6B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Global financial regulatory or supervisory forum defined</header><paragraph id="H5A7D5F5F5AED4C828B4618FD39861F05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>global financial regulatory or supervisory forum</quote> means any association or union of nations through or by which two or more foreign authorities engage in some aspect of their conduct of international affairs regarding financial supervision and regulation, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7A1C293BA6FC43689ADB6513F9AF7D09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Bank for International Settlements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35472345A9644774AB864D1D1B77363C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3A04DB5160D4EB68CFD4A765C482BA1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Financial Stability Board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53256A2A2137412E93196C02E265833B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the International Association of Insurance Supervisors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC27DF1FA7747435495B484736C41C76A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Network of Central Banks and Supervisors for Greening the Financial System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C26ED90CF6749F9BBE0F8B985EE2557"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <quote>global financial regulatory or supervisory forum</quote> does not include—</text><subparagraph id="H53B6B8F1830A4B0497CF8433D2F5CFFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>international financial institutions, as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)(2)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDADDCF7A5B5F4397BA89F792AF4FEFA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any international organization with respect to which the Comptroller participates pursuant to a treaty to which the United States is a party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H59C1F08F885D4D9B8FE33737FAC3CBAC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical correction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter nine of title VII of the Revised Statutes of the United States is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H266B43CFE6BE48A6922708B63515070C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating the first section 333 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/14a">12 U.S.C. 14a</external-xref>; relating to data standards) as section 332;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6150736F901E492DB0D12BCFA4C760C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by moving such section so as to appear after section 331; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EBAC2D877294A169C08A751288631D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the table of contents of such chapter, by amending the item relating to section 332 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H771876302CFF4C2D97FF676CB31803F7" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><toc-entry level="section">332. Data standards; open data publication.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC982CD06EB5439A92C13DE392DC4A47"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 17(a) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1827">12 U.S.C. 1827(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0D2A69A49F534D0CBE39D2B48289B531" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><paragraph id="H1C74593DBD5F492D97E1989D0D5FAC77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interactions with global financial regulatory or supervisory forums</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include a description of the Corporation’s interactions with global financial regulatory or supervisory forums, including—</text><subparagraph id="H609859D39F304FE5A994193A99CF9A5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forums in which the Corporation maintained membership during the period covered by the report; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E97ED440C40435681147A11CFF22F0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each such global financial regulatory or supervisory forum in the list provided pursuant to subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H2595261AD3794CA5A704E420212AAA43"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the general purposes of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including a list of the current members and observers of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum;</text></clause><clause id="HD50A8632EBDD421399FD51469551C3C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a discussion of how the general purposes of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum align with the purposes of this Act and the other Acts that the Corporation implements;</text></clause><clause id="HFBF952527F2F40E7B0100CD96A3BCE06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an identification of the sources that provided a material amount of funding for the operations of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></clause><clause id="HDB4E3DA003B8435A9324FF33F8190C4B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the organization the Corporation maintained during the period covered by the report to conduct interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including an organizational chart and an identification of the official staff of the Corporation with oversight responsibility for interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum;</text></clause><clause id="H470B9F13253A4E559AC30CF0DEA68008"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a discussion of the financial regulatory or supervisory standard-setting issues under discussion at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></clause><clause id="H5225AD2B0A7B4ED0BA2882205FA091A2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the positions taken by representatives of the Corporation at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report, including the rationale, objectives, and potential impacts of such positions;</text></clause><clause id="H048B1873CE674F428EBA0C7F53A37C96"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the meetings attended by representatives of the Corporation at the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report, including a discussion of the key outcomes from such meetings;</text></clause><clause id="H723EF0384E914E01BECD2C63DC8DEC3E"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the text of any final policies, standards, or recommendations adopted by the global financial supervisory or regulatory forum during the period covered by the report, including any implementing material, annex, appendix, side letter, or similar document entered into contemporaneously or in conjunction with the underlying policy, standard, or recommendation, or an identification of a publicly available source for the text of such policy, standard, recommendation, or implementing material;</text></clause><clause id="HC037E7FB84DE47F393E1CD3011C94762"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any amendments to Federal statutes, regulations of the Corporation, guidance of the Corporation, or changes to the Corporation’s supervisory practices the Corporation anticipates will be necessary to implement any final policies, standards, or recommendations adopted by the global financial supervisory or regulatory forum during the period covered by the report;</text></clause><clause id="H0C07794177B64A2494E16CA6C719B82C"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a discussion of rules proposed, rules under consideration, final rules adopted, guidance proposed, guidance under consideration, final guidance adopted, or any other similar actions taken by the Corporation during the period covered by the report to implement agreements of the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum, including an economic impact analysis and a justification for why the expected costs of implementing actions are at least offset by the expected benefits related to economic, national security, financial stability, or other national interests; and</text></clause><clause id="H45C5DD2AF59C4F1D8D635DCF04D8108B"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>such other information relating to interactions with the global financial regulatory or supervisory forum during the period covered by the report separately requested in writing by the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate or the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F935303E8474602BBC65D2E38F92764"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Global financial regulatory or supervisory forum defined</header><subparagraph id="HCF452D94A7CE427CBD52D8C8E78032B0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>global financial regulatory or supervisory forum</quote> means any association or union of nations through or by which two or more foreign authorities engage in some aspect of their conduct of international affairs regarding financial supervision and regulation, including—</text><clause id="H52BE89953D2B452E9DCE816767F03C83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Bank for International Settlements;</text></clause><clause id="H9A92A5B370E94EF584C19E84B1A30017"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision;</text></clause><clause id="H7C58076E16AD44A99FACB8DC4E245F81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Financial Stability Board;</text></clause><clause id="HD2393C8A3FFE4E8EAF8843CEFD92FFE5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the International Association of Insurance Supervisors; and</text></clause><clause id="HDFD8163D49BD485D955DEF2A7DDB8141"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Network of Central Banks and Supervisors for Greening the Financial System.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA2A7698F3C745E2A1D4355941976FC5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <quote>global financial regulatory or supervisory forum</quote> does not include—</text><clause id="H15616B662A82496F861DA3A650C47388"><enum>(i)</enum><text>international financial institutions, as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)(2)</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="HC089E6450F2E4E978942704E0AACC876"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any international organization with respect to which the Corporation participates pursuant to a treaty to which the United States is a party.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HC966EA232B5D4165A9ED2E952E2E240D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Biannual congressional testimony on interactions with global financial regulatory or supervisory forums</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (12) of section 10 of the Federal Reserve Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/247b">12 U.S.C. 247b</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>and with respect to the conduct of interactions at global financial regulatory or supervisory forums (as defined in paragraph (7)(C))</quote>.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

