<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H373DF41A13C845E89ED15ED6AE952A77" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9506 IH: To amend the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 to require the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to establish a prize competition program relating to artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9506</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 to require the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to establish a prize competition program relating to artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD7B2009055646EFA7D75AA2B9C4157A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H67ED55A2029745CBB9B346C24025540A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Federal grand challenges in artificial intelligence</header> 
<subsection id="H945DF5837B0B475F973F9ABABDDB18C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="H561256AB00F14738A531C0A91FFA4F92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National artificial intelligence initiative</header><text>Title LI of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9411">15 U.S.C. 9411 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="HA5BB216C39BB459294F3F12B5668E404" style="OLC"> <section id="H84F7E30412014086925728CF977C875F"><enum>5107.</enum><header>Federal grand challenges in artificial intelligence</header> <subsection id="HA741C8EC111A402E915727D0581B2DF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>), acting through the National Science and Technology Council and the Interagency Committee, shall establish a prize competition program pursuant to section 24 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3719">15 U.S.C. 3719</external-xref>), for the following purposes:</text> 
<paragraph id="H132B544B6FE4417E9445C0B2F0809322"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Expediting the development of artificial intelligence systems in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8E18699DE2F4FEEAA0C1743662061EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Stimulating artificial intelligence research, development, and commercialization that solves or advances specific, well-defined, and measurable challenges in at least one of the priorities in the list under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD4CBEEC2B71C4AE89C6E210290663F06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of priorities</header> 
<paragraph id="H372A7263586D47D4B54DECB4A843F900"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director, in consultation with industry, civil society, and academia, shall establish, and annually review and update as the Director considers appropriate, a list of priorities consistent with the purposes under subsection (a), for the program under such subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79B76C1392E9404788679905F97C972F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The list under paragraph (1) may include the following priorities:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA1C24BBF2F394F47881008359984100E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To overcome challenges with the engineering of and applied research on microelectronics, including through the integration of artificial intelligence with emerging technologies, such as neuromorphic and quantum computing, or with respect to physical limits on transistors, advanced interconnects, and memory elements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C82B29BCD2F4D30A33BFF1F062AFCA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To promote transformational or long-term advancements in computing and artificial intelligence technologies through any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H3E7E98520037481297ABF645BBBE8B53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Next-generation algorithm design.</text></clause> <clause id="HAD9C8B5FE8CD487495DAC347662BFAD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Next-generation compute capability.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H773C6403C8584BB7A932E4302E8DD426"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Generative and adaptive artificial intelligence for design applications.</text></clause> <clause id="HBE0CAB4382B54A63A4F3485B701449AD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Photonics-based microprocessors and optical communication networks, including electrophotonics.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4D88528FB7E740FBA5A02919B5916790"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The chemistry and physics of new materials.</text></clause> <clause id="H6F9CD23C1B8145AD9A0365BA54D6B705"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Biotechnology, such as modeling a single cell.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0F801A2E078D44D6AE32EFD8FECF8D41"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Energy utilization or energy efficiency.</text></clause> <clause id="HF5A2A4428FD24FAFBAF4CFA26FF11FFA"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Techniques to establish cryptographically secure content provenance information.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H87E06D4CE2814F829EEDAB8821E17778"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Safety and controls for artificial intelligence applications.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F625B14BCB3478A92FCBFD5883DC1A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To promote explainability and mechanistic interpretability of artificial intelligence systems.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE7E11B16F1A841048DB7DF9888D074B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To advance fundamental understanding of artificial intelligence, including through breakthroughs in theoretical, computational, and experimental methods that discover new and transformative paradigms that explain the advanced capabilities of artificial intelligence in domains such as the following:</text> <clause id="HFEB989F4FF2D4FE6AD182A627ACCDCA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Interpretability.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4FBAEE1F7621452A919424A9CDD42117"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Control.</text></clause> <clause id="HB22179D22EA84DF680405CB750FE165D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Steerability.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAC500475E14548F694C2AAB2C2D113C4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Robustness against foreign adversaries.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A04C320DE3541CBBB47A4C944BEDD42"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To develop artificial intelligence solutions, including through integration among emerging technologies, such as neuromorphic and quantum computing, to overcome barriers to innovations in advanced manufacturing in the United States, including in areas such as the following:</text> 
<clause id="H0804D1404CED4A489F49B661D912EE93"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Materials, nanomaterials, and composites.</text></clause> <clause id="H7A8690E0D73343CBB19BACAAA06E3BF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Rapid, complex design.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE9B1535393FE4D6C95F0505C7C5EDD24"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Sustainability and environmental impact of manufacturing operations.</text></clause> <clause id="H8A90ADA25E7F416080BDB0203531BCCC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Predictive maintenance of machinery.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H23C43F2562AA4E1E8FD038BF85D20F4A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Improved part quality.</text></clause> <clause id="HDD2746FE1B65496BAAD8DF37479D11AA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Process inspections.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H316F77F8E1684F869B34F3889907F6EC"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Worker safety.</text></clause> <clause id="H9A350C490C2D4B2EBD8CCF446C86B4FB"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Robotics.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3B40960966EA4E34B4AFA9C2A62F4728"><enum>(F)</enum><text>To develop artificial intelligence solutions in sectors of the economy, such as expanding the utilization of artificial intelligence in maritime vessels, including in navigation and in the design of propulsion systems and fuels.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DC2AFEA9FFD40319D1AA1370D98D58A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>To develop artificial intelligence solutions to improve border security, including solutions relevant to the detection of fentanyl, illicit contraband, and illegal activities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67D8629C92214F83A438601FDF1C4918"><enum>(H)</enum><text>To develop artificial intelligence for science applications.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H460101619DDB499EA8605F0DD0A1A4CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>To develop cybersecurity for artificial intelligence-related intellectual property, such as artificial intelligence systems and artificial intelligence algorithms for robustness, resilience, and security against foreign adversaries.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6768A54E80EA4957A2DEE94CF249D769"><enum>(J)</enum><text>To develop artificial intelligence solutions to modernize code and software systems that are deployed in the Federal Government and critical infrastructure and are at risk of maintenance difficulty due to code obsolescence or challenges finding expertise in outdated code bases.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3F4A09CC9744B569A284C764EAD367E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>To develop solutions to reduce energy consumption in developing, deploying, and maintaining data-efficient and high-performance artificial intelligence models.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E231EDCA3C2448FA14C1830C208256F"><enum>(L)</enum><text>To develop methods to prevent misuse of artificial intelligence systems for malicious purposes.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0C1D59F62B24AA0951C762540C16E14"><enum>(M)</enum><text>To find applications for artificial intelligence in wireless communications systems, including cellular networks.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE34176FFE8EF4E16B886C60660FA54C2"><enum>(N)</enum><text>To advance the capabilities of artificial intelligence, robotics, and automation for physical laboratory infrastructure and cloud laboratories.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4D1C15E7AC742C4937B9F8DCB3F87CF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Problem statements; success metrics</header><text>For each priority in the list under paragraph (1) for which there will be a prize competition through the program under subsection (a), the Director shall publish on Challenge.gov or a successor website information relating to the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H092AC9F1CFCB444B88BCD1D1643E7564"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A specific and well-defined problem statement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9FE18643EFC741FA9FAE8DC8A2A64FCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Targets, success metrics, validation protocols, and other benchmarks that will be utilized to evaluate submissions to such prize competition.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H792B2B99B92F464DAC07E4A668AAD232"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each award for such prize competition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDC012DAD15541AFBD2A811A9A9E2AAA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation on identification and selection of grand challenges</header><text>The Director, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, and such other agency heads as the Director considers relevant, shall each identify and select artificial intelligence research and development grand challenges in which eligible participants will compete to solve or advance for prize awards under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H41E6525BF379459593F79007B3DE55D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal investment initiatives authorized</header> 
<paragraph id="H4470B24629884CE0ABFDE408AF507E65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Director of the National Science Foundation may each establish, consistent with the missions or responsibilities of the Department of Commerce, the Department of Transportation, or the Foundation, respectively, a program to carry out challenge-based acquisitions and other research and development investment initiatives the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Transportation, or the Director of the National Science Foundation, as the case may be, determines consistent with the list under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB526B147A5F44DDDAE1E004120AA1B96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each agency head carrying out an investment initiative under paragraph (1) shall ensure the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFA3DCF4F4FEB491D828CBCADA262175A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to each such initiative, there is, or will be, the following:</text> <clause id="HF2F288E4D8A14563B16F9CEA222FDF72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A positive impact on the economic competitiveness of the United States.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1AED99C404D44C7D8468064792E681F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A benefit to United States industry.</text></clause> <clause id="HEB62D90D0EB64495B4C4C3FF161F932B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In developing such initiative, the resources and expertise of any industry and philanthropic partners to such initiative are leveraged to the extent practicable.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H53E98B69A61B499AB24AAF9778659A45"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Utilization of advanced manufacturing in the United States, if applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H23986CF094F14296B0E7CD3FB24CD8EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>All research conducted for such initiative is conducted in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBFCA9768EEA4EA9A5E2B372EA22C663"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Accessibility</header><text>In carrying out an investment initiative under paragraph (1), the head of the agency at issue shall publish on Challenge.gov or a successor website information relating to the following, as applicable:</text> <subparagraph id="HA8FE04ED82604152BCFC0F1AB5D487BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A specific and well-defined problem statement for such initiative.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76C03BE7192B4C38ABA3A530092ED9F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Targets, success metrics, validation protocols, and other benchmarks that will be utilized to evaluate submissions to such initiative.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF25F0F6953574D0BAC61A221C101A08F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each award for such initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3747CE4C712B4C14B9D28A4910D77700"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H48B4E52481904A51AEAB004E95CB492E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification of winning submission</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the head of an agency makes an award through a program under this section, such head shall provide to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and such other committees of Congress as such head considers relevant a report on the winning submission for which such award was made and the benefits to the United States associated with such submission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD464117CBBBB407FB918110EC1F264B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section and biennially thereafter, each head of an agency for which there is a program under this section shall carry out the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF79841EFCC674D2D8709F4D329841269"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Submit to the committees referred to in paragraph (1) a report that includes the following for the biennial period covered by such report:</text> <clause id="HBA1A6EB42A1048139AD5F307CB231EB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A description of the activities carried out by such head under this section.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F559CE40EBB4D4CA33CA3B89F75E853"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of such program, including the results of such program.</text></clause> <clause id="HE608396F6AA54B5CB2D4944804C55671"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Information relating to the efforts by such head to provide information to the public and encourage participation with respect to such program.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC3AC89AC937400A9CDAEC596A1A969C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Make such report publicly available, including by publishing such report on a website, such as the GovInfo website of the Government Publishing Office, in an easily accessible location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3A469F962F7E4545B2EEA379C4AD0A8F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Each program under this section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA7F276FF14734A9CA8E0648518AD7EF9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H21B71A7A5D47494ABAF64C16E1532304"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Executive agency</term> in section 403 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBEDA42E05C1481DAFC70E55772DE8CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>critical infrastructure</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1016 of the USA PATRIOT ACT (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H205B06D5E6D84DB08F72BF0C75D2FE66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text>The table of contents in section 2(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 and the table of contents at the beginning of title LI of such Act are amended by inserting after the items relating to section 5106 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3BBA791018354011BD0CAC18CDB061F4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5107. Federal grand challenges in artificial intelligence.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8AF333415474637A7A36498B5CAB5A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Studies</header> 
<paragraph id="H9DA9DB7E1D2D433897E9B0A3A08792B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial study</header> 
<subparagraph id="H80B8F89ABA8A43E9897B1947505230EE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of the following:</text> <clause id="HB835D54D797F4150869E1D6E7F626D65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Ongoing prize competition programs carried out under authorities enacted before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBB9531B02A804F7BA5121F3227143B11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Prize competitions, generally.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17E4A230271B44F6BFD4351676DBFAB0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under subparagraph (A) shall include, to the extent practicable, the following:</text> 
<clause id="H7309BDEF22C448EBA84F42C1CB38C3F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An identification of the following:</text> <subclause id="H60530C4AEE924EEA835FC528378AAA23"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Best practices for prize competitions.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9220E8EFC0FF44D1B830D9DC62C0E055"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The metrics the Comptroller General of the United States determines appropriate for evaluating the success of a prize competition.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H06A570F28E2D490694F53C2EE706B853"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An assessment of the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H1C2ED499676C4626A23C1FE0FC301A08"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Whether such metrics differ between evaluating near-term and long-term impacts of prize competitions.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4A2CC62B6CEB4753A521CA7F261D516E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Whether prize competitions can be designed in a way that would result in more effective or revolutionary technology being developed.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HB95D4B1CD6EC4168BE4A08A3B9ECA315"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An assessment of the efficacy and effect of the programs referred to in subparagraph (A)(i), including with respect to the following:</text> <subclause id="H12DB2C00B0E840C6A7F020FB3A7109CF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Whether, and what, technology or innovation would have been developed in the absence of such programs.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB61F847E6CBF414E80276F5D000E4AAB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Whether such programs have shortened the timeframe for the development of technology or innovation.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD539E0B5F56747E09D463D15992BC856"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Whether such programs are cost effective.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF4D05CE97B7D453AAD9C0687656A842B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>What benefits, if any, are gained from carrying out such programs.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H702DB1D4AEC145E5B3BFFCE07A9A6BDE"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Whether the utilization of a grant program or contract would have resulted in such development.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89FA55783B794A08822CDD374A354B80"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report and briefing</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives the following:</text> <clause id="H7A8A2BE0DC5D4A3A8A738DDD1F4CC929"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A report on the findings of the Comptroller General with respect to the study conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE730492252642EBB37ED6AC87464543"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A briefing on such report.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3E63F1CA8094954AA648132B17E0E5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interim study</header> <subparagraph id="HB9FA8CCAD6C54EF2B9B4C48A55563848"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of each prize challenge program under section 5107 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020, as added by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2ED91C462F8E44A593E9CAF5A76FA3AD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under subparagraph (A) shall include, to the extent practicable, the following:</text> <clause id="H4AD02AB8ED4E4348A4C443F17BAD34FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An assessment of the efficacy and effect of the set of programs referred to in subparagraph (A), including with respect to the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H3B2790B2659A4DABB6A1D660BC9F054D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Whether, and what, technology or innovation would have been developed in the absence of such programs.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFD2C9109D37F48D3A6240F0B7C571E30"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Whether such programs have shortened the timeframe for the development of technology or innovation.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0132F2E0CD2E4A5D9A7D5093F6C7282C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Whether such programs are cost effective.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1CC02C1848CA4C1A80CB6381FE8A3CFD"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>What benefits, if any, are gained from carrying out such programs.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0D7D4984C3324305B1845C0356931C53"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Whether the utilization of a grant program or contract would have resulted in such development.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE4E7E0EF7C4A4536B13D9B6091BE54D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A comparison of such efficacy and effect with the efficacy and effect of the programs referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22855BA0D1C9487A9F96D436DA85B541"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report and briefing</header><text>Not later than 42 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives the following:</text> <clause id="HA9A745BAB4A24486AC74777C3AA0AD9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A report on the findings of the Comptroller General with respect to the study conducted under subparagraph (A).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H27286665A41C401EA83C47EBA3BB973A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A briefing on such report.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

