<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H688F67F31AF44EEAA3CA93BB26907456" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8054 IH: To designate the Palm Beach International Airport in Florida as the “Donald J. Trump International Airport”, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8054</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the Palm Beach International Airport in Florida as the <quote>Donald J. Trump International Airport</quote>, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5F03FF8DB3542FF99D399D2FAFCB717" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8D042AA4D80A43F8B6A936DF780DF3C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation of Donald J. Trump International Airport</header>
<subsection id="HE60004C2C8824741938A5336E3D71164"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Palm Beach International Airport in Florida shall after the date of enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Donald J. Trump International Airport</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD160DDAAC38349E99BA1F4512A9DC5A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the airport referred to in subsection (a) shall be considered to be a reference to the Donald J. Trump International Airport.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H488B32C094234E789A3F76B0CCE24C3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identifying letters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall work with the International Air Transport Association, the International Civil Aviation Organization, the Location Identifier of the Federal Aviation Administration, the World Meteorological Organization, and any other organization or entity that assigns numeric or alphabetical identifiers to geographically specific locations to change the identifying letters of the airport referred to in subsection (a) as <quote>DJT</quote>.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

