<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC9DBFC2857E442A8188BB2B6C4E8932" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9181 IH: Rail Motive Power Source Integration Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9181</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration to establish a pilot program relating to integrating the use of multiple power sources into the rail system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1327738106504B59880B8B19D98B29DE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H05452BAF06E3474092A090A55C9D2BC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rail Motive Power Source Integration Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBF91917494374BD5AD9629E3B9AE2EC2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on integrating use of multiple motive power sources into rail system</header> <subsection id="HDCC341D4E275409AB97065F5FC4797A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall establish a pilot program to improve the ease of rotating between multiple motive power sources during operation within the passenger and freight rail systems.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3D20DF7338E242788B5EC9868BD9A484"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program established under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text> <paragraph id="H17224780A43645769AA61DC02E09E7CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H943A04F61EEF4B65BF6815DBA405CC92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the integration of the use of multiple different or new rail technologies or motive power sources such as battery, electrification, hydrogen, and diesel into the rail system; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9DD188BB9AB54FEB92FBACE367ED5B79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any challenges relating to implementing such technologies, including cost or additional land requirements;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2965061348024E65942C710593C6CEAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop rail car designs that facilitate rotation between multiple power sources, which may include different rail electrification systems; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD45295A866141BCBD1C0FD487A862EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>perform demonstration projects to test the feasibility of integrating such designs into the rail system.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF24078F9C9A84C73B8C992C9F0E46C7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall conduct a study to identify each location at which a train must be changed during operation within the passenger and freight rail systems because such train uses a power source that is inoperable in the rail system past such location.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H15DAAA6E5FB94F13BB2810C30F89CB53" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall provide to Congress a report describing the results of the pilot program established under subsection (a) and the study conducted under subsection (c).</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

