<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="uslm.css"?><bill xmlns="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:lang="en" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schemas.gpo.gov/xml/uslm https://www.govinfo.gov/schemas/xml/uslm/uslm-2.0.17.xsd">
<!--Disclaimer: Legislative measures that include compacts or other non-standard data structures will require additional modeling and may contain inconsistencies in the converted USLM XML.-->
<meta><dc:title>119 S 260 ENR: To amend the Bottles and Breastfeeding Equipment Screening Act to require hygienic handling of breast milk and baby formula by security screening personnel of the Transportation Security Administration and personnel of private security companies providing security screening, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:type>Senate Bill</dc:type><docNumber>260</docNumber><citableAs>119 S 260 ENR</citableAs>
<citableAs>119s260enr</citableAs>
<citableAs>119 S. 260 ENR</citableAs>
<dc:creator>United States Senate</dc:creator><dc:publisher>United States Government Publishing Office</dc:publisher><dc:format>text/xml</dc:format><dc:language>EN</dc:language><dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights><docStage>ENR</docStage>
<processedBy>GPO Locator to USLM Converter 4.15.98;Stage2.20260514</processedBy><processedDate>2026-07-11</processedDate>
<congress>119</congress><session>1</session><publicPrivate>public</publicPrivate>
</meta>
<preface><dc:type>S.</dc:type><docNumber>260</docNumber>

<congress style="-uslm-lc:I665502" value="119">One Hundred Nineteenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session style="-uslm-lc:I665503" value="1">A T T  H  E F  I  R  S  T S  E  S  S  I  O  N</session>
<enrolledDateline style="-uslm-lc:I665504">Begun and held at the City of Washington on Friday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty five</enrolledDateline>
</preface>
<main>
<longTitle>
<docTitle class="centered fontsize18" style="-uslm-lc:I665505">An Act</docTitle>
<officialTitle class="centered fontsize8" style="-uslm-lc:I665511">To amend the Bottles and Breastfeeding Equipment Screening Act to require hygienic handling of breast milk and baby formula by security screening personnel of the Transportation Security Administration and personnel of private security companies providing security screening, and for other purposes.<?GPOvSpace 08?></officialTitle>
</longTitle>
<enactingFormula style="-uslm-lc:I650120"><i>  Be it enacted by the Senate and House of Representa­tives of the United States of America in Congress assembled,</i></enactingFormula>
<section id="d15669e62" identifier="/us/bill/119/s/260/s1" style="-uslm-lc:I650146"><num class="bold" value="1">SECTION 1. </num><heading>SHORT TITLE.</heading><content style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  This Act may be cited as the “<shortTitle role="act">Bottles and Breastfeeding Equipment Screening Enhancement Act</shortTitle>”.</content></section>
<section id="d15669e72" identifier="/us/bill/119/s/260/s2" role="instruction" style="-uslm-lc:I650141"><num class="bold" value="2">SEC. 2. </num><heading>HYGIENIC HANDLING OF BREAST MILK AND BABY FORMULA DURING AVIATION SECURITY SCREENING.</heading><content class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="xfd6ab5af-7d5f-11f1-acc3-55210b6559dc" style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  The Bottles and Breastfeeding Equipment Screening Act (<ref href="/us/pl/114/293">Public Law 114–293</ref>) <amendingAction type="amend">is amended</amendingAction> by <amendingAction type="add">adding</amendingAction> at the end the following new sections:<quotedContent><section class="indentUp0 firstIndent1" id="yfd6adcc0-7d5f-11f1-acc3-55210b6559dc" style="-uslm-lc:I650141"><num class="bold" value="3">“SEC. 3. </num><heading class="bold">HYGIENIC HANDLING OF BREAST MILK AND BABY FORMULA DURING AVIATION SECURITY SCREENING.</heading><chapeau class="indentUp0 firstIndent0 fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  “Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section and every five years thereafter, if appropriate, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall issue or update, as the case may be, guidance to minimize the risk for contamination of any breast milk, baby formula, purified deionized water for infants, and juice (as well as ice packs, freezer packs, frozen gel packs and other accessories required to cool breast milk, baby formula, and juice) that is subject to re-screening or otherwise subject to additional screening. Such guidance shall—</chapeau><paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="yfd6adcc1-7d5f-11f1-acc3-55210b6559dc" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="1">“(1) </num><content>be developed in consultation with nationally recognized maternal health organizations;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="yfd6adcc2-7d5f-11f1-acc3-55210b6559dc" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="2">“(2) </num><content>ensure adherence to hygienic standards, as established by the Administrator, in consultation with nationally recognized maternal health organizations;</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="yfd6adcc3-7d5f-11f1-acc3-55210b6559dc" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="3">“(3) </num><content>ensure that, when any such re-screening or additional screening requires additional testing, such testing so adheres to such standards, to so minimize such risk; and</content></paragraph>
<paragraph class="firstIndent0 fontsize10" id="yfd6adcc4-7d5f-11f1-acc3-55210b6559dc" style="-uslm-lc:I650122"><num class="fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:emspace2" value="4">“(4) </num><content>apply to security screening personnel of the Administration and personnel of private security companies providing security screening pursuant to <ref href="/us/usc/t49/s44920">section 44920 of title 49, United States Code</ref>.</content></paragraph>
</section>
<section class="indentUp0 firstIndent1" id="yfd6adcc5-7d5f-11f1-acc3-55210b6559dc" style="-uslm-lc:I650141"><num class="bold" value="4">“SEC. 4. </num><heading class="bold">INSPECTOR GENERAL AUDIT.</heading><content class="indentUp0 firstIndent0 fontsize10" style="-uslm-lc:I650120">  “Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing an audit of compliance with the requirements of sections 2 and 3. Such audit shall also include information relating to the effect of various types of screening technologies, including bottled liquid scanners, on the screening of breast milk, baby formula, purified deionized water for infants, and juice (as well as ice packs, freezer packs, frozen gel packs and other accessories required to cool breast milk, baby formula, and juice) that is subject to re-screening or otherwise subject to additional screening, and the rate at which such items are denied entry into the sterile area (as such term is defined in <ref href="/us/cfr/t49/s1540.5">section 1540.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations</ref>).”</content></section>
</quotedContent>.</content></section>
</main>
<signatures>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></signature>
<signature><role style="-uslm-lc:I650114">Vice President of the United States and  President of the Senate.</role></signature>
</signatures>
</bill>