<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-NEW26117-JTT-7W-2FM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4239 IS: Plug Offshore Wells Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4239</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Interior to annually submit to Congress, and make publicly available on a website, a report on decommissioning offshore oil and gas wells, platforms, and pipelines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD260AB2862D84284B0B8AFFC65BD3CDD"><section section-type="section-one" id="H4A883F18ECEB4EAF8848E18C20FE25D7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Plug Offshore Wells Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H0EC6230D36924ED5B3CB74B98A690C24"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on decommissioning offshore oil and gas wells, platforms, and pipelines</header><subsection id="HEF0E200DEE224650981DE89E834BC995"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id679d8c3e6a5041959e75b307e3422b4b"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Decommissioning</header><text>The term <term>decommissioning</term> has the meaning given the term in section 250.1700 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99a7b713477649e6a1e318e2d78ab5b2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA755E5B00AA5405EBD7337349E72C363"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress and make publicly available on the website of the Department of the Interior a report that describes, with respect to the preceding calendar year—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H23B908FF977542D286D7C64ADD702B18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of applications for decommissioning an offshore oil and gas well, platform, or pipeline that were required to be submitted pursuant to subpart Q of part 250 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b1a94eb734d4a43b49fd684ac01ca72"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of applications described in paragraph (1) that were received by the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A0CB4F9512D4348B3C72168F36025D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of offshore oil and gas wells, platforms, and pipelines for which decommissioning did not occur by the date required pursuant to subpart Q of part 250 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB801E27335464866B5474C2DB1136A2F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of offshore oil and gas wells and platforms approved for decommissioning in place pursuant to section 250.1750 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8C9CB962D2A4D92A262060467A14832"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the length of any offshore oil and gas pipelines that—</text><subparagraph id="H85988A7D362A416A87AC25117DF1CAD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>were decommissioned in place pursuant to section 250.1750 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEACE9AEF0F747938D71E0B90537213D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>were removed pursuant to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea0101e7f2ca456d867c98b637672126"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 250.1752 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation); and</text></clause><clause id="H3B3679F997E541D296B8D813F2A46C43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 250.1754 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation); and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA2B3EE6D9674B1F83F7973A959CD1E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of enforcement actions, including notices of incident of noncompliance, orders, citations, civil penalties, and disqualifications from future offshore operations, by the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement with respect to decommissioning offshore oil and gas wells, platforms, and pipelines.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

