<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H11A8AA91D78F49AF867F3EA6FA4F168D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7086 RH: Equitable Access to School Facilities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 586</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7086</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–672]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on January 15, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support the creation and implementation of State policies, as well as the expansion of existing State policies, for improving the quality and affordability of charter school facilities and to authorize the provision of technical assistance to support the growth and expansion of high-quality charter schools.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HED00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H1F0A140FCE9446BEB77AA44909D8001E"><section id="HEAC74E8F53FC4C9EBF00680C22A23295" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Equitable Access to School Facilities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE119E4037AC9456C857417A10767FFFB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to State facilities aid program</header><subsection id="H3AA49C8A221540648616A3DD7C19B144"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4304(k) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221c">20 U.S.C. 7221c(k)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H40A4EFF34D554D14A8835B5EE6372183" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subsection id="HD6BD9685CB36428292C095B03E6AF6F2"><enum>(k)</enum><header>State facilities aid program</header><paragraph id="H6409132B780F42DE99352A65AE0CF9A3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State entity defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>State entity</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4303(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H030C0A2A1E5547E1BD6021F4CD4D5C34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants to State entities</header><subparagraph id="H829A789E8D284A6E8F25DBC8420C7D60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>From the amount reserved under section 4302(b)(1) and remaining after the Secretary makes grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall award, on a competitive basis, grants to State entities that have the highest-quality applications approved under subparagraph (C), after considering the content of such applications in accordance with subparagraph (D), to pay for the Federal share of the cost of carrying out the activities described in subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F354ABC0E2045B19196AF45679E2FBF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Period</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under this subsection for periods of not more than 5 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B88BFA111FF47F9A95CCB7460A9E65C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application</header><clause id="HF31E7E738B96414498F956560D88CF22"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State entity desiring to receive a grant under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form as the Secretary may reasonably require and containing the information described in clause (ii).</text></clause><clause id="HE940A610C3684CD5A566CFC532C6BDA0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application submitted under clause (i) shall contain—</text><subclause id="HA2D47517FBE74277B18F7885B1D84ACE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a statement identifying the activities that the State entity proposes to carry out with funds received under this subsection, including a description of how the State entity will determine which charter schools will receive assistance, and how much and what types of assistance such charter schools will receive;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDEA9AD268B3F4DE5B675495098768FB8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of the involvement of charter schools in the application’s development and in the design of the proposed activities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H321421CF500042399F4540E4622FF746"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a description of whether and how the State entity will partner with an organization as described in subparagraph (G);</text></subclause><subclause id="H8555C9DDAE244A1FB9A6D20F2B01ED0B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a description of how the State entity possesses sufficient expertise to evaluate the likelihood of success of a charter school before providing assistance to such school through the proposed grant;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF9C221E0A84D4CB5B75D3D4B786531B2"><enum>(V)</enum><text>in the case of an application submitted by a State entity described in paragraphs (1), (2), or (3) of section 4303(a), a description of the actions that the entity has taken, or will take, to ensure that charter schools within the State receive the funding they need to have adequate facilities;</text></subclause><subclause id="H17CB5645480A4B5BB915F4499481B758"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of whether and how the proposed activities will—</text><item id="H6C055DF0262D4D31BBC5DC6B9DA2D808"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>increase charter schools’ access to State funds or other financing for acquiring or operating facilities (including by reducing gaps to such access between charter schools and other public schools in the same State);</text></item><item id="H002CAED523224E56A3FB1E1633CC57EE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>increase charter schools’ access to public buildings; and</text></item><item id="H309B760144DB4B5C94624A2B5E8CB6B4"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>increase the access of charter schools in low-income and rural communities to adequate facilities; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HC6D52E5B72B941FFAF8EA2540007780D"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a description of whether the State in which the State entity is located is described in clauses (i), (ii), (iii), or (iv) of subparagraph (D).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6AE4B24960054452A819A1472307940E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>No additional information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not require any additional information to be included in an application submitted under this subparagraph that is not listed in clause (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADB80A4D712346A28118C197E55C9613"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to a State entity located in a State—</text><clause id="H3C606CEF412D4E6F8B0A5C4410C38D3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is described in subparagraph (A) or (C) of section 4303(g)(2);</text></clause><clause id="HD25BD4B529FB4BCC9107D60D1C7330C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that provides charter schools with access to tax-exempt financing;</text></clause><clause id="H89BB55A350B14910AB115FF7A0DDB496" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with land use policies (including with respect to policies relating to permits and fees) that provide for the same or substantially similar treatment of charter schools as other public schools that are not charter schools; or</text></clause><clause id="H3AB2FFFED7024C3B8A6C35ECF98F2899" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that prohibits localities and other instrumentalities of the State from imposing deed restrictions on properties that limit charter school access, including prohibitions or restrictions on charter schools purchasing surplus public property.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6B5C8919C2C4176B7F4B21827900922"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><clause id="H920E3C7F1BAF43A392A53CBCAF0B7B07"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State entity receiving a grant under this subsection shall use such grant to carry out, in the State in which the State entity is located, 1 or more of the following activities:</text><subclause id="HAE35F48773874FF497F19C7F75CCD4E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Increasing funding for, or creating financing mechanisms to support, the acquisition, access to leasing, and renovation of facilities by charter schools, which may include partnerships with local educational agencies that provide access to public buildings.</text></subclause><subclause id="HFB08972424BC446D96D40FF6CBC8DC20"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Increasing funding for, or creating funding mechanisms to support, charter schools’ ongoing facilities costs.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC132E92F970A4EE8AD745FF914792137"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Supporting the creation of alternative ownership models, to plan, develop, and manage facilities for charter schools.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5801E6F6515649DC96D422878E0A1DAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reserve account</header><subclause id="H77ED76F7E5FD4972A259B48FBA30F4EE"><enum>(I)</enum><header>State entity not receiving subsection (a) grant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a State entity that is not receiving a grant under subsection (a), such entity may—</text><item id="HCA6F7849CB544B809149E9DB9A074808"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>establish and maintain a reserve account described in subsection (f); and</text></item><item id="H06E85AF09BDE465E8BCE04CA60A9AA5C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for the purpose of carrying out 1 or more of the activities described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (i), deposit an amount of the grant funds received under this subsection (to be determined by the State entity) in such reserve account.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H6F1BAEAB66CF4E5AAA27B00402A5FA21"><enum>(II)</enum><header>State entity receiving subsection (a) grant</header><text>In the case of a State entity that is receiving a grant under subsection (a), for the purpose of carrying out 1 or more of the activities described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (i), such entity may deposit an amount of the grant funds received under this subsection (to be determined by the State entity) in the reserve account established and maintained by the State entity under subsection (f).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAD32FE16F0B94BEF88CED1C44100E9CC" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Evaluations; technical assistance; dissemination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amount made available to a State entity through a grant under this subsection for a fiscal year, the State entity may reserve not more than 5 percent to carry out evaluations, to provide technical assistance, and to disseminate information.</text></clause><clause id="H355D225C00674D65BFD570D326B7D91C"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Funds made available under this subsection shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, non-Federal funds expended to carry out the activities authorized under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2A193CBD1FA4E79864695F996377D8E"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of carrying out the activities described in subparagraph (E) shall be not more than an amount equal to 60 percent of the total such cost for the duration of the grant period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAFE89E079284BEB80B82148A4F42A14"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Non-Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State entity receiving a grant under this subsection may partner with 1 or more organizations, and such organizations may provide any amount of the non-Federal share of the cost of carrying out the activities described in subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4641BE24FCA944A0B3E257A6BE882459"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Multiple grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may receive more than 1 grant under this subsection, so long as the amount of total funds provided to charter schools increases with each successive grant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H04AB598F1AA547369B4CD69839C7A188"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to a grant awarded under section 4304(k) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221c">20 U.S.C. 7221c(k)</external-xref>) on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5836CF6B0CC14CBB816DA694DC4CF409"><enum>3.</enum><header>No Federal interest</header><subsection id="HB9668CCB544749049D34803643BA607E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part C of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221">20 U.S.C. 7221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4BB4D1ACE44B4E11BE8B5E21E1E5283C" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><section id="H3F7E78D50B1A4D32B7AD6426C628B4CB"><enum>4312.</enum><header>No Federal interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds made available under this part create a Federal interest (as such term is defined in section 200.1 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations) for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="H715D630158EE4DA183E3A5CC2EA53136"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the recording requirement under section 200.316 of such title; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A36A642285245109331236CB6FDBBFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the reporting requirement under section 200.330 of such title.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDF3D5065ED6D493287E253BE85599ECE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4311 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H063F96D64BB3464AAA75432302F4C1F9" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4312. No Federal interest.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HD572298AD22D4BE2A897231B02D59F26"><enum>4.</enum><header>Credit enhancement for charter school facilities program</header><subsection id="HD21D2DB532824B82873627B142140725"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4304(h)(2)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221c">20 U.S.C. 7221c(h)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, for each of the 10 years following the date on which such entity received such grant,</quote> after <quote>annual report</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3ECEE01174B24A89952B0C806721CAC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to an eligible entity that received a grant under section 4304(a) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221c">20 U.S.C. 7221c(a)</external-xref>) before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB3242B59C84D4042ABCCC0D85B7001A5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants to support high-quality charter schools</header><subsection id="H89B4338793AB4F83BA7D07053C1C9860"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4303 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221b">20 U.S.C. 7221b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8D406B76B61F47C8A7FA028D8D7F4F7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H9B17A660EBF64A14AE8D3C3E77742B75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(C), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF01B3CFAD0514B3CB36C3D82A5B6FE15"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8404A6890114D71B4375C21532C5BF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDE8A91FCB418442A91C82C097972C0D2" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><paragraph id="H89D79E6B566B49C1B50C9921E96B3A66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide assistance in locating and accessing a facility for purposes of opening, preparing, or expanding charter schools as described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D7D4100AFF545CEB41303D5A3BE7CB0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide one-time assistance to any planned or operating charter schools in the State in ensuring that a facility used for a charter school complies with State and local building codes and regulations.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95551456A74B4E8F8776A23D37210050"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H96C37B7D04F84EB0B5DA939485384ACC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>section shall—</quote> and inserting</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H86F56063C1394782A0347A4D7363AFC9" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><text>section—</text><subparagraph id="H104E533073E24B1BAD087F77CF15509A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall—</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEE71418573E443AB5EE1A12D791E0EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) though (C) as clauses (i) through (iii), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2EFF8C699AC458D8651D4A7B04D857A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (i), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>90 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>80 percent</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4E702D7A59240CCAFAEE2D1F6177CAF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in clause (iii), as so redesignated, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD68759F6CBED4EB38180DC300193A3F0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB52799BF3D844BD4A776A298B919F2AF" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HED00"><subparagraph id="HF8574860A278423395C0E567EC1C9636"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may reserve not more than 10 percent of such funds for the establishment of a revolving loan fund, which may be used to make loans, under such terms as may be established by the State entity, to—</text><clause id="H96BDA9ADC4CB4329AC0C9ACF0734691C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligible applicants for the operation of 1 or more of the charter schools opened or expanded pursuant to a grant under this section (for the duration of the program period described in subsection (d)(1)(B)); and</text></clause><clause id="H3589434BE2C0436CAA931235179B4991" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>eligible applicants to assist such applicants in obtaining, renovating, or rehabilitating facilities for planned or operating charter schools in the State.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4DDBD3580B64DD689B0FD016B38EA17"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(3)—</text><subparagraph id="H442E31176C1941D49F79F7C9B8381941"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>necessary renovations</quote> and all that follows through <quote>school building complies</quote> and inserting <quote>repairs, renovations, and building out of charter school facilities to ensure that such facilities comply</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27BCBC2B18A14D4F9370E8D09225789D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, and minor facilities repairs (excluding construction)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H754C479537F5437A8DD383F192CCEB7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to a grant awarded under section 4303 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7221b">20 U.S.C. 7221b</external-xref>) on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

