<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H867E7C6429484EF8B48A274DF1A93FD9" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1214 IH: Celebrating the 75th anniversary of the International Hearing Society.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1214</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Celebrating the 75th anniversary of the International Hearing Society.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 1951, the predecessor organization to the International Hearing Society was established in Chicago, Illinois, later moving its headquarters to Michigan, where it established longstanding community ties to the greater Detroit area, to promote the interests of hearing aid dispensers, now known as hearing aid specialists, and the patients they serve;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas the International Hearing Society is integral in connecting hearing professionals with one another across all 50 States and internationally to mentor new hearing aid specialists, share best practices, promote ethical standards, disseminate information, and provide education to advance high-quality patient care and outcomes;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the International Hearing Society connected thousands of professionals, organizations, and partners through its history, and promotes and facilitates dialogue among hearing health care professionals to the benefit of better care;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the International Hearing Society provides robust educational opportunities for hearing aid specialists and trainees to be successful in their practice and addressing hearing loss;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the International Hearing Society continues to focus on championing policies that safeguard the hearing care profession and guarantee individuals have access to high-quality services through their provider of choice through activities at the State, Federal, and international levels;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the International Hearing Society has tirelessly advocated for decades for increased access for hearing health care for the Nation’s veteran population; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, the International Hearing Society is celebrating its 75th anniversary: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H5158625E952449BF9139DD8BBA10F032"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H94215A3D5A4343509AC76B45B682BAC3"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7A022D17D9E14A5FB6C9FBBF81BB4C2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and celebrates the 75th anniversary of the International Hearing Society and its predecessor organizations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93CC230B514B4E5595AFFF437B50E08F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commemorates the legacy of the International Hearing Society and the lasting contributions of the International Hearing Society to the advancement of hearing health care and uniting generations through improved communication; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBE69F6ED9704B4688DFAEC8370455DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>congratulates the members of the International Hearing Society on 75 years of caring for patients in need of assistance with their hearing health care needs.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

