<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H26089BD01ECA4A9E9677EEB3FC76BD5E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7379 IH: NASA Counter-Unmanned Aircraft System Authority Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7379</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 51, United States Code, to provide the National Aeronautics and Space Administration authority to detect, identify, monitor, and track unmanned aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF44DF6875B3F45F499AB8D3C81A5EFB6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA4CF46E10B2A4000AA09CD58B709C312" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NASA Counter-Unmanned Aircraft System Authority Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NASA C-UAS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H793FC5AC4D2C4F449E800DAC051E7C53"><enum>2.</enum><header>NASA authority with respect to unmanned aircraft system identification and detection</header> 
<subsection id="HD78D7ADB80B845639A3D964F745B32C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3E1625C476F481286341908D816A49F"> <section id="HF9AF6AF0C1C849638B460B300DF9B115"><enum>20150.</enum><header>Detecting, identifying, monitoring, and tracking unmanned aircraft systems and unmanned aircraft that pose threats to certain facilities and assets</header> <subsection id="H8A8DE740C46F4326B12ECEC01EBEACD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49, sections 32, 1030, and 1367 and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, or section 705 of the Communications Act of 1934, the Administrator may take, and may authorize personnel with assigned duties that include the security or protection of people, facilities, or assets to take, the actions described in subsection (b) that are necessary to detect, identify, monitor, and track an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft that poses a credible threat (as defined by the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary) to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H834E3EBDFC624EFD95884718DC3770B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The actions described in this subsection are limited to such actions during the operation of an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft to detect, identify, monitor, or track, as appropriate, the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, without prior consent, including by means of intercept or other access of a wire communication, an oral communication, or an electronic communication used to control the unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4E8D8EE850304F5DA3FCA56B8F85A365"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Identification and assessment of covered facilities or assets</header> <paragraph id="H1009CFC8D8394DAA8A049C5578538BC8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inventory of certain facilities or assets</header><text>The Administrator shall identify each facility or asset located on or within the property of the Administration that directly relates to one or more missions of the Administration pertaining to any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4165EE2D5DCF44B781F149E84079DD41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Launch services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H25C7099F6466411EA9FC8B3AB305E020"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reentry services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96CE010C43444447B5B78486803A5DFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The protection of space support vehicles or payloads.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05238880C84C47FEA2D75E0DA85009E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Risk-based assessment</header><text>The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary, shall conduct a risk-based assessment of each facility and asset identified under paragraph (1) that includes an evaluation of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H70F29A148D42491197AB2EF38FF0A553"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Threat information specific to each such facility and asset.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7402F53A34B64B098E8F2FE0E00D61EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each of the following factors, with respect to potential impacts on the safety and efficiency of the national airspace system and law enforcement and national security needs while carrying out the activities described in subsection (b):</text> 
<clause id="H34278AFC9778493B90F5DE97F75F539A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Potential effects to safety, efficiency, or use of the national airspace system, including potential effects on a manned aircraft, an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft, aviation safety, airport operations, infrastructure, or air navigation services related to the use of any system or technology for carrying out the actions described in subsection (b).</text></clause> <clause id="HA079FA18102B4E4E8539E56BEFDA9C5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Options for mitigating any identified effects to the national airspace system related to the use of any system or technology, including minimizing, when possible, the use of any technology which disrupts the transmission of radio or electronic signals, for carrying out the actions described in subsection (b).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F97BE602A1C4A32821BA841FBCB0594"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Potential consequences of the impacts of any actions described in subsection (b) to the national airspace system or infrastructure if not detected, identified, monitored, or tracked.</text> </clause> <clause id="H7EEC0728AED54C1D9EF3DDCEA0898078"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ability to provide reasonable advance notice to aircraft operators consistent with the safety of the national airspace system and the needs of law enforcement and national security.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEF0EFE4D2C064448A6F530483C3A2240"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The setting and character of the facility or asset at issue, including the following:</text> <subclause id="H413909D26DFB4338B2B6EBDC4B07D223"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Whether the facility or asset is located in a populated area or near other structures.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2791344BC45F44F6AEDBD9AFE19D4F09"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Whether the facility or asset is open to the public.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3306F58336F84399A84C664592D81E08"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Whether the facility or asset is used for nongovernmental functions.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC8F8C4556B1040978D70DD46A1CC116C"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Any potential for interference with wireless communications or for injury or damage to persons or property.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HCEBC20B3B5634F82BE98125D98290559" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The setting, character, timeframe, and national airspace system impacts of launch services and reentry services.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE37AAA1152B49FAAB34E4E74BBF506D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Potential consequences to national security, public safety, or law enforcement if a credible threat posed by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft to the facility or asset at issue is not detected, identified, monitored, or tracked.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0318372EDA14F2D99425189EFA887E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation of covered facilities or assets</header><text>The Administrator shall designate a facility or asset identified under paragraph (1) as a covered facility or asset if the Administrator determines, based on the risk-based assessment conducted under paragraph (2) with respect to the facility or asset, that the facility or asset is high-risk and a potential target for unlawful unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft activity.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H423C980B575348B29373098215CD1B7B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Research, testing, training, and evaluation</header> 
<paragraph id="HABD8687BD0B243A9823DBF94DDB0608D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header> 
<subparagraph id="H4F40EA6E7A02453A9069461EDDB6BCCB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49, sections 32, 1030, and 1367 and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, and section 705 of the Communications Act of 1934, the Administrator is authorized to conduct research, testing, training on, and evaluation of any equipment approved by the Federal Government for the detection, identification, monitoring, and tracking of unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft under subsections (a) and (b), including any electronic equipment, to determine the capability and utility of the equipment prior to the use of the equipment for any action described in subsection (b).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H613542B2BE924A5B868041B6E811C294"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Personnel and contractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Personnel and contractors of the Administration who do not have duties that include the safety, security, or protection of people, facilities, or assets of the Administration may engage in research, testing, training, and evaluation activities pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52236B2CCDC04371AFBFFD58D3B45DFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training of personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide training on the actions described in subsection (b) to personnel authorized to take such actions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD34D94C397941648808A9CD6EDE8BE1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Aviation safety</header><text>In carrying out any activity under this section, the Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary to ensure the continued, safe, and efficient operation of the national airspace system.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9FD015BD1A441ABA9FEAFD99E92404E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator—</text> <paragraph id="H85334644499D4FE593A4C0ADFAC907BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall issue guidance and may prescribe regulations as necessary for the Administrator to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H82F6C13469324DD5B13AFCC00A6A4F8A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in developing regulations and guidance referred to in paragraph (1), may consult the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information, the Secretary of Transportation, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, and the head of any other agency determined appropriate by the Administrator.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCE5FDC9E09304AC7BC69C4AA1E7D062F" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall coordinate with the Secretary and may coordinate with the heads of other agencies, as determined relevant by the Administrator, to carry out any action authorized under this section, including issuing such guidance as required to carry out this section, in order that the Administrator is able to ensure the action does not adversely impact, or interfere with, any of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6CF2E073EA1F4AC3A0123077D535B985" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Safe airport operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEEF087C8FCA47D2A7C6E327FE9D10FD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Navigation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B98FB9AF77B46F4A6FC6FA9A273F473" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Air traffic services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D1085C3EEFB448785420FDFA5F8BC99" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The safe and efficient operation of the national airspace system.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE300ED40406B40F09ED1919681E05760"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Privacy protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations or guidance issued to carry out an action described in subsection (b) by the Administrator shall ensure the following:</text> <paragraph id="H48F165A8DC4A4BA9931F33E3850D7E27" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interception or acquisition of, access to, or maintenance or use of, any communication to or from an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft under this section is conducted in a manner consistent with the First and Fourth Amendments to the Constitution of the United States and any applicable provisions of Federal law.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8B897CCE1F14C3CB1387B2B57F7B623"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any communication to or from an unmanned aircraft system or an unmanned aircraft is intercepted or acquired only to the extent necessary to support an action described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB66149875F3E421DA7891F4C1A025769"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any record of such communication is maintained only for as long as necessary, and in no event for more than 180 days, unless the Administrator, in consultation with the Attorney General, determines that maintenance of the records is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H38B0518B92CA41288ACA98D2963AF42F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">required under Federal law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94D075A142A34BE28772B356F6039E01"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">necessary for the purpose of any litigation; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H367136C7E4D1417DB0FE13F431EB016C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>necessary to investigate or prosecute a violation of law, including by—</text> <clause id="H88DE047DCAA2488EBD2F5228DCC69B98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directly supporting an ongoing security operation; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H72CAE5C506B74C91BEAC1526B005D151"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protecting against dangerous or unauthorized activity by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB723F945A70148618217B1441E0F5246"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such communication is not disclosed to any person not employed or contracted by the Administration for the purposes of carrying out this section unless the disclosure—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA99C50C4281C4B92B1900B44B658B25C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary to investigate or prosecute a violation of law;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E6C283722074DB7B5F84DB9AE9239B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would support—</text> 
<clause id="H0A192CB3F0224FBF934E2438CE32C78B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></clause> <clause id="H311890FE84D34351BD83F17A4A526B4F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal law enforcement agency, an element of the intelligence community, or other relevant Federal agency; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HBAFFFBC456184A50AAB3A43F221860FF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a State or local law enforcement entity or person, if the entity or person is engaged in a security or protection operation;</text> </clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F9CA99E590149B3917C83B48CA9C848"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is necessary to support a department or agency specified in subparagraph (B) in the investigation or prosecution of a violation of law;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35597674BD54413FB8BF850E75E143E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>would support the enforcement activities of a Federal regulatory agency relating to a criminal or civil investigation of, or any regulatory, statutory, or other enforcement action relating to, an action described in subsection (b);</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E23A8715B954CC6A7861E113C8062D0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is necessary to protect against dangerous or unauthorized activity by an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF573D1EB929140508C21A50B8F0A1D4D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>is otherwise required by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H808740A445D242BCA025E28543C0B899"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Assistance and support</header> <paragraph id="HB448D7F1B86341B0AFFE135E1E43517B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), the Administrator is authorized to provide support or assistance to a Federal agency or department, on the request of the agency or department, with respect to an action described in any of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H45A812B24E994601A564DB0390FBC687"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 130i of title 10.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FDE3FC8AF9D4C4B8FBE42C9C55D546E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H12AB5C9FD1C5448E8B5B5D238B122483"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 4510 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2661">50 U.S.C. 2661</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6218993FBAAC457D99833C78C738AD85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall provide the support or assistance described in paragraph (1) only—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H835242D93FAC44F9BC0A4B592FCB6876"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to support or assist the requesting Federal agency or department in fulfilling the roles and responsibilities of the agency or department carried out by an action referred to in such paragraph;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H505EA39E6B194262B01FA469D67FD0D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a specified duration and location;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8CBC128C1C974B4F9128389927DBAAB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>within available resources of the Administration;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FC5BB378B1B41DA96C0008B75085F85"><enum>(D)</enum><text>on a non-reimbursable basis; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19B6EF4B2A1E4C26993D139C78A8C905"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in coordination with the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFA0C4851D83D47739692A6E7842AF480"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Semiannual briefings and notifications</header> <paragraph id="HE6F4E06130FA4AAAAC991ED908979ECE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On a semiannual basis beginning 6 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall provide a briefing to the appropriate congressional committees on the activities carried out pursuant to this section.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB27EA0ADDB594D7188CCBE305E6E8DED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each briefing required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFAB4CF4DD6BC4CCDAB9F527ECD81B3AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to policies, programs, and procedures to mitigate or eliminate impacts of the actions carried out pursuant to subsection (b) to the national airspace system.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC25CD7ADFE3C4FE49E0F555F92A5D544"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the following:</text> <clause id="HB50125DF2A76407984AB296856C3A013"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Each instance that an action described in subsection (b) was taken, including any such instance that may have resulted in harm, damage, or loss to a person or to private property.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA92BED2C98D34E668C23FCE3C3723628" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The guidance, policies, or procedures established by the Administrator to address privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties issues implicated by the actions permitted under subsection (b), as well as any changes or subsequent efforts by the Administrator that would significantly affect privacy, civil rights, or civil liberties.</text></clause> <clause id="H46D5DEF645CD43388A5B8092ABD9FA2D" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Options considered and steps taken by the Administrator to mitigate any identified impacts to the national airspace system related to the use of any system or technology, including the minimization of the use of any technology that disrupts the transmission of radio or electronic signals, for carrying out the actions described in subsection (b).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H49867158B7ED42CDB001DE22B3058244"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Such consultation conducted by the Administrator with other agencies with respect to each action described under clauses (ii) and (iii).</text></clause> <clause id="HC3D652AB1C1F448F8A7B34306A984C7C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Each instance in which a communication intercepted or acquired as a result of an action described in subsection (b) taken during operations of an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft was—</text> 
<subclause id="H8D09FDB64D1049E5BE8F10BAE8972938"><enum>(I)</enum><text>held in the possession of the Administration for more than 180 days; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H379787F394CD42F1A6CD13394D907C4F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shared with any entity other than the Administration.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE07CEED858794973BC1DA85A3C381168"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An explanation of how the Administrator has—</text> <clause id="H278430B43F574606B6F3A43E91250052"><enum>(i)</enum><text>informed the public with respect to the authorities granted under this section; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC56648DC27B94F8CB7F714E9DE513673"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engaged with Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies to implement and use such authorities.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFACB07B0D74640E8A57972E18AA1453C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of whether any gaps or insufficiencies in laws, regulations, or policies impede the ability of the Administration to detect, identify, monitor, or track the credible threat posed by malicious, inappropriate, or unauthorized use of an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft to the safety or security of a covered facility or asset.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H46C978F147A74E46B55801392598E01E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recommendations to remedy any such gaps or insufficiencies, including recommendations relating to the potential need for changes in laws, regulations, or policies, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1B310AF56B34AA0A999E829733BDF03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unclassified form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each briefing required under paragraph (1) shall be unclassified but may be accompanied by an additional classified briefing.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFFFFD511E03342F19666B7D76A02A4EC" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Scope of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may not be interpreted to provide the Administrator with any additional authority other than the authorities described in subsections (a), (c), and (d).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7778B1EDEFEB475CA5289CF7776DBC08"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section shall cease to have effect on September 30, 2031.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D8BF071AF354B499FFE65DA6639978F"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="HF6AC958DCAB84F209E152BE13843493E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>vest in the Administrator any authority of the head of any other Federal agency; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23B27F452044489D81A13BE1636BD426"><enum>(2)</enum><text>vest in the head of any other Federal agency any authority of the Administrator.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5230B236FC714F5A8ED9F2EBB47E2399"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1BBA1CF684C9469FB6494A45F393F81E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H5939202BF9B04BACA2D795A919481509"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2C1CBFF415C24B00914FDB722AD99DAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2284A5259704572A792707E4AFB4218"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94E4ADDDD48D401083AB51BC4008E8E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered facility or asset</header><text>The term <quote>covered facility or asset</quote> means a facility or asset designated as a covered facility or asset by the Administrator under subsection (c)(3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB9B13D809AC4D2BAFEAD0FE88D8EC9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic communication; intercept; oral communication; wire communication</header><text>The terms <quote>electronic communication</quote>, <quote>intercept</quote>, <quote>oral communication</quote>, and <quote>wire communication</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 2510 of title 18.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2132EC54F55B4E50871E08CBBFADB331"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B83FCEC24DE462DB35501B2AF5AAD88"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Launch services; reentry services; space support vehicle; payload</header><text>The terms <quote>launch services</quote>, <quote>reentry services</quote>, <quote>space support vehicle</quote>, and <quote>payload</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 50902.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1106CD6719644E4A57455058CA1D603"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Personnel</header> 
<subparagraph id="H36E9677C777442018CD4D112372CBD81"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>personnel</quote> means an officer, employee, or contractor of the Administration authorized to perform duties that include safety, security, or protection of people, facilities, or assets.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A2FDB4483E84E9C85BD8762B9D1531B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of authority</header><text>To qualify for use of the authority under subsection (a), a contractor conducting operations under such subsection shall satisfy the following:</text> 
<clause id="HBE79432FD06D47C284ED912787B87D1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Be directly contracted by the Administration.</text></clause> <clause id="H96146ED006284677AB598A3A12416969"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Be assigned to law enforcement duties within the Office of Protective Services of the Administration.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE8E65833171F4B4C92B6671096789398"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Operate at a Government-owned or Government-leased facility.</text></clause> <clause id="H6A76DA0127FA48C99F155C1BFE00B145"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Not conduct inherently governmental functions.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD2951330EC6F447187AB7C030581120E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Be trained and certified by the Administration to meet the established guidance and regulations of the Administration.</text></clause> <clause id="H7E6AD29BA75C4E1986D7F2FF2D24C6E7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Be subject to the penalties specified in section 799 of title 18.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE84490C013D46F99ECF53B5A7333F0C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Transportation (acting through the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7685927BAA934A94B85BFF0AFF99A344"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft; unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The terms <quote>unmanned aircraft</quote> and <quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 44801 of title 49.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7508607B958441E4944EE1DB727A1D1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/51/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 51, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/51/20149">section 20149</external-xref> the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC92155496DD549919DB678986F9E8083"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">20150. Detecting, identifying, monitoring, and tracking unmanned aircraft systems and unmanned aircraft that threaten certain facilities and assets.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

