<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO26363-CLG-XD-VDW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4453 IS: USDA–DOI Linking Information Networks for Knowledge-sharing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4453</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to ensure that the information technology and cybersecurity and information security systems of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior are interoperable, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section id="id782db968343044d39d23ec62f4a9602f" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>USDA–DOI Linking Information Networks for Knowledge-sharing Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LINK Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f084c1590e24b16994cd7c9640bd25a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interoperability of information technology and cybersecurity and information security systems of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida466c731f2814c7bb577c8e1b7ff3b4e"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition of Secretary</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd25b1630eb14093ad6495eeaeaf8c11"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordination required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4705116c6b5148cb8d9c4fcdde8d6bf3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall coordinate with each other to ensure that the information technology and cybersecurity and information security systems of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior, respectively, are interoperable to allow for the sharing between the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior of information with respect to covered activities of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior, respectively, described in paragraph (2), excluding any Tribal proprietary data, sensitive cave location data, or other sensitive or proprietary information, as designated by law (including regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id295500b9149d4bbb895f0c1c8636e785"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Description of covered activities</header><text>The covered activities referred to in paragraph (1) are—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f8e10c3b3ff4256a2e2489464555505"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal land management activities, with an emphasis on activities that would leverage existing integration efforts and capabilities, such as wildfire operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61d06e63c1864cbaba266e857ad3349e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disaster and emergency preparedness and response activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0909fd1efb294df9b721154279ec91ce"><enum>(C)</enum><text>procurement, aviation management, personnel and workforce management, and other business system activities relating to the conduct of the activities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad51443c1b964d08b0ee6d8cc5a89e97"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall comply with applicable Federal information technology system laws, including subtitle III of title 40 and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id313449528cce4d8ebe5fcbff32afd7c3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation; tribal data sovereignty</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida735b9502b2e4ba3b60bbdf6869a6ba1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with applicable Indian Tribes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04338365bdf34215802dde2bf2047a1e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide appropriate protections for Tribal data sovereignty.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2575b17bbc7e429c90774c8cc67e8104"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint interoperability implementation plan</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id97b4f7dcd309499e8cd3d5e4090d02cf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act and in consultation with firefighters, the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall jointly develop an interoperability implementation plan for the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior to enable the sharing between the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior of the information described in subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47ea35db730d4a0e8d38196d3118b233"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interoperability implementation plan developed under paragraph (1) shall include a plan for the phased retirement of siloed legacy information technology and cybersecurity and information security systems of the Department of Agriculture and the Department of the Interior that ensures that the retirement does not result in a degradation of operational capacity or mission safety.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47ba96160ccf4ab093b84e652de3b612"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall implement the interoperability implementation plan developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7fb87e9827154674b5c3cd6885318d6b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates to the information technology and security systems of the Department of Agriculture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall update the information technology and cybersecurity and information security systems of the Department of Agriculture as necessary to enable the sharing between the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior of the information described in subsection (b)(1), in accordance with the interoperability implementation plan developed under subsection (c).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

