<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H79B9A02DA53C4368B071151F456A6CB9">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7023 IH: Affordable Consumer Health Options and Insurance Competition Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7023</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260112">January 12, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to establish a public health insurance option, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC6DACF979221470ABDF1DD4598DEF471">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H6ABF6A08E52A4FBE8E6A8B822BAE7BD8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Consumer Health Options and Insurance Competition Enhancement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Affordable CHOICE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF29BBD4E2BFF43ACA57609552C098D74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public health insurance option</header> <subsection id="H66E6526526A34B8B9F961B987BD85B5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part 2 of subtitle D of title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D6B4BE09EB34E9A99B9C525B78302AC">
<section id="H1E8345CE2C8B47938C1B0DF35D41B0FB"><enum>1314.</enum><header>Public health insurance option</header>
<subsection id="HFF6DD4D1008C424A856C6647ADBF889C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
<paragraph id="H933678159A6A44FABBA83FB11B1B3334"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall establish, and provide for the offering through the Exchanges of, a qualified health plan (in this section referred to as the <quote>public health insurance option</quote>) that provides value, choice, competition, and stability of affordable, high-quality coverage throughout the United States in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3986188570994DB080CE9C6EA8233E31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Primary responsibility</header><text>In designing the public health insurance option, the primary responsibility of the Secretary shall be to create an affordable health plan without compromising quality or access to care.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H60B870D8627B4B99903E01E521409E83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrating the public health insurance option</header>
<paragraph id="HD4F7290B44024326A3BD9311947903FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offered through Exchanges</header>
<subparagraph id="HF08479A83884423F9CA180AFDD2F48C8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exclusive to Exchanges</header><text>The public health insurance option shall be offered exclusively by the Secretary through the Exchanges and not by a health insurance issuer.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FE23E86538E4374AE3498CD6BA126B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ensuring a level playing field</header><text>Except as otherwise provided under this section, the public health insurance option shall comply with requirements under this title, and title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act, that are applicable to health plans offered through the Exchanges, including requirements related to benefits, benefit levels, provider networks, notices, consumer protections, and cost-sharing.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD6146CC29F9741E0B2F59C8BE74F376D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Provision of benefit levels</header><text>The public health insurance option shall offer bronze, silver, and gold plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B1FB53711AB4B87A95AD37374FA0BE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative contracting</header> <subparagraph id="H17A0A94B748A4FB3949EBA8364E9A4D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text>The Secretary may enter into contracts for the purpose of performing administrative functions (including functions described in subsection (a)(4) of section 1874A of the Social Security Act) with respect to the public health insurance option in the same manner as the Secretary may enter into contracts under subsection (a)(1) of such section. The Secretary shall have the same authority with respect to the public health insurance option as the Secretary has under such subsection (a)(1) and subsection (b) of section 1874A of the Social Security Act with respect to title XVIII of such Act.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H03DED2DB9DBF4C2687D29F015910239D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transfer of insurance risk</header><text>Any contract under this paragraph shall not involve the transfer of insurance risk from the Secretary to the entity entering into such contract with the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F5B7517ADC941448AE33B332D8CC5BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State Advisory Council</header> <subparagraph id="H1445563AEB984EDCB62E4726FB5AB5D5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>A State may establish a public or nonprofit entity to serve as the State Advisory Council to provide recommendations to the Secretary on the operations and policies of the public health insurance option offered through the Exchange operating in the State.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8B54C506BD6E46609960D96A6F59BBFA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>A State Advisory Council established under subparagraph (A) shall provide recommendations on at least the following:</text> <clause id="HF397D508C7264BFA9646CEAB2CD6F9A4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Policies and procedures to integrate quality improvement and cost containment mechanisms into the health care delivery system.</text></clause>
<clause id="H6A3BF00D2CA5437BAD2CCF104FE667C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Mechanisms to facilitate public awareness of the availability of the public health insurance option.</text></clause> <clause id="H027B489B453A49ECBAA75542DC6C7349"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Alternative payment models and value-based insurance design under the public health insurance option that encourage quality improvement and cost control.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCFB5758014D1481680C57D4E55654ED2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The members of any State Advisory Council shall be representatives of the public and include health care consumers and health care providers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2BD92DA3DF0485386B7D1179B698D44"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Applicability of recommendations</header><text>The Secretary may apply the recommendations of a State Advisory Council to the public health insurance option in that State, in any other State, or in all States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H70A7623892164A24AADDF0A868D610A7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data collection</header><text>The Secretary shall collect such data as may be required—</text> <subparagraph id="H031CA968483E4E32B8C9A2518FAAD5C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish rates for premiums and health care provider reimbursement under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1377CF37310542338004B78DE670598A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for other purposes under this section, including to improve quality, and reduce racial, ethnic, and other disparities, in health and health care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H631AD8003E674AF1B86A2E34A912C8E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Financing the public health insurance option</header> <paragraph id="H9BC39C22E7EE4315B204374157FB965E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Premiums</header> <subparagraph id="HE53865CCE9914A889545994E02468C6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish geographically adjusted premium rates for the public health insurance option—</text>
<clause id="H4568BE734A6B446BA963EA91F358F0A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a manner that complies with the requirement for premium rates under subparagraph (C) and considers the data collected under subsection (b)(4); and</text></clause> <clause id="H3E3079ED6F08468B87ECE869D576C2A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at a level sufficient to fully finance—</text>
<subclause id="HEAF320B4AC884613B05FF870BE441799"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the costs of health benefits provided by the public health insurance option; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF9C8B9605B82498F9E740F3DAD2DDC4D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>administrative costs related to operating the public health insurance option.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF78A93F5ACE140ECBC6629C36B00BF60"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contingency margin</header><text>In establishing premium rates under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall include an appropriate amount for a contingency margin.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73D6D71F3C5E4030B23DDE909C2FB81F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Variations in premium rates</header><text>The premium rate charged for the public health insurance option may not vary except as provided under section 2701 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A5B97D912BA484F8F4898D0C0757AFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Health care provider payment rates for items and services</header>
<subparagraph id="HFA352FFED8E546F999564BACC469FC97"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header>
<clause id="HAE75B2298F4143E4B659EC40FD70E360"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rates negotiated by the Secretary</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2026, and except as provided in clause (ii), the Secretary shall, through a negotiated agreement with health care providers, establish rates for reimbursing health care providers for providing the benefits covered by the public health insurance option.</text></clause> <clause id="H4FBC410785614D6C9FD4D9CF68B9D33C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Medicare reimbursement rates</header><text>If the Secretary and health care providers are unable to reach a negotiated agreement on a reimbursement rate, the Secretary shall reimburse providers at rates determined for equivalent items and services under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act.</text></clause>
<clause id="H3EC7772D7B7844949FF20C3C7BBBBC5E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>For new services</header><text>The Secretary shall modify reimbursement rates described in clause (ii) in order to accommodate payments for services, such as well-child visits, that are not otherwise covered under the original Medicare fee-for-service program.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE7C9025EE594516BED44CA74F4E447B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prescription drugs</header><text>Any payment rate under this subsection for a prescription drug shall be at a rate negotiated by the Secretary. If the Secretary is unable to reach a negotiated agreement on such a reimbursement rate, the Secretary shall use rates determined for equivalent drugs paid for under the original Medicare fee-for-service program. The Secretary shall modify such rates in order to accommodate payments for drugs that are not otherwise covered under the original Medicare fee-for-service program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HECA695228B0D42B8B07101659907F54A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Account</header>
<subparagraph id="H9C6792E657194879A3EF2A89C1DCAAA0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States an account for the receipts and disbursements attributable to the operation of the public health insurance option, including the start-up funding under subparagraph (C) and appropriations authorized under subparagraph (D).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H06C56F9D39FB4AE6B3BACB5790D2F621"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition of State imposition of taxes</header><text>Section 1854(g) of the Social Security Act shall apply to receipts and disbursements described in subparagraph (A) in the same manner as such section applies to payments or premiums described in such section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9AA9ACD6F6254B9BA99F90536212E5BE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Start-up funding</header>
<clause id="HC8414C60F6DE41E7877925FC8F08C104"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of funding</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to establish the public health insurance option and cover 90 days of claims reserves based on projected enrollment.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H4791A7B0FE7C44928F2AC24D5E2C2C14"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amortization of start-up funding</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for the repayment of the start-up funding provided under clause (i) to the Treasury in an amortized manner over the 10-year period beginning on January 1, 2027.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H35A9EBED579D4F9290FC6F37BCB61A3B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out paragraph (2) of subsection (b), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAE07F2182FBC4A5882E6605E50ADC478"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Health care provider participation</header> <paragraph id="HB2CC452512D44560BEB9A96DBA0A57CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Provider participation</header> <subparagraph id="H49E623D78F5C423CB41F509FA25E9001"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish conditions of participation for health care providers under the public health insurance option.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7EA66BF9217A4D1198E8D889D0B1D0F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Licensure or certification</header><text>The Secretary shall not allow a health care provider to participate in the public health insurance option unless such provider is appropriately licensed or certified under State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FACD9A105AA4185A0ABBD8ED14592AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment of a provider network</header> <subparagraph id="H4D5BF210C3C04698833F7DE62A65F571"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Medicare and Medicaid participating providers</header><text>A health care provider that is a participating provider of services or supplier under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act or under a State Medicaid plan under title XIX of such Act is a participating provider in the public health insurance option unless the health care provider opts out of participating in the public health insurance option through a process established by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE7C32F531C9C4697ADC90BC762F70C16"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional providers</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process to allow health care providers not described in subparagraph (A) to become participating providers in the public health insurance option.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF490647626124A51A482377073A00828"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <paragraph id="H7281DE372B12476EB2208B8F2A703380"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment as a qualified health plan</header><text>Section 1301(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18021">42 U.S.C. 18021(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB8ADA1AC225D4E979252966BC4D91C74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(C), by inserting <quote>except in the case of the public health insurance option established under section 1314,</quote> before <quote>is offered by</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF6A5639C6904D509EF7EC7861596A6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
<clause id="H7A93CBDFAE474CF6B0D9D46AE7A96CC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">, the public health insurance option,</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">and</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H90497863B051418A806A7EC6AB3574F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the public health insurance option under section 1314,</quote> before <quote>and a multi-State plan</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1EA0E12F947C48B6BF9C81EBC1EB0C97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F3611F40C14443DAC61E5307EE1FE3E"> <paragraph id="HE7A141986E31492292B2D6CE52896FC2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public health insurance option</header><text>The term <term>qualified health plan</term> shall include the public health insurance option established under section 1314.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF7EC3F9611334D50A1145B28670D92BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Level playing field</header><text>Section 1324(a) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18044">42 U.S.C. 18044(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>the public health insurance option under section 1314,</quote> before <quote>or a multi-State qualified health plan</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill>

