<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HADF9C4628F38426CBF0FC7C06CFB6AC6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8115 IH: Precision Brain Health Research Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8115</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00"> Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To modify the Precision Medicine for Veterans Initiative of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HF090001FA3C140E9872F5209F53BD8D1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7C5C3DE170324A65B97F1A78BF07B243" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Precision Brain Health Research Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC199E1AB9A5242B589DC77F8175481BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of Precision Medicine for Veterans Initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 305 of the Commander John Scott Hannon Veterans Mental Health Care Improvement Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/1712A">38 U.S.C. 1712A</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/171">Public Law 116–171</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEAE4FD3831174D1EAD16CC37C5A2CA09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>and such other mental health conditions</quote> and inserting <quote>repetitive low-level blast exposure, dementia, and such other brain and mental health conditions</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12D7FED596434022882FB568D1A29FE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(4), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FEF5C87DD08412B9F6BA755261E54D3"> 
<subparagraph id="H1990CDF232634A5BBE5B3B93675AC189" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Data-sharing partnership</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H270B194832F94D9EBFCF475C57B36847"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Precision Brain Health Research Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall establish a data-sharing partnership between the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense. </text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C3B6B7C365B4B5292023A163CECD367"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Storage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The partnership established under clause (i) shall be stored in the open platform made available under this paragraph. </text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA39AB365E5444FA4BA79C51673C0CC72"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data supplied by the Secretary of Defense shall include all relevant data of the Department of Defense, collected through—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE261601502744ACD8FB5C17E3A8BE74F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Armed Forces; </text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33FB0AC23821408B91347D725CFC0C62"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Special Operations Command; and </text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E91F0B6F2B64555A684762A4D4A071A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Long-Term Impact of Military-Relevant Brain Injury Consortium Chronic Effects of Neurotrauma Consortium maintained by the Defense Health Agency.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HC1C60D3F480C4DD580F76BE3978B2102"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every two years during the period beginning on the date of the establishment of the partnership under this subparagraph and ending on the day when the partnership terminates, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report regarding the partnership. Each such report shall include, with respect to the period of two years preceding the date of such report, the following elements:</text> <subclause id="H3B0CC3D6615246429E5CFCD6FF60BC41"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A description of any new therapy or treatment protocol developed using data shared through the partnership.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9D299F4E08C04425B1E8DCDB0E6116CF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The evaluation of the Secretary of the partnership.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9F0AB15DD89640EBAED4D2B207A21E28"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Recommendations of the Secretary regarding the partnership.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2E5E45A33B9C4A009913D9D14F4792AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3C490EF1AB04B67B7042A6DBF548348"> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H668B966DB00E4739820C00E5B59A7596"><enum>(f)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Repetitive low-level blast exposure research</header><text>In carrying out the initiative under subsection (a), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct the following research: </text> 
<paragraph id="H0B399A8C65E34B9EBF940A091EFAD90F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A big-data assessment of the clinical and non-clinical interventions that are illustrating positive outcomes for patients within the health system of the Veterans Health Administration with likely low-level repetitive blast injuries, including a categorization of military occupational specialties, and units, known to experience higher levels of low-level repetitive blast injuries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H108FC270A1CC46D0BE95F3AADEE40B27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not fewer than two large-scale implementation studies of research-proven interventions within such health system for patients with likely low-level repetitive blast injuries, including a categorization of military occupational specialties, and units, known to experience higher levels of low-level repetitive blast injuries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BD19ECCF66A4711A3E967880435FA3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A translational research study on the use of growth hormone replacement therapy on the improvement of cognitive function, quality of life, brain structure, and other negative symptoms on patients within such health system with likely low-level repetitive blast injuries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1CD6CFEC07F46D5B0EF36041C2EC6FD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Not fewer than four large-scale quality improvement studies on improving the diagnosis and care of veteran patients with likely low-level repetitive blast injuries.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2EC657A95A214768A182A648946B039C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Assistance and report by National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Precision Brain Health Research Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall seek to enter into a contract with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine under which the National Academies shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73EF1CE012424838BC94AFE65E3F68CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work in tandem with the initiative under subsection (a) on validation of brain and mental health biomarkers among veterans; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF21C1B73B108429CB1F7AD6FAAA144C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less frequently than once every two years, submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the work completed under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC927DC753BDC4BD2ADF01A6A0452DC12"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Assessment</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H728EF96FE1BB4A4D9D1F77EDBA130588"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct an assessment of all translational research studies in progress and planned under the initiative under subsection (a), including research under subsection (f).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40F6010786404E7EA6DD2BB22B77F4DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after completion of the assessment conducted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the assessment. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2A1987F373B648CFB65256AD010DC8EA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4242D7776F1C4104BC5CF9F33AEF7552"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once every two years, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the initiative under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB197E3CD91334CC1B1C66CBAC7179904"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include recommendations for immediate administrative and legislative action to improve the initiative under subsection (a). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H15548D00B79C4836801CA2A8F5DB5DFC"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs $5,000,000 to carry out the initiative under subsection (a) for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2030.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


