<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD9E3F82DF8BF41338B3A6EE9776DDFCB" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1393 IH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7016) to prohibit action to or the use of Federal funds to invade NATO countries and territories, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1393</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7016) to prohibit action to or the use of Federal funds to invade NATO countries and territories, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HAA70802BA5324DD8A6392CE4821E2FEC"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8A8DFA16312F40078BE697B88E2A1D31"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the bill (H.R. 7016) to prohibit action to or the use of Federal funds to invade NATO countries and territories, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. An amendment in the nature of a substitute received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII dated at least one day before the day of consideration of H.R. 7016, if submitted by Representative Keating of Massachusetts, shall be considered as adopted. If more than one such amendment is submitted, then only the last amendment submitted shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text></section><section id="H627A8610757641F8A4548F8D0E771EBF"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H.R. 7016.</text></section><section id="HAAB3CFC040744E3487914B2F63E045EA"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk shall transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.R. 7016 no later than 3 days after passage.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

