<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E1E6B04696B4E67878CAA914854B213" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9234 IH: Careworker Visa Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000136">Mr. Vasquez</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a W nonimmigrant visa program for careworkers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEF88564DBFA4458D9B5108DDF89DE811" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA9432D9A042E4E65BF44707AAE2DCBD6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Careworker Visa Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7F76DC73159C46D78889CEA973F8644C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCB2413DED3F9408788943A765BE8BD1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States faces a substantial and growing shortage of qualified careworkers to provide childcare, eldercare, and in-home care for individuals with disabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D8D7F6EEBEA412CB90D9668AB6DEF05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As the U.S. population ages, demand for eldercare and in-home support services is projected to increase significantly, outpacing the current domestic labor supply.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC17F920C1A24E46B73B0414E1BA644B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Access to reliable childcare and eldercare enables other American workers to remain in the workforce, supporting economic growth and productivity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC12BD9A071745A190E6F6EFAACB9AE9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Careworkers have often worked in informal economies with exposure to poor work conditions and pay.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3D7C79800BB46E0B5EBEF357F7EDE3B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Establishing a dedicated careworker visa classification will formalize these employment relationships, ensure wage protections for domestic workers, and provide a reliable and accountable pathway for employers to obtain qualified care.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD1A2B11CD1D24F79808925DC89FE2C2D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Careworker nonimmigrants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H278CF160AD7A4C62A3FF19F0B96A0F9B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (U)(iii), by striking the <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0DAB51F22614EAC88ADF5FC64A573FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (V), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF23E006777484FD7AA23FEC38A2D8E00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H3FB1C570C7F04BE0A63DFDB8170EF151" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H8D80A9159D5D493D960F6D4BD74A4F8D"> <enum>(W)</enum> <clause id="H13B52F4B175A41E999BDF155913CD64A" display-inline="yes-display-inline"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>an alien who is sponsored by an employer who has been certified by the U.S. Department of Labor and is coming temporarily to the United States to work for such employer as a careworker in accordance with section 214(s); and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HC22325165A0641A49D0D263A361FDE0E" indent="subparagraph">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the alien spouse of an alien described in clause (i) and any children younger than 21 years of age of such an alien.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H47607774CBB444A088705F4B79B10746"><enum>4.</enum><header>W nonimmigrants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 214 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184</external-xref>) is amended by:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4BA8215F3BE94D43B8BD2DCD1C04EFA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In subsection (b), by deleting <quote>subparagraph (L) or (V)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (L), (V), or (W)</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H759085CB75C548A9B59030AF57708A25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>By adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H47C0FF85A6514AF59DD2F6E279DC20FF" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H1AF9C7B2A3B9444697858BDC8696BC6B"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Careworker</header> 
<paragraph id="HACF6D777A4514DF4952C5E507310A1F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H22395CCFC7D64343A166940D96B401E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Careworker</header> <clause id="H06DE8B6CFEDB4BE59697906575AB129A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <term>careworker</term> means an individual whose primary duties consist of providing—</text> 
<subclause id="HE381E172693346D89DC0AB26DCB6EE09"><enum>(I)</enum><text>childcare, including supervision, instruction, and developmental support of children in a home or small group setting;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE2DF686DF54D48B8AD21BDB90556E50D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>eldercare, including non-medical assistance, companionship, and activities of daily living support for older adults; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H807CB023DD22410B8DD2D87729668223"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in-home or community-level personal support for individuals with disabilities, including assistance with activities of daily living, mobility, and communication.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H14833BE4C07B4340BBABA61B0E3FA552"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The term does not include individuals primarily employed by hospitals, skilled nursing facilities, residential care institutions with 25 or more employees, or other institutional healthcare employers.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3EA56891D9F3470B8729248525BA0277"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any careworker as defined in clause (i) shall perform their duties in compliance with all Federal, State and local requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5ACAB14F813C4DA28BAE88478B2E7B44"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered employer</header> <clause id="H63634FA7135C46B5AADCCAED7F9A26AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <term>covered employer</term> means—</text> 
<subclause id="HD878DD98106B4D0084EB94526A3C1D71"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an individual or family that employs a careworker to provide care in the individual’s or family’s private residence; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6C0DA2F9339F4F62AB2FDAD68B4369FD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a small caregiving business with fewer than 25 employees, including daycare centers, small eldercare facilities, and small group-home or residential care facilities, and that is lawfully organized under the laws of a State.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H5A79B5E2AE54417DA719C670C306BD9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The term does not include an employer if the employer—</text> <subclause id="HF69EB4A75F0B4DA58F791B28514DF1E2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has, with respect to the application required under paragraph (2)(B), including any attestations required by law—</text> 
<item id="H924D3BA4F6684F188B7F5344C5507C65"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>knowingly misrepresented a material fact;</text></item> <item id="HED845455A76C44BFA02562CC15E8D589"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>knowingly made a fraudulent statement; or</text></item> 
<item id="HB0A23DF8758142BCA92E3973391ADD90"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>knowingly failed to comply with the terms of such attestations;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H471E821142814EB695A845154C3814FE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>failed to cooperate with an investigation by the Secretary or Secretary of Labor; </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4FFF503601214AB191441ADC17B2CCC9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the employer or any officer of the employer has been convicted of an offense set out in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/77">chapter 77</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, or any conspiracy to commit such offenses, or any human trafficking offense under State or territorial law;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3723D6F7FD644F969D9A94009C1124E3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>has, within 2 years prior to the date of application—</text> 
<item id="H2CE7579AB10A4B57B9D549F7957A3962"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>received a final adjudication of having committed any hazardous occupation orders violation resulting in injury or death under the child labor provisions contained in section 12 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/211">29 U.S.C. 211</external-xref>) and any pertinent regulation;</text></item> <item id="HC53150C93E0B47B7963B8C4607B752E5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>received a final adjudication assessing a civil money penalty for any repeated or willful violation of the minimum wage provisions of section 6 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/206">29 U.S.C. 206</external-xref>); or</text></item> 
<item id="H8D99C734FAFD4EDD8A16E93B4B1CE619"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>received a final adjudication assessing a civil money penalty for any willful violation of the overtime provisions of section 7 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 or any regulations thereunder; or</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HC0D971B9FAE14780B9A9D5E732BE5A62"><enum>(V)</enum><text>has, within 2 years prior to the date of application, received a final adjudication for a willful violation or repeated serious violations involving injury or death—</text> 
<item id="HC97D98F068DD44A485E91BD00D179B07"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>of section 5 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/654">29 U.S.C. 654</external-xref>);</text></item> <item id="H22CEBA68E8144959876AB9A3343EA7C2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>of any standard, rule, or order promulgated pursuant to section 6 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655</external-xref>); or</text></item> 
<item id="HE7FA55EA615F4D929BFCF97B6388C01C"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>of a plan approved under section 18 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/667">29 U.S.C. 667</external-xref>).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H510559DDDFA249D190F828FE5F32D973"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BA27CBFDB1C40B2906C04D0DE25C816"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Prevailing wage</header><text>The term <term>prevailing wage</term> means the wage determined for the relevant occupation and metropolitan statistical area using data from the Department of Labor’s Office of Foreign Labor Certification Wage Search tool, or any successor data source designated by the Secretary of Labor.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA69C9260543427FADD8BCE203EA56B9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>W nonimmigrant</header><text>The term <term>W nonimmigrant</term> means an alien with status as a nonimmigrant under section 101(a)(15)(W).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF2A368DD36E4B6DBCD8AF2D71333504"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employer participation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3C702E61D372412FA1B4565A4FA39E52"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A covered employer is eligible to participate in the sponsorship process under this subsection if the employer—</text> <clause id="H6180B58D52BE468795903C7A83167B6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employs or seeks to employ a W nonimmigrant as a careworker in a year-round role as a caregiver or personal support worker; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2C061323B0144AFBB9E8669BD5238192"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a covered employer who is an individual or family, is a United States citizen or a lawful permanent resident.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD748F8056097499FBCF0E44CB35E3717"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Petition</header><text>A covered employer seeking to employ a W nonimmigrant as a careworker under this subsection shall file a petition with the Secretary on a form and in a manner prescribed by the Secretary, which shall include—</text> 
<clause id="HB47F83B482164FDFBFD576B220954406"><enum>(i)</enum><text>submission of—</text> <subclause id="H56A93E41031F445CAB6A62F52E644BE6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a job offer letter or employment contract from the covered employer;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5F0962E08997450695F46737DD0A1B4D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an attestation of compliance with the prevailing wage requirements set forth in paragraph (5);</text></subclause> <subclause id="H86218A321FB34849BDC8D586AEA93968"><enum>(III)</enum><text>evidence demonstrating the beneficiary’s eligibility and admissibility, or waiver of inadmissibility, under paragraph (3);</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA25013DF5E664B7BA9F45D8F7B4CA750"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a fee, as required by the Secretary;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3A37402D698C43108036E9C052222F14"><enum>(V)</enum><text>biometrics of the employer, for an individual employer; and for the owner or directing officer, for a business employer; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2634F5521F254B779E7DA4437150F7DB"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the last three years of tax returns for the individual or business, as applicable, to demonstrate their ability to pay the salary of the caregiver if approved.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HDC8B7C72A5F34C96BD72A7128F3C0211"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall adjudicate petitions within 90 days of receipt of a complete filing.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE6D090193AE424090A9921EFEC3C8FE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Continuing obligations</header><text>A covered employer that employs a W nonimmigrant under this subsection shall—</text> <clause id="HC3BACD908EB14E28970EE8B7CC376F48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintain records of wages paid to the W nonimmigrant and make such records available for inspection by the Secretary of Labor upon request;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H083A496425994BEFA434B4A407AF3869"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the Secretary within 14 days of any material change in the terms or conditions of employment, including separation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H37F24016FBAC4F6ABC083483A57B81D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>comply with all applicable Federal and State labor and employment laws.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E9DD9D434074035860443B255515CAC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Beneficiary</header> 
<subparagraph id="H72E711A45F254308B09A9BDB194EF7A8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An alien is eligible for status under section 101(a)(15)(W) if the alien—</text> <clause id="HB0FDEF8347B440C88563441DEEE14F0B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has received a qualifying job offer as a caregiver from an approved covered employer;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H94A7D033E4654814B3E2BB7D34270318"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is admissible to the United States, or eligible for a waiver of inadmissibility pursuant to subparagraph (B); and</text></clause> <clause id="HEE18DC2911BD4A77975557A7D02667B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>passes a background check, including a check of criminal records and relevant databases, conducted by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDAEABA563749476A88B6FBBC4920893D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to waive the grounds of inadmissibility under section 212(a)(9)(B) if the alien—</text> <clause id="H14ACD35C16F9433087FE16BD53BEEFC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>files a petition requesting a waiver of inadmissibility;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC7F89EC1E4F44A32AFE3C7DA35972CDB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates payment of all applicable Federal, State, and local taxes, including any back taxes owed, for all periods of unauthorized presence in the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF0D3239902C240638C05E4C09211046B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>pays a fee of $500.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDACF5EA44C454B6EBD796B997794020E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Motions for termination or removal</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Attorney General, shall establish a process for an alien—</text> <clause id="HA284154E8D9F44D0AF2341E4DFC812BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in removal proceedings, upon approval of the petition in paragraph (2)(B), to request termination of proceedings; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H88EFBAB18FFC46639408DAF291301D8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with a final order of removal, upon approval of the petition in paragraph (2)(B), to file a motion to reopen the final order and terminate proceedings.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4CC451E3BE784950852B263010BDB75B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header> <clause id="H9C636E43B0944E13816AA535ECD48E6F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>An alien is eligible for adjustment of status to that of a W nonimmigrant if that alien—</text> 
<subclause id="H72F2294F9CDB43F0BFB6083B9EE3A1C1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>submits an application or has an eligible employee submit a petition on their behalf;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H17E2340B696B4234886110395C77FA9E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>pays the fee under subparagraph (B)(iii) as required and any tax liability owed to the United States;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H87B73EDC1E6844918B50BD3072CAA72F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>was present in the United States as of January 1, 2024—</text> <item id="H3FBAD71BF34A46B897659E535AAB0CF4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>without lawful status under the immigration laws;</text></item> 
<item id="H5D00C6D540CA4FF2AE5816D9DF2F8384"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>with deferred action granted to the alien pursuant to the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals program set forth in the memorandum of the Secretary dated June 15, 2012;</text></item> <item id="H54121A249033432D8D723168B0066E3B"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>as a parolee;</text></item> 
<item id="H414B1A51A48F48AD95D605DF5A7F540A"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>with deferred enforced departure; or</text></item> <item id="HBEAFB7B654EC4F74962F529EA8557A56"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>with status as a nonimmigrant that has employment authorization;</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H00F884B88A974F93A411DD865716EC91"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>has been continuously present in the United States during the period beginning on January 1, 2024, through the date of the application for status; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H46D095F2CDE94711808B9A05BC723EED"><enum>(V)</enum><text>is not inadmissible under paragraph (1), (6)(E), (6)(G), (8), or (10) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>), except that with respect to any benefit under this subparagraph, and in addition to the waivers under subparagraph (B), the Secretary may waive the grounds of inadmissibility under paragraph (1), (6)(E), (6)(G), or (10)(D) of section 212(a) for humanitarian purposes, for family unity, or because the waiver is otherwise in the public interest.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H453CCB0E021040739EFB7D512391BF53"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Ground of ineligibility</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), an alien is ineligible under this subparagraph if any of the following apply:</text> <subclause id="H93219B8370D248DDB54D171EFA1039F0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The alien is inadmissible under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 212(a).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9B5E28AE8B9E4D93B03E0841BD19F248"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Excluding any offense under State law for which an essential element is the alien’s immigration status, and any minor traffic offense, the alien has been convicted of—</text> <item id="HC30AE1EDBCDB4C5CABCBB1DA49FDA855"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any felony offense;</text></item> 
<item id="H27635CEFE3914ACAA9BC1A93C07DEC87"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>three or more misdemeanor offenses (excluding simple possession of cannabis or cannabis-related paraphernalia, any offense involving cannabis or cannabis-related paraphernalia which is no longer prosecutable in the State in which the conviction was entered, and any offense involving civil disobedience without violence) not occurring on the same date, and not arising out of the same act, omission, or scheme of misconduct; or</text></item> <item id="H5D22EBE95A2E4EA293C1853AD93ABDB8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a misdemeanor offense of domestic violence, unless the alien demonstrates that such crime is related to the alien having been—</text> 
<subitem id="HBD10F0EDCBF341D2A610620296E7680C"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>a victim of domestic violence, sexual assault, stalking, child abuse or neglect, abuse or neglect in later life, or human trafficking;</text></subitem> <subitem id="HF9E6B38163B5414EB9BFE0DDCE42220E"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>battered or subjected to extreme cruelty; or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H323EBDD6254E497AB01F604A7A39F23E"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>a victim of criminal activity described in section 101(a)(15)(U)(iii).</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H639BBC863F6B4A329EFF17080FC80FDD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Waiver for certain misdemeanors</header><text>For humanitarian purposes, family unity, or if otherwise in the public interest, the Secretary may—</text> 
<subclause id="HB7D3D79F0B654D74970E1250562135D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>waive the grounds of inadmissibility under subparagraphs (A), (C), and (D) of section 212(a)(2), unless the conviction forming the basis for inadmissibility would otherwise render the alien ineligible under clause (ii)(II); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6950E1FEDCCB4DA596197E6270890CA9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for purposes of clauses (ii) and (iii) of paragraph (1)(B), waive consideration of—</text> 
<item id="HF2838EA51CB6427BAC217CE47F56F54E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>one misdemeanor offense if the alien has not been convicted of any offense in the 5-year period preceding the date on which the alien applies for adjustment of status under this title; or</text></item> <item id="H9ABCE9530EC0438C909970376E51D001"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>up to two misdemeanor offenses if the alien has not been convicted of any offense in the 10-year period preceding the date on which the alien applies for adjustment of status under this title.</text>
                                        </item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1BD272FA870045A1A6B62B68636202A4"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph—</text> <subclause id="H523F0AFF840A43D88C8BAAF5EA7E0FB9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the term <term>felony offense</term> means an offense under Federal or State law that is punishable by a maximum term of imprisonment of more than 1 year;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE48008DDA69D49008BC348CD8F3227F0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the term <term>misdemeanor offense</term> means an offense under Federal or State law that is punishable by a term of imprisonment of more than 5 days but not more than 1 year; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H22EBBFB602F84EFDB9E4073EF2EE6D0D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the term <term>crime of domestic violence</term> means any offense that has as an element the use, attempted use, or threatened use of physical force against a person committed by a current or former spouse of the person, by an individual with whom the person shares a child in common, by an individual who is cohabiting with or has cohabited with the person as a spouse, by an individual similarly situated to a spouse of the person under the domestic or family violence laws of the jurisdiction where the offense occurs, or by any other individual against a person who is protected from that individual’s acts under the domestic or family violence laws of the United States or any State, Indian Tribal government, or unit of local government.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H63A242AE1BFD46B984B756E80A5A2BF0"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any alien who seeks status as a W nonimmigrant for the purpose of performing skilled or unskilled labor is inadmissible, unless the Secretary of Labor has determined and certified to the Secretary of State and the Attorney General that—</text> <subclause id="H8ABD0237182840E88BC58797EB9716F1"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>there are not sufficient workers who are able, willing, qualified and available at the time of application for a visa and admission to the United States and at the place where the alien is to perform such skilled or unskilled labor; and </text>
                                    </subclause> 
<subclause id="H08AC3A7E613C41D79E87174D505C8FC9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the employment of such alien will not adversely affect the wages and working conditions of workers in the United States similarly employed. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEBA9EECD528442DAC96D2BB9D2F33C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employment authorization</header> <subparagraph id="HDC7533D693894E9EB0B1FD45EA48C450"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Employment authorization under this subsection is incident to status and is confined to the covered employer named in the approved petition.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H22515C9A613B429E956827F94F3B598A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A W nonimmigrant who separates from an employer and seeks to transfer to a new covered employer shall be afforded a grace period of 90 days, during which the W nonimmigrant retains lawful status, to allow a new covered employer to file a petition on the W nonimmigrant’s behalf.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A1C8C66A8FC4617849D40423A455093"><enum>(C)</enum><text>During the 90-day grace period described in subparagraph (B), the W nonimmigrant is authorized to transition to any qualifying caretaker role with a new covered employer.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF07B926DB5664EBCAA6F3970598BDEB5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Within 10 business days, the new employer must file a petition with the Department to demonstrate that the W nonimmigrant is employed as a caregiver or personal support worker.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63513BBFB94F4F2C94FA5FCF0EC1CD73"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prevailing wage requirements</header> <subparagraph id="HB2CCC0365FEE4754BB015165659397AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A covered employer shall pay a W nonimmigrant wages that meet or exceed the prevailing wage for the relevant occupation in the applicable metropolitan statistical area.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE10D0B78BADD433D9275C513B614AECE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor shall establish an office to—</text> <clause id="H9CEB54834EC64C20BDE51C5A3BBC4AC4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>certify prevailing wages for W nonimmigrant positions;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF74DF4BBBD4E467984C0897426244A41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>receive complaints from W nonimmigrant, including for wage theft or other wage violations or poor working conditions, and imposing penalties for noncompliance;</text></clause> <clause id="H12CF22CBA3774D50AE183356E996D514"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>investigate complaints received in clause (ii);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE4EAF03D970B4D87BB8BAE0C6AEA4990"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provide information in the top ten languages of approved W nonimmigrants as well as the ability to translate information through a help-line; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8DFC85EAA8B74E40B853B0281001DCBA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>develop and share resources with W nonimmigrants about their workplace rights.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7282CFE618F24DCCAC8C62813E1F5851"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Filing fees</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC7A351F48DD8499C926841BD8AAFE9AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A covered employer shall pay a filing fee at the time of submitting a petition. The Secretary shall set the filing fee in an amount sufficient to cover the full cost of processing the sponsorship petition and W nonimmigrant application.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE91386939114E539B44A85E929CD8B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall review and adjust filing fees not less frequently than every 2 years to ensure that fee revenues remain sufficient to cover program costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0DDA399248AE48FCA6727892A9F4BEFA"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Annual limit</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFC5C41DBE655424AB2804F6B71F1A32C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not more than 100,000 aliens may be accorded status as W nonimmigrants each fiscal year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F6369696EAF448985E4575783AF260B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>The Secretary shall by regulation establish procedures for the allocation of available visas when demand exceeds the annual limit, including provisions to ensure equitable access for both individual/family and small business employers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92535C3A705045B6AEE38BD59261B10B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Duration</header> 
<subparagraph id="H2BDCBCF28B7848A9A0F03244B223CE68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A visa issued to a W nonimmigrant shall have an initial validity period of 3 years.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9E32A2720D74ECBBAA21A399E24A3E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A W nonimmigrant may renew a W nonimmigrant visa in additional 3-year increments, subject to continued eligibility under this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H15E1E8D59EA847F59D9CF30204CF014C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Applications for renewal may be filed from within the United States and shall be adjudicated by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16E53989B22A4B2A9396CB414D62A1F0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A W nonimmigrant may seek adjustment of status to lawful permanent resident in accordance with the following:</text> 
<clause id="HBCBBF04AD1EA494AA0817D3FD96BC85D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish a process and required fees no higher than $500 for adjustment of status in accordance with this section. </text></clause> <clause id="HF5802C189BB1401FAC8F6829B8EFAC9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An alien whose status is adjusted to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residency under this section is not subject to the worldwide levels or numerical limitations of section 201(a).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF22F5B8BC370495C9EF4DA7FC592E052"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Non-retaliation</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB2470280E5134E608BDE47AA2235CC13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>It shall be unlawful for a covered employer to—</text> <clause id="H2EFC538EC61C4502A50568599473508C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intimidate, threaten, or retaliate against a W nonimmigrant for exercising any right under this Act;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H22010E732C1C4C5F827D0ABD336D1CD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use the W nonimmigrant’s immigration status as a means of coercion or control; or</text></clause> <clause id="H2AD6949E20284F2EBB8296A5B0C9C16F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>terminate the W nonimmigrant’s employment in retaliation for reporting wage violations or unsafe working conditions to a Federal or State agency.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H51CD35E3685549468E5D695673723103"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Secretary shall provide each W nonimmigrant, in plain language and in the W nonimmigrant’s primary language where practicable, a written summary of the W nonimmigrant’s rights under this Act and applicable Federal and State labor laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9478487AFE34150AC04D67E832E77C9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of State, shall finalize regulations implementing this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H396B7309AFCB495F81329E9B0C509FDD"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Annual report to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on the implementation of this Act, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HFDC781F99FDA46B9BBF0EAFE2F7AA673"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of sponsorship petitions filed, approved, and denied;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H288DA89E52014257B3E2DEE516C2E7E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of W nonimmigrant visas issued and renewed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7A61155F3544839BE5BE0B7866403D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number and disposition of wage violation complaints; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0C26FE27B914FAA89763B647EDA0304"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative changes, if any, to improve the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H25CDE44FF29242919F990C7651425E90"><enum>5.</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 214(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5E509FC6C6994BD387E37AEDBAB437A6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H2478D21D49144FC5A8E4E6DF51B29CC4"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header> 
<subparagraph id="HB56AAC9447A141F99A98A343019C57E6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person may not discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, harass, decline to hire, or in any other manner discriminate against a worker in the terms and conditions of employment because such worker—</text> <clause id="HF397175C1B5A48CC8CB93AB7EC04A70B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has filed a complaint, testified, assisted, or cooperated or seeks to cooperate, in an investigation or other proceeding concerning compliance with the requirements under this title or any rule or regulation pertaining to any workplace claim;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFB019FFABA9E4046B3550712E3F192EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has disclosed information to any other person or entity, that the worker reasonably believes evidences a violation of this title or any rule or regulation pertaining to this title, or grounds for any workplace claim;</text></clause> <clause id="H6EEF007CE1C1442781D466DB46ED804E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has assisted or participated, or has information that may assist, in any manner in a proceeding or in any other action to carry out the purposes of this title or any workplace claim;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB41CC797D43E4B71B75828FC638B9EC9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has furnished information to the Department of Labor, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the National Labor Relations Board, or any Federal, State, or local regulatory or law enforcement agency relating to a violation of this title or any workplace claim, or has such information to furnish to the relevant agency; or</text></clause> <clause id="H9960C7E6BE3F456E8F325B00C2B4F423"><enum>(v)</enum><text>has objected to, or refused to participate in, any activity, policy, practice, or assigned task that the worker (or other such individual) reasonably believed to be in violation of any provision of this Act or any other Act, or any order, rule, regulation, standard, or ban under any Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA220B3567B4435EB7D59582BFC51846"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A worker who believes that he or she has suffered a violation of subparagraph (A) may seek relief in accordance with the procedures, notifications, burdens of proof, remedies, and statutes of limitations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HC72259D0C3EA475F943B282328350812"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment, except that the Secretary may implement any provision earlier to the extent necessary to prepare regulations and operational capacity.</text></section> 
<section id="HCD75642E257D4EEE95FA01757CE2386F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of State, shall finalize rules implementing this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> <section id="H26330629951A4FDD9E4682EAA955BB1A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Annual report to congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report on the implementation of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE0E51F668FFE4B38ACD72C7E432672AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of sponsorship petitions filed, approved, and denied;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAA7120716124F7DA685254312F5841E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of W nonimmigrant visas issued and renewed;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5160E27000C44821BFE2E174152FF560"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number and disposition of wage violation complaints; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6DD95E7F6DD490CB1188A1D445432A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative changes, if any, to improve the program.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

