<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H35D0A54A0C9A437DAC3B424CF99F758B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9311 IH: Build Housing Affordably Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9311</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260615">June 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To exempt certain covered projects from the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, or any regulation or guidance issued for such chapter.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0EEE703F343149C781EA9F1CFF8CCFFC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCE4CEAADF47B495BB1DB19128EA413EA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Build Housing Affordably Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE6157BE4DD984191B11F9E6C2E645DDF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Buy American Act study and report</header> <subsection id="H56ABAD2DA04142768738C5F5081833E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall conduct a study of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H873FB254AC2E488284998C00DC08F969"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impacts of the Build America, Buy America Act (title IV of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8301">42 U.S.C. 8301</external-xref> note) and its implementation on grantees, subgrantees, builders, developers, and contractors using covered programs to build affordable housing, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H02B19227C28641F0B3334A2CA0250269"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the direct costs of procuring materials for federally assisted housing projects;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BED7E1E56ED4F609C1A6289439C52BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the indirect costs associated with compliance, including any increased administrative costs, costs incurred while pursuing a waiver, and costs of consultants or other labor required to deal with increased administrative costs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79F524B118224094AFDCE9FC7904915F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the costs of delays associated with compliance; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAD64C64EA2D4C7A9C24616A860BB454"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the costs associated with any housing projects left incomplete as a result of compliance, and the number of units not built as a result of compliance; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H842616824AC5481289B4465A51623CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Build America, Buy America Act (title IV of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8301">42 U.S.C. 8301</external-xref> note) waiver process with respect to covered programs, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA2348A84FE154478A4371728B7829522"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Housing and Urban Development’s processes and policies for reviewing waivers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B7CC6F320CC417FB4ADCFF6D003CA17"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of time it takes the Department of Housing and Urban Development to process waivers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H785C5404A99B49B087EDE1EC521E7F78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of waivers granted for housing projects;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF153F1EFD4E54BF7BB5FED3497E9B46A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which general public interest waivers are utilized currently and whether issuing additional general public interest waivers could reduce costs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8795A3FD33B745D29D6FCA64FC33D147"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the de minimis general waiver; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA757A5D613D42469D3E5741801A5C5C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the materials or products most often subject to requests for waivers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H315C938DD7744EAFA07576BD399433D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, not later than 90 days after completing the study required under subsection (a), submit a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing all findings and contents of the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H9BAF3BE8DDB0479A8BF485E3EFBBC9F8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirement to pause implementation of Build America, Buy America Act requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, regulation, guidance, or policy, any covered project assisted in any part by amounts provided under a covered program shall not be subject to any of the requirements of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code, or any regulations issued for such chapter until the date that is 60 days after the report required under subsection (a) is delivered to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></section> 
<section id="HB15C9E4597224D2B8B04C2C5FD1B989C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Timing for review of waiver applications</header> 
<subsection id="H7817F14F12234E3D8602F629EEBC2909"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an entity that is undertaking a covered project assisted in any part by amounts provided under a covered program submits a request to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development for a waiver from the requirements of Build America, Buy America Act (title IV of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8301">42 U.S.C. 8301</external-xref> note), notwithstanding any other provision of law, regulation, guidance, or policy, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall render a decision on such request for a waiver not later than 90 days after receiving such request.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H81BF959C80F4459BBC2BF1AF51FC488C"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Failure To render a decision</header> <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, regulation, guidance, or policy, if the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development fails to render a decision on a request for a waiver under subsection (a) in the time period specified in subsection (a), the waiver shall be deemed to have been granted.</text>
      </subsection>
<subsection id="H6D8DFB7A307B4AA08AF95923D15337A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any waiver deemed to have been granted under subsection (b) shall be final and irrevocable and may not be subjected to further review by any Federal official.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H243AF9336E9843F19FFA9C33460742BC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H1EEEE533BD5146798F3DB932EC6B109E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered program</header><text>The term <term>covered program</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9808E7DC6FC4EC4A621B2345C0F8E77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public housing program under the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8414D5CA8DB84A518AB887C930CD8355"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the program for rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BA13DF932AE4C06AF7B1A78D6EA9C03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the HOME Investment Partnerships program under title II of the Cranton-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12721">42 U.S.C. 12721 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD666EBC8BA434767A7911F7F15B3E469"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the program for supportive housing for the elderly under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC004D7CDB23F41C9B7C850B819963090"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the program for supportive housing for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8013">42 U.S.C. 8013</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8AED6DBD9CC043D29D6C87386DA17EE9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the program for Native American housing under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4101">25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F2E44044ADD418A98E1BC3A1F06476A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the program for housing assistance for Native Hawaiians under title VIII of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8FBE645DB8A4740BA7DD40A5A3485BD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Housing Trust Fund program under section 1338 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB823040BB7BE48E698206A47D902701E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the programs under title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11360">42 U.S.C. 11360 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H767A72265EAB4E08AC6031E563C24A40"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the AIDS Housing Opportunities program under subtitle D of title VIII of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12901">42 U.S.C. 12901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89A81DBACE27437E8D971575B9139BB1"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the programs for assistance for rural rental housing under title V of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1471">42 U.S.C. 1471 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C71A51CF5CD433B8284D5E786FF6132"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Community Development Block Grant program under title I of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5301">42 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60F42059CA614C91B9FC38C454F29AF4"> <enum>(M)</enum> <text>the Capacity Building for Affordable Housing and Community Development program under section 4 of the HUD Demonstration Act of 1993 (Pub. L. 103–120, 107 Stat. 1148, <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9816">42 U.S.C. 9816</external-xref> note); and</text>
        </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB320D5A3C04C46B5B7F1CD4B66C9BB7F"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the Choice Neighborhoods Initiative, initially authorized under title I of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/117">Public Law 111–117</external-xref> (123 Stat. 3093).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73AB22B606CE42219E99CD9F9BF2378A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered project</term> means a project assisted in any part by amounts provided under a covered program that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0D53776ACD8A4DE2A236C70909327C84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is subject to the requirements of Build America, Buy America Act (title IV of division G of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8301">42 U.S.C. 8301</external-xref> note); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBD6EB8537AE43A1BE36A5B5E041E08E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has as its primary purpose the purchase, construction, rehabilitation, preservation, or improvement of residential housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

