<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3207FD70C3BE4206965C277B724B8998" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7657 IH: Military Family Diaper Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7657</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to provide funds to the National Diaper Bank Network for the establishment of a Military Family Diaper Fund to provide diapers and diapering supplies to military families in need, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4FAD5FF0F40742F79414D292E709726F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7428E8C1BCCE4828A2405F3180BD41F1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Family Diaper Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H381C89AF3601472FA671A352F10D2A62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provision of funds for establishment of Military Family Diaper Fund</header> 
<subsection id="H088BA2DBE0CA47C0BF296E565A5A833D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter an agreement with the National Diaper Bank Network to provide to the Network $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 for the purpose of establishing a military family diaper fund to distribute diapers and diapering supplies to military families.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H96E7F7371FA24EE8952052CF43FEACCE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An agreement under subsection (a) shall provide that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H01EBB0170B944F25B89C6A27E57F76D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the National Diaper Bank Network shall establish a military family diaper fund and deposit funds received from the Secretary under the agreement into such fund;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9E2F01230D245EA8CD8A47AA3CBD490"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Diaper Bank Network shall deposit into the military family diaper fund matching funds or in-kind contributions from non-Federal Government sources that are of a value equal or greater to the amount of funds provided by the Secretary under the agreement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H349C6DF842BB4FC69B5A35919F62A0C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>funds or in-kind contributions in the military family diaper fund shall only be provided to members of the National Diaper Bank Network who have engaged in the distribution of diapers or diapering supplies in an area located within 20 miles of a military installation for a period of not less than five years;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H575AAF2EA5B94E67BF2A1B8924A215F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such funds or in-kind contributions shall only be used—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB31B38021536476CAC23F82BCB007B02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide diapers and diapering supplies to military families in need of diapers or diapering supplies; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5E5D21EE5F643AA9BD6D42FAFC04342"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for technical assistance and evaluation provided by the National Diaper Bank Network; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FDBBD50328D42259B4F95653CD23424"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the National Diaper Bank Network shall submit to the Secretary of Defense an annual report on the activities carried out using the military family diaper fund during the preceding fiscal year.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

