<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" dms-id="H11163c62-e350-4162-8969-f5fde25d3399" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-House" key="H" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1014 EH: Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7148) making further consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7147) making further consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="no">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="no">2d Session</session>
<legis-num>H. RES. 1014</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="yes">In the House of Representatives, U. S.,</current-chamber>
<action>
<action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date>
</action> 
<legis-type display="yes">RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="no">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7148) making further consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7147) making further consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="Haf37bdb1-ba33-4c65-a982-5ad0982f03f8">
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H7c9e9cab-fd31-408e-9b16-7cef388934aa"><text>That at any time after adoption of this resolution the Speaker may, pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XVIII, declare the House resolved into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7148) making further consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes. The first reading of the bill shall be dispensed with. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. General debate shall be confined to the bill and shall not exceed one hour equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations or their respective designees. After general debate the bill shall be considered for amendment under the five-minute rule. The amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. No further amendment to the bill, as amended, shall be in order except those printed in part B of the report of the Committee on Rules. Each such further amendment may be offered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, shall be considered as read, shall be debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, and shall not be subject to a demand for division of the question in the House or in the Committee of the Whole. All points of order against such further amendments are waived. At the conclusion of consideration of the bill for amendment the Committee shall rise and report the bill, as amended, to the House with such further amendments as may have been adopted. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto to final passage without intervening motion except one motion to recommit.</text></section> <section id="H1FD09CD2D75C425ABFFA90E2EEDECE04"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to consider in the House the bill (H.R. 7147) making further consolidated appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2026, and for other purposes. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment specified in section 7 of this resolution shall be considered as adopted. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as read. All points of order against provisions in the bill, as amended, are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill, as amended, and on any further amendment thereto, to final passage without intervening motion except: (1) one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the chair and ranking minority member of the Committee on Appropriations or their respective designees; and (2) one motion to recommit.</text> </section> 
<section id="H9EF3DDB389C944D5BEBAD29A2DAC087F"><enum>3.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chair of the Committee on Appropriations may insert in the Congressional Record not later than January 23, 2026, such material as he may deem explanatory of H.R. 7148 and H.R. 7147.</text></section> <section id="HA23857D7CFBF43FD88C036CA53A18956"><enum>4.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clerk shall not transmit to the Senate a message that the House has passed H.R. 7148 until H.R. 7147 is passed by the House.</text></section>
<section id="HF22E820DDC6944D08A888F5C061E3565"><enum>5.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the engrossment of H.R. 7148, the Clerk shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA54EF05C00E044BF85BEA7507CB41FEC"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">add the text of Divisions A, B, and C of H.R. 7006, as passed by the House, as new matter to follow Division D of H.R. 7148, redesignated as Divisions E, F, and G, respectively;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8B5B9CD947D48FDA30F742379C9CFDB"><enum>(b)</enum><text>add the text of titles I through V of H.R. 7147, as passed by the House, as new matter designated as Division H, to follow the text added pursuant to subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF137C13124D244D49569D58402B298BB"><enum>(c)</enum><text>redesignate Divisions E and F of H.R. 7148 as Divisions I and J, respectively;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB4FA118569EA42A3BE654FD41ED67ACA"><enum>(d)</enum><text>assign appropriate designations to provisions within the engrossment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6071224D995B427CB672C618CF398776"><enum>(e)</enum><text>conform cross-references and provisions for short titles within the engrossment; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HABFDA055CFF74F228E899893B8073B72"><enum>(f)</enum><text>be authorized to make technical corrections, to include corrections in spelling, punctuation, page and line numbering, section numbering, and insertion of appropriate headings.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H1578E36A2E48455F91D3B73784FC9B65"><enum>6.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">House Resolution 375, as amended by the amendments printed in part C of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, is hereby adopted.</text></section>
<section id="H134B16D6129D4FFC9E19599FF99EA5DD"><enum>7.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment referred to in section 2 of this resolution is as follows: </text></section> <section id="H4535740761FE40B4920510DD80558956" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><list level="section"><list-item><pagebreak/>At the end of the bill (before the short title) add the following:</list-item></list> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H563EF7C3F8D54366AAD4F3AA234D34D5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H9823133C79F242B0AF10CBA286723B97"><enum>___.</enum><header>Repeal of Senate Notification Requirements Relating to Legal Process on Disclosures of Senate Data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 213 of title II of division C of the Continuing Appropriations, Agriculture, Legislative Branch, Military Construction and Veterans Affairs, and Extensions Act, 2026, and the amendments made by such section, are hereby repealed and shall have no force or effect.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</resolution-body>
<attestation><attestation-group><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</resolution>


