<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B68715B28DE4834B60BFE87670310EF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8121 IH: To designate the Christiansted Bandstand at the Christiansted National Historic Site, St. Croix, Virgin Islands, as the “Peter G. Thurland, Sr., Bandstand”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8121</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the Christiansted Bandstand at the Christiansted National Historic Site, St. Croix, Virgin Islands, as the <quote>Peter G. Thurland, Sr., Bandstand</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3EE4B3D4DD414071BB8CF8E4E5958EF5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE62F72C3C3C741B49203E8418F64B64D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H9219EAAD718C401591703959CAA0E796"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Peter Gregory Thurland, Sr.—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBAC3C6D76F004BB0B17AA4DA25E2F116"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was born on February 19, 1892, in the town of Christiansted on the island of St. Croix in the Virgin Islands;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68BDC92B48524F82A272DB94412D3FF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">excelled in playing the trombone and baritone horn and dedicated his life to attaining excellence in music;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B5DB243B23E4B5B9CE602C6E8D120B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shortly after the transfer of the Virgin Islands from Denmark to the United States, joined the United States Navy on June 12, 1917, and served as a member of the Navy Band;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF9A59FC7DB8E4D40913D40B42D811579"><enum>(D)</enum><text>worked on the construction and design of the Christiansted Bandstand, where he played with the Christiansted Naval Band at their monthly concerts until he was honorably discharged in September 1921;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4C917EEE7254F4EA9A29888A87BBB60"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is renowned in his native Virgin Islands as a master craftsman and a skillful cabinetmaker;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA84AE80791C44B38F2828BACB87F41B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>founded the St. Croix Community Band in 1938 and trained many young musicians who performed free at monthly concerts at the Christiansted Bandstand; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E514FA479444EB6A00EA76337436DFD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>conducted the St. Croix Community Band until his retirement for health reasons in 1968, at which time he turned over the leadership position of the band to his son; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0ADE5CA04344E358C90AA4FFC210540"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>it is a fitting tribute to his leadership, courage, and contributions to the community of St. Croix to designate the Christiansted Bandstand in honor and memory of Peter G. Thurland, Sr.</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H3E0CFA3EF291456B82A1578261DE07F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The bandstand commonly referred to as the <quote>Christiansted Bandstand</quote>, located at the Christiansted National Historic Site, St. Croix, Virgin Islands, is designated as the <quote>Peter G. Thurland, Sr., Bandstand</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H66357583D4404AEDAB1ECA7489766CA9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Legal references</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any reference in any law, regulation, document, record, map, or other paper of the United States to the bandstand referred to in section 2 is deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Peter G. Thurland, Sr., Bandstand</quote>.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

