<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON25581-1G0-HK-8C0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3337 IS: Strategic Plan for Aging Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3337</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to require the Assistant Secretary for Aging to award grants to States, Indian tribes, and tribal organizations to create or implement Multisector Plans for Aging and Aging with a Disability, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id157D350188D24280A18EFF43E0B44A99"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strategic Plan for Aging Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id8173e83913f34053b4a0d97f0528c018"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supporting Multisector Plans for Aging and Aging with a Disability</header><subsection id="id6452b7276b744a12b1727959786a598f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part A of IV of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3032">42 U.S.C. 3032 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6adf5b59f0d048d4b201b7cee576e254"><section id="id985e63761982480c8c3edb456dd48d8e"><enum>423.</enum><header>Supporting Multisector Plans For Aging and Aging with a Disability</header><subsection id="id7d7667b166a841b1b1c0f765bcf01126"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id2ecca68e14ff4527a3e78ebad66bc610"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aging and disability stakeholders</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id463c823b29d94d86847223fb653d5129"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>aging and disability stakeholders</term> means a group of individuals with experience or expertise in aging or disability issues, which shall consist of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14550fd50d274411963dadea4e744d11"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from area agencies on aging;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id484604757fc8452ab5c536d108e27072"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covered individuals; and</text></clause><clause id="id6e18b53d36174d6596ad7582dcd7e708"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>representatives from not less than 3 of the groups described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id941271c3f98e4b02910da61679b9caee"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional groups</header><text>The groups described in this subparagraph are the following:</text><clause id="id0339c9badd2042e8bec2759c5ce67cea"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Advocates for covered individuals.</text></clause><clause id="idd334bf78e84041e4a96875421b91e55f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Academics with expertise in aging or disability issues.</text></clause><clause id="id2ea9102080364c34af1bf7a300c119d2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Philanthropic organizations with experience in supporting aging or disability initiatives.</text></clause><clause id="id09b4dbc0eef34e8abf9d6370672ef3a0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Individuals and community partners serving older individuals, including individuals employed by area agencies on aging or by multipurpose senior centers.</text></clause><clause id="id4dc6f83cf8fd4605a74abc6eeff43017"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Providers of aging or disability services.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id760d01d8e79b4c71b137402923483698"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Representatives of units of general purpose local government (as defined in section 301).</text></clause><clause id="idfd56e5042a7f4148b5b6d5d43f640985"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Any other group of individuals serving or representing covered individuals, as determined appropriate by the Assistant Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70d13a504ee54e7d9622f7fc0b1158fe"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered individuals</header><text>The term <term>covered individuals</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida7584c96e64c496a9bc145efb2b347ab"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">older individuals, including older individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9f5c93f886744f17ab45f20e21577bbe"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals who are family members of older individuals, including family members of older individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA5C5F4F7AB5B4996BD3768E0DBB5DF2C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paid caregivers, and unpaid caregivers, of older individuals, including any such caregivers of older individuals with disabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3BF2ECF2DD6E4BDEAC020F536A3218EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>older relative caregivers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc79ce441b5b04e209a70c8a11966c352"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disability</header><text>Notwithstanding section 102(13), the term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4a8a041db1343aeb9cff029de74a776"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State, Indian tribe, or tribal organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc3df7905ad4649f0b981323d1db1d663"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Multisector plan for aging and aging with a disability; master plan for aging; plan</header><text>The terms <term>Multisector Plan for Aging and Aging with a Disability</term>, <term>Master Plan for Aging</term>, and <term>Plan</term> mean a multi-year planning process, administered by an eligible entity, that convenes cross-sector stakeholders, including aging and disability stakeholders, to collaboratively address the diverse needs of covered individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id695f95ab827b489c99391aaa143b22f2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Older relative caregiver</header><text>The term <term>older relative caregiver</term> has the meaning given such term in section 372.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1d3cc56988c4789a7fafea2660e85f3"><enum>(7)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Qualified leader</header><text>The term <term>qualified leader</term>, with respect to an eligible entity, means—</text><subparagraph id="id3cd9dc8d183648749471e9d9fe3316ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the head of the eligible entity, or the head of an agency or department of the eligible entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a700208f2b744d686144737e2327c2a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a legislative committee of the eligible entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id33e6778cc97b448c8c2ad7cb27433e10"><enum>(C)</enum><text>another leader of the eligible entity, as determined appropriate by the Assistant Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id417d1e9f4077413395632da4d9b1590d"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Targeted subgroup</header><text>The term <term>targeted subgroup</term> means a subgroup of older individuals (including older individuals with disabilities) who are older individuals with greatest social need, or greatest economic need, as a result of geographic location, disability status, sexual orientation, gender identity, sex characteristics, socioeconomic status, language, immigration status, or other factors determined appropriate by the Assistant Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id9c950676e592456ead6219cddbacaeda"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to provide eligible entities with resources to create, coordinate, implement, and evaluate cross-sector plans to improve the health, well-being, and quality of life of covered individuals, which may include targeted subgroups.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide261010f6788428eb356248e5c49388a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants</header><paragraph id="idbd1690be850b42d584da184dd1e9728b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis in accordance with this section to eligible entities to each create or implement a Multisector Plan for Aging and Aging with a Disability (also known as a <quote>Master Plan for Aging</quote>) that meets the requirements under paragraph (2). Such grants may be used in the creation or implementation stage of such a Plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf0b94bca16774c9fa4a28e1468c322d3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plans</header><text>A Plan created or implemented by an eligible entity through a grant under this section shall—</text><subparagraph id="ide2c60a0081544567b8da1afde7f9d1f4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a creation or implementation process that is informed or led by a working group of aging and disability stakeholders (which may include stakeholders who represent targeted subgroups) that reflects the diversity and demographics of the population in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id381904d7cb97452dae02ae658a82dbe9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serve as a strategic planning resource that helps the eligible entity work across agencies or departments of the eligible entity (including political subdivisions of the eligible entity), in collaboration with public or private programs operating in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, and through collaborations with other eligible entities receiving such a grant to serve an area in the jurisdiction of the first eligible entity, to transform the infrastructure and coordination of key services, supports, and initiatives described in paragraph (3) for covered individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id55494709bb6a4fd0a8c451a0f0dd15d4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enable a qualified leader of the eligible entity to communicate a clear vision, and priorities, for a period of not less than 10 years for the eligible entity with respect to the transformation described in subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8bb2f6ffdd4a4ff7a36f5e46570ddf82"><enum>(D)</enum><text>guide policy of the eligible entity (including a political subdivision of the eligible entity), including through public or private programs, and through funding priorities, to assist people in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity in aging with dignity and autonomy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id379afd5b7d964d17b21e87b7b2c79459"><enum>(E)</enum><text>include at least one goal for each of the key aging issues described in paragraph (4) and develop initiatives to carry out each such goal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id00f5c1581e0e4fc4b475e8ca6e22deb1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>be more comprehensive than the area plans approved under section 306 by the State agency prior to the date of the creation of the Plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida43f329950b04333af2c35a47ffdea83"><enum>(G)</enum><text>be more comprehensive than the State plans approved under section 307 by the Assistant Secretary prior to the date of the creation of the Plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fd9dc765fa647878a5e05810165ec62"><enum>(H)</enum><text>be created through a planning process that builds on the planning processes for the area plans described in subparagraph (F) and the State plans described in subparagraph (G).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9243b1b78eb40ed9164bd6e1a2b40b4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Key services, supports, and initiatives</header><text>The key services, supports, and initiatives described in this paragraph may include—</text><subparagraph id="id3bd6cafa1c954ee0b0c24481435d78ff"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disease prevention and health promotion services, long-term care services and supports, human services, and any other public health or health care, services, supports, or initiatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57da1ba5ccc54fbb80e507cc51a93691"><enum>(B)</enum><text>services, supports, and initiatives with respect to—</text><clause id="id2aee020be5c641a885ef96ca674ace95"><enum>(i)</enum><text>retirement security;</text></clause><clause id="idc41da3e990504e64ab946be2c4071007"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>nutrition and food security;</text></clause><clause id="iddf4651ffa0014afca2df1d8544ab24ea"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>economic security, including benefits access and job training and placement;</text></clause><clause id="id4ef97766de7e461fa588c5b855342435"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>elder rights protection and autonomy;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37abd2b31e31460a9b8622f8883bde55"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing, including home modifications, minor home repair, and home technology improvements;</text></clause><clause id="id825b5f415c7042829d27fd6f79007a17"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>education, including digital and financial literacy and education on retirement planning;</text></clause><clause id="idc60dc4c12c0e40e699c12839473f23d9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>accessible and reliable transportation;</text></clause><clause id="id0994d90e6ccc4322a168b0abc859df56"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>civic participation and social and community engagement; and</text></clause><clause id="id2dadee1bd8164e59a0e5b33f437465b1"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>broadband access;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide78e32f6d58c40f0a495977e0ba78cab"><enum>(C)</enum><text>services, supports, and initiatives for assisting covered individuals with disaster preparedness and during a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 401 or 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>, 5191) or any other natural disaster declared by the Governor of the applicable State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id997bb519ed26430f8d4a8f966ba4c909"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">affordable, accessible, and culturally and linguistically appropriate services, including translation, interpretation, and outreach for limited English proficiency communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef33a0a1200646d5bcea5b283cba8853"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other services, supports, or initiatives with respect to covered individuals, as determined appropriate by the eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95ed9bf4638f4caeae212abaf45488f9"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Key aging issues</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The key aging issues described in this paragraph are each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="id47585c6c4aad4e7c8a4582708683ed85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Supporting the ability of older individuals to be stably and safely housed, which may include supporting their ability to age well in the setting of their choice and to access homelessness prevention services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idecd40f3c316a4332ab8755c9cd6a73aa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Expanding access to affordable, age-friendly disease prevention and health promotion services and health care, including nutrition services, exercise programs, stress management services, fall prevention services, mental health services, behavioral health care, and substance use disorder services to promote longevity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id455158fdae7142e5837f00de0672adf0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Promoting disaster and pandemic preparedness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a8f88b109344e7cb661d5d0f6b08317"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Promoting age-friendly communities, as defined in section 203(c)(9).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0966c106c307449492af4f866143dcf3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Addressing the ability of older individuals to access affordable, high-quality long-term services and supports, including access to caregivers and home and community-based services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id094f26a4ca18486dad2a86f7fb2c9f30"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Expanding access to services that promote elder justice and reduce elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05a45cdcb5834d1dad9d7c06354a646c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Reducing disparities in outcomes for covered individuals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc725ec07babe4a8995a975b343709341"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Promoting economic security and retirement security and reducing poverty for covered individuals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85c8fa7ab1004d3594df897ddb152a2a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Promoting social connection and reducing isolation and loneliness for covered individuals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id041d68b1a9e347509134a2bd41d80105"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Ensuring public spaces are accessible to, including safe for, older individuals, including older individuals with disabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8963d78408924e8ea953eaae1276441b"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Ensuring access to healthy and affordable foods and reducing food insecurity, hunger, and malnutrition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id13954a7309064b8890a710486eb2e4cb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Assistant Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Assistant Secretary may require, including—</text><paragraph id="idd521ba0200f0443286daa8b7523eab6e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information demonstrating the commitment of the eligible entity to creating or implementing a Plan, as evidenced by—</text><subparagraph id="id833241cccfff4cf298c590a5dea79ddb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an Executive order issued by the head of the eligible entity, or legislation enacted in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, authorizing a Plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4345066ccecd4e2caed8424321ddbd84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a letter from a qualified leader of the eligible entity demonstrating the commitment of the eligible entity to working across government agencies or departments of the eligible entity, as well as with aging and disability stakeholders and other stakeholders in the public and private sectors, to create or implement a Plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcedbe9f846054ec6b5edc3b34beae297"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other declarations, activities, or actions as determined appropriate by the Assistant Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe63c5541fb24984b00c9dc603e341dd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd3cd7ea82cd4f02aa3742dacb8b743e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the working group described in subsection (c)(2)(A) that the eligible entity has convened or plans to convene; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id739ba1b5f6994e3986ac9890b2265379"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other anticipated activities and programs (such as public hearings, public comment periods, or listening sessions) to support creating or implementing a Plan that reflects demonstrated input from aging and disability stakeholders, including covered individuals, and other members of the public, including input from members of Indian tribes or tribal organizations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd1e68c8a8694496b4b0e67e168af388"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the needs of covered individuals, which may include targeted subgroups, served by the eligible entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide707940d1ea847b88c8cceeb5c3d9239"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a consideration of varying needs of populations across different types of geographies in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, including urban, rural, and frontier, as applicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24ebe01e58df4b2aa57a8a6860c6d70a"><enum>(5)</enum><text>details on how the Plan will comply with subparagraphs (F), (G), and (H) of subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8132ba28edf0472ab89721d8d54e7649"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Awards</header><paragraph id="idd0e24083e0c2412f9e556d52ca4d456a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall award not more than 65 grants under this section during the 5-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d3c85efe1b44ace9d5a175f32490818"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Set aside</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the grants awarded under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary shall award not less than 10 grants to eligible entities that are Indian tribes or tribal organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2744fa42dcd4d14b09f4b57f5867a59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall establish a process for—</text><subparagraph id="ida2b262a32a7b4f18bf2d295f3beec717"><enum>(A)</enum><text>selecting, including for prioritizing, eligible entities to receive a grant under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff7c4a11d83145969269a50148da25f6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (4), determining the amount of each such grant, which shall include a tiered system depending on the population in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddef3a232818e4c459c18b35ad5aa6787"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text>No grant awarded under this section to an eligible entity shall exceed $500,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d895d7bf34a41ae8887a6838ff251eb"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Terms</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a632c1eef3c42adaad895287964f1f2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc436d95a37d54cdb9fedf23da885fade"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive a total amount for the grant as a lump sum; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb9613acc8364eb7a147cd444336befb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (B), obligate and expend such total amount in accordance with this section not later than 3 years after receiving such lump sum.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83b01fb9d20347fb9734df287ff3fcb7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension of availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may, pursuant to an agreement with the Assistant Secretary, obligate and expend amounts from a grant under this section in accordance with the requirements of this section after the 3-year period described in subparagraph (A)(ii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id66d4b7ef18434b5fa7f936722bc6d918"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>In the case of a grant awarded under this section to create a Plan, the eligible entity receiving the grant shall create the Plan and begin implementing the Plan not later than 2 years after receiving the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3e030968f80847bcb7ae4684fb0fc1d9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Assessment and evaluation process</header><paragraph id="id7523204abc9446c5abb58c24e21f7537"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Developmental assessment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving a grant under this section, the eligible entity receiving the grant shall submit to the Assistant Secretary a developmental assessment. Such assessment may include—</text><subparagraph id="idda219f7a41a54d99a8330837c4c2e7ce"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 or more goals with respect to the Plan that the eligible entity commits to addressing in the final Plan described in paragraph (2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id485d8da857244893b34ae2a80f91a3d1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrated use of data metrics to inform the goals of the Plan, which data metrics are derived from—</text><clause id="id1f88479ef2f546cf9a11ca601aca2b74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>datasets or qualitative data with respect to the population in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity; and</text></clause><clause id="ide10a419e256e4cdf9102ab64152d9061"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>nationwide datasets or qualitative data, with an awareness that national datasets may not include data with respect to Indian tribes and tribal organizations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb22b12118c3d461bb38593a2907a4a5d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrated involvement with 3 or more governmental departments or agencies of the eligible entity on creation or implementation of the Plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd3af9f4b07c74083a6886b2c1bdad635"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrated input from—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f063f9a3eda4ad4aa847f7a47764a35"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the working group described in subsection (c)(2)(A) convened by the eligible entity; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80604a0b571d4b8ca78a35702deffc57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other aging and disability stakeholders;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7b8522824fc34ad89cb2c5e6e02bed12"><enum>(E)</enum><text>demonstrated input from other individuals who will be impacted by the Plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc77137a43c3545efb2199a3cf89a8dfa"><enum>(F)</enum><text>as applicable, demonstrated incorporation of aging, disability, and older relative caregiver plans and initiatives existing on the day before the receipt of the grant in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity, which may include such existing age-friendly plans, Tribal plans and resolutions, initiatives in area plans submitted under section 306 and State plans submitted under section 307, and working groups or task forces related to aging, disability, or older relative caregiver initiatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1939dd483b47438e91f4551e9ab4b434"><enum>(G)</enum><text>demonstrated assurances that the eligible entity agrees to make available (directly or through public or private entities) non-Federal contributions towards the costs of the Plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id229a50d2d5a04be9b1780cb272443313"><enum>(H)</enum><text>as applicable, a timeline and working plan for finalizing the Plan and beginning implementation of the Plan not later than 2 years after the grant is awarded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb908c235e2c14d978c469f65085a66eb"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation assessment</header><text>Not later than 2 years after receiving a grant under this section, the eligible entity receiving the grant shall submit to the Assistant Secretary an implementation assessment. Such assessment shall include—</text><subparagraph id="idaf362126d3a44490945156e18590b3ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a final Plan, including 3 or more goals for the Plan and short- and long-term priorities or initiatives to meet each of those goals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2bfdf77d6b014c40aa5ded708c029777"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an update regarding all matters included in the developmental assessment submitted under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9e9e4b34dbcb4143822234fc96db7a97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for each priority or initiative described in subparagraph (A), identified benchmarks or data metrics that are identified in a publicly accessible way such as through a data dashboard or in a report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id478a48c335084bc9a0600c3d5014ef94"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan for accountability that includes—</text><clause id="id2f9ad1f153cc407abb4a1503a10aab62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrated commitment of a qualified leader of the eligible entity to execute and oversee such plan for accountability, as evidenced by information determined appropriate by the Assistant Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="id882a16549e144eb9996cec51f0946fd8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one or more departments or agencies of the eligible entity listed as accountable for each priority or initiative described in subparagraph (A);</text></clause><clause id="id2b929b5b0a284b26ae83453f91145530"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan to continue to engage aging and disability stakeholders, and other key players or partners as determined by the eligible entity, through advisory groups, public hearings held by the implementation committee as described in clause (iv)(II)(cc), or other means;</text></clause><clause id="id183582e0966b406eb4f6980c6c2b803e"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the establishment of an implementation committee, which shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9752e271f10a4ce8994e4c220092af72"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consist of the working group described in subsection (c)(2)(A) convened by the eligible entity and as applicable other regional, State, local, or Tribal participants as determined appropriate by the eligible entity; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf846105bc7e84af8b70742ffec9995e3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be responsible for—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcad624bbf68949a686265c1c7a1f336f"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assisting in ensuring that the goals of the Plan described in subparagraph (A) are implemented;</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2735163852004517b7b954aab35be199"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participating in the development of the progress report described in subparagraph (E); and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34803d3a563d4748a23d44fc823b3ca8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>holding public hearings, with an opportunity for public comment, for the purposes described in clause (iii); and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idf868f48f39044065bb573e2904ac5aec"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a plan for identifying and responding to any disparities in access to key services, supports, and initiatives in the jurisdiction of the eligible entity as described in subsection (c)(3); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb1742376c9f41ffb91fe1daba3dcf51"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a progress report schedule that includes—</text><clause id="id5060325891f244cb95abd15fb9324ae5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an established process for bi-yearly updates to the Plan throughout a 10-year period; and</text></clause><clause id="id8396ff89451b4a3390b30290c38762fe"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>opportunities for input from aging and disability stakeholders and any other individuals impacted by the Plan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id63e847407255454bb914ad596de21960"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Assistant Secretary shall consult the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Healthy Aging and Age-Friendly Communities established under section 203(c).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1fa01783aa73489ca490a0e0e0364b2b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall provide technical assistance to eligible entities who are seeking or have received a grant under this section in complying with the requirements of this section or otherwise creating or implementing a Plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb3d8c7aeef894052842fe358bceb50c8"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id78eedc6b66c742c382d6c6d94c87b915"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to the Assistant Secretary to remain available until expended $6,500,000 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb865269903864619bf80080dcd006ff6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts appropriated under this section for a year, the Assistant Secretary shall use not more than 3 percent to carry out subsection (i) and for any other administrative costs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id9965822d0b2d47fc8792eb9b4a70a800"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency Coordinating Committee on Healthy Aging and Age-Friendly Communities</header><text>Section 203(c)(1) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3013">42 U.S.C. 3013(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>with respect to aging issues and</quote> and inserting <quote>with respect to aging issues, advising the Assistant Secretary on carrying out the grant program under section 423, and</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

