<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F6EBF041EA84167A083187D24E64720" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9018 IH: Fostering Transparency, Understanding, and Support for Veterans Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9018</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260522">May 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide to Congress notice of any suicide or attempted suicide of a veteran in a facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs or of a Community Care provider, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCDFC382C868D425186D5A2639BDB3456" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H40D2A76A5132454B99A86B53D47CEFFC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fostering Transparency, Understanding, and Support for Veterans Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Fostering TRUST Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6349DF26CF5643F4863A7F786A250386"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional notice of suicides and attempted suicides of veterans in Department of Veterans Affairs facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1720F of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF94CB20E49544D409E08542FC0B49991" style="USC"> <subsection id="HD1555CFFA77F4CDC9320F8326F1179AE"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Congressional notice requirements</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7F328EEF60334751B8785F83EDF7887F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of the suicide or attempted suicide of any veteran that occurs in, or on the grounds of, a Department facility or the facility of a non-Department provider through which the Secretary furnishes care under section 1703 of this title, to the extent that the Secretary or any employee or senior leader of the Department is aware of the suicide or attempted suicide, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives and the Senators and member of Congress representing the district in which the facility is located and the Senators and member of Congress representing the district in which the veteran resides the following notices:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39515F99224F4888ABC481FDD8BA7385" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Not later than seven days after the date on which the suicide or attempted suicide occurs, notice of—</text> <clause id="H619ADAB1607A44038DB27729A828A82D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the suicide or attempted suicide; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9E56D618B18040EC8CE100584C23BBA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name of the facility and location where the suicide or attempted suicide occurred.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H52CA3B95FE434A0A8B5AFB35E1489E71" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), not later than 60 days after such date, notice of the following information (if available) regarding the veteran who committed or attempted to commit suicide:</text> 
<clause id="H511DCD4532804C55965AA4C2540EA5B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The enrollment status of the veteran with respect to the patient enrollment system of the Department under section 1705 of this title.</text></clause> <clause id="H12264ADED09745B49F6E66F6EE5414B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The date and circumstances of the most recent encounter before the suicide or attempted suicide occurred between the veteran and any employee or facility of the Veterans Health Administration or any non-Department provider.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC667288BDEE4433C93268030F8E9F7E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the veteran had other medical insurance or coverage (including under the TRICARE program (as defined in section 1072 of title 10), the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>), or the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>)).</text></clause> <clause id="H3C432B5BF17943658819F9E735BB9253"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Armed Force in which the veteran served.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF27BC2D665E24A2A875E7C61AB55ED1C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The time period during which the veteran served in the Armed Forces.</text></clause> <clause id="HBA65B7726715475B9CF6902A2F4E0FEE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The age of the veteran.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2EFB37E389E942C4A0DFCB615C541118"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The marital status of the veteran.</text></clause> <clause id="H4C142BDF0FEE46EBB0E38A35E3397B4D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The employment status of the veteran.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51BBE5419F26495A992989A6AB911404"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The housing status of the veteran.</text></clause> <clause id="H160F8725C97A48798E1FB59B2674691C"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The gender identity of the veteran.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H91463421A3AD495D8F69D13E6AB6F97B"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>The sexual orientation of the veteran.</text></clause> <clause id="HB66BDE7337E8417488B0767C951BF963"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The race and ethnicity of the veteran.</text></clause>
<clause id="H78E82850B83B400A97F518FF866B511C"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>The disability rating of the veteran.</text></clause> <clause id="H6D992322FA9C45CEB738D0C7554FF309"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Confirmation that the Secretary has provided to the immediate family members of the veteran notice of any Department support or assistance for which such family members may be eligible.</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB660B0C8E4734A76BF95790EA5591459" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In collecting and reporting information under paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary shall take all steps the Secretary determines necessary to respect the privacy and dignity of the veteran and the family of the veteran.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H323D01F664334495A5AA52B5FEDBF37D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Each notice submitted under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) shall include a copy of guidance developed by the Secretary for purposes of dissemination that is designed to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1D6BDE0AA4534011B572C2E969F5F815"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deter the sensationalism of suicide;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19E9258331194A27BFE31148850FE172"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide information regarding warning signs that are often exhibited by veterans at risk of suicide;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B809A2F3A4241AC98758CE23AE34E94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide notice of the resources the Department offers to veterans who may be at risk of suicide, including the Veterans Crisis Line and readjustment counseling provided through Vet Centers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H378D062ECB5C45E8A38D9150593C0CBC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide information about best practices for lethal means safety and resources to secure lethal means available through the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

