<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN26021-CF7-PN-GN7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3624 IS: NATO Unity Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3624</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260113">January 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To limit the use of funds to assert control over the sovereign territory of a NATO member state, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NATO Unity Protection Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NATO UP Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idccf098ef58024c53ba203330d8abc800"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id82a032d5e4bf450ab7bcf1a366d40904"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The unified strength of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) is critical to the national security and foreign policy of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60580f13447149dcaeaab353461b59fc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any occupation or takeover of the sovereign territory of a NATO ally would violate the Charter of the United Nations and numerous articles of the North Atlantic Treaty, done at Washington April 4, 1949, and approved for ratification by the United States Senate on July 21, 1949 (also known as the <quote>Washington Treaty</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id589917d695734892aeebface9f24e9e8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Occupation or similar actions against the sovereign territory of a NATO ally by the United States in circumstances other than to repel a foreign invasion by a non-NATO-member state would put the United States in a conflict with NATO and NATO member states, possibly weakening NATO to the point of it ceasing to be an effective collective security alliance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82675c05fb8d45519e65c5546ffbdfe6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Such an outcome would serve the strategic interests of the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China while significantly undermining the national security and foreign policy objectives of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id0599e9ffb032418b93d2694f15f70374"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on use of Department of Defense funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be used to blockade, occupy, annex, conduct military operations against, or otherwise assert control over the sovereign territory of a NATO member state, other than as authorized by that NATO member state or the North Atlantic Council.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idc631fbcde34243b9bbe5f5b2da8d29f8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on use of Department of State funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of State may be used to develop, support, or implement any plan for the United States to blockade, occupy, annex, conduct military operations against, or otherwise assert control over the sovereign territory of a NATO member state, other than as authorized by that NATO member state or the North Atlantic Council.</text></section><section id="id0fc24893ac49408481f8ddccd494fa1b"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent the United States from defending itself or an ally from an armed attack or from a credible threat of an imminent armed attack.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

