<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE518699E39A24A7C9D21B0F1994C3380" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7993 IH: Somaliland Economic Access and Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7993</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000175">Mr. Ogles</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to submit to Congress a comprehensive report on barriers to Somaliland’s access to the United States financial system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD18342FD11B44D2FABDB555058E67BEA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB6B8C20D77F943529C0CE4EB9C0B499F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Somaliland Economic Access and Opportunity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H03AE132987504A16961F5393288D0D28"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="HE1359173B38A42CAB237CB09599D74DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HFBF6A003463F4FC19374BDF1A697FBF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Somaliland occupies a strategically significant position in the Horn of Africa, adjacent to critical maritime routes in the Gulf of Aden.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3461B0828C53433898D5E2C9DB5F297F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Financial engagement with Somaliland has the potential to advance U.S. interests in regional security, and economic stability.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0916FC2B4E6F4A5C8D3B38BF97C6D2BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Somaliland faces legal, regulatory, and institutional barriers in accessing the United States and international financial systems, which may adversely impact remittances, trade, anti-money laundering efforts, and counter-terrorism financing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4B3E3F075FD44899FC49E04B6E28A4E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States has a national security and humanitarian interest in ensuring that Somaliland’s financial sector operates with transparency, integrity, and compliance with international standards.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDA94378A352540759F34FBA4A64D780A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H8FCBFA443E8742338AE366B851736147"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should explore opportunities to promote stronger financial cooperation and transparency with Somaliland to encourage stability and expand economic engagement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB7E20C534304B249BA9D228DCA51D80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhanced financial access, conducted under appropriate compliance safeguards, would serve to strengthen U.S. policy objectives in the region.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HAC235440A5F24E71A804D843E2419922"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on barriers to Somaliland’s access to the United States financial system</header> <subsection id="H67EA633922A74C30824CD9D04909A738"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the Committees on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a comprehensive report analyzing barriers to Somaliland’s access to the United States financial system.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAD1974827F44D4CB321B384D65A7D13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HAE2B56A2E8B745769CDBB31003D56EC9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification and analysis of barriers</header><text>An examination of legal, regulatory, and policy barriers that limit Somaliland’s access to the United States financial system, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB5C5F9DE07274736B450484ABC18B68C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issues relating to Somaliland’s international recognition status;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8503DC2C77A40258C53C8F288E91676"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compliance with <quote>Know Your Customer</quote> (<quote>KYC</quote>), anti-money laundering (<quote>AML</quote>), and counter-terrorism financing (<quote>CTF</quote>) standards; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H616964B78D9D43C08370FB03EF02705B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>challenges related to remittance flows.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H338AC4A75E894A40A00EB886F49A1C9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations for United States engagement</header> <subparagraph id="HBBA80E2A448B44E48A91FC2A73B2F5E9"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for steps the governing authorities of Somaliland can take to enhance compliance with international financial standards, including adherence to International Monetary Fund (<quote>IMF</quote>), World Bank, and Financial Action Task Force (<quote>FATF</quote>) norms.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDEABB28730A14BAA950B39BF7570A3CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for steps the Government of the United States may take to facilitate financial access for Somaliland, including—</text> <clause id="H1308BB2FF93045EF916B8E034A2AED28"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encouraging the Department of the Treasury to use the United States voice and vote at international financial institutions (including the IMF, World Bank, and FATF) to promote financial engagement with Somaliland;</text>
            </clause> 
<clause id="HDE19BDD960934FF9B107C0BD3E6C14EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluating whether World Bank and IMF resources are allocated to Somaliland in a manner consistent with its population and development needs; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE63B79B74CC64D2BA170555AEBEEA270"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessing the steps necessary to incorporate Somaliland into the SWIFT financial messaging and payment system.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAE9414E3DC44763BFB9F10A4129EF6D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mitigation of illicit finance risks</header><text>Recommendations on mechanisms and technologies to prevent money laundering, terrorism financing, and other illicit activities in connection with remittances and U.S. financial system access, including guidance on information sharing, due diligence, and monitoring tools.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H1A900E1C1624467B9E4BC1218C4B0C84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury may—</text> 
<paragraph id="HABEF3CEDA80C449ABB8861828E6BD957"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in preparing the report required under subsection (a), engage directly with—</text> <subparagraph id="H97A5DDEBCA9E43D4830F5E0956ADEBF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant officials of Somaliland, including officials from the—</text> 
<clause id="HED53878BA9C14768BC8E6CEA8D484636"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ministry of Finance and Economic Development;</text></clause> <clause id="H8F188240102E4900A4D5C6E6E4D52D7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Ministry of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6E484965280E4B5298569B7B34ACDCAE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Office of the Economic Advisor to the President; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3E0A09612FEE48E3BB536DE3C66353FC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Central Bank of Somaliland; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66E66C59F3AD43C882A9327A00F1414E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">private-sector financial institutions and other stakeholders; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD1E9BA9CF92450E867FF2616387FA92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines it appropriate, engage directly with such officials in future dialogues.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

