<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H67D3D4872A704576BE65D41EC301E464" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1113 IH: Censuring Representative Andrew Ogles and Removing Him from the House Committee on Homeland Security.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1113</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Censuring Representative Andrew Ogles and Removing Him from the House Committee on Homeland Security.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 9, 2026, Representative Andrew Ogles used his official accounts on the social media platforms X and Instagram to publicly state that <quote>Muslims don’t belong in American society</quote> and that <quote>pluralism is a lie</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative Andrew Ogles has made statements on the podcast, Restoring The Republic, suggesting that Muslims will <quote>breed their way through our society</quote>; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative Andrew Ogles has repeatedly made public statements regarding Muslim elected officials, suggesting that they are conspiring to institute an Islamic government; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative Andrew Ogles has a repeated history of using his official accounts on social media platforms to spread Islamophobic, racist, and anti-immigrant rhetoric; language and behavior unfit for a Member of Congress, going so far as to call for the denaturalization and deportation of elected officials for no reason other than their religion and background; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Representative Ogles’s behavior and predisposition to discriminate against immigrants and minorities are alarming and inappropriate given his role on the House Committee on Homeland Security, raising serious questions about his ability to serve; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States of America is built on the principle of <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote> and the welcoming of people across cultures and our strength through diversity; and </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Constitution of the United States guarantees freedom of religion as one of the five fundamental freedoms detailed in the First Amendment: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="id8C19BE93D624470EB6D6185BCDD5CDC7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><text>CENSURE OF REPRESENTATIVE ANDREW OGLES.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE257D6F862DD4736AC6C542E3158FFAD"> <text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
            <paragraph id="H0C505522F1934A54B93F13ABF86C5DB7">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Andrew Ogles be censured;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="H588C9DCC79BB415AAF6DA17E7C3EEEDC" commented="no"
                display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Andrew Ogles forthwith present himself in the well of the House of Representatives for the pronouncement of censure; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idD9B1AE018BD64EB79A5E8B5FD8124122" commented="no"
                display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Representative Andrew Ogles be censured with the public reading of this resolution by the Speaker.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section><section id="id4138FDA3827340A6AFD9DF1AD829D1A2" section-type="subsequent-section">
            <enum>2.</enum>
 <text>REMOVAL FROM HOUSE COMMITTEE ON HOMELAND SECURITY.</text> </section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="id3B0522DFEBD74710BBF6A47DF0EC9958"> <text>The following named Member be, and is hereby, removed from the following standing committee of the House of Representatives:</text>
            <committee-appointment-paragraph>
                <header>Committee on Homeland Security:</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mr. Ogles.</text> </committee-appointment-paragraph> </section></resolution-body></resolution> 

