<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-LAN26208-X16-M3-42S"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 692 ATS: Designating the week of April 20 through April 24, 2026, as “National Home Visiting Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 692</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week of April 20 through April 24, 2026, as <quote>National Home Visiting Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas every child deserves the opportunity to live up to his or her potential;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the early childhood years are the most active period for the developing brain, and a stable, secure relationship with a nurturing, caring adult is a key factor in the development of young children;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas home visiting programs help parents meet the unique needs of their children, promote healthy development, strengthen family relationships, and reduce the risk of abuse and neglect;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in 2024, evidence-based home visiting was implemented in all 50 States, the District of Columbia, 5 territories, 32 Indigenous communities, and 65 percent of United States counties;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, in fiscal year 2024, the Federal Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program served over 150,000 parents and children and provided over 990,000 home visits;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas more than 280,000 families received evidence-based home visiting services in 2024, over the course of more than 3,000,000 home visits;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas more than 20,000 home visitors and supervisors delivered evidence-based services nationwide in 2024; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas home visitors provide practical, emotional, and educational support that helps families thrive, promotes positive parenting practices, and ensures children have a strong foundation for a healthy, successful life: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate supports—</text><paragraph id="idc8adecf162854ea8b7c70358bb50ce22"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the designation of the week of April 20 through April 24, 2026, as <quote>National Home Visiting Week</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39dbcba727544d42866900ba3aadcf16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the goals and ideals of National Home Visiting Week.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

