<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H207F1CA49EC548BCB2157BDE93E62DD4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5874 IH: Firearm Access During Shutdowns Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5874</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000634">Mr. Downing</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001235">Mr. Moore of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To ensure that certain operations, functions, and services of the Federal Government relating to enforcement of firearms laws and firearm export licensing continue during a lapse in appropriations.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HF03ECCB693534828A8DA03D3059626D0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC9AE12FBCF5C4EA7B0BACC7D1446CBD4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Firearm Access During Shutdowns Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H8A8E23F4A44E49E39413C88196C2D4CA" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continuation of certain firearm-related operations during Government shutdowns</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H222C28AE88BC44C689CC31740EE86137"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The operations, functions, and services described in subsection (b) shall be deemed to relate to an emergency involving the safety of human life or the protection of property for purposes of section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, and the employees carrying out those operations, functions, and services shall be deemed to be excepted employees, as defined in section 1341(c) of that title.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8648A195B2DE4F98A5A9C11945B4A67E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operations, functions, and services</header><text>The operations, functions, and services described in this subsection are the operations, functions, and services of—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EF97CACD90F426B98322561908EC8A1"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the National Instant Criminal Background Check System of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, including the processing of background checks in support of the operations of the Directorate of Enforcement Programs and Services of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H377025AB495B4E38B53AA9C68DE050C7"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the Directorate of Enforcement Programs and Services of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAC1B46A76E04EB78F34E4664981F71D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce relating to firearms and firearm-related products, including activities related to processing of applications for export licenses; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H149AAA54B6C24D499D4A1F012F43FE21" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls of the Department of State relating to firearms and firearm-related products, including activities related to processing of applications for export licenses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

