<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E8FE8DB19B34DB98FA3B47EDDAD24DB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7246 IH: Addressing Climate Financial Risk Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Climate Financial Risk Committee and Climate Financial Risk Advisory Committee on the Financial Stability Oversight Council.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4662075217E64145A6D1D0148D0C52FD" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H404FF409607841D9917554E56EC29B56"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Addressing Climate Financial Risk Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3857554967BB415B82316E56C362E577"><enum>2.</enum><header>Financial Stability Oversight Council committees on climate financial risk</header><subsection id="H57C26EAAB92F4C9699BF1959B01C7808"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of the Financial Stability Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5321">12 U.S.C. 5321 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 121 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5331">12 U.S.C. 5331</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F528CDDC0FA4451A3176A9D138D2263"><section id="H21AB8F57F3B44D6FA03A9CB48F1E6D98"><enum>121A.</enum><header>Climate Financial Risk Committee</header><subsection id="H60D7E54C00304557858D3372021AE8C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Council the Climate Financial Risk Committee, which shall—</text><paragraph id="HED650625CB41437D978038E5CED07797"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the Council in identifying priority areas for assessing and mitigating climate-related risks to the financial system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H270F30DE0FEC4923B5BAD3536805F8DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve as a coordinating body to share information, facilitate the development of common approaches and standards, and facilitate communication across Council member agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECEB0A7B5876400F8B2E8FA4648642D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collaborate with the Office of Financial Research to compile climate and financial data from public sources and from member agencies of the Council, provide analytical tools and software, and otherwise assist member agencies of the Council in jointly analyzing potential financial stability risks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31EF4D6696EB41F7A878AD3DD88D837C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide updates to the Council on the status of the efforts of the Council and its member agencies to identify and address climate financial risk, including related to—</text><subparagraph id="HAB99FB1838B648888960F65EE7445BC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporating climate financial risk into regulatory and supervisory programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ED53B73E1BF48C481B0DE5DFEE4B027"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving data and methodologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE496A7225B34883AF10335391CDA027"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhancing climate-related disclosures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE09AF408C5B440A5882BB457877466E7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assessing climate-related risks to the financial stability of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5FEEC8A80EE44508897E0464ADFD0BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Climate Financial Risk Committee shall consist of staff representatives from each of the member agencies of the Council and shall be led by the Deputy Assistant Secretary of the Council.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E7E4700046A44ED833F766EFFEDBCEB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restriction on termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Climate Financial Risk Committee may not be terminated or modified except pursuant to an Act of Congress.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF4CE9D11B43D4187B7242B0A9383791F"><enum>121B.</enum><header>Advisory Committee on Climate Risk</header><subsection id="H5C911B7262F4402E982D1A994D426228"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Council the Advisory Committee on Climate Risk, which shall—</text><paragraph id="H6EA99B34F79A4034ACED415B07AB2D91"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult and assist the Council with gathering information on, conducting analysis of, and making recommendations to identify, assess, and mitigate climate-related risks to the financial system, and other duties that the Climate Financial Risk Committee or the Council may assign; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACEAD667588A4577831C5F63FCC009E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meet with the Council on a bimonthly basis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6DE4B608E1344939014841FFDAFB049"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Committee shall consist of not more than 30 members as follows:</text><paragraph id="H6780D10F480B4FF9984B0DEE67BF95AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">8 members who are climate science experts with a demonstrated record of peer-reviewed publications and professional contributions to climate modeling, climate financial risk assessment, or related areas, of whom—</text><subparagraph id="HA175778E92EC41838814FA84EA09A118"><enum>(A)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Secretary of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H821FF9D0B50B4AB28687A696496100F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H057213FE98484CC68C93ACFA2232F8B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>4 shall be appointed by the Director of the National Science Foundation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC44FCD37868E4B80933FC205A2AFE254"><enum>(2)</enum><text>8 members appointed by the Council who are experts in climate economics or climate financial risk, of whom not fewer than one member is an expert in one of the following areas:</text><subparagraph id="H2BB64C6524B84761A2D812C8577ED293"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Insurance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H880E9F98386042F7A89FA5BBD83DA59A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Capital markets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H227C9FC4C64E4DEA8353C96234550517"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Banking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C04A297C30F40E093B3D814CCDF8875"><enum>(D)</enum><text>International financial markets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B041AFF0CBC4AA1BB6FE2AB47D492E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Housing finance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFF2A8704EBF48B8BC35C14E8A533012"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The perspective of asset owners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF22AED1A6A04499FA64143E20DEC89D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>2 members from non-governmental research institutions that offer expertise in environmental or clean energy policy, appointed by the Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3985E0CBDB7E47F9B5FF4F05D49693DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 members from consumer advocacy or labor union groups, appointed by the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49D3E9AD6B914491A595BB97D5861DE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>4 members from investor networks or shareholder advocacy groups, appointed by the Chairman of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EFCA943D3B24940B5D0CE4FEEC10F77"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relevant stakeholders from the financial services industry, commercial businesses, or other organizations, which shall not include any stakeholders from the oil or gas industry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H102641D52DED43AC820E6A9AFB5D796C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The members of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for 3-year terms, except that the initial terms of the first members of the Advisory Committee shall be staggered so that—</text><paragraph id="H1FBE4D3A17D24143B28FF33AB0DD089C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>8 members serve terms of 3 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90F038C3C1DB447CAC21B6A80FAB9F85" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>8 members serve terms of 2 years; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD850739E39C44CC8BA3C3C7B2729508D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>8 members serve terms of 1 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94F55B03EB35473485E4BB5AC8DC4A0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restrictions on Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Advisory Committee may not be removed prior to the expiration of the term of such member unless <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the heads of the member agencies of the Council vote in favor of such removal.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9C06A3C0BA204BD9AD1F74DDB4CDD09A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Council shall consult with the Advisory Committee in carrying out the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H602C6E7BCA194E6FB7131411DBC0ABC5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Member agencies</header><text>Each member agency should develop and make publicly available a strategy to identify and mitigate climate financial risk within the jurisdiction of the member agency.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0C3B7B689D464FE99DE76BDF79D2B8F8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Council shall—</text><paragraph id="HB51F0F24D1814247ADAB5EC9B61B075D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the sharing of best practices on addressing climate financial risk across agencies with members serving on the Advisory Committee; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86C8B31F44C3441DAFF6BA53EF410507"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assign the Office of Financial Research to conduct ongoing research into climate financial risk.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA42DA4CA48B6424C89448CFAC84A4B1B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Inclusion in annual report</header><text>The Council shall include a section on climate financial risk in—</text><paragraph id="HB139E5601F4F4342AECE75390C2AD4DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the annual report of the Council to Congress; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF935865F93A94A3D833FB3FDD9462B93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if relevant, in any other report to Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H66BFDF82A74E4A34ADD154466CA4C882"><enum>121C.</enum><header>Report on climate financial risk</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Council shall, in coordination with the Advisory Committee on Climate Risk established under section 121B and the Climate Financial Risk Committee established under section 121A, publish a report that—</text><paragraph id="H11050943A1724E19BE26F025B349A6AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses—</text><subparagraph id="H8F9F980DCD7140478A1937EEB0E7863C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential impact of climate-related risks on the financial stability of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE78566335AD4758A1D146EA4B1D696F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which Federal and State financial regulatory agencies have sufficient expertise on climate financial risk;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5011EE74FDB04B13BFBAF2A291F05D55"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the quality of data available to Council members to properly assess climate financial risk and any gaps in data that exist;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC82D4965553D4CAF99631897B02D215C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which property and casualty insurance availability and affordability trends are affecting credit markets, housing finance, and financial stability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69CC372C39E64211A7330203E59A0DBE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which nonbank financial companies and large, interconnected bank holding companies supervised by the Board of Governors are engaging in safe and sound management of climate financial risks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF40FB4420C2F44A895A1C5820BA50905"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the degree of coordination among Federal and State financial regulatory agencies on climate financial risk;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC4DFA9455CC4BE49AA7AAF920DD3B3B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the degree of coordination by Federal and State financial regulatory agencies with international financial regulatory authorities on climate financial risk;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41C855C8662843E48C5515E0759DBF04"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how climate-related disclosure requirements in the United States compare to similar disclosure regimes in other countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7BE2063C8014B6C8626677CE78BF500"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any other areas the Council determines important; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BB92DFE77904D27B95BD4E63C52714D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides recommendations based on the assessments conducted under paragraph (1) to Federal and State financial regulatory agencies and to Congress on how to improve the ability of the financial regulatory system in the United States to identify and mitigate both the short- and long-term financial risks associated with climate change.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H737DE2B947764CBBA72A73D5E62C6DDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Technical and conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act in section 1(b) of that Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 121 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD93D9DA445794F7DB19054D7B5F79F8C"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HF4CE9D11B43D4187B7242B0A9383791F">Sec. 121A. Climate Financial Risk Committee.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HF4CE9D11B43D4187B7242B0A9383791F">Sec. 121B. Advisory Committee on Climate Risk.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HF4CE9D11B43D4187B7242B0A9383791F">Sec. 121C. Report on climate financial risk.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HE3FF4DCC3B284CC09E09C1F03A7E7257"><enum>3.</enum><header>Update on supervisory guidance on climate financial risk</header><subsection id="H4E42A9472F7548DBBA5F0B5FC0DBF65E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Federal banking agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5301">12 U.S.C. 5301</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H38304AF02094480AA05AD1686632D1E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal banking agency and the National Credit Union Administration shall update applicable supervisory guidance to include climate financial risk, including credit, liquidity, market, operational, and reputational risk to ensure that each institution supervised by the Federal banking agency or the National Credit Union Administration, as appropriate, with greater than $50,000,000,000 in assets appropriately identify and mitigate climate financial risk.</text></subsection><subsection id="H30706031CC1048F0A2DD164A0DE404B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Financial Institutions Examination Council shall ensure that the guidance updated under subsection (b) is—</text><paragraph id="H47A9C3361C874E1CA2D41F7469293670"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriately coordinated among the Federal banking agencies and the National Credit Union Administration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3D448AB0BC14D5A8BDF44C0D8C3D1E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shared with State regulators.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0FF4673D51D64B7A8E491C90AB3E8108"><enum>4.</enum><header>Update nonbank SIFI designation guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Financial Stability Oversight Council shall update subpart B of part 1310 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, to specify how the Council will incorporate climate financial risk into determinations described in that subpart.</text></section><section id="H4FE93E1538974ACCA688F22D5DB4FC4C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal Insurance Office report on insurance regulation and climate financial risk</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Insurance Office shall publish a report, which may be submitted along with the report described in section 6, that—</text><paragraph id="H6AF4CE0E6DBD47DC815BCAD603E063C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assesses the potential impact of climate financial risk on the insurance sector in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15844BDD544B49388B45F751D496E6AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides an update on the implementation of recommendations made by the 2023 report of the Federal Insurance Office titled <quote>Insurance Supervision and Regulation of Climate-Related Risks</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H670A8AAD23DB4F0BAAB616D7108602AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommends ways to modernize and improve regulation and supervision of climate financial risk by the insurance sector in the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA4FCEDCE30DC4DF49AB5317BB3498C2F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Federal Insurance Office data collection on climate-related risks</header><subsection id="HE20BBC1B92C549C8B28714AA64475FB0" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Insurance Office, in consultation with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and State insurance commissioners, shall publish a report on the homeowners insurance underwriting data described in subsection (b) for calendar years 2023 and 2024 to assess climate-related risks across State insurance markets and how such risks could impact the financial stability of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE663AADBF0B545F3B9763388247C1825" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Data described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data described in this subsection—</text><paragraph id="H4D2904F6B1F242A98B25ADD54619AE79" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be disaggregated by zip code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DF341E982DD4135B673687A79537019" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include granular data on premiums, policies, claims, losses, limits, deductibles, non-renewals, and cancellations, consistent with the information requested under the <quote>Federal Insurance Office Climate-Related Financial Risk Data Collection for U.S. Homeowners Multi-Peril Underwriting Data</quote> (88 Fed. Reg. 75380) as modified by the most recent National Association of Insurance Commissioners Property &amp; Casualty Insurance Market Intelligence Data Call; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6929011944044548B7768CFA18F40F88" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be collected directly by the Federal Insurance Office from insurance companies, across all lines of business of such insurance company, pursuant to section 313 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE127CD8B76C84A6A8709EE0C59528FB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request, the Federal Insurance Office shall provide to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, or the State insurance commissioner with regulatory authority over an insurance company the report required under subsection (a), including the data described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H662842AF0EFA4F80ADDF493F4358A994"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Insurance Office shall ensure that the report required under subsection (a) does not include any personally identifiable information.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3223760966CC45798AD518526FADE8D4" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after December 31, 2025, and annually thereafter, in accordance with the requirements of this section, the Federal Insurance Office shall make publicly available a report on the homeowners insurance underwriting data described in subsection (b) for the calendar year preceding the date of the report.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6B308038B8574A56B6176EA8ED889E90"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sense of Congress relating to improving global coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that relevant Federal financial regulatory agencies and the Department of the Treasury, including the Federal Insurance Office, as applicable, should—</text><paragraph id="H368EDA28FA644525BB006EA566F0DC47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>join the Network for Greening the Financial System and other international organizations focused on climate financial risk;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15197079562141F0941C424FD35EE3F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>formally join the Task Force on Climate-Related Financial Risks of the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B31C0CDD4B74A479862C1375BAA1F8E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>work with international regulators on climate financial risk whenever possible, consistent with United States law.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

