<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25H03-39F-7G-9V1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3381 IS: To require coordination of depot-level maintenance in multinational exercises conducted by the Air Force.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3381</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251208" legis-day="20251204">December 8 (legislative day, December 4), 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require coordination of depot-level maintenance in multinational exercises conducted by the Air Force.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="H691EA775BB4A4E06BD5B1898A12B7755" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Depot-level maintenance coordination in multinational exercises</header><subsection id="H93543A1E6D9A4DF1BC24449C2DE7D7FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year, the Secretary of the Air Force shall incorporate in at least one multinational exercise conducted in the area of operations of the United States Indo-Pacific Command—</text><paragraph id="H9FE5A2E1D4BC47B38C59ED1324DECE20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>depot-level maintenance, repair, and sustainment considerations, including binational or multinational planning sessions with covered nations on—</text><subparagraph id="HD417A3C1E5534414816E10728B02CE4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying opportunities to cooperate on depot-level maintenance and repair in ways that minimize transportation requirements in such area of operations and determining the authorities necessary to deliver necessary joint capabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA799A43069A4F208893A5EC38138564"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating real-time coordination between the United States and covered nations to maintain munitions stock levels and resupply routes in such area of operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H603C68A9EA9C4AF8A547B1D3AFF5D771"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mutual recognition of airworthiness and maintenance certification between the United States and covered nations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75CD481EBF0E457F83599D8AC1E44117"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>emergency tabletop exercises, such as when an aircraft of a covered nation breaks down in United States territory, and vice versa, in a contested logistics environment.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19591CA9E71641AF8DC785CD2C1DC3D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordination with the Air Force Sustainment Center, including the participation of representatives of—</text><subparagraph id="H5B5CA9E9B53949EDB3B0EDDAB95065DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Indo-Pacific Command;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D46F3060441462682421E777E799365"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the United States Pacific Air Forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04984D40BCC9439681266BDD1E0DB4D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Air Mobility Command; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A9319F820F847AEB16442D8D7429883"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Air Force Sustainment Center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EEED1B4733E4D56973051EF45255836"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde6aab9d4fb84130b2c55b560b59aa29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Air Force shall submit to Congress a report summarizing the lessons learned from carrying out an exercise in accordance with subsection (a) with respect to the Republic of Korea and the Commonwealth of Australia.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a9346f97d9441beac2c6942ebb5ba34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H94F96505026C4262BC275F5D639096BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of candidate systems for co-sustainment with the Republic of Korea and the Commonwealth of Australia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H388F179BC63A423FA11C1DCC72580D79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A list of depot-level repair workload opportunities to undertake with the Republic of Korea and the Commonwealth of Australia, including testing equipment or line replaceable units.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F36649F257D486FA69E39B1E98B90DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Opportunities to incorporate Korean and Australian industry partners in depot-level maintenance repair activities, including through public-private partnerships.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H551ADA8F17B142A1B30EA30EC6F14989"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An identification of any potential logistical challenges that could arise with the host country, including with respect to workforce, housing, and location of workload.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EF61F2AD0FA4DF1B32F91511F145166"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An identification of any potential impediments involving intellectual property or data rights between original equipment manufacturers and the Department of the Air Force or between the Department of the Air Force and the Republic of Korea or the Commonwealth of Australia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FF7CBE6D5A048B4A8D813BDEA667794"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An identification of any potential impediments related to International Traffic in Arms Regulations and related statutes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72BD411B2094450BA0104689E897C99A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any additional recommendations to Congress that would ease the facilitation of depot-level maintenance repair partnerships with the Republic of Korea and the Commonwealth of Australia, including changes to existing status of forces agreements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C8F26EAA7A548A5841D169277157EDE"><enum>(H)</enum><text>An analysis of current maintenance and repair capabilities and gaps in the organic industrial base of the Republic of Korea and the Commonwealth of Australia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DDBA1E093EF4064AC826E5DFE910C71"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An assessment of the types of maintenance and repair activities (including depot-level, preventative, and corrective) that may be most appropriate for a partnership with the Republic of Korea or the Commonwealth of Australia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BAC54FA32094ABF9CEE4FD27C13EFAA"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An assessment of how any such partnership may contribute to allied contingency operations, interoperability, and regional posture resilience in the Indo-Pacific region.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB95A428002A74AFF870AD3BA9C65ECDA"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A consideration of planning factors related to the evolving force generation models of the Air Force, future-generation aircraft programs, deployment schedules, statutory maintenance thresholds, and other relevant operational requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD21117DEB0645C7841855777163861E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id282c08c4aa0943d6905b37fbe2c607e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered nation defined</header><text>The term <term>covered nation</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2CD69CA66CC548E697043E4629EC2222"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Commonwealth of Australia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCF353E1CB7B4EFC849E80D1BC212EB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Canada.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7C8E86BC8BA435B86E7B58D9A024B58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Japan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16DB95F01B7042E4B692A738CD40FB4D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>New Zealand.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H872C950F3DE146A68C3B83822A602B10"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Republic of Korea.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB10624B1A0F469CA6EB5E7B1C13678A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H863E5B43232D43578361A868DF2C5309"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other nation as designated as a covered nation for the purposes of this section by the Secretary of the Air Force.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7c98d126a2143718d9b68b63e47c379"><enum>(2)</enum><header>International Traffic in Arms Regulations</header><text>The term <term>International Traffic in Arms Regulations</term> means subchapter M of chapter I of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

