<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3C7F91127A8E49E6BC76F60D1843F029" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8211 IH: Army Security Agency Monument Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8211</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Army to place in Arlington National Cemetery a monument honoring Army Security Agency veterans of World War II, the Korean conflict, the Vietnam Era, and the Cold War era, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC1F5E68AEDB7486AA295DB1DD63FA38B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H346E4165F4A548DFAD63B181156E373A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Army Security Agency Monument Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4892C4DB77864993BC367FF6960CD07C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Placement of monument honoring veterans of the Army Security Agency who served in the Armed Forces between 1945 and 1976, during World War II, the Korean conflict, the Vietnam era, and the Cold War era</header> <subsection id="HBC54796D9974428F8BE88DC3A203DCC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Placement</header> <paragraph id="H685EBABCE012461CA77103469296C300"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the requirements of subsection (c), the Secretary of the Army shall place in Arlington National Cemetery a monument honoring Army Security Agency veterans who served in the Armed Forces between 1945 and 1976, during World War II, the Korean conflict, the Vietnam era, and the Cold War era.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEDD9BF0B5A254347925265CAC891CE3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative location</header><text>If the Secretary of the Army is unable to identify an appropriate place in Arlington National Cemetery for the monument described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall place the monument at a location outside the entrance to Arlington National Cemetery.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC08E9F7EBED54804972F12510451F7E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design</header><text>The monument placed under subsection (a) shall be—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF568F9A694B040A4B7D3909E16515302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>based on a design approved by the Secretary of the Army and the National Army Security Agency Association;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE48F1579D8E4D74BA7F15CB0DCCB414"><enum>(2)</enum><text>placed on a non-burial plot; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4686389B6D9A45F0A4C54669C2298440"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limited to 52 inches by 18 inches in base dimensions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFAE42C4C74564B2CB6F52269D463307A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Agreement for construction and maintenance</header><text>The Secretary of the Army may only place a monument under subsection (a) if the Secretary enters into an agreement with the National Army Security Agency Association under which the Association agrees to pay all costs necessary for preparation of the site for the monument and to construct, install, and maintain the monument, and to such other provisions as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H563131448A454DDC8619ED87CC8A1B40"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>World War II</term>, <term>Korean conflict</term>, and <term>Vietnam era</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

