<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4BF965427D144A3EA01B06BF8A8030E2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 151 IH: Providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to “Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 151</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000369">Mr. Amodei of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Providing for congressional disapproval under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to <quote>Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan</quote>.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HD088F996219240F799BB5B0A02414934"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H54BA2981BEE04908AE4C2F7D4B9AB575"><enum/><text>That Congress disapproves the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to <quote>Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan</quote> (issued January 13, 2025, as a record of decision and approved resource management plan, and a letter of opinion from the Government Accountability Office dated January 15, 2026, printed in the Congressional Record on February 25, 2026, on pages S675–S677, concluding that such record of decision and approved resource management plan is a rule under the Congressional Review Act), and such rule shall have no force or effect. </text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

