<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBFE97053CBE140738DE47E55DD2F7AC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8450 IH: Save Willy Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8450</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000607">Mr. Liccardo</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a pilot program to enhance existing efforts to mitigate vessel impacts on large cetaceans in the San Francisco Bay region, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF0DF59DEF61840D58E92F87C1446ACE7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3AFD2B34CA3042509AD2CCC6F5662210" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save Willy Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H7F21122923D84B2E8BF2A68F5B6B4B88"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to enhance efforts to mitigate vessel impacts on large cetaceans in San Francisco Bay region</header> 
<subsection id="HDDBE366A2CF043EEB010C7378904C9CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="HA06A510D29AC4EB7B811479A018A8099"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, with the concurrence of the Under Secretary, shall carry out a pilot program to establish a Cetacean Desk, which shall be—</text> <subparagraph id="H46BC82D091124BF6A3C6DF658B1578D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located and manned within the San Francisco Vessel Traffic Service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83BF0FA5F66C437AB007EFD7412B9CFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>designed—</text> <clause id="H89D2AD43A8E14E4FB7AA658F3BF9FF8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to improve coordination with the maritime industry to reduce the risk of vessel impacts on large cetaceans in the San Francisco Bay and the strait of Golden Gate, including impacts from vessel strikes, disturbances, and other sources; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8EC4AD13C5A64FBD894C0FA346E54C8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to monitor the presence and location of large cetaceans in the San Francisco Bay and the strait of Golden Gate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB903DF44507844BC959D79A56C028CF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration and staffing</header><text>The pilot program—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7A65530C0C90413C9C558C6BFC917617"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall—</text> <clause id="HF5FC2521FFAA4C308727312C68F44018"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be for a duration of four years; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H136783FA62784CDAA1A5A983C88FD0C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require not more than two full-time equivalent positions, whose responsibilities shall also include contributing to other necessary San Francisco Vessel Traffic Service duties and responsibilities as needed; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2F00CFD025C45E0A61DA40A96237A8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be supported by other existing Federal employees, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFFB4481AA1E444529BFAE3DBE46DB349"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Engagement with vessel operators</header> 
<paragraph id="H89FBC866C8F844E8A04082431176E844"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall require personnel of the Cetacean Desk to engage with vessel operators in areas where large cetaceans have been seen or could reasonably be present to ensure compliance with applicable laws, regulations, and voluntary guidance, to reduce the impact of vessel traffic on large cetaceans.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H449C2376F73042EE80CA52A773950D74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In engaging with vessel operators as required under paragraph (1), personnel of the Cetacean Desk shall communicate where and when sightings of large cetaceans have occurred.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H91E7C37CF69F421B9CF37B82E74847D1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Under Secretary may enter into a memorandum of understanding to facilitate real-time sharing of data relating to large cetaceans between the State of California, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the San Francisco Vessel Traffic Service, and other relevant entities, as appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8B80FD4F64034D29A27671860E7776F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary shall leverage existing data collection methods, the program required by section 11303 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1391">16 U.S.C. 1391</external-xref>), and public data to ensure accurate and timely information on the sighting of large cetaceans.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H512753FBB9BA412897F1AD8F26078178" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of technologies</header> 
<paragraph id="H19B54D13A55040919945AA95A42E4182"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emerging technologies</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Under Secretary and the Commandant, shall evaluate for potential use under the pilot program, and, as appropriate, adopt for such use, new and emerging technologies to enhance the effectiveness, efficiency, and responsiveness of the Cetacean Desk, including technologies capable of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA515CAAE174D4803B59413E93FAE3C79" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Improving the detection, identification, tracking, or forecasting of large cetacean presence, including through the use of automated, algorithmic, or artificial intelligence-enabled tools.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA17CA650F5424D39809C170E3056350D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Improving the integration, processing, or dissemination of data from Federal, State, academic, nongovernmental, and public sources in near real time.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE27F2A97A2946D58C5BB6D96B1C12D8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Enhancing communication with vessel operators to reduce the likelihood of vessel interactions with large cetaceans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF0CD1CC196A475BAADEE3D42AC67528"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing partnerships and programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, leverage existing research partnerships and other Federal programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1507F75200148B9A94F2E43FAE3F82F"> <enum>(f)</enum> <header>Consultations</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program, the Secretary shall consult with Tribal governments, the State of California, institutions of higher education, the maritime industry, ports in the San Francisco Bay region, and nongovernmental organizations.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H1330B764C8A742B781D0CA7CDEA1CDD0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>San Francisco Vessel Traffic Service local variance and policy</header><text>The Secretary, with the concurrence of the Under Secretary and in consultation with the Captain of the Port for the San Francisco Bay—</text> <paragraph id="HFD883289F7D047D1B0B993D30ADFC844"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall implement local variances, as authorized by section 70001(c) of title 46, United States Code, to facilitate communication, reporting, and voluntary coordination between vessel operators and the San Francisco Vessel Traffic Service regarding the presence of large cetaceans;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48C403C35E5B4B728E4A021AC282B67D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall ensure that any local variances implemented under this subsection maintain safe vessel navigation and are consistent with the communication and coordination functions of the San Francisco Vessel Traffic Service; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59AFB344347440C890DC5D88C64A9B90"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may enter into cooperative agreements, in accordance with section 70001(d) of title 46, United States Code, with Federal, State, Tribal, and local officials to reduce the likelihood of vessel interactions with protected large cetaceans, which may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8054E5A600BE423D9787A1D51D9D6743"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communicating marine mammal protection guidance to vessels;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9AA432E76F77421CA0B81CFBDED41872"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training on requirements imposed by local, State, Tribal, and Federal laws and regulations and guidelines concerning—</text> 
<clause id="HB7F09A70E3C84EEF9BD67A6DF439E594"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vessel buffer zones;</text></clause> <clause id="H0FA6A459CBE74095B6D109977E9689C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>vessel speed;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD7DCC5579F11441B8D666AE454135F5E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>seasonal no-go zones for vessels;</text></clause> <clause id="H6E78DFA0C507467C95CCEEB09762C88D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>protected areas, including areas designated as critical habitat, as applicable to marine operations; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2DBD8CF403374050962D89316B7A36B4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any other activities to reduce the direct and indirect impact of vessel traffic on large cetaceans;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0116DB9BE1B64673AAA1867055D4C085"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training to understand, utilize, and communicate large cetacean location data; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEDD63CDB567A42E88F7AEAA74F6B914A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>training to understand and communicate basic large cetacean detection, identification, and behavior, including—</text> <clause id="H74E320B4B60542CA966CE83940B29BD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cues of the presence of large cetaceans such as spouts, water disturbances, breaches, or presence of prey;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H019061502C1C4116B52B10EC87AE58BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>important feeding, breeding, calving, and rearing habitats that co-occur with areas of high risk of vessel strikes;</text></clause> <clause id="H8CBA4C0FA65C4871A2B74B96FFA4399F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>seasonal large cetacean migration routes that co-occur with areas of high risk of vessel strikes; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H511BB10C18A345B6AB02DC852512972F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>areas designated as critical habitat for large cetaceans.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6402774221154743B79A3998D3004C38"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter for the duration of the pilot program, the Commandant, in coordination with the Under Secretary and the Administrator of the Maritime Administration, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA26C9ED02B314BD98409E325C01A8D04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluates the functionality, utility, reliability, responsiveness, and operational status of the Cetacean Desk, including a quantification of reductions in vessel strikes to large cetaceans as a result of the pilot program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20FD7933E61845B886F03D57B922161A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses the efficacy of communication between the Cetacean Desk and the maritime industry and provides recommendations for improvements;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7022F508CAF740D58A9FEDB46EFF2E06"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluates the integration and interoperability of existing data collection methods, as well as public data, into the Cetacean Desk operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2067C41FEE134320BE9B8A66E465969A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assesses the efficacy of collaboration and stakeholder engagement with Tribal governments, the State of California, institutions of higher education, the maritime industry, ports in the San Francisco Bay region, and nongovernmental organizations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F75ACC3875E4472A78373F36D86AEA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>evaluates the progress, performance, and implementation of guidance and training procedures for San Francisco Vessel Traffic Service personnel, as required under subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA44E8C4109FB4628AC4D8BF07471121B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD2C2E2F4CB4D49C8972852B0149C09FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote>, <quote>institution of higher education</quote>, <quote>Tribal government</quote>, and <quote>Under Secretary</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 11301 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1390">16 U.S.C. 1390</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4211A065647247AFBC17087FA833EF4A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Cetacean Desk</term> means the Cetacean Desk established by the pilot program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A03D59A3AC14A679B8B6A716AADCD4F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Commandant</quote> means the Commandant of the Coast Guard.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71A5EF30304A4983919C2CDE3F453254"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>large cetacean</quote> means all species within—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9D81C2994E724D03AADA94B9C922608B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the suborder Mysticeti;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88BAFE56A20643AB8A9923DBE80C06DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the genera Physeter; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1FB89442294B46E898A12F7A37F78528"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the genera Orcinus.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E968D7400144366BAF39975FEA66EA9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>pilot program</term> means the pilot program required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5179EBD4DDC4DB59EB9287A398FEAE5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

