<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HB5A4E0C63C734E9C88FF83A15B14F9C4">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5956 IH: Defending Against Foreign Propaganda Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5956</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require certain disclosures on advertisements paid for by the governments of foreign countries or by foreign persons, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HFC6207EF7BF148C68E719620718B7880">
<section id="HC9F8FF2EC3BF4DB0A476E5C91E0875C5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending Against Foreign Propaganda Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5751FFD680654D10BDB179D9981BB968"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement for disclosure with respect to advertisements paid for by the governments of foreign countries and foreign persons</header> <subsection id="HF355B1CB18F84A62B4F851FFD06BA6B9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header> <paragraph id="H97CAC84F0969489E98028CB43025999F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person may not disseminate to a consumer an advertisement paid for by the government of a foreign country or by a foreign person without disclosing to the consumer, in the manner described in paragraph (2), that the advertisement was paid for by such government or by such person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6DD17D923A24E4899D08D6753BECD51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manner described</header><text>The manner described in this paragraph is the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H60060465C4574AC0AFCCD6573B950863"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to an advertisement that includes a sound component, a disclosure made pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be included in the advertisement as a sound component.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3FD2FC83824D481284B8B0EC8C806F5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>With respect to an advertisement that includes a printed language component, a disclosure made pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be included in the advertisement as a printed language component.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H178066EFA67544AD9BAF8EA8A8568C94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to an advertisement that includes a video component, a disclosure made pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be included in the advertisement as a sound component and a printed language component.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF0E284F2D00C43A3B5D26E5FA8C81073"><enum>(D)</enum><text>With respect to an advertisement paid for by a foreign person, a disclosure made pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include the following as applicable:</text> <clause id="H37399B4C5AC241BEBA976317ED86B67F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The name of the foreign country from which the foreign person is a citizen of.</text></clause>
<clause id="HC972C15E5B1943F891D92DBBF1C20582"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The name of the foreign country in which the foreign person has its principal place of business.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDFB41951889C4FD0B4045473C70F9B5D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by federal trade commission</header> <paragraph id="H3DF3AAE1B6DC4797B3873ACE3F09278A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9ADBCE9CDBF44CEE8275CBAC93FDAE5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of commission</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act. Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB87959C2C7494E7898025F89AF9785D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H3687F708FC124BC4BB5CA1BA0D8CA8CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alien</header><text>The term <quote>alien</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C4931D3803E4884843FE47FE2A6A4F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H02277D8520D4410CA2EA9B8272765216"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An alien.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C3BA65FB54442018C356C50477E2918"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A partnership, association, corporation, organization, or other combination of persons having its principal place of business in a foreign country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


