<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E8360D637C64962A64AD9B07EC41D76" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7416 IH: Methane Monitoring Science Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7416</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a Federal science strategy for the monitoring and detection of methane, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H29E373C9691A42D28A6D473A40A478C0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9698AB4C4E174BBA866C016E758400C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Methane Monitoring Science Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H93573900B24842EBBD664FF83955E14E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Methane monitoring and detection strategy</header> 
<subsection id="H76158724872247EFAAE2CAB7AF0DCAA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEB6726AD1159465784D4D8A866ACF827"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Develop, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal departments and agencies, a consensus- and science-based strategy to assess and evaluate the utilization of present and future methane monitoring and detection capabilities, including ground-based, airborne, and space-based sensors, source- and site-level technologies, and the integration of data relating to such monitoring and detection from other indicators, with a focus on the ability to detect methane emissions and large methane emission events, to strengthen American energy security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BA52BAC47D3447484AB94F7CF7FF80A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Submit to Congress a report on such strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB823B552A2C84DE797BCD1BCAC22F333"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy under subsection (a) shall be developed with the goal of enhancing the scientific and operational value of the capabilities referred to in such subsection, such that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEA0CB93CD4FB4E38B62307BCFCAA3133"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator may use such strategy to inform the planning of relevant research and development activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62B9C1E7ACC8424988176C9F72083276"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">non-Federal entities, including State and local governments, academia, nonprofit organizations, commercial industry such as the natural gas and oil industry of the United States, and international organizations, may effectively leverage data and information provided or enabled by such capabilities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4F4E144216E4735B1B774F792827E77"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such data may be quickly operationalized to support the rapid mitigation of methane leaks.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5C8881674D304632BE6FDE7E73651EF1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement authority</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as conferring enforcement authority to the Administrator, or the head of any other Federal department or agency, with regard to methane emissions, that was not in effect on the date before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

