<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25L99-MYT-XT-GHS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 S3567 IS: Cartel Marque and Reprisal Authorization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the President of the United States to issue letters of marque and reprisal with respect to acts of aggression against the United States by a member of a cartel, or a member of a cartel-linked organization, or any conspirator associated with a cartel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6CBD7D4757EB44698E5AF50915A0E2B1"><section id="iddd9dff8801df4a01bffed1d5566cc4e1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cartel Marque and Reprisal Authorization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ided5785ffc7dc4d4e822d7e063edc3e67"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idd878f2400e9946b0af564b8c332c0f0c"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Article I, section 8 of the Constitution grants the Congress the power to grant letters of marque and reprisal to punish, deter, and prevent the acts of aggression and depredations and other acts of war committed by cartel conspirators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf91998f2815a4348ac4505d26ef85751"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cartels present an unusual and extraordinary threat to national security and foreign policy of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id7255917db32644f2832b95c0d8ed7bab"><enum>3.</enum><header>Issuance of letters of marque and reprisal</header><subsection id="id7994ab52a196483f99a52acdae588dc6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority of President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President of the United States is authorized and requested to commission, under officially issued letters of marque and reprisal, so many of privately armed and equipped persons and entities as, in the judgment of the President, the service may require, with suitable instructions to the leaders thereof, to employ all means reasonably necessary to seize outside the geographic boundaries of the United States and its territories the person and property of any individual who the President determines is a member of a cartel, a member of a cartel-linked organization, or a conspirator associated with a cartel or a cartel-linked organization, who is responsible for an act of aggression against the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6edf895465c145d5a86db979c2ba57ac" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Security Bonds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No letter of marque and reprisal shall be issued by the President without requiring the posting of a security bond in such amount as the President shall determine is sufficient to ensure that the letter be executed according to the terms and conditions thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc95f2623f13246dc847a7985518c5cb8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition of cartel</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>cartel</quote> means an organization that—</text><paragraph id="id7514aba49d2a4bc5872f9b8375d5813d"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is described in section 1 of the Executive order titled <quote>Designating Cartels And Other Organizations As Foreign Terrorist Organizations and Specially Designated Global Terrorists</quote> and dated January 20, 2025; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b3bb513475242d8b5a472f5a7799412" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a <quote>transnational criminal organization</quote> under the meaning given that term in section 3003(5) of the <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/50">Public Law 118–50</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/2341">21 U.S.C. 2341(5)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

