<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4185FA60012B4C0FACA28E8DE4DAF366" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5905 IH: Helping Our Heroes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5905</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251104">November 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001327">Mr. Bresnahan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a charitable deduction for the service of volunteer firefighters and emergency medical and rescue personnel.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3A5D072709BB492D968C59D79473F146" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAE381F81A4F64169882263357F6B429E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Our Heroes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB7C437407FBB43DDB980FA4CAD816943"><enum>2.</enum><header>Allowance of charitable deduction for the service of volunteer firefighters and emergency medical and rescue personnel</header> <subsection id="HD41F9B2BD53D4B3799C09A6A0D7DF1B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">Section 170</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H9DB447CED04141C2A4FFC57CAD266B54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (q) as subsection (r), and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB869B6E319AE4B1EA73E79DBDF3B53C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (p) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE26797DDACA44AC1A436129AA992A8C1" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H58DD4EDF67C647EFBD98C71807F775F4"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Service of volunteer firefighters and emergency medical personnel treated as charitable contribution</header> 
<paragraph id="HF466B4F789114B04BF1C65936C2C5D63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each hour of qualified services rendered by an individual as a bona fide volunteer shall be treated for purposes of this section as a contribution of $20 to the organization to which such services are rendered.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F75BCCA176B49398601B8907FBA8A4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 300 hours of qualified services shall be taken into account under paragraph (1) with respect to any individual for any taxable year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2753CD66C55E4FC791C54EDD57C0901F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H5FD64432504142B98B1CE9144488D2BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Bona fide volunteer</header><text>An individual shall be treated as a bona fide volunteer if the only compensation received by such individual for performing qualified services is in the form of—</text> 
<clause id="H25CD21349ECB4D4DB4FFF2A488BEB992"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reimbursement for (or a reasonable allowance for) reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of such services, or</text></clause> <clause id="HBED222DC4D594E0C87A0CDD9AFB01A36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonable benefits (including length of service awards), and fees for such services, customarily paid by eligible employers in connection with the performance of such services by volunteers.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC3F53F4A4E244B385DD7B0FE5E18D5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified services</header><text>The term <quote>qualified services</quote> means fire fighting and prevention services, emergency medical and rescue services, ambulance services, civil air patrol, and search and rescue services. Such term shall include all training and training-related activities related to the services described in the preceding sentence which are required or authorized by the organization referred to in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43F66082C25B47AC84EE1906A8154CEA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>A contribution to which this subsection applies shall be verified in such manner as the Secretary may provide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA09FCFD295A04F68A5088F12C4A87D77"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2026, the $20 amount contained in paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2D4988A46D148D18D307B6040D2CAD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCF0A0C8F881A40A8922B934A1198F02F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Any increase determined under the preceding sentence which is not a multiple of $1 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $1.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDADF6229D163403894533080DAF9C9B0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exclusion for Members of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Services rendered during any period with respect to which such individual is a Member of Congress (as defined in section 2106 of title 5, United States Code) shall not be treated as qualified services for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8C1CC8FA22934369A5643E0E75708886"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allowance of deduction to individuals who do not elect To itemize deductions</header><text>Section 63(b) of such Code is amended by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H588FF772411C43498C89E44B2A53C3AC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H2589789BA6154DC8BA9C1460D510FF04"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">so much of the deduction allowed under section 170 for the taxable year as does not exceed the amount of such deduction which would be determined if only contributions treated as made under section 170(q) by reason of services rendered during such taxable year were taken into account.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBB4DDF4FE51841D0A02891BEA979494C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

