<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26269-SK3-DF-HWR"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3989 IS: Community Training, Education, and Access for Medical Students Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3989</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide community-based training opportunities for medical students in rural areas and medically underserved communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H83A6EDD3302B42B38240D369D0A1DF86"><section section-type="section-one" id="H20AF9CF6128B4EAA810A6DC2FB1FCDF9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Community Training, Education, and Access for Medical Students Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Community TEAMS Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0AD688A4612E47449927458292240717"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for community-based training for medical students in rural areas and medically underserved communities</header><subsection id="H725FDDE7A4A5490881395ABBF7E88E1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 330A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c">42 U.S.C. 254c</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC85E0C5BF33340A98D4FDE591051BCC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (h), (i), and (j) as subsections (i), (j), and (k), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2F20E0167524CB6AD520665D2BB1907"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC7276FC23A474082B43BCE19FD60822C"><subsection id="HE4A21DCC8EBF4B4F976ED1493AD706DC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Grants for community-Based training for medical students in rural areas and medically underserved communities</header><paragraph id="H7691A9BEEFB744EBAD1A64AA94882BD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director may award grants to eligible entities to expand the availability of community-based training for medical students in rural areas and medically underserved communities, including by supporting clinical rotations in health care facilities in such areas and communities, including in outpatient settings, to facilitate long-term, sustainable physician practice in high-need communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58230A100A274B2089FD8FE5752E9395"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of grants</header><text>A grant under this subsection shall be for a period of 1 to 5 years, as determined by the Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0177631450C049D4B559B7D5B85504CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this subsection, an entity shall be a consortium of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2B8597891B304956A3830B36CDB2A755"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One or more schools of osteopathic medicine or allopathic medicine.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7F184C73C754E738A7143D681638F66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One or more of the following:</text><clause id="H53A497B8E9EB4C06B128D6465648BE16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A rural health clinic.</text></clause><clause id="H853D03E71A174EBBA461FEB4A7332F1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federally qualified health center.</text></clause><clause id="H71EB0B936534419AA7F50798BEC44261"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health care facility located in a medically underserved community.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC5B3F117A943CBB15851A0BD9A6A4A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subsection shall, in consultation with the appropriate State office of rural health or another appropriate State entity, submit to the Director an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDD23C3DC8A434A039A045E0CD4E866E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the project that the eligible entity will carry out using the funds provided through the grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06959FB3F7E54B51A880DF1445088848"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an explanation of the reasons why Federal assistance is required to carry out the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC589EE09CE64C7FB570E928690043BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the manner in which the project funded through the grant will ensure continuous quality improvement in the provision of services by the entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40A918960BA64E7C9AC0449D7CDA0CE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of how the populations in the rural area or medically underserved community to be served through the grant will experience increased access to quality health care services across the continuum of care as a result of the activities carried out by the entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3154F4722595415596B536EF74A2FCB2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a plan for sustaining the project after Federal support for the project has ended;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5AE241A6555410C9AAE49212232FBD4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of how the project will be evaluated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21FF83F6FD614F1CA5B9F38A2DCE6AA5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other information as the Director determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACBD4E383EF84A3FA927986CF884B9A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 330A of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c">42 U.S.C. 254c</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H489510AFDAF3495FB929D126ADC6019D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>and for the planning and implementation of small health care provider quality improvement activities</quote> and inserting <quote>for the planning and implementation of small health care provider quality improvement activities, and for expanding the availability of community-based training for medical students in rural areas and medically underserved communities</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5ca55605590401fa0e9e8320229962e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>In this section:</quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Definitions—</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H988532B7C11F4FE08E0A5F71615AC576"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H49FE8AA0FC8343119104BEBE72B3C219"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subsections (e), (f), and (g)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (e), (f), (g), and (h)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5111CFF58894027BABD30AE772A8BF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="H1AE95292906449B58B2138074C8BE344"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="H98F2144ACB894B19A58B6485D613B3EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H3A6CF2F4F7A543EEB5895BACA32E9D28"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7B21C8F09FFF405DB7A998F58C483C50"><clause id="H4BB177EE45A34D30A7B322D149FB9718"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand the availability of community-based training for medical students in rural areas and medically underserved communities under subsection (h).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H318B7E2A44884CF782E2B765E6EC3FF5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (j), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subsections (e), (f), and (g)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (e), (f), (g), and (h)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida48a153aa33541afabc2aa70434543da"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (k), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>2021 through 2025</quote> and inserting <quote>2026 through 2030</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

