<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0B91FFEE5F014AC2A4FD1BD965148051" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8486 IH: Data Driven Suicide Prevention and Outreach Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8486</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a program to award grants for the development of predictive models to evaluate risk factors that contribute to the incidence of suicide among veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA9F6B7FB5A4346E8B55B44093EE9C93A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE97FD79F3BC64BBD8748C852DEB7F116" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Data Driven Suicide Prevention and Outreach Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB7366B2618824080AFED9B9500164CCC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs grant program for predictive models to evaluate risk factors that contribute to suicide among veterans</header> <subsection id="H9ACA5763F5AA4AAEAE71242D92FEDA02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Center for Innovation for Care and Payment of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall establish and carry out a program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to award grants to eligible organizations described in subsection (b) to use artificial intelligence to develop a predictive model to evaluate risk factors contributing to the incidence of suicide among veterans.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H0E26145C4126416EB824B9DC33499DEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible organization described in this subsection is a nonprofit entity, academic institution, private research organization, or other entity with demonstrated capability and experience—</text> <paragraph id="H37E01581043446B5A87CEDD48F81DC3F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developing and deploying artificial intelligence and machine learning solutions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAD66DD9AB2DF414788E83B222C6DBE1D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyzing health care data, including de-identification and protection of—</text> <subparagraph id="HE5D0701916CA4448BD5D535CF097F6C5" commented="no"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>personally identifiable information; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9023FADA809042E1A18F52B052F9D657" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protected health information;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8821A5FBABF454EA0AB06677260D6EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>developing predictive models or decision-support tools used in clinical or population health settings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H14D53D6809434A058E27EE17737E030A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applying advanced statistical methods or machine learning techniques to large, complex health datasets; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C8BEE666DBC4588837805E9E0E5A7CD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>complying with Department data security and interoperability standards.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1BAD45310C9F489FA03018E70E18ED6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible organization desiring a grant under the Program shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H44D0B180143B417D903D6A437FBC61D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection procedures</header> <paragraph id="HAC89390AC6374209AA6F31E911D9A9E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Number</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4), the Secretary shall select not fewer than two eligible organizations to which to award a grant under the Program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H09763E672B484986941B5136E49FD652"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In selecting an eligible organization pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the following criteria:</text> <subparagraph id="H5CAFE1429EE045B4A12989D225E0F833"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to the VISN in which the organization is located—</text>
<clause id="HC39AAA32DF2B4A369FCFB108E2E845CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the geographic distribution;</text></clause> <clause id="HF1574B0F949F4EF9B077FD75388C4E8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the complexity of applicable Veterans Health Administration facilities; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H180FDE46B33242718737C89B68299168"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the density of the veteran population.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD154E02ED5374E4394E33BD6E2C3B841"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Geographic proximity to Veterans Health Administration facilities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF78B7A44B4CE4AA89EEDE0342A62FCC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Demonstrated experience in collaborating with local Department facilities and community partners.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFCECDFB34EA543EA9C3FD6B7308A4515"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Demonstrated capability to deploy a predictive analysis solution in a health care system that serves more than 500,000 patients and beneficiaries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94129C1FDD204A27A34490F01CD09197" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In evaluating the criteria described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall give priority for selection under paragraph (1) to eligible organizations—</text> <subparagraph id="HBEB693287978497CB3F0F63444849257" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located in areas with—</text>
<clause id="H163732C620AC4331A24BD2D65D8B484D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a high rate of suicide among veterans;</text></clause> <clause id="H1153363404A1413A96706BE7527B03A6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a high rate of calls to the Veterans Crisis Line; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HAC7E291AF2354E4F8CD34C515AD259CD" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">long wait times for mental health care services at Department facilities;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9566137DB9124FA6A580B912BE93EA79" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with experience in administering predictive analytics or population health solutions for Government-owned health care systems pursuant to an agreement with the Federal Government (including the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H83EF3DB3FA5741149785BC8DEAA45380" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with a demonstrated capability to deliver tools that are—</text> <clause id="H2FDDB9EE4E2C44CAB110A3DCF51F80BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>explicable;</text></clause>
<clause id="H1646F05062D049868575BB826656BB7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>interoperable; and</text></clause> <clause id="H631620BB01584EBB8A18C336A54C15CD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>clinically actionable;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFCA4BC30047C4CEA89AC1A6B42CDDFAE" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that employ data scientists, clinicians, and suicide prevention specialists;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62F26E72421841B2B6F64C3AFEA66170" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>with existing infrastructure for secure data storage and transmission that complies with Federal cybersecurity requirements; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5BA4610F9AC442989ECE977637472447" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>that agree to make any predictive model or finding resulting from activities funded with a grant under this section available to the Secretary for Department of Veterans Affairs-wide implementation and evaluation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EA2B91D7D4047B5A4C5B96F99E1A3A5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may not, pursuant to paragraph (1), select an eligible organization located in a VISN in which another eligible organization in receipt of a grant under the Program is located.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1545E16F6BB94E8292DBDA3B0007FD25"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Capability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible organization in receipt of a grant under the Program shall ensure that the predictive model developed using such grant has the capability to integrate data under the jurisdiction of the Veterans Benefits Administration, including the military service records of veterans, with clinical data under the jurisdiction of the Veterans Health Administration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC468B84CF6F443A1A2CAF6C76275EE5A" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subsection (d) may be construed to require an eligible organization in receipt of a grant under the Program to transfer to the Secretary ownership of the predictive model developed using such grant, or any proprietary technology associated with such predictive model.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4025D2BAB8E045B99657D915C3588DAD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out the pilot program under this section shall terminate on September 30, 2029.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H65F5D9B493E84F6FAEE6C35243A39303"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HD37AE4706F554F888A55AF66979CA1FB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 238 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2358">10 U.S.C. 2358</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0E1FE5E4E534EB5B3A815EBA50CA1E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2EFF416F08D4C77809DB1692F5A856D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>Veterans Crisis Line</term> means the toll-free hotline for veterans established and operated under section 1720F of such title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2DB45309D9B490188427DB0C103020D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>VISN</term> means a Veteran Integrated Services Network.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

