<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F6E0A4F51674033A58BF8DB6E6CD4AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6026 IH: To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Education to submit a report on the availability, accessibility, and affordability of childcare for veteran families.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6026</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Education to submit a report on the availability, accessibility, and affordability of childcare for veteran families.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H817349B43308489FA10A535EC5232FD5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6DFEE30E2CE943E0831A3227D731CF5B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Education joint report on childcare for veteran families</header> 
<subsection id="H8B21AA9C17614C1E97A32E9151CF8377"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans and the Secretary of Education shall submit to Congress a joint report on the availability, accessability, and affordability of childcare for veteran families. Such report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H17EFE103C584466AB937D700C8E65441"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of childcare options available to veteran families as of the date of the submission of the report;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AC3E59854954232AF010B60CDE98568"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of gaps in childcare options for veteran families; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8038E148E5D44D709E457DEFEEC23F78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an evaluation of barriers to childcare for veteran families, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD7A37205F61049CCAD57BFA81DE4D307"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cost;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C5D5795ED49433CB3B9D6BF1B8202BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>geographic distance; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08F402FAD54A47FD835B7F0789B2435B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>eligibility criteria.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H255133064A234FD881F5A3B89E1F6CB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veteran family defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>veteran family</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2044 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

