<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE31A2C5D7C6541E39FBDD7FF3D701BFD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>95 HR 6206 IH: Protect Culturally Sensitive Information Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6206</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect the confidentiality of culturally sensitive information.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA49BFB4529874CE6AD8007E8CA8078BF" style="OLC"><section id="H4EB44B5C5ADA4B4BA5E295E83135AC6F" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Culturally Sensitive Information Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAB7B5686D8094F34B0AC12396CAE58AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="H539F7FC239C4465CB2D9E2DEE0F21C1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to protect the confidentiality of culturally sensitive information provided by Indian Tribes, Alaska Native Entities, and Native Hawaiian Organizations to the Federal Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0842DDD1435244F9A45DF7861179A36F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to create a safe, respectful space for consultation between the Federal Government and Indian Tribes, Alaska Native Entities, and Native Hawaiian Organizations that encourages a free-flowing exchange of information and ideas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9699DF88BC044EEE9A98C3ECEC9A015C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to build trust, strengthen relationships, and expand opportunities for costewardship between the Federal Government and Indian Tribes, Alaska Native Entities, and Native Hawaiian Organizations by ensuring that culturally sensitive information provided to the Federal Government will be protected to the maximum extent practicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H392C91F9D0B943D1AD3D9064FD2B0F20"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to advance repatriation of cultural items, including human remains, under the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26A1162C9AFD4179BBBA97715C6BEE61" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to strengthen support for the policy of the United States of protecting and preserving traditional, cultural, and ceremonial rites and practices in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H669A05A823AA4201B390584AE47F8A57"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HEEA36F7F54634E73806F5143DBE2434C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7127762608C4DFE81AF095966156D9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alaska Native Entity</header><text>The term <term>Alaska Native Entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8E20433740214797A0814C4D520F10CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Native Corporation, as defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EBB48D9A89947D4B3A5BFED69148898"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Alaska Native Association referenced in section 7(a) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>), including respective successor organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H898AC94A2EAB42B1ADD1855B4E7BE099"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorized Representative</header><text>The term <term>Authorized Representative</term> means a person authorized by an Alaska Native Entity, Native Hawaiian Organization, or Tribal Government to make determinations with respect to culturally sensitive information on behalf of the Alaska Native Entity, Native Hawaiian Organization, or Tribal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H825059E7B1C149BDA77F4A2444CE4E92"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cultural items</header><text>The term <term>cultural items</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E5B38233EDB421286D3AB611D34AC74"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, or other community the name of which is included (including parenthetically) on the list published by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D825D00A9BD4CBE87F89E35A47738F9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Native hawaiian organization</header><text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian Organization</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H39962E4346E74F9D981F342262361380"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an organization that—</text><clause id="H222EFB41FFD8434AA662ED5FBB637A7A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serves and represents the interests of Native Hawaiians;</text></clause><clause id="HC5361E5476494969AF86E156DEC8EEBE"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>has as a primary and stated purpose for the provision of services to Native Hawaiians; and</text>
 </clause><clause id="HDBB2D38C5566446EB99669858C01BA65"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has expertise in Native Hawaiian affairs; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73B6EB2FC29244EF9F826534D1D91ED9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes Native Hawaiian Organizations registered with the Department of the Interior’s Office of Native Hawaiian Relations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5AF9E1D421B4A34AE476ED0E55E2B3B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Culturally sensitive information</header><text>The term <term>culturally sensitive information</term> means information described in section 4(a) that is subject to the disclosure protections and handling requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F13CFA646AB48999F332FA18352E2DE"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal Government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal Government</term> means the governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9B0A5F3219C446AD8E3694C80174B2F6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on disclosure</header><subsection id="H0811FE3B10D7456D9107BD9D4FAD8DB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of culturally sensitive information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Tribal Government or an Authorized Representative may designate information provided to any agency (including information shared with the agency prior to the date of the enactment of this Act) relating to the location or attributes of culturally or religiously significant sites including burial sites, or to cultural items, or the existence or details of cultural or religious practices, as culturally sensitive information.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4631A664F50D434A9AB6095EE3E08063"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Protection of culturally sensitive information</header><paragraph id="HF58D8BAA64B24E62BF32A4EA54FF5727"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Handling of culturally sensitive information</header><text>Any agency that receives information designated as culturally sensitive information under subsection (a) shall consult with the appropriate Tribal Government or Authorized Representative to determine—</text><subparagraph id="H58CE8E653850475082F1121D73F0FD57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the agency may store the information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61F836C8FA984E81B163BEB1F3402623"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which other entities within the Federal Government, if any, may have access to the information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB7704D71B1D4F40B62636BEEFE10D37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition against public disclosure</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), any information designated as culturally sensitive information under subsection (a) is exempt from disclosure under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), and may not be made available to the public under any other provision of law or in any Federal publication.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H985B1F49DB8747D49465B9AAACEAFD56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limited release of culturally sensitive information</header><subparagraph id="H9B4ED60F84FB4261BB768613B47A4F3F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Compelled disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any lawful order (including a subpoena) compelling an agency to disclose culturally sensitive information in its possession—</text><clause id="HC14728886D4248ACB072DB7326739B98" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the lawful order shall, to the extent practicable, provide for the mitigation of any potential adverse effect deriving from the release of culturally sensitive information;</text></clause><clause id="H99A03099959D4061B262653B6466F6CE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the agency shall, not later than 3 business days after such order takes effect—</text><subclause id="HA3D87CE936F740D1A594AD032CF7906F" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>notify each applicable Tribal Government or Authorized Representative in writing of the intention of the agency to comply with the order or subpoena; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6720F29A20FB47BE9E8E93B5EB615D6A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, and in consultation with the applicable Tribal Government or Authorized Representative, mitigate the potential adverse effect of releasing the culturally sensitive information, including by requesting that documents be redacted, provided under seal, or reviewed in camera; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9E0E4C14A95E436989A6E5973ED58DFE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the court shall accord due deference to any mitigation undertaken by the agency under clause (ii)(II).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H131FB41DBEAA43D2AA5E67F0F580EE6A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consent to disclosure</header><text>In the absence of a lawful order or subpoena compelling the release of culturally sensitive information, the agency may disclose information designated as culturally sensitive information under subsection (a) only if each applicable Tribal Government or Authorized Representative consent to the disclosure in writing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H708E52CC42F44C0585D78A1F1CD29575"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Closed consultations</header><text>At the request of a Tribal Government or an Authorized Representative, a consultation or communication that is likely to involve discussion of the location or attributes of culturally or religiously significant sites, or to cultural items, or the existence or details of cultural or religious practices shall be closed to the public, and all records created in relation to that meeting shall be designated as culturally sensitive information.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBE1ABA76ED73472F99CE8C304C679472"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with Indian Tribes, Alaska Native Entities, and Native Hawaiian Organizations, shall establish guidelines for Federal agencies that includes information to understand the significance of and best practices to handle culturally sensitive information.</text></subsection><subsection id="H191674449D3F47898BBB9B8458EB7B94"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="HB9E8B904DCCC41CAA87C15EFA11A7F9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Promulgation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, except as provided in paragraph (2), the head of each agency shall promulgate rules and regulations to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A19CE4E3B544FB79BCA1E1A12E60CEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the head of an agency with jurisdiction over other agencies may promulgate rules and regulations on behalf of those other agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

