<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4D445D38974481DAA0F9CBE78CEEC44" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7820 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules for investments in qualified opportunity funds, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules for investments in qualified opportunity funds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8EFE5D46D8F24A3E983D9495B0C3B0B8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCBF1C6851FA946799790A2C70DECAE67" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Modification of rules for investments in qualified opportunity funds</header> 
<subsection id="HA10849FB2ED0444398C8FBC1670D5CFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of designation period of qualified opportunity zones</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1400Z">Section 1400Z–1(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>10th calendar year</quote> and inserting <quote>20th calendar year</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H739F357DEBD743F4B5E7B54E8F6C5D42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension of election period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1400Z–2(a)(2)(B) is amended by striking <quote>December 31, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2036</quote>.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC80D074E10247318E80A22A15E8D618"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Year of inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (B) of section 1400Z–2(b)(1) of such Code is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1EF9C603F3544CE4A52877E601FF1E2C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H8B66A27179EF449D8D7E63D802703090"><enum>(B)</enum> <clause id="H65A64F97703346B895DCEA65BDCF5D17" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>December 31, 2026, in the case of an amount invested before the date of the enactment of this clause, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2D0CDB2AB8FC459D941A778510551607" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>December 31, 2036, in the case of an amount invested after the date of the enactment of this clause and before January 1, 2037.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HE2ADE067C4074597B3E8AB244E69613C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules applicable to investments involving residential rental projects</header> <paragraph id="HBC9D813321114127AAF0E240D86D9809"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Increases in basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1400Z–2(b)(2)(B) of such Code is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDB92D87B93194A6B9250D2B3E353929F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, if the taxpayer invests in a qualified opportunity fund that holds any asset in qualified opportunity zone property that is a residential rental project, the basis in the taxpayer’s investment shall be increased in accordance with the preceding sentence if, and only if, at least 50 percent of the occupied residential units in the project are occupied, as of the date gain is recognized by reason of subsection (a)(1)(B), by individuals whose income, adjusted for family size, is 100 percent or less of the area median income.</quote>,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF691FA464AE44254B7B47D90AA7422CA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (iii), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In the case such investment so held is an investment in a qualified opportunity fund that holds any asset in qualified opportunity zone property that is a residential rental project, the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting <quote>15 percent</quote> for <quote>10 percent</quote>.</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76FA97167E614DEFBDBA58536FE19FAF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>In the case such investment so held is an investment in a qualified opportunity fund that holds any asset in qualified opportunity zone property that is a residential rental project, the preceding sentence shall be applied by substituting <quote>7 percent</quote> for <quote>5 percent</quote>.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF02BFF21A3B74DDE9FFDC575F50245BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of residential rental projects as qualified opportunity zone property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1400Z–2(d) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA06E2A4282574177A59C9BE0530A986A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H0BC745C53D1C4BCBBC3009461A244E9D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of residential rental projects as qualified opportunity zone property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A residential rental project shall be treated as qualified opportunity zone property if, and only if, the project meets the following requirements:</text> <subparagraph id="H4B26DED9BA714E71930182F5BECA8F01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The project meets the definition of qualified opportunity zone business property in paragraph (2)(D).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA7AF3DB1315345B8B2ED5909E14B6689"><enum>(B)</enum><text>At least 30 percent of the occupied residential units in the project are occupied by individuals whose income, adjusted for family size, is 100 percent or less of the area median income during substantially all of the qualified opportunity fund’s holding period for such property.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2FE5AA8F6904E47A21F7FE5F0E4D407"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Rent increases do not exceed 3 percent annually for any of the residential units in the project.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2A5A9C38F384ECBAF54B47969E8657D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>At least 60-day advance notice is provided with respect to any rent increase for a residential unit in the project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HC27CF1D76DC94464B4DF72D35C8F303E" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective dates</header> <paragraph id="HCC5C135378294F788757490C5D9CDF25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7193369322924AC7A55940F88F42152A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of designation period of qualified opportunity zones</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to designations in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

