<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4F68644D6FB441188297252F982339F4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6638 IH: To require a report on merits and options for establishing an institute relating to space resources, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6638</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on merits and options for establishing an institute relating to space resources, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24AA402CCB084DFD9D4075934AF34B3F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H140D7D5B123146FCA83EDEF8223AB032" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Report on merits and options for establishing an institute relating to space resources</header> 
<subsection id="H899E841A787543A4AB3BE3704CC5FE3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) and Secretary of Commerce shall jointly submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the merits of, and options for, establishing an institute relating to space resources to advance the objectives of NASA and the Department of Commerce in maintaining United States preeminence in space. Such objectives shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1EC0996AEC73458EB1DE8E5140AC8FB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Identifying, developing, and distributing space resources, including by encouraging the development of foundational science, industrial capability, and technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H335A5E0EB71B459EAB52AED7F1B06315"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Reducing the technological and business risks associated with identifying, developing, and distributing space resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8EF238374314F148EC1333D0778E388"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Research to maximize the responsible use of space resources.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE171266E5E3B4CD69C8A95DCDE81881C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Developing options for using space resources to carry out the following.</text> <subparagraph id="HAFF3A6638CD3450EB5D76CFCCCE0052F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Support current and future space architectures, programs, business, and missions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1141B2490E447D4A8CFFBC14E458958"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Enable such architectures, programs, business, and missions that would not otherwise be possible.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E6E9D4752F14704A5A5293C3F671123"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Supplement the supply of such resources available on Earth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8193E77D6E44B31B710264B4ABA78A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional matters</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall also include the following assessments of the Administrator of NASA and the Secretary of Commerce:</text> <paragraph id="H5597458B81D742089256E60EC7BFC520"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whether a virtual or physical institute relating to space resources is most cost effective and appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9A0D3018EBF4AC4A02F130A391B5DA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether partnering with institutions of higher education and the aerospace industry, and the extractive industry as appropriate, would be effective in increasing information available to the institute with respect to advancing the objectives described in such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1DCF31E31D2D472E90EAE088C62909E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H814CB923E78742CA92B6693838E6A553"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extractive industry</header><text>The term <quote>extractive industry</quote> means companies and individuals involved in the processes of extracting, including mining, quarrying, drilling, and dredging, raw, natural materials or energy sources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3155EFD40AF04856AF6951D945AFB595"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institute of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H80A469414F4B44B595B854C6AD51891B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Space resource</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC9AB18FC0813416C81CBB9334E7E0BFA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>space resource</quote> means an abiotic resource in situ in outer space.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCEF2BD994C9944C59CEDF31B008B172A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <quote>space resource</quote> includes a raw, natural material or energy source.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

