<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFFA98AD7B40C431C8F9063CEF2ADD2DA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6455 IH: Health Insurance Premium Fairness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6455</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to take certain Medicare premiums of household members into account in determining the health care insurance premiums tax credit.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE407E07B84E24CA1BE3E5BBDFF758C66" style="OLC"><section id="H41E383DBD6AD43CD973D585DE7D5D0FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Health Insurance Premium Fairness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF8A7E9D0ECF848C7A93B969E0BD936EE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certain Medicare premiums of household members taken into account in determining health care insurance premiums tax credit</header><subsection id="HCEED9AB1BC88472BB9A0211462B5BA7D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAE956D40B5484E8690DF015A340A16DE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H9DB682380D004FCE8C849CE84258AC5F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Adjustment for certain Medicare premiums of household members</header><subparagraph id="H223B93069E4F4ABAAC4090836176B8A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any applicable taxpayer who elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide) the application of this paragraph with respect to any coverage month, the amount determined under paragraph (2)(B)(ii) with respect to such coverage month shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate amount of specified Medicare premiums of such applicable taxpayer’s household members for such month.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD918F086160F4B8D87E6AFADC8FA2E2F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Household members</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>household member</quote> means, with respect to any applicable taxpayer, any individual who is taken into account in determining the family size of such applicable taxpayer under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F32ABA6296540AA91A21FDD29178C83"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Specified Medicare premiums</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>specified Medicare premiums</quote> means premiums paid by the applicable taxpayer or such taxpayer’s household members (and not reimbursed by any other person) for coverage under part A, B, C, or D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act, and premiums for coverage under a Medicare supplemental policy under section 1882 of such Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H12C019A4BCB846BCA625DACF9C20F61F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to coverage months beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

