<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2816D70283F64F22A3C5DF073C1406A8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6609 IH: Pharmacists Fight Back in Medicare and Medicaid Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6609</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XI, XVIII, and XIX of the Social Security Act to establish certain requirements under Medicare and Medicaid with respect to prescription drug benefits and pharmacy benefit managers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0472934523084CCEA61E934C18AF9766" style="OLC"><section id="H76672B79B5A84CF2ADD61DDAACB02F2B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pharmacists Fight Back in Medicare and Medicaid Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0139D405009049B6953DFD5187FCBDD4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishing certain requirements with respect to PBMs</header><subsection id="HD0E9B250A4894DC5BC08D1835A9E6819"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicare</header><paragraph id="H57800AB95FDE41FC99B978E966BCF909"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prescription drug plans</header><text>Section 1860D–12 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FC52DB9D4E34AF8A25E9ECE97EBFAD6"><subsection id="H1848C2700ABE401E846FA31BD8B70A36"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Requirements relating to pharmacy benefit managers</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2027:</text><paragraph id="H4E266EBB558A4037B6F58B063C004F97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each contract entered into with a PDP sponsor under this part with respect to a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor shall provide—</text><subparagraph id="H6597F5F11CA44D99877C13E192BDCCFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the sponsor (and any pharmacy benefit manager acting on behalf of such sponsor, including any affiliate of such PBM, as applicable)—</text><clause id="H6249743623C74EB38706726308E708C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall comply with the pharmacy payment requirements described in <internal-xref idref="H90D1A684289E4D8DAECB4530CA54692A" legis-path="(h)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref>;</text></clause><clause id="H6BEC9266BD704E0CA4A46025086FBA29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall comply with the rebate pass-through requirements described in <internal-xref idref="HD9E62D3DEBAB40E1B98E3D989EF1CDB5" legis-path="(h)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref>;</text></clause><clause id="HF43C7974B6934D3F9638C6594BEE6381"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall comply with the reporting requirement described in <internal-xref idref="H95DE437F51994DBABC4B07FFCB924889" legis-path="(h)(4)">paragraph (4)</internal-xref>; and</text></clause><clause id="H8581D499E7D14FFDA12D8CA19E596D70"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may not engage in steering; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99A9101DAFE244599C3EE1FE11C65EB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that any pharmacy benefit manager acting on behalf of such sponsor has a written agreement with the PDP sponsor under which the PBM, and any affiliate of such PBM, as applicable, agrees to meet the requirements described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90D1A684289E4D8DAECB4530CA54692A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pharmacy payment requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H6249743623C74EB38706726308E708C2" legis-path="(h)(1)(A)(i)">paragraph (1)(A)(i)</internal-xref>, the pharmacy payment requirements described in this paragraph are, with respect to a PDP sponsor (and a PBM acting on behalf of such sponsor, including any affiliate of such PBM, as applicable) the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBF116582047F4D02A7A2672DAA46C49D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sponsor, PBM, or affiliate reimburses an in-network pharmacy for the ingredient cost of a covered part D drug in an amount equal to the sum of—</text><clause id="H6C1239F129A8441887C482E49C9639BA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national average drug acquisition cost for the drug as of the day that the pharmacy submits a claim for payment for such drug (as determined based upon the retail survey prices obtained under section 1927(f)(1)), or, in the case of a drug for which no such national average drug acquisition cost is available, the wholesale acquisition cost for such drug as of such day; and</text></clause><clause id="H4CD509935EFE443893F43EA529D06305" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to 4 percent of the amount described in clause (i), or $50, whichever is less.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6C8C8724077449D86C43BF67D66B6FF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each covered part D drug obtained from an in-network pharmacy by an individual enrolled in the prescription drug plan, the sponsor, PBM, or affiliate—</text><clause id="H8294D8368CAF477ABDC02A31391592E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pays such pharmacy a dispensing fee that is equal to the dispensing fee paid for such drug under the State plan under title XIX in the State in which such pharmacy is located, as reported by the State under section 1927(f)(2); and</text></clause><clause id="H6872ABECE54047CCB54FFEE4FEDA99EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not require such individual to reimburse such dispensing fee or otherwise increase the amount owed by such individual with respect to such drug to account for such dispensing fee.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB70A2AA91F9E4F58B42E5A8697A39D81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The sponsor, PBM, or affiliate does not impose any fee or other payment requirement upon an in-network pharmacy that would have the effect of reducing the amount received by the pharmacy under the other provisions of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E62D3DEBAB40E1B98E3D989EF1CDB5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rebate pass-through requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H6BEC9266BD704E0CA4A46025086FBA29" legis-path="(h)(1)(A)(ii)">paragraph (1)(A)(ii)</internal-xref>, the rebate pass-through requirements described in this paragraph are, with respect to a PDP sponsor (and a PBM acting on behalf of such sponsor, including any affiliate of such PBM, as applicable), that, in the case that such sponsor, PBM, or affiliate receives a manufacturer rebate in connection with a covered part D drug—</text><subparagraph id="H45A176447C3145D68EA81EBFF5A31BF3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that such drug is obtained from an in-network pharmacy by an individual enrolled in the prescription drug plan, the PDP sponsor, PBM, or affiliate applies, at the point of sale of such drug, a reduction to the amount of any coinsurance or copayment owed by such individual with respect to such drug, such that the amount of coinsurance or copayment so owed is calculated based on an amount equal to the reimbursement amount for such drug determined under <internal-xref idref="HBF116582047F4D02A7A2672DAA46C49D" legis-path="(h)(2)(A)">paragraph (2)(A)</internal-xref>, less the amount of such rebate (or, in the case of a rebate described in paragraph (5)(B)(ii), the amount of such rebate that is attributable to such drug and such individual); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H534917B0B3E14143A23C8A29B8F9C639" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that the entity receiving the manufacturer rebate in connection with such drug is a PBM (or any affiliate of such PBM), the PBM (or affiliate) remits to the PDP sponsor an amount (in this subparagraph referred to as the <quote>rebate remittance payment</quote>) equal to the amount of such rebate (or, in the case of a rebate described in paragraph (5)(B)(ii), the amount of such rebate that is attributable to such drug and such individual), less the amount by which the coinsurance or copayment owed by an individual enrolled in the prescription drug plan with respect to such drug was reduced pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H45A176447C3145D68EA81EBFF5A31BF3" legis-path="(h)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF82229847C7C40408AD2468761096D2B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that such drug is obtained from an in-network pharmacy by an individual enrolled in the prescription drug plan who is a subsidy eligible individual (as defined in section 1860D–14(a)(3)), the PDP sponsor remits to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may specify—</text><clause id="H96FA44445935433BB4210386507B9B0B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case that the entity receiving the manufacturer rebate in connection with such drug is a PBM (or any affiliate of such PBM), the amount received by the sponsor under <internal-xref idref="H534917B0B3E14143A23C8A29B8F9C639" legis-path="(h)(3)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> with respect to such drug and such individual; and</text></clause><clause id="H96CE79136E1F42BABA1B9B7B167F759E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that the entity receiving the manufacturer rebate in connection with such drug is the PDP sponsor, an amount equal to the amount of such rebate (or, in the case of a rebate described in paragraph (5)(B)(ii), the amount of such rebate that is attributable to such drug and such individual), less the amount by which the coinsurance or copayment owed by such individual with respect to such drug was reduced pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H45A176447C3145D68EA81EBFF5A31BF3" legis-path="(h)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95DE437F51994DBABC4B07FFCB924889"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>For purposes of <internal-xref idref="HF43C7974B6934D3F9638C6594BEE6381" legis-path="(h)(1)(A)(iii)">paragraph (1)(A)(iii)</internal-xref>, the reporting requirement described in this paragraph is, with respect to a PBM and any affiliate of such PBM, that, not later than July 1, 2028, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the PBM (or affiliate) submits to the PDP sponsor and to the Secretary a report containing a certification that, during the preceding year, such PBM (or affiliate)—</text><subparagraph id="H19EA540FD4EE47E99DED6D61A342BF68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complied with the requirements under paragraphs (2) and (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B74CFB6C75548488CFD2422B0CEE614"><enum>(B)</enum><text>did not engage in steering.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0FABACA30B3422CB6860E01BCD51BD4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HB3794AD64DA64D769721C91487D7AD23" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>affiliate</term> means, with respect to a PBM or PDP sponsor, an entity that, directly or indirectly—</text><clause id="H8CCD17E8B8B849DE88B53BBA677750F7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>owns, controls, or has an investment interest in such PBM or PDP sponsor;</text></clause><clause id="HE0DECCF6984D4C49ABF2215F29CFCE6C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is owned by such PBM or PDP sponsor or controlled by such PBM or PDP sponsor;</text></clause><clause id="HEA737775C06C46D892C829FE47401992" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that such PBM or PDP sponsor has an investment interest in; or</text></clause><clause id="H96DB54F4F8254EBE830D36606DBC9015" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is under common ownership or corporate control of such PBM or PDP sponsor.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EF3558537DC42269DE63030F6ED2273" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Manufacturer rebate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>manufacturer rebate</term>—</text><clause id="H80A5250976C2465C9E1387F557D30C29"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any price concession (including any payment, discount, administration fee, credit, incentive, or penalty) provided by the manufacturer of a covered part D drug (or any affiliate, subsidiary, third party, or intermediary of such manufacturer) to a PDP sponsor (or any PBM acting on behalf of such sponsor, including any affiliate of such PBM, as applicable), in connection with the furnishing of such covered part D drug to an individual enrolled in a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor; and</text></clause><clause id="H95AE92E04CCA4341A33953E7A9232D3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any such price concession that is determined based upon—</text><subclause id="H4EF79B27BEC24EACA713E1C9EFA9C5E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the aggregate volume of such covered part D drug (or a group of covered part D drugs that includes such part D drug) furnished to individuals enrolled in a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H5F9077CE255A49AA8426A819386A24F9"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the furnishing of any service provided to the manufacturer by such sponsor (or any PBM acting on behalf of such sponsor, or any affiliate of such PBM (including an off-shore entity or group purchasing organization), as applicable) in connection with the furnishing of such covered part D drug (or a group of covered part D drugs that includes such part D drug).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E72558C73E0493D9B06FF6DF130CBF3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefit manager; PBM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>pharmacy benefit manager</term> and <term>PBM</term> mean a person, business entity, affiliate, or other entity that performs pharmacy benefits management services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C6B9B5B4F024C1D9A1C8E5795FE933B" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefits management services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pharmacy benefits management services</term>—</text><clause id="H2148A68059A841A2B511F5AA8A7EF42E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means the managing or administration of a plan or program that pays for, reimburses, and covers the cost of prescription drugs and medical devices; and</text></clause><clause id="HCA09E31E50A747469B9A9E6D4B190AB1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes the processing and payment of claims for prescription drugs and the adjudication of appeals or grievances related to qualified prescription drug coverage under this part.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H377625855BB346D486D78674F6B7537F"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Steering</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>steering</term> means, with respect to a PDP sponsor (and any PBM acting on behalf of such sponsor, including any affiliate of such PBM, as applicable)—</text><clause id="H4B57C5B70023494AA121FA09073BF66B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directing, ordering, or requiring an enrollee in a prescription drug plan to use a specific pharmacy, including an affiliate pharmacy, for the purpose of filling a prescription for a covered part D drug or receiving services from a pharmacist;</text></clause><clause id="HBBA3B713D2D34487A3B64C66C3ABF011"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering or implementing a prescription drug plan design that—</text><subclause id="H421F0FDBB7FF4507ABC224A126006EA4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>requires an enrollee in a prescription drug plan to utilize a pharmacy, including an affiliate pharmacy; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3625EDA86A91468E8D58014C9EC38B5A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>increases costs to the PDP sponsor or an enrollee, including by requiring an enrollee to pay the full cost for a covered part D drug when such enrollee chooses not to use an affiliate pharmacy;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8099A924AC5A4A9F88BB15AA8F2C7664"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advertising, marketing, or promoting a pharmacy, including an affiliate pharmacy, in a manner that encourages enrollees to choose such pharmacy over another in-network pharmacy;</text></clause><clause id="HC67D4F733EEE43FEB9BDE6B90726D53A" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating more than one network of pharmacies with respect to a prescription drug plan such that an in-network pharmacy belonging to a specific network (such as a preferred pharmacy network, narrow pharmacy network, or specialty pharmacy network) receives preferential treatment, or engaging in any practice (including accreditation or credentialing standards, day supply limitations, or delivery method limitations) that has the effect of excluding an in-network pharmacy from participation in the network of the PDP sponsor or restricting an in-network pharmacy from filling a prescription for a covered part D drug; or</text></clause><clause id="H8DF7BDBB8DB148A6B9EDEC964A672717"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaging in any practice that attempts to influence or induce a manufacturer of a covered part D drug to limit the distribution of such drug to a small number of pharmacies or certain types of pharmacies, or to restrict distribution of such drug to non-affiliate pharmacies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA30771835B1E4BEABB26868D0382014A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement to deduct expected rebate amounts from plan bids</header><text>Section 1860D–11(b)(2)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111(b)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H4D9E5D9F955B42C58776ECD2567168A4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1C01FAFFCA640DAA78AD845AE564BBB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating clause (iv) as clause (v); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H371B9299F609478B85664D88C33C00C0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (iii) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE6A82185D78A444EB16ED3D322D0C5B1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H181C4EF0411B4A90B5E58D3138BDE918" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to bids beginning with plan year 2027, assumptions regarding any rebate remittance payments provided under section 1860D–12(h)(3)(B), subtracted from the actuarial value to produce such bid; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE498E1AAC8F64AAC91B6D3F3DF02E45E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>MA–PD plans</header><text>Section 1857(f)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59D079029FD84C60A9F07C8CC864895D"><subparagraph id="H88077B38788B45D29391FAF7D55F44F9"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Requirements relating to pharmacy benefit managers</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2027, section 1860D–12(h).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DF5E695C494411C883C0799445393B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medicaid</header><paragraph id="H783FE3B07E6743978D8F3826548C3A38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1927 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H639EE18B614C4EE4BBFF15135851784E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HB858F9920BC040739B31DF92B356DCEC" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H23E284515B0D4D288D8B0620BF97F5CE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requirements related to pharmacy benefit managers</header><text>A contract between the State and a pharmacy benefit manager, or a contract between the State and a managed care entity or other specified entity (as such terms are defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D) and collectively referred to in this paragraph as the <quote>entity</quote>) that includes provisions making the entity responsible for coverage of covered outpatient drugs dispensed to individuals enrolled with the entity, shall require—</text><subparagraph id="H5F59C6B2A15A4888A91892BD7F47C8F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that the entity or PBM (as applicable) does not engage in steering;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8898DDF770A4B78A555937540DFF13B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that any payment made by the entity or the PBM (as applicable) for such a drug and related administrative services (as applicable), including payments made by a PBM on behalf of the State or entity, is equal to—</text><clause id="HC79FF28BC560422BB51C65E24B6EF92D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ingredient cost of such drug, which shall be in an amount equal to the sum of—</text><subclause id="HB62B32CAC6994E8F938F986F20550FB4" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national average drug acquisition cost for the drug as of the day that the pharmacy submits a claim for payment for such drug (as determined based upon the retail survey prices obtained under subsection (f)(1)), or, in the case of a drug for which no such national average drug acquisition cost is available, the wholesale acquisition cost for such drug as of such day; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H99E12CB0AB384D4D827A65B96E51BDF1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an amount equal to 4 percent of the amount described in <internal-xref idref="HB62B32CAC6994E8F938F986F20550FB4" legis-path="(6)(A)(ii)(I)(aa)">item (aa)</internal-xref>, or $50, whichever is less; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE23CD8CB67E1424D9EFC4D5750489B7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a dispensing fee that is equal to the dispensing fee paid for such drug under the State plan under this title in the State in which such pharmacy is located, as reported by the State under subsection (f)(2); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C8B39D30F7943039BB915B19887DD7B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that, in the case that the entity or PBM (as applicable) receives from a manufacturer of a covered outpatient drug a rebate or discount in connection with the furnishing of such drug to an individual enrolled under the State plan (or waiver of such plan), the entity or PBM remits to the State an amount equal to the amount of such rebate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88689CEFAC51437E949D2C809059B860"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (k), by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5EE31B6FE9C34834A5EBF81DAA0CC3BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H7F17FFFBCA8448AE8BDEF792307AF6EC"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Pharmacy benefit manager; PBM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>pharmacy benefit manager</term> and <term>PBM</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 1860D–12(h)(C).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H750A69A6D69143359CF81D1C6E4D433F"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Steering</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>steering</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1860D–12(h)(E), except that any reference in such section to the <quote>PDP sponsor</quote> is deemed a reference to a managed care entity or other specified entity (as such terms are defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D)) that is responsible for coverage of covered outpatient drugs, and any reference to a <quote>covered part D drug</quote> is deemed a reference to a covered outpatient drug.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69F2F93BA5C247F7A28C9CE6847D90CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 1903(m) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H838DB5A611D34CA3A12C0915D1C006FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)(xiii)—</text><clause id="HAFF4C3F2C54241D185A52B70F2C32009"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (III)</quote> and inserting <quote>(III)</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H3586C6269A7748FDA6F9147BF7422D37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and (IV) if the contract includes provisions making the entity responsible for coverage of covered outpatient drugs, the entity shall comply with the requirements of section 1927(e)(6)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H9A6764E20EBA4F7B8FBF3E660ECB24BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by moving the margin 2 ems to the left; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE77AF5ECDFBF4E8D80E12A91B208F2A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HDA3DB2F4340A4A208D01318C3585C89C" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H420FC479BBC64F8A9F9092752874BE89" indent="up1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>No payment shall be made under this title to a State with respect to expenditures incurred by the State for payment for services provided by an other specified entity (as defined in paragraph (9)(D)(iii)) unless such services are provided in accordance with a contract between the State and such entity which satisfies the requirements of paragraph (2)(A)(xiii).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE72144DB8252488899CD82100A800FFF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to contracts between States and managed care entities, other specified entities, or pharmacy benefit managers that have an effective date beginning on or after January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC18554A3B262425B99FC4C79B4E04CF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties for noncompliant PBMs</header><paragraph id="H030A2E6180BD44CEB40857343D6072D9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Criminal penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128B of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7b">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4DD2DF2B40DF429187F5F9F11EF31FF8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HFACE1DDE943E43F4B2E883E2A6420A26" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever provides pharmacy benefits management services on behalf of a prescription drug plan sponsor under part D of title XVIII or a medicaid managed care organization under title XIX and—</text><paragraph id="HC7284254A3AE460883B0322DC7CD59AB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly and willfully fails to comply with the pharmacy payment requirements under section 1860D–12(h)(2) or section 1927(e)(6)(A), as applicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE280A6939ED34A6696E15A1CD036FF69" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly and willfully engages in steering (as defined in section 1860D–12(h)); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC5E554990B0454B9869F3DDF5E6D7D3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>knowingly and willfully fails to comply with the rebate pass-through requirements under section 1860D–12(h)(3) or section 1927(e)(6)(C), as applicable,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">shall be guilty of a felony and upon conviction thereof shall be fined not more than $1,000,000, or imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2271D4250C3402FBDFED3A2B16852A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil monetary penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128A(a) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7a(a)) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA84528DB9C1946EBA8FE7901CF3B6AF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by adding <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92C63B33F2A046B48CA1F969EDF9423A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (10) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9239677C128D4B1F93C84501330280C0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H30120F79039A4A8D95CF4A2D4F2F679C"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commits an act described in section 1128B(i);</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0558F5D1F34B47EA93F5AC0D0E07AF4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text><clause id="HC24DBE09A767432DA487741CCC9627C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or in cases under paragraph (9)</quote> and inserting <quote>in cases under paragraph (9)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H9DC5A60BDD6944C5BF178941A979EC6A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>fact)</quote> and inserting <quote>fact, or in cases under paragraph (11), $1,000,000 for each such act)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05D7E0EA3DC74E4FAE921153C0FA8C83"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply beginning on January 1, 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD300BB86B4214F1BAD71576B92721B83"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving prescription drug transparency under the Medicaid program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1927(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3DAFA02AB3E64AD8B174FC620475F8A4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">retail</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">covered outpatient drug</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H607BB6D266D54DFABFCB569BB96DA33E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HC18BFF9D57C54E6C9DB1481ECBAC5104"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">retail</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">covered outpatient drug</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69433B2619B04B86918D9B8DD3AA07C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>retail community pharmacy</quote> and inserting <quote>pharmacy that dispenses covered outpatient drugs, including a retail community pharmacy, mail-order pharmacy, specialty pharmacy, nursing home pharmacy, long-term care facility pharmacy, hospital pharmacy, or clinic pharmacy (but not including a charitable pharmacy or a not-for-profit pharmacy)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC607629D6A6A4E26A9573DC6C2D22FAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><clause id="HC6F469F7B21F4509BCD18D86B4BF6399"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text><subclause id="H96881055B45B45779B6291C0D7572D5A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>retail</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H346CF7BD4CB8433BABDD8DADE6EDDB2C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>prescription</quote> and inserting <quote>covered outpatient</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H10484065C8414FF29FEE9A75B26D2A93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>retail community</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD53EB2AD9DC84D4CA8E8B338F8890364"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii), by striking <quote>retail</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1844E7505A704F0B89E8711EB7A50137"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the term <term>retail</term> each place it appears; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFA2043CCE7A4A7D8484AEEC315EC770" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H71DBD4816DE14F42A06441DF0B2825C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H963F7494BE3C4221B582A95612DC4E5C" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Survey reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to meet the requirement of section 1902(a)(54), a State shall require that any pharmacy in the State that receives any payment, reimbursement, administrative fee, discount, rebate, or other price concession related to the dispensing of a covered outpatient drug to an individual receiving benefits under this title, regardless of whether such payment, reimbursement, fee, discount, rebate, or other price concession is received directly from the State or a managed care entity or other specified entity (as such terms are defined in section 1903(m)(9)(D)), or is received indirectly from a pharmacy benefits manager or another entity that has a contract with the State or a managed care entity or other specified entity (as so defined)—</text><clause id="H71BDC3B2F57D434EA7003F631A020F2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall respond to surveys conducted under this paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H6170D11C62DF468C91AEC9F0607E17B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include in each such response the pharmacy’s acquisition price for each such drug, net of all such payments, reimbursements, administrative fees, discounts, rebates, and other price concessions (or, in the case that the pharmacy is unable to determine the net acquisition cost for such a drug at the time that the survey is received, the pharmacy’s negotiated price for such drug).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02699F289A5242AC9A6B42E8A2C7EC43" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Survey information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make information on national drug acquisition prices obtained under this paragraph publicly available. Such information shall include at least the following:</text><clause id="H55C35F3AAE3E420EB7D6F924D573673B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The monthly response rate to the survey, including a list of pharmacies not in compliance with subparagraph (F).</text></clause><clause id="HEEC24C23F40E4D6C91CBF6FEB2D7F507" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The sampling methodology and number of pharmacies sampled monthly.</text></clause><clause id="H8494289D68714011B6116C86E6045770" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Information on price concessions to each pharmacy, including discounts, rebates, and other price concessions, to the extent that such information is available during the survey period.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBABF6C5F45C6492ABC5FAAD36B900B3F"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Limitation on use of applicable non-retail pharmacy pricing information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State shall use pricing information reported by a pharmacy that is not a retail pharmacy to develop or inform reimbursement rates for retail community pharmacies.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

