<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9A9594B1832847C9B93D9610603F04B9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8901 IH: Securing Innovation and Research from Adversaries Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8901</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain federally funded research collaborations with certain foreign entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEB8F1E55CA3E4CEE88671B8041E976DF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB16955772DD04FCFBAAF8F794F722529" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Innovation and Research from Adversaries Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H78131D903D5A48A6B103EED03C2F25D6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on federally funded research relationships with certain foreign entities</header> 
<subsection id="H367C81061287483DB58764717A22D6FB" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds awarded through a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or any other form of Federal financial assistance or other awards issued under other transaction authority (in this section referred to as a <quote>federally funded research award</quote>) may be used by an individual or entity described in subsection (b) to enter into, support, or carry out any research collaboration with either—</text> <paragraph id="HCFF5E8CDB2EC47D6A5C8E6A2B4A6C42C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an entity listed on a United States Government restricted entity list; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD313D77C4A8418AB14FA0BFBBAD5FB2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an individual associated with such an entity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H11C02C61DDB04EA896481ED26B4AF4C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individual or entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual or entity described in this subsection is an individual or entity participating in, receiving, or performing work under a federally funded research award.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC2FF8A8A74546AA9F0DE800459ED2E0">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Guidance</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal research agencies, shall issue government-wide implementation guidance to ensure standardized compliance requirements, definitions, and enforcement mechanisms.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6E6CE79CAC2409C96216ADC865EC94F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver Authority</header> 
<paragraph id="H2BCFF77110D24780A2E54C9F611F303D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of a Federal agency may waive the prohibition under subsection (a), on a case-by-case basis, if such head determines—</text> <subparagraph id="HD3CC255DCE1245099FD954C230797B5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such waiver is necessary to advance the national security interests of the United States; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB155F965143449E4AA7EFAA23F37921E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the research collaboration under subsection (a) that is the subject of such waiver is essential for a clearly defined scientific, public health, or national security purpose that cannot reasonably be achieved without such collaboration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C87D5F64ACD4F9ABE146B242233400D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after granting a waiver under paragraph (1), the head of the Federal agency who so granted such waiver shall submit to Congress a written notification that includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H901F1B59AA634A4BA3A4A09B76FB16D4" commented="no">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>The identity of the individual or entity that is the subject of such waiver.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC97FA5B53D34BA882A806E9949E28C0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The justification for such waiver.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0122ED440EC4733873E127222308EA8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The mitigation measures implemented to protect the national security interests of the United States, if applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H454BD29639034381AA3A11C65091589E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5AD376FD6B1842D892DCBBA55FAF83A5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Research collaboration</header><text>The term <quote>research collaboration</quote> means any activity conducted as part of a federally funded research award, including the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H48811D7D5F3D4383A297417C83C41167" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Joint research activities or projects.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DE57B72767E4FC59B80162F5F1988F2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Co-authorship of scholarly publications, technical reports, or research outputs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFCB0176A82E8472C84567DFBBC32A9ED" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data sharing or processing, material transfer, or exchange of research results, including access to datasets, software, or research infrastructure.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E6A846038D047DEA167CD62EC846212" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Joint laboratories, research centers, or institutes.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA082E468054A471A94FCE946DD25B35A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Personnel exchanges, visiting scholar appointments, or joint supervision of students or researchers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBEC47EB0D538491091C114BDC218D0DF" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any other arrangement determined by the head of the relevant Federal research funding agency to constitute research collaboration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF30BD0164CC448AB99BEF10CA0BA808"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>National Laboratory</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE121FA332AEA47D6BF6FDA026EA6460D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States Government restricted entity lists</header><text>The term <term>United States Government restricted entity list</term> includes the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6DC032AC5813496DA1674FBE01970822"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Commerce Bureau of Industry and Security Entity List (Supplement No. 4 to Part 744 of the Export Administration Regulations).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6BAFB79538247A28D140F136C7467E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of Commerce Bureau of Industry and Security Military End User List.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B7D46AF4BCA4FB4B4800E829736359C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury Office of Foreign Assets Control Specially Designated Nationals List.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F78A054101847E6B334FCCF2357D5AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Denied Persons List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce and described in section 764.3(a)(2) of the Export Administration Regulations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A06C7939B03403EB9C61BB1D5DB63BB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Department of Defense Chinese Military Companies List maintained pursuant to section 1260H of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/113">10 U.S.C. 113</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFA45EC9E59041B884DF6EA912FFBB93"> <enum>(F)</enum> <text>The Debarred Parties List maintained by the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls of the Department of State.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5491CA0CF85B44328334A56F4BB4D1AB"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The list of telecommunications companies of the People’s Republic of China designated under section 889 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>) as posing national security risks to the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H333B9897A56245A99EE307F41200EEA3"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The list of institutions of higher education and other entities determined to be affiliated with, or supporting, the People’s Republic of China’s military-civil fusion strategy maintained pursuant to section 1286 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2358">10 U.S.C. 2358</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD2AFACC9812641F6B8C56379C3AE7D1A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The list of semiconductor companies of the People’s Republic of China and affiliates designated under section 5949 of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/41/4713">41 U.S.C. 4713</external-xref> note) as posing national security risks to the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9844E2347989403E956614E8EFE15243"> <enum>(J)</enum> <text>The Annex to Executive Order (EO) 14032, <quote>Addressing the Threat from Securities Investments That Finance Certain Companies of the People’s Republic of China,</quote> dated June 3, 2021, or superseding Executive order.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BC33FEAB27141D59F5C1884A8DEC9B4"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The list maintained by the Federal Communications Commission of equipment and services covered by section 2 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1601">47 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref>; commonly referred to as the <quote>FCC Covered List</quote>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCD995F5FB6540EA8A6DE2A34B2F76B2" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Any foreign entity included on the Department of Commerce Unverified List.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H083C42FB110547118ECB2CCCB920C796"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act Entity List maintained by the Forced Labor Enforcement Task Force pursuant to section 2(d)(2)(B) of the Uyghur Forced Labor Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/78">Public Law 117–78</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5FFC357050FA4A1B9F893730E4C0FEE0"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The list of biotechnology company of concern pursuant to section 851 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/60">Public Law 119–60</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7EB54ADA62A84DB68326DFB94B2DD5D9"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Any other entity list designated by the President, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, or the Secretary of Defense as restricting or prohibiting transactions with foreign entities for national security, foreign policy, or human rights reasons.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

