<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF86DD4B1FAC4EB08385D32CF6F01C70" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7576 IH: AI Workforce Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7576</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260213">February 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a credit for workforce artificial intelligence training, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F48E52E78C540F9A68023BAED284318" style="OLC"><section id="HEC46DA9A20694052A5E51A9CB06679B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI Workforce Training Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H06DC8BF4DC414F06A93AD34CCC6485DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tax credit for workforce artificial intelligence training</header><subsection id="H57658AFFBAFF432CB8CC6DF37F050A06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of credit</header><paragraph id="HB3049788D54A463EA19F9412202D8E79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H2BE0E96862E04A0F9161F654C98A3F91" style="OLC"><section id="HE0C01E22B252482C90909B5F04521F85"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Credit for workforce artificial intelligence training</header><subsection id="H3CFA82A2249746F0B947C89875E57185"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, the workforce artificial intelligence training credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to 30 percent of the qualified artificial intelligence training expenses of the taxpayer for such taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3C652A07DBA54A018C815B8D2879F063"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Dollar limitation</header><paragraph id="H36875B15F0744754A6E580EBC3EA103D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the credit determined under subsection (a) for any taxpayer for any taxable year shall not exceed $2,500 for each employee of such taxpayer with respect to whom qualified artificial intelligence training expenses are paid or incurred by such taxpayer during such taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA55DD246EDC242ECB3AFA77779C9792D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>In the case of any taxable year beginning after 2026, the dollar amount specified in paragraph (1) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text> <subparagraph id="H8F2D532E0A0545ADAA1B02919FA899EF"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90D4ABB878A044A1958964D00A8D59E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which such taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2025</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75E37158C1C3497EB41ADD7610BD1936"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualified artificial intelligence training expenses</header><paragraph id="H426FC6578B4B48C58B32ABA139A7E126"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified artificial intelligence training expenses</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer, amounts paid or incurred for—</text><subparagraph id="HE19B6528399C442590736386AF469D37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any expenses required for the enrollment or attendance of any employee of such taxpayer at an accredited artificial intelligence training program, including workshops, certificate programs, and courses on prompt engineering, data literacy, machine learning fundamentals, or artificial intelligence ethics,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A2748B5F5D743DE8465469FAA91365F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the wages of any such employee while such employee attends a program, workshop, or course described in paragraph (1), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBBFBD22481C4A3095392AD58D3D8E6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any expenses related to developing or providing in-house artificial intelligence training for any such employee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62C3D1D3E1094503965A26D01A1B65E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>wages</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 3306(b) (determined without regard to any dollar limitation contained in such section).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EEBF07A415449AFADF892B53C4405DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any qualified artificial intelligence training expenses with respect to which credit is allowed under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="HB2C19DBD87CE435B9EE77FF42D9C9CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no other credit or deduction shall be allowed for, or by reason of, any such expense to the extent of the amount of such credit, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F7AA6C7BE1A4A618D38084DB61846EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the basis of any property shall be reduced by the amount of such credit to the extent that such expenses were taken into account in determining such basis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23D6B0F0AF3B4C8D9F2B30245A178935" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations to prevent the abuse of the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1232B9A123E240078F46DF6C874191AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBA41807EDFF64ECAB559A8E4774D2211" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">45BB. Credit for workforce artificial intelligence training.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5961F498CF524202B555445C8550A210"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6CBA862AA8464BC79EF356E4EA2326E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HCE176DE5769146F98FD226EFFCB59653"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the workforce artificial intelligence training credit determined under section 45BB.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF2F473E8F24D4DF6945F48EF7BF50819"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text></subsection></section><section id="H98EDADD951A242748AA1365D2E3A9627" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public outreach campaign; report to Congress</header><subsection id="H7ECF98C2EC9C4C23928E0F6B8855D35C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public outreach campaign</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, Secretary of Labor, and Secretary of Commerce (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretaries</quote>) shall jointly develop and carry out a public outreach campaign to promote the availability of the workforce artificial intelligence training credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45BB">section 45BB</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by section 2. Such campaign shall include the publication of information on such credit, informational webinars for businesses, and distribution of multilingual informational materials through small business development centers, trade associations, and workforce boards.</text></subsection><subsection id="H894CD5B06EAE4103B55157A172777950" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 360 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretaries shall submit to Congress a report on the public outreach campaign carried out under subsection (a) and any measurable outcomes of such campaign.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

