<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3C9C12915C144CF9B107D55019887095" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8292 IH: Original Alternative Data for Additional Credit FHA Pilot Program Reauthorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8292</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize a pilot program under section 258 of the National Housing Act to establish an automated process for providing additional credit rating information for mortgagors and prospective mortgagors under certain mortgages.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC0C825B6093F4750AAD71C8860F065DD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF7DAD533B68A4560B50D57F5B30182CE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Original Alternative Data for Additional Credit FHA Pilot Program Reauthorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H86D193DB7AE74F139FAF8FF28B1C01C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for borrowers without sufficient credit history</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 258 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1715z-24">12 U.S.C. 1715z–24</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H215102AC6D99474C83CA99BD2D4E2EE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H02D801DF40C5471BB3819908B2C22E16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>carry out</quote> and inserting <quote>establish and carry out</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H92AA8D31DE294E81B718C8641DBC240D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>establish, and</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H762CDE360B1040B4ABDFBEC0B8BF041A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>who elect to participate in the pilot program</quote> before the second comma;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFBB215A9D5E54722A8DFD3CF6056401F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>mortgagors and</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4801092A60354214A3AE869EE82CE8AD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>their creditworthiness</quote> the following: <quote>and have opted into the use of additional credit information</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF962AC9FD4084F508BBF1CC39D2CB5D2"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>alternative</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>additional</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65B2F12F4BEA4DA7A2458775F20D649E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding after the period at the end the following: <quote>The pilot program may not be carried out with respect to any mortgagor or prospective mortgagor under a mortgage the proceeds of which are used to prepay or pay off an existing loan secured by the same property.</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED5E7B4EBE9A453F830E4EB9A918382E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD953A836EA97460ABAC1A52131D45AD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) (as amended by paragraph (2) of this subsection) and (d) as subsections (c) and (k), respectively;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H424CB5A07AEC4EFDA78DC4FE07F8C2FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H89EEB656A28C492AB3E1CDC6776FB5FB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H4F6C2461ECA64FA68632A6A20906CA45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The goal of the pilot program under this section shall be to examine and evaluate the benefits of using such a credit scoring model that uses additional data.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA6AF90DDD8264E3AAAE1D8BCE115073B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) (as so redesignated by paragraph (4) of this subsection) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H92E5F99625424F25B7E1F296CFBD24D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H4BCE7568D1ED476286657602EB734943"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Additional credit information</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, after consultation with the Government National Mortgage Association and not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, select one or more commercially available credit scoring models that will be available under the pilot and that utilize additional data, as the Secretary considers appropriate based on the goals of the pilot program. In selecting the model or models to use, the Secretary shall consider the criteria under part 1254 of the regulations of the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency (12 C.F.R. Part 1254) to the extent appropriate.</text>
          </subsection>
<subsection id="H3143526F5E4B4641987F587ADAD16E61"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notification</header>
<paragraph id="H00A7EA3B130C4DCE8FA516779099CBC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop a notice for prospective mortgagors, and require mortgagees to provide such notice to prospective mortgagors, that informs prospective mortgagors of—</text> <subparagraph id="HDD2CD09026C547C6BD696ED365085CEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability to opt into the use of the credit scoring model selected for use under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H84FE74625DC5497480F10F5B9F07606B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on how the pilot program credit scoring model differs from the FHA’s current credit scoring models, including the types of additional data that are included in the pilot program model; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DC481564D5946FC992A2616E8A91DE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing counseling agencies in the area that are approved by the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF1BF10509D9A4EE4A05BEA3AB2AD1D1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comparison of lending options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require mortgagees participating in the pilot program to provide information to prospective mortgagors sufficient to allow comparison of the mortgagor’s lending options using the credit scoring model under the pilot program and using the credit scoring model then in effect for mortgagors not opting into the use of the credit scoring model under the pilot program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA4D28625FD934456AC9BF5538CA6EDBA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Underwriting options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may not be construed to preclude a prospective mortgagor who opts to use an approved credit scoring model under the pilot program under this subsection in connection with underwriting for a mortgage insured under this title from thereafter obtaining a determination of creditworthiness involved in underwriting for such mortgage using information other than that provided under such approved credit scoring model.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HFF35EC9A256F47F4AFA0E56F526983E3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Protection of proprietary information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section may not be construed to require the disclosure or sharing of any proprietary information.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H909E9A15B6D24372B5C014BB22757779"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <paragraph id="HB20B177A96E845D98B9F8D9954A2017F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit reports to the Congress in accordance with paragraph (2) that provide a detailed evaluation of the effectiveness of the pilot, including data that shows—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5B8DFF92CD8A4683A1C54131A75CF46F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of mortgagors who had the option to opt into using additional credit information and the number of mortgagors who opted into using additional credit information;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE085D8A303BB4ADCA0445BEAC2348206"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number and percent of mortgagors who opted into the pilot and were subsequently approved for a mortgage;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3C2D1CE7D07141868B9986074F8B08F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demographic information about mortgagors who opt into using additional credit information, compared to demographic information about mortgagors generally, which shall include race, ethnicity, marital status, sex or gender, geographic location regarding mortgaged properties, and any other information the Secretary deems appropriate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E3D4AE6EB2141F9BDE5DA5D49D520A7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether or not mortgagors with no or thin credit files benefitted from having this option and how;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD794071D62D44A26853539F9A3C09658"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether or not other borrowers who did not have thin or no credit files benefitted from this option and how;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75CF0EA0931E43F28A04F0587E7AE437"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of the additional credit information in predicting mortgage loan default;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H44117545F070474FBE7D6E056EEACFD3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the rate of participation of mortgagees in the pilot program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC70C4F719A3C406CBC69D7C87F1D9433" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether or not the pilot program had an impact on the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund, in general, and specifically whether it had an impact on the economic net worth ratio of the Fund;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H80CDE46C7FF84BBBA86AA63301757E65"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether or not there was sufficient income from the pilot program to offset the risk posed to such Fund by the pilot program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2A141C1CDF6498F89D54B4B7AEE060C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>whether the pilot program had an impact on the ability of other borrowers not participating in the program to obtain the products and services of the FHA; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE1BF8A894A81431787C5965789B1050B"><enum>(K)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary determines relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBBEA929D1384EE1B39FB9C1D3AD3793"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit a report described in paragraph (1)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB804C79D8766432FB1618E18C7B688B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 6 months after the conclusion of the 2-year period beginning on the date on which the Secretary begins accepting the additional credit scores through the pilot program established by the Secretary pursuant to this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE08CF10B9E9F4084B961FF6B1D97F454"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the conclusion of the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Original Alternative Data for Additional Credit FHA Pilot Program Reauthorization Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H043A05A7C58E4BDA9DA9CC21E773D5BE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report on selection of additional credit model</header><text>Not later than the conclusion of the 6-month period that begins upon the conclusion of the 1-year period under subsection (d), the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report explaining why the additional credit scoring model or models selected pursuant to subsection (d) were selected in lieu of other commercially available credit scoring models.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C01FB097191467D8CDECC46AEDA863A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make publicly available in an easily accessible location on the website of the Department—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6D9D7260BCCC42E8B57DB77FFCBE3465"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each report submitted to the Congress pursuant to this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85FD827E440A4A6094D616288A4C05CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information about the pilot program, which shall include an up-to-date listing of mortgagees participating in the pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDE0CD68457D847C18AE04A76F1764ECB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authority To limit participation</header><text>The Secretary may establish a limitation to cap participation in the pilot program under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H473CA115BC784C8693E10030675C0837" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated—</text>
<paragraph id="H042E48F9CB764F1E91BE7F07EA8DDF4E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 for establishing and carrying out the pilot program under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF153B3F621C452689CDE1B51044CCDE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2027 for carrying out the pilot program under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5DA9C1AAD88240738F98823F8B1E830C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (k), as so redesignated by paragraph (4), by striking <quote>5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the Building American Homeownership Act of 2008</quote> and inserting <quote>5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Original Alternative Data for Additional Credit FHA Pilot Program Reauthorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

