<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1D73FA0074F941C4A36D1D3B41B4DF18" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7234 IH: Human Trafficking Awareness Training Recognition Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7234</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260122">January 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a Blue Campaign Certification Program to encourage employers in covered industries to encourage employees to complete training to recognize and respond to suspected human trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDB8C9F4C10BE42CFAB09D08DB56A03CB" style="OLC"><section id="H43C09FB480C64C569B4D60E10B314A39" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Human Trafficking Awareness Training Recognition Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAF8810A2C53546DCB89FE34D856244A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Award</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/231">6 U.S.C. 231 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 434 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7146F24B8609466B858D00F93AA6107B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE25190B35FD240B3B2BE953BCB54A74F"><enum>434A.</enum><header>Blue Campaign Certification Program</header><subsection id="H592135A4272143F08FE98747E63239BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a Blue Campaign Certification Program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to encourage efforts by employers in covered industries to encourage employees to complete training to recognize and respond to suspected human trafficking. The Secretary shall provide a certificate of completion to eligible employers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F78CB83BF324007BD203C8E790124FF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application process</header><paragraph id="H24538CAD71494D8F8D726EAC63F1F5AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Solicitation of applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During each year in which the Secretary provides a certificate of completion, the Secretary shall solicit applications, beginning not later than January 31 and ending not earlier than April 30, from employers to consider whether such employers should receive such certificate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80C07CDAC9624E3DAF323B50F02AEF95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review of applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of Homeland Security Investigations, shall review each application received in a year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC37FCBCF6CF04AA0B3ED2C2954EE5DB9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of applications</header><text>The Secretary shall require each employer who submits an application to provide in such application—</text><subparagraph id="HD0C4C15BD2FD401A8CD32672A216D98B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information about the training to recognize and respond to suspected human trafficking that such employer provided to the employees of such employer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D7A344AFFE44CA6AC4BD860E059D5DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EFD637ACB5A49D7A505B1600D96165F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recognition of recipients</header><paragraph id="H707638924DDD499ABF66023984D08811"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuance of awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide a certificate of completion to each employer whom the Secretary determines is eligible. The certificate of completion shall state that the recipient may display such certificate for a 1-year period beginning on the date on which such certificate is provided.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7905C690EEF4886AAD30A356F6FFAA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice in Federal Register</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall recognize each such recipient through publication in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BC058C12FB94120BDC94CA959C4A997"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibited display</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is prohibited for any employer to publicly display a Blue Campaign Certification of Completion—</text><paragraph id="HF7D316B830254245BCB8CDDCAA2EAEBF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purpose of conveying, or in a manner reasonably calculated to convey, a false impression that the employer completed the Blue Campaign Certification Program, if such employer did not complete such Program; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3313A37F0A064776B2353044BFC8B049"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purpose of conveying, or in a manner reasonably calculated to convey, a false impression that the employer received a certificate of completion through the Blue Campaign Certification Program for a year for which such employer did not receive such certificate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D53A05E8B2F49689CEF66B543A0590D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During each year beginning not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, a report on the Program, including—</text><paragraph id="H010572F8C7A547A5963EA9983261BEFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of employers who submitted an application for Blue Campaign Certification in the prior year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E822D2BCC724227B8046C189FD7CF7B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the fees collected under subsection (f) from such employers, and any changes in fees to be proposed in the present year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03865D9DADF94B2A90606B7EF73FFC5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of Blue Campaign Certifications of Completion provided in the prior year, including the name of each employer to whom a Blue Campaign Certification of Completion was awarded;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F6600AFD155432BA3581095AFEB32FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the cost of administering the Program in the prior year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF59A174D75ED4405BAF0C2BD8093E3C4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other matter the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAA418AA94274BF4ADB893B2B3F3089F" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization for application fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to establish a reasonable fee to be imposed on employers submitting applications for a Blue Campaign Certification of Completion to cover the cost of carrying out the Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A66293576004F76ABBE4C9CAD52F171"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H654F7C7ADD9D49EAB1BF1A71B29EDA1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered industry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered industry</term> means any industry that the Secretary has determined—</text><subparagraph id="HBC249A0019CE49C48A739B2BD6BBFE14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a relatively high prevalence of human trafficking; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2CF4B203217419B99663A6AD3FB0D70"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that human trafficking awareness training could have a significant impact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71FE3AB2305E4D8498801BF347FA7A87"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employer</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>), except that such term does not include a public agency (as defined in such section 3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9A47119EE4840AE90A6ED6C097E38F8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Human trafficking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>human trafficking</term> has the meaning given the term <term>severe forms of trafficking in person</term> in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2592E3DB2BF94B7EB3E8EE81C1A47CCC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary of Homeland Security</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Blue Campaign.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62FB641855B64D7CA1475E3668E2A1FD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>training</term> means the training to recognize and respond to suspected human trafficking.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H16FF50536E124C81B7CB73AB6A6C16CF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Blue Campaign</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 434(e) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/242">6 U.S.C. 242(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB272073003664ECDA843A36DB602C95B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2F5A75980EC4A09AEFF66D6094627B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (8) as paragraph (9); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H028BC1A58F424F18BA5DE9DED492D42F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (7) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0146308D9B134AD6837E7B7B67B89B18" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H791113137960489EA0F033D76716C306"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increased coordination with experts from the private sector, academic institutions, and other covered industries (as such term is defined in section 434A).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

