<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25769-2T7-R4-26T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 429 ATS: Designating September 2025 as “National Infant Mortality Awareness Month”, raising awareness of infant mortality, and increasing efforts to reduce infant mortality.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 429</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250930">September 30, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating September 2025 as <quote>National Infant Mortality Awareness Month</quote>, raising awareness of infant mortality, and increasing efforts to reduce infant mortality.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the term <term>infant mortality</term> refers to the death of a baby before the first birthday of the baby;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States ranks 33rd out of the 38 countries in the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) for infant mortality rate, with 5.4 deaths per 1,000 live births;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas high rates of infant mortality are especially prevalent in African American, Native American, Alaskan Native, Latino, Asian, and Hawaiian and other Pacific Islander communities, communities with high rates of unemployment and poverty, and communities with limited access to medical providers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas premature birth and low birth weight are leading causes of infant mortality;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States spends nearly twice as much on health care as other OECD countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas infant mortality can be substantially reduced through community-based services, such as outreach, home visitation, care coordination, health education, interconceptional care, and paternal involvement;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas support for community-based programs to reduce infant mortality may result in lower future spending on medical interventions, special education, and other social services that may be needed for infants and children born with a low birth weight;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Health and Human Services has implemented the Newborn Supply Kit program;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Pregnancy Risk Assessment Monitoring System (PRAMS) provides information that is vital to addressing preterm birth rates and conditions that put babies at risk;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Maternal and Child Health Bureau Healthy Start program has invested in communities facing high rates of infant mortality and maternal illness to improve health outcomes before, during, and after pregnancy;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Advisory Committee on Infant Mortality provides advice and recommendations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services on improving the health status of infants and pregnant women and on a national strategy for reducing infant mortality;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Secretary of Health and Human Services is encouraged to partner with educational institutions and States to increase maternal health and infant health initiatives; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public awareness and education campaigns on infant mortality are held during the month of September each year: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id1B5C916FE2C4471DAA3CC3126C4675C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates September 2025 as <quote>National Infant Mortality Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f4ee03468a74c03a9efa15cb8f402b8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports efforts—</text><subparagraph id="id321C1DE356974CC89FD7E0C334AB9385"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to educate people in the United States about infant mortality and the factors that contribute to infant mortality; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF5695DB4B63147DEB93C60B30D3BA93D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to reduce infant deaths, low birth weight, pre-term births, and disparities in perinatal outcomes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBA99DA74ED1E4802A5A7FE53D97ED123"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the critical importance of including efforts to reduce infant mortality and the factors that contribute to infant mortality as part of prevention and wellness strategies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id92E44FCAF7D846AE955921DA43138188"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to observe National Infant Mortality Awareness Month with appropriate programs and activities.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

