<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5740E8B275094EB794CA26F7EFA38480" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7483 IH: Dual Hatting Limitation Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7483</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain senior Federal officers or acting officers from carrying out the duties of other Federal positions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB22C74B48ADD41A7BE0297BEF685D3C8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBEF754BCFF74429894F06C913DED5133" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dual Hatting Limitation Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD377F94FC89A47AC9390E676EFC7809C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain officers and acting officers from carrying out duties of other Federal positions</header> 
<subsection id="H9C01AB425360495987DF4E790056ECED" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Director of Office of Personnel Management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1102(c) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0597487834414C899E02C321378D0302"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>Director or</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1DF9AC058CFC469195E1317278AEEF36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after the period at the end the following: <quote>The Director, or any other individual occupying a position in the civil service performing the functions and duties of the office of the Director temporarily in an acting capacity, may not occupy, or carry out the functions or duties of, any other position in the Federal Government.</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2A33254F27A74C1ABF6CCC882FCD08E9"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Special Counsel</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1211(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the last sentence and inserting the following: <quote>The Special Counsel, or any other individual occupying a position in the civil service performing the functions and duties of the office of the Special Counsel temporarily in an acting capacity, may not occupy, or carry out the functions or duties of, any other position in the Federal Government.</quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E434F1E22BC40E8B05E266CCCCD4B25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director of Office of Government Ethics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13121(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Director, or any other individual occupying a position in the civil service performing the functions and duties or of the office of the Director temporarily in an acting capacity, may not occupy, or carry out the functions or duties of, any other position in the Federal Government.</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0F240A4A9DB24EE5BE8739D4B8D4EA79"><enum>(d)</enum><header>NARA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2103(c) of title 44, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Archivist, or any other individual occupying a position in the civil service performing the functions and duties of the office of the Archivist temporarily in an acting capacity, may not occupy, or carry out the functions or duties of, any other position in the Federal Government.</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEBF24275F0B4F1CBEB96D868727EAB6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal vacancies</header><text>Section 3345(a) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HB0216D5F9711483C80D42C62B0616583" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HA4014FD746B34D6A9F1CB4BD52232464"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a), the President may not direct under either such paragraph any individual to perform the functions and duties of a vacant office temporarily in an acting capacity if such individual is performing the functions and duties of any other office temporarily in an acting capacity.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H167E6F7D68304496A9EB5C89AD9366D4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Positions under level I of Executive Schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual occupying a position listed under level I of the Executive Schedule (section 5312 of title 5, United States Code), or any other individual occupying a position in the civil service performing the functions and duties of the office of such position temporarily in an acting capacity, may not occupy, or carry out the functions or duties of, any other position in the Federal Government.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

