<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ26319-1DN-8D-FX7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4529 IS: Build Nuclear with Local Materials Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to allow the use of commercial-grade steel and concrete in non-safety-related structures at nuclear power plants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section id="idb30990bbfd3c44ffb4f1d630eae6c3ba" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Build Nuclear with Local Materials Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id335034bc6fd2462187182a0a338a5143"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of commercial-grade steel and concrete</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ae7557887c64457aa281879c4a39a69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (referred to in this section as the <quote>Commission</quote>) shall initiate a rulemaking that authorizes the use of commercial-grade steel and concrete in non-safety-related structures at nuclear power plants, unless, subject to subsection (b), the Commission determines that stricter material standards are necessary to address a specific safety risk.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb7168378be643c0a6d994f59be5df7e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may make a determination under subsection (a) that stricter material standards are necessary to address a specific safety risk if the Commission determines that not using a stricter material standard would be contrary to the common defense and security and adequate protection of the public health and safety (within the meaning of section 182 a. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2232">42 U.S.C. 2232(a)</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

