<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEDB37F3C0F45454F94876CD5E5A1C92B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1429 IH: Expressing support for continued efforts to safeguard the supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 from fraud, waste, and abuse for the Nation’s most vulnerable.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1429</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for continued efforts to safeguard the supplemental nutrition assistance program under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 from fraud, waste, and abuse for the Nation&#8217;s most vulnerable.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the supplemental nutrition assistance program (commonly known as SNAP) is a largely federally funded, State-run program that is overseen by the Food and Nutrition Administration, which operates out of the Department of Agriculture;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas SNAP is the largest Federal nutrition assistance program in the United States and is designed primarily to increase the food purchasing power of eligible low-income individuals and families;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, to administer SNAP, the Department of Agriculture spends nearly $235,000,000 per day;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in order to ensure those who are the most vulnerable in the Nation are the ones rightfully receiving benefits, it is the duty of Congress to end all fraud within the program;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, over a year ago, the Trump administration requested all SNAP data from States in order to ensure those receiving assistance are not being defrauded by criminal actors;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 29 States shared their data with the Department of Agriculture, but 21 States have sued the Department to keep their SNAP fraud data hidden from the American people;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Secretary Rollins of the Department of Agriculture has reported several eye-opening figures in the 29 States that have shared their SNAP fraud data, which does not even include the data from the 21 other States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, from the 29 States that shared their data, the Department of Agriculture reported that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H17B9FF0660594E55A658769FF6D502DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>186,000 recipients who are deceased continue to receive benefits;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H782230EC442B4218980C9363FC56CA21"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 440,000 recipients of SNAP use Social Security numbers that are not theirs or a family member’s;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F11FB27381C4B20A54445CA13D5A1E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 247,000 individuals were receiving benefits in multiple States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6DEA15E2357451CBB0199C184C25253"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 4,400 individuals had been flagged as disqualified participants but were still receiving benefits;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the removal of fraud is in the best interest of the taxpayer, as the Department of Agriculture reported that individuals receiving fraudulent benefits total nearly $3,000,000,000, which could be redirected to those most in need;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, from October 1, 2025, to March 31, 2026, the Department of Agriculture Office of the Inspector General’s work resulted in a total dollar impact of more than $1,000,000,000, resulting in cost savings and recoveries of more than $21.02 for every dollar invested;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas just one individual stole $19,700,000 from a program meant to feed Missouri children;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas States should also work to decrease improper payments, which the Government Accountability Office found to be over $10,000,000,000 within SNAP in fiscal year 2025;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in fiscal year 2025, the average State payment error rate was over 10 percent; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Congress should continue to consider items that give transparency to the American people and bring integrity back into SNAP: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H24F116067244463A8E8A2DAF5C18F187"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H2B9DC6557ABC40D4BBF7D5CD3CD36F57"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H64005536E7E049DBABA63C187A8C7B6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for continued efforts by the Trump administration to identify, prevent, and prosecute waste, fraud, abuse, and improper payments in the supplemental nutrition assistance program (SNAP);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAD4EA59518041569D44E15C697F63AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applauds the Trump administration’s efforts to counter SNAP fraudsters and crack down on criminal actors hurting the Nation’s most vulnerable;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDB7E17C0216459E87556D57B6F9FE66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of strong program integrity measures to safeguard taxpayer dollars and preserve resources for the most vulnerable Americans;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC3D59E2912C48559852A3C9552DF406"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports efforts to improve oversight and transparency within SNAP to ensure the program is working effectively for those eligible; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2F17E7ABEF84D6494E8FCD90DA83B2E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>affirms that reducing waste, fraud, and abuse is essential to the long-term sustainability and effectiveness of SNAP.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

