<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HA81A82EA911D45298BC4909BFD6D9718" resolution-type="house-joint" key="H"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 126 IH: A joint resolution to direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities that have not been authorized by Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">1st Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 126</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20250919">September 19, 2025</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">A joint resolution to direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities that have not been authorized by Congress.</official-title> 
</form> 
<resolution-body id="H704DBC791D354972B664483A9D582A2B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFE10A9F853304F038DA02C530CDE67C2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HBD7C92C30A7A43478C56EE6EA878BB1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under Article I, section 8, clause 11 of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BFE31D0878B44D0A310D9333F17DFB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war upon, nor enacted a specific statutory authorization for use of military force against—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7F982223E974A26868FEE9DE2DED69E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any organization designated on or after February 20, 2025, as a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189(a)</external-xref>) or as a specially designated global terrorist pursuant to Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FBC758D1C5445F58410FFAB14C3D424"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any states in which those entities operate; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC99FE36983A54B55ABEE2C53B0558878"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any non-state organization engaged in the promotion, trafficking, and distribution of illegal drugs and other related activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABC8C7C0BA924877BCBBBE45F9E2792D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The designation of an entity as a foreign terrorist organization or specially designated global terrorist provides no legal authority for the President to use force against members of designated organizations or any foreign state.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FBFAB7B3BFA454CADACA59DA0F37CDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>There has been no armed attack on the United States by—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H681E8B7B2DA541AE82F2D3AEC003B649"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any organization designated on or after February 20, 2025, as a foreign terrorist organization or specially designated global terrorist;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C4BD62DE69641D6B1AD55464E15C8B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any states in which those entities operate; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2DAB69A78964DE0B8BCAE8D813FDEE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any non-state organization engaged in the promotion, trafficking, and distribution of illegal drugs and other related activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1679A7BCD1C94B9D8CC025F95EF99683"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The United States military strike on a vessel on September 2, 2025, and the subsequent United States military strike on a vessel on September 15, 2025, constitute, within the meaning of section 4(a) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1543">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)</external-xref>), either hostilities or a situation where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances into which United States Armed Forces have been introduced. The application of the War Powers Resolution is without prejudice as to whether the strikes themselves violated United States domestic law, international humanitarian law, or international human rights law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD403F78077C74CF9A6597F72AD29B1F6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Congress has not received sufficient information regarding—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12D0752C3273441BA73818D9A5CB7ED3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the vessels' passengers, cargo, or affiliation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF50589E7250D48D4A26F8F2AAF57F0C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the vessels' intended destinations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H816B23E2D93845388D9A9C2D74805F9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any threats the vessels posed to United States interests;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0F5D9C8A9A0249E0B5A06F580691AA5F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any justification for the use of lethal force against the vessels;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD22557BE8A664117A3D409E15C38665C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the availability of non-lethal means to interdict the vessels; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CAC313D92C14661A7293FAFEE4910E8"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the purported domestic authority or international legal basis to conduct the strikes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H349A6C5118C94B1AB67D8DF89FCEB2E6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>), provides that any joint resolution or bill to require the removal of United States Armed Forces engaged in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures of section 601(b) of the International Security and Arms Control Export Act of 1976.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75DAAE64497446D799BEFB2912DFF0E8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Congress is resolved to provide resources and authorities to the executive branch to prevent and mitigate drug and narcotics trafficking into the United States, including through the use of intelligence, law enforcement, personnel, and detection technology at and between ports of entry and diplomatic and military tools as appropriate to deter, prevent, and prosecute illicit drug and narcotics trafficking, and will consider providing additional resources and authorities if they are requested by the President to combat the spread of illegal drugs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6791415588F4C928F6C16EE8FC11C13"><enum>(9)</enum><text>On September 4, 2025, the President formally notified Congress of the September 2, 2025, strike, noted the potential for further military strikes, and stated that <quote>it is not possible at this time to know the full scope and duration of military operations that will be necessary</quote> to address the continuing threat of drug trafficking emanating from unspecified countries by unspecified organizations.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0DC6C6ED7EB46F79C1E7601468EFC33"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of use of Armed Forces</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H638B703C6523454CAAABEFCD952B8545"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Termination</header><text>Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) and in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976, Congress hereby directs the President to terminate the use of United States Armed Forces for hostilities against any organization designated on or after February 20, 2025, as a foreign terrorist organization or specially designated global terrorist, any states in which those entities operate, or any non-state organization engaged in the promotion, trafficking, and distribution of illegal drugs and other related activities, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or specific authorization for use of military force.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC0348DC38EA4E78A7A65F3A0F941AA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as preventing the United States from defending itself from an armed attack or threat of an imminent armed attack or using the United States Armed Forces in support of civil authorities as part of authorized counternarcotics operations. The trafficking of illegal drugs does not itself constitute such an armed attack or threat of an imminent armed attack.</text></subsection></section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution> 


