<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC45AEAD3C36A40019C992F95405A0CAD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7735 IH: Improving Mental Health Support for Servicemembers and Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7735</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260226">February 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee to assess the effectiveness of certain mental health activities of the Departments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB934002B7C6241C39ABC03372119E496" style="OLC"><section id="H851B123C7833424992A59033A685C9DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Mental Health Support for Servicemembers and Veterans Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H9B01E4C5A3334A999DE3F230C99492EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessments by the Department of Veterans Affairs–Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee of certain mental health activities</header><subsection id="H19B0E4AA5B744999AA0E73051E7163CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Overall inventory, assessment, and report</header><paragraph id="H1ABC36A7713F478988F9675B76765017"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inventory and assessment</header><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs–Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee under section 320 of title 38, United States Code, shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE5A9CA25ACC34A49A171C6B66B3163A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complete an inventory of the programs and processes of the Departments that facilitate access to mental health services across the transition spectrum; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50BCC9A408114B4F8F085B495CB8FDDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of the overall effectiveness of such programs and processes in facilitating access to such services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9439F3D9B2BE477DA642131A19C419A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Joint Executive Committee shall submit to the Committees on Veterans Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the results of the assessment. The report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H3A5F7CCE26F3470CBB4FEF0AF4F30390"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the inventory under paragraph (1)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81C0AD07892A40EFA3A1664FA53A4F18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the results of the assessment under paragraph (1)(B), including whether the assessment identified any deficiencies, gaps, or inefficiencies (such as duplicative programs);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC36961EAD1149A7AC7EF855E44AE9DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations to address the identified deficiencies, gaps, or inefficiencies, if any, including plans of action, milestones, and metrics; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H051C525FF9EC4054821668ADE070EA9C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other information or recommendations that the Joint Executive Committee considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12AE68E24AF144989A6C39F1FD30F072"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Biennial review of the joint separation health assessment</header><text>Section 320(d) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HBBCA5C00B0444189B4ADD4DFEA097FA4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H672ADFC8489641A986C711D73DA8FEB7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review, at least once every two years, the joint separation health assessment to validate the questions posed by the assessment and to recommend whether any questions should be removed, revised, or added.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

