<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB9A75CCA486B4002871B4B1EAD9DCAFF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9632 IH: Accelerating Innovation (AI) for Kids with Cancer Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9632</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260709">July 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To better coordinate Federal efforts to utilize advance technologies, such as AI, to improve diagnoses, treatments, cures, and prevention strategies for pediatric cancer, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C1C32E859D841F4956B96036AC65D48" style="OLC"><section id="H272A96D1FD4947358E0C606537AA9732" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerating Innovation (AI) for Kids with Cancer Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1A64AB46DC0D4A2081CC9F5015B1A3D2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Harnessing United States AI innovation to treat and cure pediatric cancer</header><subsection id="HBDF4ADB15E3F4B99B23D059011EC58B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall appoint an individual or entity to serve as the coordinator of Federal efforts to utilize advance technologies, such as AI, to improve diagnoses, treatments, cures, and prevention strategies for pediatric cancer. Such individual or entity shall be known as the Coordinator of AI Innovation (in this section referred to as the <quote>Coordinator</quote>). The Coordinator shall serve as a member of the Domestic Policy Council. </text></subsection><subsection id="H564B3F13421A4354A7D06DBEB78B2400"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of CCDI opportunities</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Coordinator shall identify opportunities to accelerate the progress of AI-driven solutions at the Childhood Cancer Data Initiative (in this section referred to as the <quote>CCDI</quote>), including—</text><paragraph id="H934DAEA992904455820D3F751763A572"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by improving clinical trial design and access through incorporating AI approaches;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B77D158EA3E4D1EA6C1515DC0F05E18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by making data platforms and tools available as part of the CCDI Data Ecosystem; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11FB15E3A83B4569A4B9758D6EA03D30"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by improving data infrastructure through consolidating data from multiple sources for AI-ready analysis and through utilizing AI to better select participants for clinical trials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4CE87952DDA4216A007B57FAA1310BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by enhancing data analysis through integration with AI tools—</text><subparagraph id="HC72DCC4BC0E7433183682FA42EE9E519"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to improve predictive modeling of patient response, disease progression, and treatment toxicity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD4C6A395C964708B752429AA1353C58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to turn multi-omics data and imaging data into novel diagnostic, prognostic, and therapeutic biomarkers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F9FE4EC11247998900EF542A1DCF30"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by improving clinical trial design, access, and outcomes for patients by incorporating multimodal data and using AI approaches.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1640FE66D4EF4142B904E61474510119" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Improving data sharing and empowering patients</header><paragraph id="HC0F0A6DF96C04817B78B920251055120"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Integration of AI innovation into current work on interoperability</header><text>The Secretary shall work to ensure that AI innovation is appropriately integrated into current work on interoperability to maximize the potential for electronic health records and claims data to inform private sector and academic research and clinical trial design, while ensuring that individuals (or authorized representatives) control their health information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE609C2A1A7C48FF905EF3B3C75568BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interoperability standards for patient data to be used with AI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><italic></italic>The Secretary shall work to finalize interoperability standards for patient data to be used with AI that—</text><subparagraph id="H2CCEF98E8CDB492BA35FB26D4BDE7366"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appropriately account for structured and unstructured data; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H725D925876534CE3888A616D40F70FD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enable safe and privacy-compliant exchanges of data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0DF246E9765493997FE5C1CB3BDBA8E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF3796C919D34F25AC04551A15CF133A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD79ABD2A198043B08578A5790D72F953"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence; AI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>artificial intelligence</term> and <term>AI</term> have the meaning given the term <term>artificial intelligence</term> in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AF89DD7CAAB42B489B77A71C1A6AD58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC7CF0BE05DD149D6B43E18CA3F37DD8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H653B2EB38F8C44EE94D0D5A51462C422"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC72B52DAF9204A218666710C88CA66F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A205972BD1340228C7248E50BC76594"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2779D7614C2147E6958ED57ADA40FAF2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H3E22A343EF5E4B83AC6F71613FF2206B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such funds as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4D36998F7B544C08883CFFA3869C02D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>CCDI</header><text>In addition to amounts made available to carry out this section under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, there is authorized to be appropriated to carry out subsection (b), $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

