<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3037C481C604234BD8EB4DADE315B85" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8932 IH: Hate Crimes Commission Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8932</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a United States Commission on Hate Crimes to study and make recommendations on the prevention of the commission of hate crimes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD208C6409EB14CF3AA4774A0CADBBD52" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H1EF8ADCE5D1347509C43FDACB1AE3C5A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hate Crimes Commission Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCDC4ACB7B81E47749775F9C3004D630A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7946FD137567486EA6F1E4C9378C1569"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Bureau of Investigation (referred to in this section as the <quote>FBI</quote>) defines a hate crime as a criminal offense, such as murder, arson, or vandalism, against a person or property motivated in whole or in part by an offender’s bias against a race, color, national origin, religion, disability, sexual orientation, ethnicity, gender, or gender identity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H268B8F0CA51D4A41ABD5AA6C79A95A32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Forty-six States and the District of Columbia have statutes criminalizing various types of bias-motivated violence or intimidation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D4A8AC865E74E2D8168CB675E186A9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress has enacted various statutes to address hate crimes since 1968, with the most recent statute, the COVID–19 Hate Crimes Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/113">Public Law 117–113</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 265), enacted in 2021.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8A104E7A9E74D20899748ECF39564E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2024, the FBI reported 11,323 single-bias incidents, involving 13,768 victims.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D6C258587DE4789AC9E88E54FFC734E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Hate crimes not only damage the individual victim or victims but also traumatize entire communities and erode public confidence in their safety.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57D471E4C1644CEBA46EEB34C66FECC9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 2024—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE8262036B31448F2A4F86C82DDCA550F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>53.2 percent of victims were targeted because of the offender’s race, ethnicity, or ancestry bias;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H092EA0CF2C284D0B9274A612322505ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>23.5 percent of victims were targeted because of the offender’s religious bias;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C3CE42D9F8B4864B89DF78B6FC15FB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>17.2 percent of victims were targeted because of the offender’s sexual orientation bias;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED585C9D1DC349FBB5738BD01AE8261C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>3.9 percent of victims were targeted because of the offender’s gender identity bias;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC046B7512004015BA25EA8AD6DC529A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>1.3 percent of victims were targeted because of the offender’s disability bias; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8233F055D7447728F2EDD164A5A25BB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>0.9 percent of victims were targeted because of the offender’s gender bias.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD15AF20C613D4459832C61618316F231"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In testimony before the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives in September 2020, FBI Director Christopher Wray said, <quote>Within the domestic terrorism bucket, the category as a whole, racially motivated violent extremism is, I think, the biggest bucket within that larger group. And within the racially motivated violent extremist bucket, people subscribing to some kind of white supremacist-type ideology is certainly the biggest chunk of that.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C5816D617D6421ABAC6594C7EC5EE86"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In August 2012, a shooting at the gurdwara in Oak Creek, Wisconsin, left 6 people dead, and a seventh victim of the shooting succumbed to his injuries in 2020.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE67FFA4D7B040AC98CF03B6C7695EB4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In June 2016, a shooting at Pulse, an LGBTQ+ nightclub in Orlando, Florida, left 49 people dead and an additional 53 people wounded.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1217E70E2FC42FC90F7D3DEBFCE864A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In October 2018, a shooting at the Tree of Life synagogue in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, left 11 people dead.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H289588AA868C4A0385F1BDAA980218C9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In July 2019, a Hindu priest in New York City was hospitalized after a man attacked him and screamed <quote>this is my neighborhood</quote> during the incident.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H629071CDFE5C4F15ADD0863C2EA96AF1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In August 2019, an assailant entered a Walmart in El Paso, Texas, to target Hispanic immigrants and left 22 people dead.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD5A847237A040D8B8B392ECB7CA12EB"><enum>(13)</enum><text>In November 2020, a woman shouted anti-Muslim slurs and attacked a couple in New York City, leaving one victim needing surgery for facial fractures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD95E255F555742D595264B5ABDF149D3"><enum>(14)</enum><text>In March 2021, a gunman targeted 3 spas across Atlanta, Georgia, killing 8 people, 6 of whom were Asian women.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBCFFEE96C9904530A67E8134371D824D"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In May 2022, a gunman injured 3 people after entering a Korean-owned business in Dallas, Texas, and firing 13 rounds before fleeing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B9B448BA9604160A875943182CDCAF0"><enum>(16)</enum><text>In May 2022, a gunman targeted a Tops supermarket located in a predominantly Black neighborhood in Buffalo, New York, killing 10 people and injuring 3 others. Of the 13 victims, 11 were Black.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60B16E5E793543129FEC1786212F5C5C"><enum>(17)</enum><text>In November 2022, a gunman killed 5 people and wounded 25 others after opening fire on an LGBTQ+ nightclub in Colorado Springs, Colorado.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5577192C5F984D98B144688F90D57FF2"><enum>(18)</enum><text>In response to the COVID–19 pandemic, Asian Americans have suffered an increasing number of hate crimes. According to Stop AAPI Hate, nearly 11,500 <quote>hate incidents</quote> toward Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders were reported between March 2020 and March 2022.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13E709728883408996973FE3BD062C28"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The Anti-Defamation League (commonly known as the <quote>ADL</quote>) annually surveys and reports anti-Semitic hate incidents across the country. In 2024, the ADL reported a 344-percent increase in anti-Semitic incidents over the previous 5 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H259F74F66DE8455D92B43B07839A868C"><enum>(20)</enum><text>In the original 2021 Hate Crime Statistics published by the FBI in December 2022, the FBI acknowledged the significant discrepancy in reporting from local law enforcement agencies as a result of transitioning to the National Incident-Based Reporting System. Due to the lack of reporting by local enforcement agencies, the FBI acknowledged that the 2021 Hate Crime Statistics cannot be compared reliably across years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H079EB6D3123F44EA87D0FDF89ED0B738"><enum>(21)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In March 2023, the FBI released supplemental data for the 2021 Hate Crime Statistics consisting of data collected through the Summary Reporting System by local law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5527F393EFFD438FBAD889E8B37C88A3"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Law enforcement organizations have consistently recognized the need to modernize nationwide crime reporting and related data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B8841861E144BA4BD5DE40676D1F7BD"><enum>(23)</enum><text>There is a clear need for stronger action to accurately report and effectively combat hate-based attacks.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H57078B52FE0D40F8874563FDA6F6A6DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of Commission</header> <subsection id="H2B9C560A24DD46CA92A6BD9C86988600"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>civil rights community</term> means nonprofit organizations that—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE908AC47246846BAB363230C84FA4C99"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage in documentation, reporting, or analysis of hate crimes or bias-motivated incidents; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD81D802F5D046DC8793574D3AAFDEFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide legal services or public education relating to civil rights or discrimination.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE3491DCDB654F2494217625B032EB26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the United States Commission on Hate Crimes (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H327ADA2F27B84036A3BCEAB8176503A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C5164915E7644F08C0229F1EC35B454"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Size of Commission</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 10 members.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38FDE1A63D7142DABD7A417020E9B80C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Commission shall be appointed in accordance with the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB7501A3B9BBF4C6F963BB24683299895"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23794AFED0F94E8A8D46D7544172CA59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1524AEA14A554F2DB133CAF0432AE5BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7B417F3E5384C9FB0D9119C2A562D79"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H296DC2E0557644D38CCF6D422FE8EBAC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Two members shall be appointed by the Attorney General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C128D95EFE74D6B8009088D43B2BE99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB00EBB56FE674B3485C594259187BC1A"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Background</header><text>Not more than 5 members of the Commission may be from the law enforcement community and not more than 5 members of the Commission may be from the civil rights community.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AADC0724E0F43588B419D96DC38EBF2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Government officials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member of Congress or any other elected Federal, State, or local government official may not serve as a member of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9445661B43D2463E91645747582CBA8C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be appointed not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7736716C0CF34A0BB5061C93189F622D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F75FDDA3FDF475D94E5C3E43D277E0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First meeting</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADE31FB01245488781DDCF9CFF291D5C"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall hold its first meeting not later than 90 days after the date as of which all members of the Commission have been appointed under subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFFE567E73EC453F8F950010D26834C0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During its first meeting, the Commission shall develop a schedule for completion of the investigation and report required under section 4.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DFEF503903B4FCCBE88F2AED84074BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent meetings</header><text>After the initial meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall meet bimonthly until the Commission terminates under section 5.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD8E8CF9320D143399C3B526D7F6D5AB3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of the Commission</header> 
<subsection id="HEC803EAD9A424AA5B4FF24B2ADBFB7C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>hate crime</term> means an offense under section 249 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCEFF2BC27C8C4BBCBE5D95E273D84030"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>The Commission shall investigate the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H592B0C4246E9423189A5168F3D56D99F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The factors, including social media and technology, that have contributed to the consistently high rate of hate crime incidents across the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0971151242EC4EAEB23B9E3D3CD29AF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Policies or actions that law enforcement agencies might adopt or engage in to reduce the commission of hate crimes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C0C931BA30C42B19E956546FF3E3D64"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The impact of underreporting on hate crimes statistics and hate crimes prevention.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9067905B641C43A1AEBC859B932D1AB6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ways to improve hate crimes reporting and ensure full and complete participation in the National Incident-Based Reporting System by local law enforcement agencies, including by identifying any barriers that may deter such reporting.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD7535F6A9AF34F2A95E54B7752E8CA7D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bias prevention efforts and responses to hate crimes that are successful and possible through coordination with nonprofit organizations, local education agencies, and government entities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1339B2E51ACC4890B0A6EE9B72823E8B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The prevalence and rise of online hate crime incidents.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3413BB994C464EAD8F781F6E64F0CA29"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date as of which all members of the Commission have been appointed under section 3(c)(2), the Commission shall publish and submit to Congress and the President a report that sets forth the results of the investigation conducted under subsection (b) of this section, including recommendations for—</text> <paragraph id="HB991A2A3C85D48489C4DFE566F285AD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actions Federal agencies can take to help improve hate crimes reporting by local law enforcement agencies, as described in subsection (b)(4); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7A477919F5E401889D8AF753026B432" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>bias prevention efforts and responses to hate crimes, as described in subsection (b)(5).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2B21A31E4B4F4104A3A9CC9CEA61FE72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies and other entities</header><text>Any department, agency, bureau, board, commission, office, or other instrumentality of the United States shall directly provide to the Commission, upon request, any documents, statistical data, or other information the Commission determines necessary to carry out its duties under this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD140DA45F14D45AABD15D9207A7761AA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate on the date that is 90 days after the date on which the Commission publishes and submits to Congress and the President the report under section 4(c).</text></section> <section id="HBA774160242149B5B796695B0B5EEBEC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office audit</header> <subsection id="H6567AE33E0914B4AA353AEE119ED5B01"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE3383D298333423FB290492D264FB808"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B83616663A94C36A2C1961F871FFB08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Zero-reporting agency</header><text>The term <term>zero-reporting agency</term> means any State, local, or Tribal law enforcement agency that reports zero hate crimes in a calendar year to the National Incident-Based Reporting System of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB9EACDE3B494684B655C3AADC047A1D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an audit of the hate crime data collected by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA592C50495B14A5A8E259E62E6CFA6B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents of audit</header><text>In conducting the audit under subsection (b), the Comptroller General shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6A6B4285532E418686D068C2260D87F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the methodologies and procedures used by the Federal Bureau of Investigation to collect and verify hate crime data; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A0F0897657F47FA8DD83BCC9D82BF01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate the accuracy of the data described in paragraph (1) by conducting a comparative analysis with other relevant hate crime data sources, which may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H112450AAC38747CE86C92E6F96D3B781"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data collected by civil rights organizations serving communities frequently targeted by hate crimes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB03F1CCB58C14BBD910235FFA3CF9A5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>data collected by the Bureau of Justice Statistics through the National Crime Victimization Survey.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H308D093A17164FDD8003C19B3195C472"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after completing the audit under subsection (b), the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text> <paragraph id="HEDCA031F11C24021A38942B7350E5672"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the audit, including recommendations to improve the accuracy, completeness, and reliability of hate crime data received through the National Incident Bias Reporting System, which may include the use of automated systems to identify anomalies in the collected hate crime data such as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H92F128B1CA14483C80B1C254592D0E21">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a State, local, or Tribal law enforcement agency classifying as a zero-reporting agency for consecutive years; and</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA2EDEA7700D742FAB6097D06A3D1F29E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hate crime data reporting patterns from a law enforcement agency that are statistically inconsistent with hate crime data reporting patterns observed in other comparable reporting agencies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H949342B135C848109E0F04C1A1F7EB44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the response of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to the findings of the audit detailing any actions that the Bureau has taken or planned to take to improve the accuracy and oversight of hate crime data reporting.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

