<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEY25C05-S7K-1S-V5R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3559 IS: To designate the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in San Jose, California, as the “Corporal Patrick D. Tillman VA Clinic”. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3559</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To designate the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in San Jose, California, as the <quote>Corporal Patrick D. Tillman VA Clinic</quote>. </official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H06CB3B7A77BA4BA2B563C49FFD0B080A"><section section-type="section-one" id="HDF930B1F0DB9429FB4ED5FF91821C710"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H5F917B1790CB4F34B164D32E84453CEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Patrick <quote>Pat</quote> Daniel Tillman was born on November 6, 1976, in San Jose, California.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1945BB35DB2B4B3099947031B144E38A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>From 1990 to 1994, Pat attended Leland High School in San Jose, California, where he subsequently helped lead his team to a Central Coast Division I Football Championship. Shortly thereafter, Pat was offered a scholarship to and played football for the Arizona State University Sun Devils. While there, he led Arizona State to the 1997 Rose Bowl after an undefeated season, earned three consecutive selections to the Pac-10 All-Academic Football Team, a 1st team Academic All-American honor, as well as the Post-Graduate Scholarship of the National Collegiate Athletic Association for academic and athletic excellence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A0D8907B0564CBDB2E714DBAD255DC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Upon graduating college, Pat Tillman was selected in the 7th round of the 1998 National Football League Draft by the Arizona Cardinals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21E6ADF4052E4459849C00E388C7F804"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In July of 2002, less than 1 year after the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, Pat chose to suspend a lucrative career in the National Football League to join the United States Army alongside his brother, Kevin.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95DFDA03741D41E58C61A1D13A0FB5E4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Pat and Kevin were subsequently assigned to the second battalion of the 75th Ranger Regiment in Fort Lewis, Washington. As an Army Ranger, Pat deployed in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom in 2003 and Operation Enduring Freedom in 2004.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44BD76857BC34C71A9C8805FBB468740"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On April 22, 2004, Pat Tillman was killed by gunfire while on patrol in a rugged area of eastern Afghanistan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C5D1244BBE244608BDB1B1C6837459A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Further investigation and subsequent reporting confirmed Tillman was killed via fratricide as he attempted to provide cover for fellow soldiers as they endeavored to escape from a canyon wherein they were trapped.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H716B21875A35482E91AB4346CE791810"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Pat Tillman is undeniably known as a national hero, was awarded the Silver Star and Purple Heart medals, and was posthumously promoted to corporal.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD042B536367F4626BF559F371C3D747C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Corporal Patrick D. Tillman VA Clinic in San Jose, California</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ed1e54674ef412bb378e4ff977b1a25"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in San Jose, California, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Corporal Patrick D. Tillman Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</quote> or the <quote>Corporal Patrick D. Tillman VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd98ca8c2f774e7489e9adfbe78561f1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the community-based outpatient clinic referred to in subsection (a) shall be considered to be a reference to the Corporal Patrick D. Tillman VA Clinic.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

