<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE8AD3223ED0344EBAF83937B62E44F87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6905 IH: Argentina Bailout Oversight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6905</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to study and report to the Congress on the 2025 financial crisis in Argentina.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F1AFF44DCD1494FABA7D98CE4E8B8EB" style="OLC"><section id="HA9E97806975E4A12A40F073FBB9D290D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Argentina Bailout Oversight Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF061D02C8F5048FF9F78208E70064B8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO report</header><subsection id="H6AB1A8118C624147A01C21E8F07E4EA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of the 2025 financial crisis in Argentina.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD68D731556DE4871B128766139A92612"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The study shall include—</text><paragraph id="H5DF9AE49F02F458EB2826220ACF58220"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an examination on the origins of Argentina’s financial crisis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB04D19DB71B48308538ECBEF4BF1134"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the extent to which the United States Government and the International Monetary Fund have been aware of Argentina’s financial problems and provided relevant advice to Argentina;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1D74B84E59149BBA3EEE774854AD8DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the United States and international response to the crisis, including an assessment of the terms and conditions of the agreements implementing United States assistance to address the crisis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB55DB0DFB4A04300B1C8CB9827765B1C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of the statutory authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to use the Exchange Stabilization Fund to fund United States assistance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D9F265924CF47FEBFDC6F6E64CD5D82"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an examination of the efforts of Argentina to recover from the crisis.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE28AD48D14814E3B995307CDA80060AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Within 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report containing the findings and conclusions of the study required by subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB0952919952D41EAA957D36B23381230"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>After submitting the report required by subsection (c), the Comptroller General shall make the report publicly available on the website of the Government Accountability Office.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

