<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2177E470D3764E62B7A2DDAC7E6836E8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8131 IH: To authorize the creation of a service ribbon to be awarded to a member of the National Guard who performs homeland defense duty.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260327">March 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the creation of a service ribbon to be awarded to a member of the National Guard who performs homeland defense duty.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5E5BA19C58E04424BBE5442E97BE26F8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4E00CCC4710F45E695070A36817204A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HA8B0E08EEB3E43BC831DC7C4157F80D7"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Section 252 of title 10, United States Code, authorizes the President, whenever the President considers that unlawful obstructions, combinations, or assemblages, or rebellion against the authority of the United States, make it impracticable to enforce the laws of the United States in any State by the ordinary course of judicial proceedings, he may call into Federal service the militia of any State, and use such of the Armed Forces, as he considers necessary to enforce those laws or to suppress the rebellion.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H736DF7851F954015B632B90BEC40B0C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The National Guard, under title 32 and title 10 authority, ensures the survivability of Federal law enforcement personnel, facilities, and citizens, in the protection of the Homeland and the American way of life.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCB58AA032264247978A14A5E0589686"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>President Trump, by Presidential Memorandum titled <quote>Military Mission for Sealing the Southern Border of the United States and Repelling Invasions</quote> dated April 11, 2025, granted authority to the Secretary of War to authorize and request that State Governors order members of the National Guard under authority of title 32 of the United States Code to conduct Department of Defense activities, including, as appropriate, to support law enforcement activities, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, border security operations, and provide aviation, reconnaissance, and logistical expertise in support of Department of Homeland Security mission requests.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H09AC35FE391646A3A64BC0DF739FF24E">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>President Trump, by Presidential Memorandum titled <quote>Department of Defense Security for the Protection of Homeland Security Functions</quote> dated June 7, 2025, directed the lawful mobilization of at least 2,000 National Guard troops under section 12406 of title 10, United States Code, to protect Department of Homeland Security personnel and Federal property where unlawful violent protests against necessary Federal enforcement actions were occurring.</text>
      </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEECCE4BEB2DC4AC89918DE2DCE27891D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The National Guard, lawfully mobilized in support of President Trump’s Presidential Executive Order 14333 <quote>Declaring a Crime Emergency in the District of Columbia</quote> dated August 11, 2025, the National Guard supported more than 1,914 arrests between August and September 2025, removing 198 firearms from the street and disrupting homeless encampments, providing clean and safe streets and parks to the citizens of the city.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43F5861225B74B9E8E3DFCCAA37FF87D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The District of Columbia, with a strong National Guard and Federal law enforcement presence, saw a decline in overall crime of 17 percent in 2025 compared with the same period in the previous year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58070AADD4904615B2F2A33F81A04538"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The District of Columbia saw a decline in homicides of 32 percent in 2025 compared with the same period in the previous year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88D8E2DBDEF54B0A81C9BEF1B228C4C7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The District of Columbia saw a decline in assaults with dangerous weapons of 10 percent in 2025 compared with the same period in the previous year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8FBB6D8E9954518B884531E60AB9C1E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The District of Columbia saw a decline in robberies of 37 percent in 2025 compared with the same period in the previous year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE015C2EB30BC4094BA806BA3CF63A6AA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The National Guard, lawfully mobilized in support of President Trump’s Presidential Memorandum titled <quote>Restoring Law and Order in Memphis,</quote> dated September 15, 2025, to restore law and order in Memphis, Tennessee, supported public safety and law enforcement operations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF34E75D1119748AD908B862AC83CFD75"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Honorable Pete Hegseth, as authorized by President Trump’s Presidential Memorandum titled <quote>Department of War Security for the Protection of Federal Personnel and Property in Illinois</quote> dated October 4, 2025, extended National Guard troop deployments to Illinois in response to credible threats of continued violence and interference with officers upholding the laws of the United States, to protect vital ICE, FPS, and other Federal personnel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H114C0C45DE0D40B9A82876821E8548DF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The National Guard has provided safety, security, and predictability to law-abiding American citizens in American cities that were previously overrun by criminal illegal aliens, gang members, and criminals threatening the peace.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9E059E664AC74F55B533FBDEB003BAEC"><enum>(13)</enum><text>National Guard troops have contributed to the most significant one-year drop in homicides on record.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H836878D5AFD64C359C942692EA2F15B0"><enum>(14)</enum><text>National Guard troop presence in communities contributed to a national decline in rapes by 4,175 monthly occurrences between June and December of 2025.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7745F29ED7E040899933F0A915C6E03A"><enum>(15)</enum><text>National Guard troop presence in communities contributed to a national decline in robberies by 5,604 monthly occurrences between June and December of 2025.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAD26DA49D1F42848F03FAABD0BF4C5B"><enum>(16)</enum><text>National Guard troop presence in communities contributed to a national decline in aggravated assaults by 27,521 monthly occurrences between June and December 2025.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAC5080437EEB4D949C01A2EF26174EA6"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The National Guard, in support of President Trump’s strong commitment to the American people by setting Federal policies in support of public safety and border security, contributed to a decline in opioid-related deaths by 25,695 monthly occurrences between June and October 2025.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="H82F1866A317C491CBE49488AAB60E3AD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of service ribbon for a member of the National Guard who performs homeland defense duty</header> <subsection id="H165BFF98E99D4A048FEB657105894A7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ribbon authorized</header><text>The Secretary of the military department concerned may award a service ribbon to a member of the National Guard who performs duty under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/32/9">chapter 9</external-xref> of title 32, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6DDF240AF92D4DC28D7F7E78EDF88815"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ribbon shall be of an appropriate design approved by the Secretary of Defense.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC9B086905EFC49419B18B944F93116C2"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Issuance to next-of-Kin</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the member is deceased, the Secretary of the military department concerned may issue such a ribbon to the next-of-kin of the member.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F8E2A69D09E4852A85FED3F6A5984AB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The award of a ribbon under this section shall be subject to such regulations as the Secretaries of the military departments concerned shall prescribe for purposes of this section. The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that any regulations prescribed under this subsection are uniform to the extent practicable.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

