<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP26475-1H2-3J-XRT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4388 IS: Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To make available necessary disaster assistance for families affected by major disasters, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H798A11DB32314D05BE7FAB7FD630EB05"><section section-type="section-one" id="H3471E6494DCE4DE08A92D8512D909058"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Survivors of Major Disasters Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE7B64F855F8E4D55B68BAF4D32C8A119"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE163A8A1160049BF9397AE331619507A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>FEMA</header><text>The term <term>FEMA</term> means the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC12916060B342FD82EC5EC0FDBFBBB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of FEMA.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCEEB5D0FACDB4F1C846B3CFD2DE598FE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility for and use of disaster assistance</header><subsection id="H089839B57AC64603A9C258955AE61244"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Financial assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, individuals and households described in subsection (c) may be eligible for assistance made available under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) in connection with a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>), including Hurricane Maria of 2017.</text></subsection><subsection id="H12CC4E3A08354929A02D0AF9E5887F19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Any assistance provided pursuant to subsection (a) may include costs relating to obtaining title for a property described in subsection (c)(1), including the cost of land surveys and any other taxes or fees associated with obtaining the title for such property.</text></subsection><subsection id="H417EDF2D1062414EACA50A11897CB91F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible individuals or households</header><text>With respect to a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>), an individual or household described in this subsection is an individual or household who—</text><paragraph id="H23E1D0222BEE4789A441497DB53F63B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is residing on a property located in the area for which the major disaster was declared but does not have documented ownership rights to such property and is not renting such property; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F498E050F514ECCBAF0CD039B6D54D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is or was residing in, or otherwise permanently or temporarily occupying, an area for which a major disaster has been declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>), during the designated incident period, including individuals experiencing homelessness and those residing in any housing accommodation or property upon which a housing accommodation is located, including any living quarters, boardinghouse, bunkhouse, manufactured home, mobile home, or travel trailer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F2A0E71ABF84E3FBA5E2D48C9F267E2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evidence</header><paragraph id="HAD0E1EAB33EC44FAA63772457E31A760"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In the case of an individual or household that does not have documented ownership rights in the predisaster primary residence of the individual or household, in making a determination to provide assistance pursuant to paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 408(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174(c)</external-xref>) for owner-occupants, the Administrator shall consider evidence demonstrative of the individual or household having constructive ownership of the predisaster primary residence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0889BC342FC744299FC76D6B908FA7D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forms of evidence</header><text>In determining whether an individual or household has constructive ownership for the purpose of paragraph (1), the Administrator shall consider a wide range of evidence, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HDEF0431C18E043E485ACE508AEC5F44A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A utility (including gas, electric, sewer, or water) bill with the name and address of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CD87FAFC8754909B8047204ED6695CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A merchant’s statement (including a credit card, delivery notice, or first class mail) with the name and address of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC58FD65EB7444278B2102DF6C600A9C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A pay stub from an employer with the name and address of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27E453634FAC43BFA1B3391BDC4F4145"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A current driver’s license or State-issued identification card of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96732D18B4204C369D7888BA55D274FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The deed or title for the applicable property.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE956EA4C9BF4F17B8EAF3CDE19DF99A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A mortgage payment booklet or another mortgage document.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8DFA2C37433483C964196065EBBE105"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Property title of mobile home certificate of title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC673AF6B2974B79BC56F6C82516A115"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A real estate property tax receipt.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E4B1936A6148D7A8D1A12AAE1984AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A school registration containing the address of self, child, or children.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H943440B966C34692966F2FEAAD9BFDCA"><enum>(J)</enum><text>A will and testament with the name and address of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1648816728146959A79D917F404693D"><enum>(K)</enum><text>In a State that does not require a will and testament for the transfer of immovable property, a death certificate and birth certificate that establishes an automatic transfer of legal ownership.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE77C50891DB643648F1E056CA12860AB"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Medical records that list the name and address of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AF1DB4156C5491CB7DCF6FB2D4310E4"><enum>(M)</enum><text>A charitable donation receipt that lists the name and address of the individual.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEDA9F46964F489FA2B19A394EACF1FF"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Any other documentation, certification, identification, or proof of occupancy or ownership not included on this list that can reasonably link the individual requesting assistance to the applicable property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3547A8CFF27946E286EA106AF75AA92D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply to funds appropriated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H265D0FEA96FF485B93274CD11B897250"><enum>4.</enum><header>Declarative statement</header><subsection id="H3998AE06D289455F9D045385C06E402E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of declarative statement</header><paragraph id="HFD44523323324683ABA7477CF53F2C91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall create, in coordination with the appropriate authorities of the applicable jurisdiction, and distribute, where necessary, a declarative statement form that an applicant for assistance provided pursuant to section 3 may use to self-certify such applicant’s eligibility for assistance pursuant to this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H250ABADD5DA34EFAA2838F349BCE63A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition of notarization</header><text>The Administrator may not require the declarative statement form created under paragraph (1) to require notarization by the applicant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0192C9E2E3E544EC81C8160C43DBB72B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>A declarative statement form created under subsection (a)(1) shall be exempt from publication notice, public comment periods, and agency information collection review and approval by the Office of Management and Budget required by the Paperwork Reduction Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6442634A1ACE4733B20BE4701F59EF9C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall provide written notification and guidance to employees of FEMA regarding the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6B69D48B767F44F38A603CF2F0BFBF72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H72910662F2E848A9800C400332FD1878"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the declarative statement form created under subsection (a)(1) available in Spanish and English at all active Disaster Recovery Centers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7D13291BCD6432CA47087F0588537B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish in English, Spanish, and any other locally predominant languages on the website of FEMA and on social media the declarative statement form and instructions on how applicants can reopen or seek further appeal of relevant determinations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H98620089901744E0930FAB223544FDB8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Past disasters</header><text>For applicants of assistance provided pursuant to section 3 since January 1, 2017, the Administrator shall provide an applicant not fewer than 180 days to submit the declarative statement form to reopen or appeal a case after such applicant has received notice of the right to do so.</text></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA368AB07E230494BA24DE24050223F1C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Repair and rebuilding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96D0348DB3D948C194C85ADA7699A1FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="id785d74ad614948ad9d5042e025dd30b3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>rendered uninhabitable</quote> and inserting <quote>damaged by a major disaster</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id502dde95a24f460e88ad666cd779d2bd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>uninhabitable, as a result of damage caused by a major disaster</quote> and inserting <quote>damaged by a major disaster</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6C7D01EC0347484EB68191F13833715D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H8191747D5E4540ED9F8FBD3FAE049018"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)(i) by striking <quote>to a safe and sanitary living or functioning condition</quote> and inserting <quote>to ensure that such residences are habitable during longer term recovery (including through coordination with other sources for repair and rebuilding of such residences)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B7F1B1EC3704315AC9D7196C238B2E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4) by striking <quote>in cases in which</quote> and all that follows, and inserting <quote>if the President determines such assistance is a cost effective alternative to other housing solutions, including the costs associated with temporary housing provided under this section.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HB584E39CCE874068B783DB18D08757F5"><enum>6.</enum><header>FEMA HUD Agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case of any major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>) on or after the date of enactment of this Act, not later than 60 days after the date of the declaration of the major disaster, the Administrator and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall engage in consultations regarding the implementation of a disaster housing assistance program or similar joint program under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) to provide temporary rental assistance to individuals and households displaced from their residences by the major disaster, including individuals and households eligible for such assistance under section 3(a) of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

