<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HD2C3C24A66ED4A9EBE31DA0847EDE218">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 999 IH: Providing for the consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 997) enabling the House of Representatives to be responsive to its membership.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 999</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Providing for the consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 997) enabling the House of Representatives to be responsive to its membership.</official-title>
</form>
<resolution-body style="traditional" id="H2B6CB7390C4D4FC58C214DC8A0BC0E4F">
<section section-type="resolved" id="HD2C3C24A66ED4A9EBE31DA0847EDE212"><text>That immediately upon adoption of this resolution, without intervention of any point of order, the House shall proceed to the consideration in the House of the resolution (H. Res. 997) enabling the House of Representatives to be responsive to its membership. An amendment in the nature of a substitute received for printing in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII dated at least one day before the day of consideration of H. Res. 997, if submitted by the ranking minority member of the Committee on Rules, shall be considered as adopted. If more than one such amendment is submitted, then only the last amendment submitted shall be considered as adopted. The resolution, as amended, shall be considered as read. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the resolution, as amended, to adoption without intervening motion or demand for division of the question except one hour of debate equally divided and controlled by the majority leader and minority leader or their respective designees.</text></section> <section id="HD7C3C24A66ED4A9EBE31DA0847EDE212"><enum>2.</enum><text>Clause 1(c) of rule XIX and clause 8 of rule XX shall not apply to the consideration of H. Res. 997.</text></section>
</resolution-body>
</resolution> 


