<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBDCD61C6B35C4A7B81E18E74C4686B1D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7784 IH: Secure Tracks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7784</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to establish requirements regarding visual and automated track inspections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC0B8741AFA714C27920F804FB4C80A59" style="OLC"><section id="H0BA492908B6F428B8B0F58AA9F45D707" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Tracks Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H966F314E87D645E7A86BF614BB8F50E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Track inspections</header><subsection id="HC45041AFFC3F44E09EF465876264E926"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H3C00A26326C241CE9589CA78059CF9C5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H2C9691CE8119483BB0987901FBBE50A9"><enum>20172.</enum><header>Visual and automated track inspection requirements</header><subsection id="HA4E5727919F84B64877DBC5AF0CD53DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minimum frequency for visual track inspections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All main line track designated for operation at Class 3 track speeds or higher under section 213.9 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026, shall be subject to visual inspection by a qualified inspector not less frequently than twice each week, with at least 1 calendar day between each inspection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6979CAC6F86943F4BFF0539B1DEBD02C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Immediate remediation of safety defects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any defect or unsafe condition identified by any inspection, detection, or monitoring method shall be corrected, protected, or removed from service immediately upon detection, consistent with the requirements of part 213 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA5DCCD19102C4EF2AB10BA9FED09EA41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Remediation by qualified person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a qualified inspector making a track inspection under this section finds a deviation from the requirements of part 213 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026, the qualified inspector shall—</text><paragraph id="H30BC2C984D3E4FAD9CF1E1E29224AD2E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>immediately initiate remedial action; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED9F2B419909433598AB3CCC7525A734"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have the sole authority to authorize any subsequent movements to facilitate repairs on track that is out of service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD17B13214C54DA590D9BF634C1F1A6C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on granting waivers that reduce safety coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 20103 of this title, the Secretary of Transportation may not grant a waiver, exemption, or modification of any safety regulation issued under chapter II of subtitle B of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026, if the proposed alternative inspection, detection, or monitoring method fails to identify or detect all defect conditions defined or recognized as unsafe under applicable Federal Railroad Administration regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B984E9E2E9D47B48E1EB0167CCD354F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Automated track inspection requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall update subparts F and G of part 213 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to require that a Track Geometry Measurement System operate over the following track classifications at the following frequencies and be subject to the following requirements regarding TGMS inspections:</text><paragraph id="H691E397D43144A58B62D3A64D2E88795"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For operations at a qualified cant deficiency (Eu) of more than 5 inches on Classes 1 through 5 track, at least 4 times per calendar year, with at least 43 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF97A7001E674C3B833B69523D0B337E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For Class 1 track operating more than 15,000,000 gross tons annually, at least once per calendar year, with at least 170 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB374950D3D0E4B6482B9D87943F83CB1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For Class 2 track—</text><subparagraph id="H010BB980DAAB4A84AD7146B9400AAD63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operating 15,000,000 or fewer gross tons annually, at least once per calendar year, with at least 170 days elapsing between TGMS inspections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E546198EC84F6099DF9A58951754F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operating more than 15,000,000 gross tons annually, at least twice per calendar year, with at least 120 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0645750B3E1149CAAEA6B38EFE014EB5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For Class 3 track—</text><subparagraph id="H5AAF24F8750645B5942ED52AEFE7A4BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operating 15,000,000 or fewer gross tons annually, at least twice per calendar year, with at least 120 days elapsing between TGMS inspections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C4EA83F426740B88B84F665DB3DE733"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operating more than 15,000,000 gross tons annually, at least 3 times per calendar year, with at least 90 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H546DE1A721FD4413B052FBCC84C967F8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For Class 4 track—</text><subparagraph id="H005A84E64E464847951836F247AF09C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operating 15,000,000 or fewer gross tons annually, at least 3 times per calendar year, with at least 90 days elapsing between TGMS inspections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75EFDDA3480E45C692644D8124DE6076"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operating more than 15,000,000 gross tons annually, at least 4 times per calendar year, with at least 43 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8668D21BF5A24869B3E57A30D55A024F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For Class 5 track, at least 4 times per calendar year, with at least 43 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H471F9A8D12024517884831138F39AC9E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>For Class 6 and Class 7 track, at least twice during any 120-day period, with at least 25 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA43B38A73E99431D963BB5BD789C69BA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>For Class 8 track, at least twice during any 60-day period, with at least 12 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06FB8BD304644ED1853633B654B649D0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>For Class 9 track, at least twice during any 30-day period, with at least 6 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0103774C35FA42A3A77EABD2FA90C9A7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>For crossovers where the track speed is more than 30 miles per hour, at least twice per calendar year, with at least 120 days elapsing between TGMS inspections.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB747DDEA8A1A411EAC1D01692CDACD42"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Fixing deviation requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall update part 213 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026, to require that when any inspection, whether done by a qualified inspector or by a machine (including a TGMS machine), finds a deviation from the requirements of this part, the qualified inspector or other authorized personnel shall immediately remediate the deviation in accordance with such part.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3E4213576E554020944C1618B5448744"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicable requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that any requirements of subparts F and G of part 213 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026, including section 213.333 of such part, generated by an update to the regulations made pursuant to subsection (e) or (f) are applied to the applicable track classification.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1D84A6AE85F6436A987C1E84A0DA3A3F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0BE38CBC24DC4681BF6C68E75604B61A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Class 1 track; Class 2 track; Class 3 track; Class 4 track; Class 5 track</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Class 1 track</term>, <term>Class 2 track</term>, <term>Class 3 track</term>, <term>Class 4 track</term>, and <term>Class 5 track</term> means Class 1 track, Class 2 track, Class 3 track, Class 4 track, and Class 5 track, respectively, as such terms are used in section 213.9(a) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C3F8676D0ED42AFB2B31561A582073F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Main line</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>main line</term> has the meaning given such term in section 236.1003 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F581592F5E14B96A67F6E38560C7F90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified inspector</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified inspector</term> means a person designated as a qualified person to inspect track for defects under section 213.7(b) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC6217A3FB64DF991B37F1E32A0FD61"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Track Geometry Measurement System; TGMS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Track Geometry Measurement System</term> and <term>TGMS</term> means a Track Geometry Measurement System as such term is used in section 213.333 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7F5B625A49554EF7AE5F9F7DCF9B6795"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/201">chapter 201</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H65FE5482DEF24AD6BEC54F54D394C852" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">20172. Visual and automated track inspection requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

