<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26632-5JC-WW-J6S"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 SRES 759 IS: Recognizing World Oceans Day and celebrating the maritime heritage, ocean leadership, fisheries stewardship, and coastal communities of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 759</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing World Oceans Day and celebrating the maritime heritage, ocean leadership, fisheries stewardship, and coastal communities of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the ocean has shaped the history, security, economy, and identity of the United States since its founding;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks the 250th anniversary of the United States of America;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for 250 years, the United States has grown into a global maritime leader through naval strength, exploration, scientific discovery, commerce, shipbuilding, fisheries, aquaculture, and ocean innovation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is home to vibrant coastal communities and working waterfronts that serve as economic engines supporting millions of jobs in fishing, shipping, tourism, energy, recreation, marine transportation, seafood production, research, and trade;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the ocean economy contributes trillions of dollars annually to the United States economy and supports millions of American workers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas generations of American fishermen, mariners, shipbuilders, scientists, members of the Armed Forces, port workers, and indigenous communities have contributed to the strength and prosperity of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the strength of the United States Navy, Coast Guard, and Marines has defended the shores of the United States, protected freedom of navigation, safeguarded international commerce, prevented the occurrence of illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing from occurring in United States waters and abroad, and strengthened America’s maritime leadership throughout the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has developed world-class ports, maritime infrastructure, shipbuilding capacity, and ocean technology that have helped power economic growth and global trade;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States has preserved and celebrated its maritime heritage through historic ships, lighthouses, museums, waterfronts, and educational programs that honor the Nation’s seafaring traditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States global leadership is due to its excellence in ocean science, mapping, exploration, and innovation through the work of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, academic institutions, Federal agencies, and private sector partners;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas scientists estimate that a majority of the ocean remains unexplored, making ocean exploration one of the last great frontiers for scientific discovery and innovation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks the 50th anniversary of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>), landmark bipartisan legislation that was signed into law in 1976;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act established a 200-mile exclusive economic zone, strengthened United States fisheries management, protected American fishermen from foreign overfishing, rebuilt fish stocks, and helped create one of the most successful and sustainable fisheries management systems in the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas commercial, recreational, and Tribal fisheries support food security, sustain cultural traditions, strengthen coastal economies, and contribute to the maritime heritage of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas American seafood producers, processors, and fishing communities continue to provide high-quality domestic seafood while supporting jobs and economic growth across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks the 20th anniversary of the Marine Debris Program established under the Marine Debris Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1951">33 U.S.C. 1951 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas bipartisan efforts through the Save Our Seas Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/265">Public Law 115–265</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 3742) and related legislation have strengthened the country’s response to marine debris, supported innovation and international engagement, and protected coastal communities, waterways, fisheries, and marine ecosystems;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas marine debris and microplastics threatens navigation safety, coastal tourism, fisheries, working waterfronts, marine wildlife, and human well-being; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas World Oceans Day is celebrated annually on June 8 to recognize the importance of the ocean to the people, economy, heritage, and future of the United States and the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id1e06f5e0ba264919b4847183bce14abe"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes June 8, 2026, as World Oceans Day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8c2cb0ffd8834b42877b24674f0e09b9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates the ocean’s vital role in the history, heritage, economy, security, and future prosperity of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fa667ce9e49419ca029d33a777bf382"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the contributions of America’s fishermen, mariners, members of the Armed Forces, scientists, explorers, shipbuilders, port workers, indigenous communities, coastal communities, and working waterfronts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93b0aeb120814cf2aec96d979274cab0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the 50th anniversary of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) and its role in strengthening American fisheries, supporting coastal economies, preventing illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, protecting the country's seafood resources, and ensuring long-term fisheries stewardship for future generations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9781d53a309243e990e74ac7e5602f2f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the 20th anniversary of the Marine Debris Program and bipartisan congressional leadership through the Save Our Seas Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/265">Public Law 115–265</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 3742) to reduce marine debris and protect coastal communities and waterways; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2f96295978c4ed6b1c39b1b1957a83d"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to advancing maritime leadership, ocean exploration, scientific discovery, economic opportunity, and responsible stewardship of ocean resources for future generations.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

