<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25M05-LFR-0X-49G">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 490 IS: Affirming the critical importance of preserving the United States' advantage in artificial intelligence and ensuring that the United States achieves and maintains artificial intelligence dominance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>III</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. RES. 490</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20251106">November 6, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr.
                    McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>)
                submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
                Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Affirming the critical importance of preserving the United
            States' advantage in artificial intelligence and ensuring that the United States
            achieves and maintains artificial intelligence dominance.</official-title>
    </form>
    <preamble>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas artificial intelligence (AI) will be one of the defining technologies of the 21st century;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas preserving American dominance in AI will allow the United States to hold an advantage in military capabilities, economic might, scientific achievement, and geopolitical influence, all of which will enable the United States to shape the world’s future on a foundation of democratic values;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas AI will unlock untold opportunities in nearly every sector in the global economy, from healthcare to manufacturing, defense, energy, and finance;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas AI is also a national security imperative, with the potential to reshape military strategies, cybersecurity, and intelligence operations, requiring both the United States Government and the private sector to collaborate in preserving the technological superiority of the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the United States has historically led the world in AI research and development, fostering a dynamic ecosystem of cutting-edge technologies driven by the collaboration between government, academia, and the private sector;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the global competition for AI supremacy is intensifying, with the Government of the People's Republic of China making substantial investments in AI research, development, and deployment with the stated goal of becoming the world leader in AI by 2030 and leveraging state-backed policies to accelerate AI adoption across various domains;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas the White House AI Action Plan notes that <quote>just like we won the space race, it is imperative that the United States win this race</quote> and <quote>achieve and maintain unquestioned and unchallenged global technological dominance</quote>;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas AI dominance will be decided by relative strength across multiple pillars, including talent, energy, and compute, with the United States maintaining a clear lead in compute while China’s investments have yielded advantages in energy and talent;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas United States chipmakers, working with manufacturers in Taiwan, produce millions of United States-designed AI chips per year, while Chinese chipmakers are projected to produce no more than 200,000 advanced chips this year, according to Secretary of Commerce Howard Lutinick, each of which is far less powerful than AI chips designed in the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas United States companies produce 43 to 120 times more computing power than their Chinese equivalent, taking into account both the number and quality of United States-made chips, and United States chips are in effect the only true option for training advanced AI systems such that even leading Chinese firms use United States-produced chips;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas China—despite more than a decade of major Chinese indigenization efforts and more than $200,000,000,000 in investments since 2014—has struggled to produce advanced AI chips and therefore has to rely on smuggling or legal exports of advanced chips from the United States;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas export controls on advanced chips, chip design software, tools, and manufacturing equipment have denied the Government of the People's Republic of China the opportunity to develop domestic chipmaking capabilities and capture significant market share of global AI infrastructure;</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas it is essential that the United States remain the world’s hub for AI development, training, inference, and innovation; and</text>
        </whereas>
        <whereas>
 <text>Whereas preserving the United States lead in AI will require ensuring United States AI companies can access the energy, compute, and talent they require: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas>
    </preamble>
    <resolution-body>
        <section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section">
 <text>That the Senate—</text> <paragraph id="id4948a0cd63f44a09b4868594334f3270"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>affirms that the preservation of the United States’ primacy in artificial intelligence is a national imperative that is critical to maintaining our global leadership, economic prosperity, and national security;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idaee98cbfac4a443491d8446bee45ab99">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>commends the White House AI Action Plan, including its recognition that <quote>advanced AI compute is essential to the AI era, enabling both economic dynamism and novel military capabilities</quote> and that <quote>denying our foreign adversaries access to this resource, then, is a matter of both geostrategic competition and national security</quote>;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id246b7075140a474599c363926c42b622">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>applauds United States Government efforts to deny the Government of the People's Republic of China access to advanced chips and chipmaking equipment, and affirms the importance of continuing these efforts;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id8e2890d0c9ef4a80a88a7799bb4d1114">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>recognizes that efforts of the Government of the People's Republic China to close the AI gap and leap ahead of the United States in developing frontier AI models, and deploy Chinese AI models for the world to use and build on, present a clear and imminent threat to the United States, and that China’s self-acknowledged inability to make and access computing power is the main impediment to its progress;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idc0c48a190f9c44e681cc8a017411c4ab">
                <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>emphasizes that the world’s most powerful supercomputers and next generation of AI models must be built in the United States and by United States companies;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id5932a51a00424df388ecbade0d4af536">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>calls on the United States Government to ensure that United States companies maintain priority access to the cutting-edge AI chips they require to build frontier AI models and are not deprioritized in favor of buyers in China or other arms-embargoed countries;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idf2e262932515417dab8ba55d28d63deb">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text>emphasizes the importance of exporting the full United States AI stack—which includes United States AI chips, cloud infrastructure, and models—to allies and partners, while restricting access to the most sophisticated chips and models that United States adversaries may seek to use against the United States, whether by enforcing export controls and countering illegal chip diversion or by strategically limiting legal exports of advanced chips to adversary countries; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id5b03f639460947df9a0e0f6727fb628c">
                <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>asserts the need to prioritize investments in the energy, telecommunications, and physical infrastructure necessary to enable widespread adoption of AI technology.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

