<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF00BE578CA249F28DB60D5D8E3B1577" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9381 IH: AI Workforce Assessment and Research Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9381</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260622">June 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Bureau of Labor Statistics to report on the usage of artificial intelligence in the workplace.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0E7AE2CE4C1640B9835AD0869D49B9A5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H47D5BAB107E744F2A1A7462C1BBB60EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI Workforce Assessment and Research Enhancement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AWARE Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H75FD6B6424524FF6BA8E645210081FA3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HB45CE415595B47AC983E7010AF8EB79D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Artificial intelligence (in this section referred to as <quote>AI</quote>) has significant potential for workplace applications and may alter labor market demand by automating, augmenting, or creating workplace tasks and changing the nature of work across industries and occupations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92A661851EE7442B97AAC80A3363F762"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Policymakers, educators, workforce training providers, businesses, workers, and researchers would benefit from improved data and analysis to understand and respond to the effects of AI on employment, occupations, tasks, wages, hiring, training, and general workforce needs.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H503C371E565841E09BA3768C16F11B9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor is the principal Federal agency responsible for collecting, analyzing, and disseminating labor market and workforce statistics through employer-side, worker-side, and longitudinal statistical programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEAB96E7FD52426A95B785727C0C15A1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Labor Statistics conducts surveys and data collection activities relating to employment, wages, occupations, labor force participation, work arrangements, and business conditions.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC668204CBF09409697E11636798C7B25"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The data collection programs of the Bureau of Labor Statistics provide essential information on labor market conditions and workforce trends, but were not designed to adequately measure on a timely basis—</text> <subparagraph id="HE61B88989B0242EF96F6D3D432FF74BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>employer adoption of AI technologies;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB41FB784FEE44CEDBCB626F73F5E1BE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>worker-level use of AI technologies within jobs and occupations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9870347E1428496AA78B36C1AB71C7F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>AI-related changes in workplace tasks, duties, and work organization;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEF761CF1187042CEB0DFFE5B75B9F40A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>AI-related training, retraining, or upskilling activities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0B053485DFD435088AB862701337FF1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the effects of AI on hiring, vacancies, hours, wages, contracting arrangements, or employment levels; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDCD01858B6A74D8BA8157B1A0BFC7F77"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the emergence of new workplace duties, tasks, job titles, or staffing needs associated with AI.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BD0102E699D48ACB289526EB8104744"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Certain related concepts are measured in other Federal statistical programs, including programs administered by the Bureau of the Census and the National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics, but important gaps remain in the issuance of timely, representative, and consistent labor market data.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0A7F10511394472AAC8A9BE3A8B1A0A1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Effective measurement of AI in the workforce may require coordinated employer-side and worker-side data collection approaches in order to capture business adoption, worker experience, task-level changes, and labor market adjustment effects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD985B8FE5F47488DBD9BCCCF88EB826F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Improved measurement of AI use and its labor market effects will strengthen workforce analysis, support further economic and workforce policy development, improve employment projections and related research, and provide employers, workers, and educators with more information to more effectively respond to technological change in their workplaces.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HAA3B4BB9B40143C3B54E3AA91A10BB73"><enum>3.</enum><header>Labor statistics reporting on the usage of artificial intelligence</header>
<subsection id="H3AAF6A74769846518E844D5BAC122CBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4 of the Act of March 4, 1913, titled <quote>An Act to create a Department of Labor</quote> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2">29 U.S.C. 2</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H284BF290325F4FF88E45CE02A0A39395" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>which shall include full and complete statistics on the usage of artificial intelligence (as defined in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>)) in such conditions of labor and such products and distribution,</quote> after <quote>full and complete statistics of the conditions of labor and the products and distribution of the products of the same,</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDB15F21181C244BF97B164541ACBF34D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by striking <quote>and the total hours of employment,</quote> and inserting <quote>the total hours of employment, and the usage of artificial intelligence (as defined in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>)),</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H45D0A54ED8FD44CAB216279C9862A046"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline for initial collection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Labor Statistics shall begin collecting, under section 4 of the Act of March 4, 1913, titled <quote>An Act to create a Department of Labor</quote> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2">29 U.S.C. 2</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), the statistics on the usage of artificial intelligence described in the amendments made by paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H0540271951B349DAB10C72A1CA069500"><enum>4.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

