<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD846F15D02A54730BA9200A71D5A8CDD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7369 IH: United States Capitol Police Reserve Fund Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7369</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001216">Mr. Mills</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a reserve fund for the United States Capitol Police, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H92A0F5D3B55140E28910078EF64DFA0B" style="OLC"><section id="HD982E6D412B84E54BBB1B15E0A8B6047" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Capitol Police Reserve Fund Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4C0050D820D34778B25B69C2A4C65F0F"><enum>2.</enum><header>United States Capitol Police Reserve Fund</header><subsection id="H967155947EC24349BA80DC0F30F9E4F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a fund, to be titled the <quote>United States Capitol Police Reserve Fund</quote>, for the payment of salaries of employees and necessary expenses of the United States Capitol Police during a lapse of appropriations for the United States Capitol Police.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE842679B0B8943F39115B6DA4043DA97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of the fund</header><text>The Chief of the Capitol Police, under the approval of the Capitol Police Board, may use amounts from the United States Capitol Police Reserve Fund only to make payments of salaries of employees and necessary expenses of the United States Capitol Police after the start, and before the end, of a lapse in appropriations with respect to the United States Capitol Police.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD71B982534D94D35972526CCEADD34C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>There is hereby appropriated, out of money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $50,000,000 for the United States Capitol Police Reserve Fund.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2378FF4D86446BFB8BC930C6DCB8C0A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit of appropriated funds into the fund</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit amounts appropriated under this section to the United States Capitol Reserve Fund.</text></subsection><subsection id="H974F411FD26B416E82EBD2D93ED7F7DF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Release of funds to the Treasury</header><text>Not later than January 31, 2027, the Chief of the Capitol Police shall transfer any amounts not used for the purposes described in subsection (b) remaining in the United States Capitol Reserve Fund as of December 31, 2026, to the Secretary of the Treasury, and such amounts shall be rescinded.</text></subsection><subsection id="H53374015DF7D4030BA8589F23E2314E0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 calendar days after the date of compliance with subsection (e), the Chief of the Capitol Police shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the uses of, and the transactions relating to, the United States Capitol Reserve Fund.</text></subsection><subsection id="H422DA36D64AC4054BF92F683B01B5C76"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the following:</text><paragraph id="H2A219A0584584F8F8285C92B53947741"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9D090B0E2B841FBAFD04E1A66E954E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB202B6A88D8048BCA2A1B1867F31FCB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4394CA1F4C3A414587E299E28167D1F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

