<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H86C9FD63866A43D49502DA43B664078B">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8127 IH: Permanent Housing Affordability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8127</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To promote shared equity models of homeownership, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H263675119E7B4FB9A51A3236C2B6AF00">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H7460FE833FF344E7BB6324BBC47D6B85"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Permanent Housing Affordability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H024B64DCA09949CEA8F3A40233437AC3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HF49FF3F92B354B6193AC596FD12E9CA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community development financial institution</header><text>The term <term>community development financial institution</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D11DB55EA45426FB978AD6E5EFE40C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community land trust</header><text>The term <term>community land trust</term> means a nonprofit entity, a State, a unit of local government, or an instrumentality of a State or unit of local government—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC45214010F77400D888020B9EE52ADB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is not managed by, or an affiliate of, a for-profit organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H954E3E9FD1974F58A8DF5187513587C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the primary purpose of which is acquiring, developing, or holding land to provide housing that is permanently affordable to low- and moderate-income persons;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H872EEDE7E49C4DFA8335F34FCDC42FD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that monitors properties to ensure affordability is preserved;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E27DF8569C54257908BFE437C188068"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that provides housing that is permanently affordable to low- and moderate-income persons using a ground lease, deed covenant, or other similar legally enforceable measure, determined acceptable by the Secretary, that—</text>
<clause id="H3D0BC3E25E3348B7B6C3647A1BE934C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>keeps the housing affordable to low- and moderate-income persons for not less than—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB5D17AFBDBA64A5B82DDDFCA9C1C5970"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">99 years; or</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7693026797744EC093DA2C3A749F0606"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the greatest minimum affordability period permitted by applicable State law, if that law restricts minimum affordability periods to a number of years that is less than 99; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5296B0A95222422E997FD4ADFAEACA5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enables low- and moderate-income persons to rent or purchase the housing for homeownership; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6BE66B6602A94BB394ABDF5590FFB98A"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text>that maintains preemptive purchase options to purchase the property, if such purchase would allow the housing to remain affordable to low- and moderate-income persons.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E1A709CF0E844B08374587704E0A672"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a unit of local government, an instrumentality of a State or unit of local government, or a nonprofit organization, including a community land trust, that manages a shared equity homeownership model program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H369E3D7F5F8040DFB8A7CC527D865E2D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible grantee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible grantee</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4D5AB7371114E6581884BCAB436F3B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any agency of a State;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H700C93B0E5A74B3FB8176A8B3AC77857"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any authority chartered by a State to help meet affordable housing needs of the residents of the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H739B15100A874B4CADD029BD8F67ECFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a community development financial institution that is certified by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5937615DF5C2421AA008232CC0BA1175"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified homebuyer</header><text>The term <term>qualified homebuyer</term> means a homebuyer with a household income that is not more than 120 percent of the area median income.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA7CF631E64A4BB680E2003DA8E4D267"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Resale formula</header><text>The term <term>resale formula</term> means a permissible method of determining fair return and resale price under section 92.254(a)(5)(i)(A) of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on March 28, 2025.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07BE0C4FCDB44323B4F52DCE24F22673">
                <enum>(7)</enum>
                <header>Shared equity homeownership model</header>
 <text>The term <term>shared equity homeownership model</term> means a model of resale-restricted, owner-occupied housing the primary purpose of which is to create and preserve a supply of owner-occupied units affordable to low- and moderate-income households that—</text>
                <subparagraph id="HCED77CE561FB45A5B20B9AA37519B7F7">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>carry terms of affordability that are not less than—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67941BD2D6D1452DB985EEEED3067953"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">99 years; or</text>
                    </clause>
                    <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="H517BB66495A54FC2AB12D82465892686">
                        <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the greatest minimum affordability period permitted by applicable State law, if that law restricts minimum affordability periods to a number of years that is less than 99; and</text>
                    </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="H9FA31AB8639C41728A2EDCF5C2560A46" commented="no"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>restrict the resale value of properties in the program according to a resale formula described in a ground lease, deed restriction, or similar legal mechanism.</text>
                </subparagraph>
            </paragraph></section>
<section id="H8EE0906BD6E84684BB2EA268BAABEC8F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Lasting Home Affordability Fund</header>
<subsection id="H9D7BCBAC1B114DC7BC9B3263B6FD2E24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (in this section referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible grantees to use for the purpose of providing low-interest construction loans to eligible entities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6708A142B52A4CE7BFBB0FD5779BB065"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application by eligible grantees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive amounts under this section, an eligible grantee shall submit an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require, including a detailed description of—</text>
<paragraph id="H405EC8EC98F247D09159380894E245DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how the eligible grantee intends to use any amounts provided under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB679BC35B06472D8DDDE3AE0F157120"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the qualifications such eligible grantee has that will allow such eligible grantee to successfully administer a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7893C1B6679D4304A59F5BD67C7C86AA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of amounts by eligible grantees</header>
<paragraph id="H58F79B571AB149A6AAC7FEB1F70ADF9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any eligible grantee that receives amounts under this section shall use such amounts and related proceeds to establish a revolving fund and provide low-interest construction loans to 1 or more eligible entities, which amounts may be awarded to eligible entities on a rolling basis.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDADED476A30E4C2889B7F810C451ADAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Loan requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H19C5E8FD565D42998CA1E35E0A97A158"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Loans provided by an eligible grantee to an eligible entity using amounts provided under this section shall—</text>
<clause id="H4EE3CDF9862D4880A0783A40C0A05A53"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have an interest rate of not more than 3 percent; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8DF55187E96743E4BE39FD9414607AC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have an origination fee of not more than 1 percent of the amount of the loan.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAF9AA99C8A7643CE8FF930CFB4B2B5BA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Liquidity requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible grantee may not require, as a condition of receiving a loan under this section, that an eligible entity has more than 10 percent of the amount to be loaned in liquid assets at the time of the loan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4EDC371F1BE9405BAF86E7AF0518298F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An eligible entity that receives amounts under this section may not be the same entity as the eligible grantee that provides those amounts.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80A993EE56ED4F13B18F5AE4E0D66D46"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>An eligible grantee shall prioritize loans to eligible entities that plan to use amounts loaned under this section to construct or rehabilitate properties—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7966CC67C09644A1A5A07B90C540E28F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">located in areas with high cost burden, as determined by the Secretary, individuals at risk of displacement due to rising housing costs, or redlining; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H747BA8993F594E7190CCCB85EDE9C0D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that are required to be affordable as described in subsection (e) for terms that are more than 99 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDC18DE53F71740FB81993DB3F4E1AE29"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of amounts by eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may use amounts loaned by an eligible grantee for costs associated with the construction or rehabilitation of housing intended to be sold to a homebuyer, a member of a limited equity cooperative, or a community land trust and used as a primary residence, including materials, labor (including contractor fees), land development (including demolition and grading), permit and developer fees, insurance costs, on-site infrastructure costs (including the installation of roads, water, electrical, sewer, storm drainage, and sidewalks), and predevelopment (including architectural costs and engineering costs).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB77ACBF5DC7844EFA303F1248CFF3748"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Affordability requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that uses amounts loaned under this section to construct or rehabilitate a property—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEB25C8750AB47FA9149BA82209EEC73"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only sell or facilitate the sale of such property to qualified homebuyers; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3A90E49C1A94025AB24AF2D00E01FD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall ensure any subsequent sales are to qualified homebuyers at a below-market value that is determined by a resale formula described in a ground lease, deed restriction, or other similar mechanism.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C7C567899294DE49598670A6FC95210"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Areas of service</header><text>The Secretary shall seek to provide grants to eligible grantees that will fund activities in geographically diverse areas, including areas of persistent poverty, underserved areas, and rural areas.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H57250B9989474A28B9EFE450B70F5487"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary may issue rules to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1200F6CAA1A745A0966D741FDEB32578"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <paragraph id="H49C290641E144D2FB6B9C976AEEA14D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grantee reports</header><text>The Secretary shall require each grantee receiving grant amounts in any given year under this section to submit a report, for such year and each year that loans are made using grant funds, to the Secretary that includes—</text>
<subparagraph id="H805A1A66F78F4496B2C43694474A7E2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of qualifying loans made;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9245FB71767B44AC801651BA24EE6755"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the organizations receiving loans;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FAC58B47142499AA8BB9DFA7F807FC7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of outstanding loans on September 30th of the report year;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2AB5247ECCC04DEA80B19696DC4ED3AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the percentage of organizations belonging to each type of eligible grantee as described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of section 2(4);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC568129A62C7401B8E47A4E8D339BC77"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the projected number of units constructed or rehabilitated by each loan;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB133C0AB55CE4870BC149A366BD775A5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the average interest rate on qualifying loans;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H45C6B865E58E4AEAA68C537B78692F35"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the average origination fee on qualifying loans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD7ACC23625874B70BECBAF9F7B647C07"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the median purchase price of the homes constructed or rehabilitated by each loan compared to the median market rate price in the area;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H78A0A1F3AF494AC1B65C69AA64119FB8">
                        <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the ZIP Codes where the homes constructed or rehabilitated by each loan are located;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H207A60CFF8D84F86A757D38D1D42B4D2"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the area median income level of households assisted;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73E155027A564E09989535462FEF9543"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the percentage and number of loans made for the purpose of construction;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA1F6B22F455E45BD81BC67146D907527">
                        <enum>(L)</enum>
 <text>the percentage and number of loans made for the purpose of rehabilitation;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBABEDCF40C7F4AF6B2543EC027A89224"><enum>(M)</enum><text>a description of any mechanism used to ensure permanent affordability by each grantee, such as ground leases, deed restrictions, covenants, or other mechanisms;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DCDF80DE6DB43B6A3D292B4BFA784C8"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the resale formula used by each eligible entity that receives a loan from the grantee; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9B385247B41943E49022F327841F9B8D"><enum>(O)</enum><text>where applicable, for each loan made, the percentage of total project cost expected to be covered by the loan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0108E0D6F4D14233BB5E6CBC85047D09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the conclusion of each fiscal year in which assistance under this section is made available, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on amounts provided under this section that contains, with aggregates, averages, and summaries, as appropriate, information provided by grantees under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA35FC624C42A4058BF8C5718AFE3E4EB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2027 to carry out this section, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H80B6DFDCF2994EB8B71643F6E84FD588"><enum>4.</enum><header>Lasting affordability homeownership grant pilot program</header> <subsection id="HA77F286DDDDF45F0800C000FE6DD7151"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>) shall establish a pilot program to provide grants to eligible entities.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HFC8C67D5CE474177BC7659263CBA547A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives amounts under this section shall use such amounts to—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF774F182A9C442C19415CFB1D29173A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchase vacant land to develop housing and sell that housing to homebuyers or members of a limited equity cooperative; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D2B467F6BC8480F897E53A51DF80CF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>purchase existing properties or predeveloped land on which properties will be developed that will be sold to homebuyers or members of a limited equity cooperative.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE598992E3A9443D959545230684C4F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize the award of grants to eligible entities that will maintain affordability for the homes sold by the eligible entity for the longest term.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83C84DD7050040B2A6138B662C2E68D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71F6CE48A7D6427596D62CB320002E3B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vacant land</header><text>In the case of vacant land purchased by an eligible entity under this section, the housing shall be built and marketed for sale not later than 3 years after the date of the purchase, which period may be extended at the discretion of the Secretary for extenuating circumstances, such as delays in the development process, provided that the Secretary makes public a list of localities where such extenuating circumstances are occurring.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11C1A7835CAC497B8651CD38C471E142"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing land or properties</header><text>In the case of existing properties or predeveloped land purchased by an eligible entity under this section, the homes shall be ready for sale to homebuyers not later than 3 years after the date of the purchase, which period may be extended at the discretion of the Secretary for extenuating circumstances.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2600BDBCA954507BAF457E2998B4ECC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>All properties</header><text>Each home developed with amounts provided under this section shall be sold to households—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3FE7F47489E465A8B18CFBDE24704BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with an income that is less than or equal to—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F32441365CA46E4BFAA3763FD4FAA03"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">80 percent of the area median income; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5AE25A7AB4FE458E89E8513DC36B78B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>120 percent of the area median income, if the home is located in a rural area;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C779AC7D0C34261B6ADEFC72D7B5E7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with ground leases, deed restrictions, covenants, or other mechanisms to ensure permanent affordability; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD57A8AE3D87B4F99914D5E2CCA6B0363"><enum>(C)</enum><text>according to a resale formula determined by the eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EDB19C317CA4D849FC1C0D99D7D238F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H725B8D75273440A1B877EFAFCE24CE60"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entity reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after receiving a grant under this section, and biennially for 6 years thereafter, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary a streamlined report that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HA90CAE2C7A134CA294BEC089D6714FDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as applicable, the number of acres purchased;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1F2D75104B4F42FB8C335751AA36C048"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as applicable, the number of units purchased;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2CC9F978221461C935120B973E3AA22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as applicable, the number of buildings and units developed;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3D8773BF4F124B99B2CC3AE3A255384D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>as applicable, the number of buildings and units renovated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H826A0D1805094FC0B7A19529BBFA428B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of the ground leases, deed restrictions, covenants, or other mechanisms used to ensure permanent affordability;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4674DFC3016C4FA698DB5104B54DC967"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of the resale formula used;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H718B1F2097A84125BAD327B9F4C36C1E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the number of households served;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6AD50B1947DC43DAACC13EB7BECB185A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the average size of units;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D42BA79ADE44A888268AC74A68D362C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the median purchase price;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5D4BD93F707416481E24281DC1DA688"><enum>(J)</enum><text>to the extent possible, the average amount of the down payment paid by households;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F4BA64D9BEB4F5D9F3C4FCF4A3A55FA"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the average tenure of residents;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5ED0A31474514CB88C045AE54ACB837C"><enum>(L)</enum><text>to the extent possible, the average credit score of purchasers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EEDAEE3CB9C4879AD15BE7FC101A13D"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the average delinquency and foreclosure rate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3DADD9A6DE634BE2B804F4472C4B4165"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the average annual resident fees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA563D189CE794F76938678E857540839"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the conclusion of each fiscal year in which assistance under this section is made available, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on this section that contains, with aggregates, averages, and summaries, as appropriate, information provided by eligible entities under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H53FF93D92B7A42F7B58A1D5CCDFEB6FD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97A88BBE6D164BAEBEA7A20E2D5B1BB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54E9BA6136E34308A47A4A69B6E61973"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) may be used to provide technical assistance to eligible entities that receive a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HFA2F8532E47B4D0F89F6E152E0ABE1BB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Shared equity housing research and awareness programs</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77AC5A8719944C3CB8D4D15E05233CBA"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Housing research</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDDF85CB952242939D3D44337CEEF6F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the <term>Secretary</term>), acting through the Office of Policy Development and Research, shall establish a program that conducts, supports, and disseminates research about best practices for community land trusts and other shared equity homeownership models, including best practices regarding ground leases, deed restrictions, or other legal mechanisms for preserving long-term affordability.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD801F0D9D914E4290372C7CA2210827"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Awards</header><text>For States, local governments, Tribal governments, and entities managing shared equity homeownership models, including nonprofit organizations, the Secretary shall provide funding to organizations representing nonprofit shared equity model interests to create or sustain shared equity homeownership models through technical assistance and capacity building.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF433B4807A5434486F858946A9BFC4F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79422BCEA64340279C210A10E06BEE0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public awareness</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB469D0D6CF284F858B53C3A7667B6396"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a public awareness campaign to educate the public and the financial sector about the benefits and responsibilities of shared equity homeownership models, including community land trusts, which may include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H43F978FBDAE349CCBBB24B97A93C7B9A"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>creating a web page to publicize shared equity homeownership models;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE41AFC4064E44EA1B605E2C47F1851E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disseminating information to housing counseling agencies or other entities to provide information to potential homebuyers;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2F12EDFB935842A791B1AD78F88675EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing information to lenders about the shared equity homeownership model, including standard ground leases and appraisal guidance developed by the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD427419B280149F7B0064D1667AB6CA1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to the extent possible, work with States, local governments, Tribal governments, and entities managing shared equity homeownership models, including nonprofit organizations, to advance public awareness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2B42F607AFE43DE8AD998321412446C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2029 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F8DD52E85A342108AB47478CD77E45C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Outreach</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF65E8292C6A74B678951F9AF74060FED"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text>The Secretary, in consultation and coordination with other appropriate entities, including the Federal Housing Finance Agency, shall carry out an education and outreach campaign to inform and educate consumers, homebuilders, residential lenders, and other real estate professionals on the availability, benefits, and advantages of community land trusts and other shared equity homeownership models.</text>
                </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C54BC543C794E1B9C0E3FC52BEFB889"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6D285D66B5744C71B2200A17F05CE2F0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the conclusion of each fiscal year in which assistance under this section is made available, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on the shared equity housing research and awareness programs described in this section that includes, for the period covered by the report—</text>
<paragraph id="H3F959E30D4DF49A8B8FF210A1BB1D4D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of public awareness and public outreach campaigns conducted by the Secretary;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB272914E6184AF2A853DB45746E2F02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of consultation and coordination efforts with the Federal Housing Finance Agency, including a description of Federal Housing Finance Agency activities to improve mortgage lender education and outreach that resulted from consultation and coordination efforts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H34E2129928174335A6A0DDEBD1952A2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the research conducted on best practices for community land trusts and other shared equity homeownership models; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC788E3610FDC450B8B76B25D16F06A1F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number and location of entities that received technical assistance and capacity building on community land trusts and other shared equity homeownership models.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H8384EFE9AE5D4B86914AB82D76FC4E1F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Surplus land</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H535AB2D96F1D4F30B509B74B509102FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 550 of title 40, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEBAC31CFB2A4AB1B537103E8BE2D33F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9118DE33D5C14CFEAE4F5EC15B7E1CFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Definition</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Definitions</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD1D51804C1B5425CB00E08D03E72B4D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section, the term</quote> and inserting</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H53B741BE12D34D40B80E756790FBD278"><text>section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F9D9E17CFB34078A21F14B329B08724"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>shared equity homeownership model</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the <short-title>Permanent Housing Affordability Act</short-title>; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAAF0F6D188F4ECD86CAFDDE0C6450C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(2)(D), by inserting <quote>and for property transferred under subsection (i) to a community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model</quote> after <quote>families</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1CF19EA949604A06BD6654BD47F05673"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0FC3925BF56941C2B590FF8229E9AFB1">
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34FBDD3F049B468CA37A3596E04233BE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Property for community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7FA830333674E13A1B84A44EE2D9C01"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may convey to a community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model the right, title, and interest of the Government in and to any surplus real property that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development determines is suitable for a community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC27252ADFD241DBA20C99F159B7041B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deed of conveyance</header><text>The deed of conveyance of any surplus real property disposed of under this subsection—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD210E256242849F687633D0E4127B0B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall provide that all of the property be used and maintained for purposes of a community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model in perpetuity, and that if the property ceases to be used or maintained in a community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model, all or any portion of the property shall, in its then existing condition, at the option of the Government, revert to the Government; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0F295B7B093E49F1A0A400C4E10C8AED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may contain additional terms, reservations, restrictions, and conditions the Administrator determines are necessary to safeguard the interests of the Government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H381D00DB75E940E48EF22FFBB53C1A09"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fixing value</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDDC0F2761F1468197C3B30E493E7CAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>In fixing the sale or lease value of property disposed of under paragraph (2), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall take into consideration and discount the value for any benefit which has accrued or may accrue to the Government from the use of the property by the community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2F285DD95374CC2A05536B812D1C5FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount of discount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the discount under subparagraph (A) is 75 percent of the market value of the property, except that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may discount by a greater percentage if the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator, determines that a higher percentage is justified.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H835A93CAF976406383C84B42CCC7E182"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the conclusion of each fiscal year in which assistance under section 550(i) of title 40, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), is made available, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall submit to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a report on surplus land that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H0661021F8E5143C0B819F0BBBD740112"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of surplus real properties conveyed by the Federal Government for the purpose of affordable housing, including such properties that were conveyed to a community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFD3EC7E0D41B4DD6ADF7AAA69CFE0FBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the average discounted value of real property conveyed by the Federal Government for the purpose of affordable housing, including such real property that was conveyed to a community land trust or other shared equity homeownership model.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill>

