<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H01D65817E4624BADAE8BBEB198EB70B8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8649 IH: Expanding the Defense Industrial Base Sales Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8649</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Arms Export Control Act to authorize the use of foreign military financing for direct commercial contracts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDB139960329C4E84BE2CB385CCDFB9C8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H89EA446740FD4CC0A3A5EF91592860FA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding the Defense Industrial Base Sales Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H9904F8BF6DF740328FA8336DA50A5CCE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of foreign military financing for direct commercial contracts</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 23 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H26CFC0326D514CBC88FC0C237E61A032" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2F255B2761B24C90B93E3112BE101A5B"><enum>23A.</enum><header>Use of foreign military financing for direct commercial contracts</header> 
<subsection id="H152C985506FF4D14A622588E8090D07D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Notwithstanding section 23(h), funds made available to carry out the foreign military financing program under this Act may be used to finance the procurement by any foreign country or international organization eligible to receive such financing under this Act of defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services that are not sold by the United States Government.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H562EAA819EE14E30AC3BE16C7A027B93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval and oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of foreign military financing authorized in subsection (a) shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H07051D3F2CB3431BB3B0DE1F2FAB4C23"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be approved by the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, prior to the extension of such authority to any foreign country or international organization; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE457628F0FCD4074AC509D371EFBD3CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be subject to such terms, conditions, and limitations as the Secretary of State determines appropriate to advance the foreign policy and national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8696C6263864F3596640AE2013EC909"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementing regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall prescribe regulations to implement this section, including regulations relating to, with respect to foreign military financing for direct commercial contracts authorized in subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H74A8CD850E1A47C7884124C949C9C2F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procedures for review and approval;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD53E4FFF459E4BCA87F6420E5C395D96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>audit, reporting, and financial accountability standards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8886251D24D4ACA8EC572270EFF27C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>compliance with end-use monitoring and export control requirements; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC05C6E7ED3094142B44FB55834947955"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">efforts to encourage participation by nontraditional defense companies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF236A964F83F43E1BEC78CC8B463A79E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The authority provided by this section is in addition to, and shall not be construed to limit or replace, the foreign military sales program otherwise authorized by this Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

