<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42AFF9CBE23447BDA059C269C9630644" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8591 IH: No Capital Gains Tax on Family Farms Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Ms. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000246">Mr. Edwards</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001316">Mr. Burlison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000482">Ms. Fedorchak</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an exclusion from gross income of gain from the sale of qualified farm property to qualified family members.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA879857EF9EE40ADB8358216E8E7C53B" style="OLC"><section id="HE39418DC69EF4582A01F7BD48A17E939" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Capital Gains Tax on Family Farms Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H527CA6508CEB465F80662DED1C80D054"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income of gain from sale of qualified farm property to qualified family members</header><subsection id="H0A2A8014343F4F17B2DDEDA431716184"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part III of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 121 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H18EEBD1F90E24907BDCF5CAC710FB469" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H461D2855172D41AA90C830EC9A1E79CC"><enum>121A.</enum><header>Exclusion of gain from sale of qualified farm property to qualified family members</header><subsection id="H7BCEF61CE6194B40953258648C96D6A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Gross income shall not include gain from the sale or exchange of qualified farm property to a qualified family member of the taxpayer.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4F63002C043749329184177B474AAFEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H5584205238F0440F97F159116038187A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified farm property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified farm property</term> means any interest in real property located in the United States if, during periods aggregating 2 years or more during the 8-year period ending on the date of the sale or exchange of such real property, such real property was owned and used as a farm for farming purposes (within the meaning of section 2032A(e)) by the taxpayer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48F11B35C0D14995A4B8A6CE4B275F64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualified family member</header><text>The term <term>qualified family member</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer—</text><subparagraph id="HDA9F8F67D96246B999AD0B9082052511"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the spouse of such taxpayer,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H645DBD9466724E0BA94BC95C0C6DD9E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a lineal descendant of such taxpayer, of such taxpayer’s spouse, of a parent of such taxpayer, or of a parent of such taxpayer’s spouse, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H874075A18E0443D392633AC52950B955"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the spouse of any lineal descendant described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of the preceding sentence, a legally adopted child of an individual shall be treated as the child of such individual by blood.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC1D0CB8FC4D488DB3E9914429CDB7A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header><paragraph id="HB18AF8AA7C8A4516891C375A098FE55D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basis of qualified farm property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><subparagraph id="HBBA9E6BFAF4A422C915A41EC03BEB72F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The basis of qualified farm property in the hands of a qualified family member following a sale or exchange described in subsection (a) shall be the adjusted basis of such qualified farm property in the hands of the taxpayer immediately before such sale or exchange.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H704D4BABD95140A9BD1A63488C8A2DB8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Increased basis following 10-year holding period</header><text>If, following a sale or exchange described in subsection (a), the qualified farm property is not sold, exchanged, or otherwise disposed of for the 10-year period beginning on the date of such sale or exchange, the basis of such qualified farm property in the hands of the qualified family member (as of the first day following such 10-year period) shall be increased by an amount equal to the excess (if any) of—</text><clause id="H6D093D6AD47B448C88C84FC70C82F83E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the fair market value of such qualified farm property (as of the date of such sale or exchange), over</text></clause><clause id="HBB430D3C230B43A7A1A2352995B1F6B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the basis of such qualified farm property in the hands of such qualified family member (as otherwise determined under subparagraph (A)).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91B158B8D3084751851C0C76731E081C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election to have section not apply</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 121(f) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47BB8843D60A49AE8F8E85600E3DD34A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including with respect to the application of subsection (c)(1)(B) in cases other than where the entire interest in qualified farm property is not sold, exchanged, or otherwise disposed of for the applicable 10-year period.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0C540F009E3E4ECDAD298B7531BBE5F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for part III of subchapter B of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 121 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD5838B8429284CAD923DB38F8B8489B4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 121A. Exclusion of gain from sale of qualified farm property to qualified family members.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0C0689395B3D4C0DAB926442BE29E5E0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to sales or exchanges after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

