<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H43DAB76313374BA79BA2026E395A34FE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8284 IH: Bureau of Industry and Security License Administration Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8284</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance the administration of export control licenses under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018, and other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE92B9619052148B48701F8B5261FFA69" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFCA1FF50DD34418C9A271C5FDBAB7EE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bureau of Industry and Security License Administration Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA2F4175D053D4DA597DA5945A583570E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhancement of administration of export control licenses</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part I of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (50 U.S.C. 4801 et. seq.) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HCD61252ADFFE41D7927A22D63C762656" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6E1D661039AC4C88A2407E569BAFFA0C"><enum>1769.</enum><header>Enhancement of administration of export control licenses</header> 
<subsection id="HF316E671B7D04E898E5263301AD169C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhancement of administration of certain communications</header> 
<paragraph id="H3DB80006E16B4870865EA59B9CB89344"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer any export control license or other authorization considered pursuant to an is-informed letter or similar targeted regulatory guidance or supplemental license requirement communication sent to a United States person or foreign person by the same interagency process as any license or other authorization administered pursuant to the Export Administration Regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B215F39A2A54F8AA15BB379E23C7803"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 60 days after issuing a license or other authorization described in paragraph (1), the is-informed letter or similar targeted regulatory guidance or supplemental license requirement communication with respect to the license or authorization shall terminate unless the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, publishes in the Code of Federal Regulations a regulation that provides for the parameters of the letter or guidance or publishes in the Federal Register the communication.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H64AB413C29884B0FBB13C24552B4E09A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters relating to the presumption of denial standard</header> 
<paragraph id="H7B384F5573FA41CE9608D03FA6B05D02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to prevent United States and allied technology from being used to facilitate the military modernization and human rights abuses of foreign adversaries.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED0E2AB7CC0B487293ADC7F130A51C8F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standards and factors for presumption of denial standard</header> <subparagraph id="H60827660DA8F43DBAB27DB2F973C2445"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, shall publish in the Federal Register the standards and factors that licensing officers should consider when considering a license under a presumption of denial standard.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FAF83F010AB4DA79609E8B98F21B101"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 7 days prior to the date the Secretary publishes or otherwise makes available to the public such standards and factors, the Secretary shall submit such standards and factors to—</text> <clause id="HC4B0F9B5ECCE4E71809AAB3B1F935466"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4BB5136004B940219400036C04B6AF37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H5706FCD806954E749F536784AF8C1A05"><enum>3.</enum><header>Export control technical advisory committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1754 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC2A152B2E5A2459B970CF7488686C1C6" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H2845D926F54F486BBC3855848306BF29"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical advisory committees</header> 
<paragraph id="H85E662CAAC0F4F43A8FF1D3E164BFB57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The technical advisory committees shall advise the Secretary on—</text> <subparagraph id="H40FF1B41BA524775AB23F12B8B541F99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the state of global technology supply chains and the development of advanced technologies by adversaries;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2211DCE9E7344B07B68A246B12B1D02E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>national security threats posed by access by adversaries to technologies sourced from the United States or an ally of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DD7D28975C743A29CB22D2B35C07834"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technical parameters for export controls;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5CD56B72BCD4E43B2D4ECAD0D7908A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which existing and proposed export controls achieve the policy of the United States described in section 1752;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD364759531AC4002889C167203510B12"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the identification of emerging and foundational technologies pursuant to section 1758;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCF478472AB584BC2964E5656F6741F8A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improvements to export licensing procedures, compliance mechanisms, and export enforcement strategies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6AABE1AF98A4129AA9117A2EB0312AE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other matter requested by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6CB91029D5041C1BC661D110BEF2E2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required committees</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint a technical advisory committee for each of the following topics:</text> <subparagraph id="H5B0312E4D4244F75BFF234EDC739665A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Computing technologies and information systems, including semiconductors, microelectronics, artificial intelligence, and quantum computing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EED273D6A984FC68D890988D04ECBA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Biotechnologies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E5E872138B5476A99A9ED42CA0FCF77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Automation, including robotics, advanced manufacturing, and autonomous systems.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB601748215034C8383204A62BC7D27DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Aerospace and space technologies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF92BADCD934E4D218E4CAE50B3ADB1E7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Advanced materials.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36BAE714D7D6406FB5A45D79C95DD6D3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Weapons of mass destruction.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4A018F9B0834C22AF58705B1DDC9108"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Emerging and foundational technologies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16512B972947405DB1CC89A99DE5009B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Regulations and procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABB11544228D4519933CC8B7835585B1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subcommittees</header><text>The Secretary may appoint subcommittees for any technical advisory committee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27B76B190A2042A087F1741C7A54F23E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Committee review</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary may, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, review the technical advisory committees and create additional committees or adjust the topics of existing committees as necessary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8F1EE1A4D724AE39CCD837C7078EDB9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Choosing committees</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, shall adjust the topics of the technical advisory committees to reflect relevant executive branch strategies and critical technology lists, such as the National Security Strategy, the National Defense Strategy, the AI Action Plan (or a successor plan), the Critical and Emerging Technologies List (or a successor list), and the America First Investment Policy Memorandum (or a successor memorandum).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90B2B2F158C849658078AA36AF97D4C7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF9579381AA8643519D143E78978C8BAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The membership of each technical advisory committee shall be equally divided between national security experts, technical specialists from a relevant industry, and academic experts in a relevant field.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED1C813FE8314BEEA4D72DBB16C5CE75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of a member on a technical advisory committee shall be 3 years.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD3A08D7792A74067BC2C14D9A37F433F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Non-disclosure agreement</header><text>No individual may serve as a member of a technical advisory committee unless such individual has entered into a binding non-disclosure agreement with the Secretary that prohibits the individual from making an unauthorized disclosure of proprietary information, policy deliberations, and national security information communicated through or related to a technical advisory committee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79B5DDA6ED5E425F9B7106D701483F91"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Staffing</header><text>The Secretary shall process applications to join any technical advisory committee in a timely manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64704DC5549A4AD9851DA955E560B05D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Meetings</header> 
<subparagraph id="H59AACA9012B7493EA63B0ADA0F9AC84F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>Each technical advisory committee shall meet not less frequently than once every 120 days.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C58B5062D30452DA6A68FC90158AAC0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission of minutes</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the minutes of each meeting of a technical advisory committee within 30 days of each meeting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H49CF31550BA7440482438C9ADFE8E494"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Webpage</header><text>The Bureau of Industry and Security shall maintain on the website of the Bureau a webpage describing each technical advisory committee, including the membership and meeting schedule of each such committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22AAE157BB9146919D8EC17D613EC307"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Technology and policy assessment</header><text>Each technical advisory committee shall, not less frequently than annually, submit to the Secretary, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Energy, and the appropriate congressional committees—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H326A434BC6FE4C81B5B0ED6D05553AB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of developments within the purview of the technical advisory committee; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96A92106B4B14D8DAD7AA9131BC513BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations related to the purview of the technical advisory committee for advancing the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA8CE288F16B1470DB4CACAE23C3B4883"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H728DF9F03E8245BF9961403555DC578B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Adversary</header><text>The term <term>adversary</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H96495428DE9C4F6A9975D9F6F4C6B606"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China, including the Hong Kong and Macau Special Administrative Regions;</text></clause> <clause id="H9B730D9989B741B880BABAE69093F4B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Republic of Cuba;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE2FE55EBFE9F4FE6B73EFED1C4DCA3FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text></clause> <clause id="H3077481F677F4B0AA296BEB48BD3AA93"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5870A66E82BD4EA998E0D676DC148273"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Russian Federation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H49A67597F2C64386BCBF5673728B52DF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other foreign country listed in Country Group D:5 under Supplement No. 1 to part 740 of the Export Administration Regulations, as published on January 1, 2026, that is designated by the Secretary of State as an adversary for purposes of this section and for which notice of such designation has been published in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7A3D81204EAA4B85ADE6FEF234872E51"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9E4191A89EB45AFA14C4411C3F40956"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Technical advisory committee</header><text>The term <term>technical advisory committee</term> means a technical advisory committee appointed pursuant to subsection (a)(13).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H5311B8B8C28E4682BFF69F048C219C76"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review and report regarding controlled integrated circuits</header> 
<subsection id="H5A1B40A67E7E491EB80C6A1DAB74025D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Secretary of State, Secretary of Defense, and Secretary of Energy, shall regularly review the implementation of the interim final rule of the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce entitled <quote>Implementation of Additional Due Diligence Measures for Advanced Computing Integrated Circuits; Amendments and Clarifications; and Extension of Comment Period</quote>, published in the Federal Register on January 16, 2025 (90 Fed. Reg. 5298; Docket No. 250108–0013), or any substantially similar successor rule, and consider any appropriate update or change to such rule to ensure that such rule is implemented effectively and fulfills the initial policy intent of such rule.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3A6746B249C64ACB9E82855FA8EAE81F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Energy, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H04C741AF316D41DEB2A5DF651DB86A8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the review required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF487BB57222E4171A16544D1EAAA1E4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any change to the rule described in such subsection that has been made or is under consideration pursuant to such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0D32DA258EDF4EF7B56622099C319E00"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H72B2AB37E6A3455B8E8B168922EACEA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFA8D528F6D0E4DFAB9450A96FBDDFA6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E618C943D1841F09B3B742FCBDCD168"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD05EADE70E2044FCB95068A271D469FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce acting through the Under Secretary for Industry and Security.</text></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

