<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7AB3BD999840496A9339DA7671354F0D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6621 IH: Workforce of the Future Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6621</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote a 21st-century workforce, to authorize grants to support emerging and advanced technology education, and to support training and quality employment for workers in industries most impacted by artificial intelligence.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC279EC2ACB1343BE8ACF5197EA646915" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H29721FBFA22A4635AF9D321B06E578B8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce of the Future Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H10A7B2F7C46D4E1593A9BC01CADDAB18"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H29721FBFA22A4635AF9D321B06E578B8">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H10A7B2F7C46D4E1593A9BC01CADDAB18">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H7D4C4CA2E9FE423B86F057598149396F">TITLE I—Impact of Artificial Intelligence on Jobs</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H5962B3AC3D9F46059F2B5B15F638C1F1">Sec. 101. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H81A9C11764B848519DBE84A8ED11DD4D">Sec. 102. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H39519CC3060A4910B7A76DE09F76F443">Sec. 103. Report on artificial intelligence.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H94C523B054BD467695B0296D32BBB198">TITLE II—Emerging and Advanced Technology Education and Workforce Development</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H0508BE450C05425799A5B6ADE660E247">Sec. 201. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H95360E5117E943A2B304D9171D55D1D9">Sec. 202. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA7F4602D02D44C4CB8E8095004E5C3BD">Sec. 203. Department of Education grants.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC047060D25C84243A631545C35891446">Sec. 204. Department of Labor grants.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H660E971ADE504647B2D5DAA8D03EC73C">Sec. 205. Reporting requirements.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H94E91EB4EE7F4CD7851956E593F85971">Sec. 206. Amendments to the Education Sciences Reform Act.</toc-entry></toc></section><title id="H7D4C4CA2E9FE423B86F057598149396F" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Impact of Artificial Intelligence on Jobs</header><section id="H5962B3AC3D9F46059F2B5B15F638C1F1"><enum>101.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H991F7CF161E94772A0A5475E8E5484F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while the field of artificial intelligence is evolving quickly and has potential to disrupt jobs, there are opportunities to prepare the American workforce to develop and work alongside this new technology and mitigate the potential negative consequences of job displacement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70019A7798BB4A5DB87B4A51E884CB0D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure these opportunities, it is imperative to identify the following:</text><subparagraph id="H3827198A8DC949049E2FA6FF8BC07029"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data and data access necessary to properly analyze the impact of artificial intelligence on the United States workforce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AE28383AE174C8E89152F28A15A12E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Industries projected to be most impacted by artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F207D9735F448E1AC6A252144596C02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Opportunities for workers and other stakeholders to influence the impact of artificial intelligence across industries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C22E6F1CE3D48D3AE690E79CF814800"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Characteristics of workers and communities whose career opportunities are most likely to be affected by the growth of artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6699A1010E514189A091F93C93C46DE9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The skills, expertise, and education needed to develop, operate, or work alongside artificial intelligence.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ECA3B0328AA4DC0A3444567B02846C8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Methods to ensure necessary skills, expertise, and education are accessible to all segments of the current and future workforce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H81A9C11764B848519DBE84A8ED11DD4D"><enum>102.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="H166FF0F94F4B49CF90E6774D32B150D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A404EA70FDA4306A3F69D8D85456C6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community college</header><text>The term <term>community college</term> has the meaning given the term <term>junior or community college</term> in section 312(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H504CEFFDBE20446B9DA8940302832092"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3DBE785E344C4965B293CD9DE16871AD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> includes a labor organization as defined in section 2(5) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152(5)</external-xref>) and an organization representing public sector employees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B849E64A264D9E9FB119C9465BC6C4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H359F25E9DB77418FB98C25B44DED54F3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text>The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means an eligible institution as described in section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H288EAB144BFB4F18A5183E1D8A2BB063"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDFC6E252C56944AF9881664D84F58578"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Technical college</header><text>The term <term>technical college</term> means a postsecondary vocational institution, as that term is defined in section 102(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H241D946023AD4EF3A6AC2A708EF19E80"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text>The term <term>Tribal College or University</term> has the meaning given the term in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H39519CC3060A4910B7A76DE09F76F443"><enum>103.</enum><header>Report on artificial intelligence</header><subsection id="HAABC2FA0EA6947A3A61579ED6F2E68E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E1939A0A7FC47CA811D5D6E79B51D8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim and final reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Education shall, jointly and in collaboration with the individuals and entities described in subsection (c), prepare and submit to the Committee on Education and Workforce, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate—</text><subparagraph id="H2FF837213D4D4991BFA18136A6AD62D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, an interim report on artificial intelligence and its impact on the workforce of the United States, which shall include the information and recommendations listed in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H185487E06EB04D91BDA475FD0F9546AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, a final report on artificial intelligence and its impact on the workforce of the United States, which shall include the information and recommendations listed in subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACA5ED59D6014EF19F06A4F656B9BA77"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 3 years after the final report described in subparagraph (B) is submitted, an updated report reassessing the information and recommendations listed in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D39D3978F59496EA3E6DDCEE52FE850"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Education to establish procedures for the preparation and submission of the interim and final reports described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H80A82DB78E144CEF8D037D945AF25DA4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required information</header><text>Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H43519B96F6154B2A997A6207DEE305F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of the specific data relating to the workforce, and the availability of such data, necessary to properly analyze the impact and growth of artificial intelligence on the workforce of the United States and outline how much of this data is privately owned, and the effectiveness of Federal, State, or industry efforts (including public-private partnerships) to make privately owned data on the workforce of the United States available for Federal research purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2E384A4605924C7FA1399B38B8EA4C75"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of industries and occupations projected to have the most growth in artificial intelligence use, the extent to which the technology is likely to result in the enhancement of workers’ capabilities or their displacement, and level of education currently consistent with industries and occupations identified.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4C96B00323240E083373F92F4F271E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Analysis of how growth in artificial intelligence use will impact job quality in the industries and occupations identified in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4BEE36C9CBD944B2B3C625546E4587AA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of opportunities for workers, educators, institutions of higher education, Congress, labor organizations, or other relevant stakeholders to influence the impact of artificial intelligence on workers across various industries.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD6B7991576254CA1BE1B0A6E80774ABF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Analysis of how educational entities, workforce development organizations, and labor organizations can collaborate to advance new opportunities for education and workforce development to support an artificial intelligence-enabled economy and workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4A17C591F0B14D56957918F6F3913F58"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analysis of which demographics (including ethnic, race, gender, economic, age, disability status, and regional) currently stand to experience expanded career opportunities, and which demographics currently appear most vulnerable to career displacement, due to artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6A5E51ED57B647E5B08A68506F831A58"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analysis of the skills, expertise, and education in emerging and advanced technology needed to develop, operate, or work alongside artificial intelligence over the next decades, as compared to the levels of such comparable expertise and education among the workforce as of the date of enactment of this Act, with a differentiation between core competencies required across the entire workforce and competencies required within the industries and occupations identified in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HAED71F2C32E34EC4A88224E847FB9C0B"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of methods by which necessary skills, expertise, and education can be effectively delivered to various segments of the United States workforce, including promising efforts underway as of the time of the report that can be expanded.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H239E4C489450451F82E68BDBB354399A"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of industry leaders, institutions of higher education, and labor organizations at the forefront of research and application of artificial intelligence in the industries and occupations identified in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H09EAAC0B9FC546769991EBB4E212C201"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of the resources and opportunities required for labor organizations and institutions of higher education, including community colleges, technical colleges, minority-serving institutions (including Tribal Colleges and Universities), and institutions of higher education serving rural areas, to deliver skills, expertise, and education identified in paragraph (7).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A79D827D27F4738B08D856E95314F2E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Identification of the demographic characteristics and educational background (including level of education) of the individuals who deliver skills, expertise, and education to students at the institutions described in paragraph (10).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H076B5F54411041EBA2E9FB5678EBA1BF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Recommendations to support enhanced workforce development and prepare future workforce members for the artificial intelligence economy, and any other relevant observations or recommendations within the field of emerging and advanced technology, which shall include recommendations on—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H29D53D00CC3246F89903F3222619AD09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>methods to expand public access to privately owned workforce data and government-owned workforce data, for the purpose of researching the effect of emerging technologies on the United States workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9579AB8B7DB64108BF0F5D712D0937C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>policy, regulatory, or programmatic options for stakeholders (workers, educators, institutions of higher education, Congress, labor organizations, or other relevant stakeholders) to effectively enhance educational and workforce development opportunities, including mitigating perceived negative impacts of artificial intelligence on segments of the United States workforce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA1C9A332E290495B9CFE720A6915AA48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations to employers on best practices to engage workers and representatives of workers, including labor organizations, in decision-making on the integration of artificial intelligence into the workplace;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC5A5928E1EA841E289306116483AE94B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>methods to upskill or mitigate earnings or income losses to demographic groups identified in paragraph (6) as most vulnerable to career displacement, due to artificial intelligence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H067DE4A9342E4460B4AB0CB95DAE661D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>methods to encourage low cost, open source sharing of industry valued credentials certifying the types of skills, expertise, and education identified in paragraph (7);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC688B5C5221445FB2AB05CA405BD58D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>methods to ensure core skills and competencies identified in paragraph (7) can be evaluated, updated, and made public by relevant stakeholders as needed, given rapid developments in the field of artificial intelligence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90EA514441A040C49F5119D58EE03D74"><enum>(G)</enum><text>methods to ensure community colleges, technical colleges, minority-serving institutions (including Tribal Colleges and Universities), and institutions of higher education serving rural areas receive resources and opportunities identified in paragraph (10);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D547B7C38184F4C93832A0C6F165B8C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>methods to promote knowledge sharing and capacity building between industry leaders, labor organizations, and institutions identified in paragraph (9) and community colleges, technical colleges, minority-serving institutions (including Tribal Colleges and Universities), and rural institutions of higher education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4479270002A445818578E7A73872A669"><enum>(I)</enum><text>other methods to ensure that the skills, expertise, and education needed to develop, operate, or work alongside artificial intelligence are delivered to vulnerable demographic groups identified in paragraph (6), rural workers, and other historically underserved segments of the United States workforce (including workers with disabilities).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28DE7D0C15B146D4832274A072B1B06C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Education shall collaborate, through a series of public meetings, roundtables or other methods, with—</text><paragraph id="HB6911D8D78FE4334B25E6B53AC2DC40B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local educational agencies, State educational agencies, State agencies with responsibility for the administration of a core program (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)), institutions of higher education (including community colleges, technical colleges, minority-serving institutions (including Tribal Colleges and Universities), and institutions of higher education serving rural areas), labor organizations, workforce-training organizations, National Laboratories, and teacher and educator preparation programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B102CBC0254C5FA7A13548AB56B66E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a broad range of industrial stakeholders in the technology, manufacturing, employment, human resources, and service sectors, including companies (large and small), think tanks, organized labor, and industry organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD5B5A047E904FACBDE6539EA8175AAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, including by sharing relevant information obtained as a result of the study conducted under section 5105 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 4530); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2A5A49370224D0FBE5C9493E457060E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Director of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Office, the National Cyber Director, and the heads of any other Federal agency the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Education determine appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H94C523B054BD467695B0296D32BBB198" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Emerging and Advanced Technology Education and Workforce Development</header><section id="H0508BE450C05425799A5B6ADE660E247"><enum>201.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H16B004253AC34343B70357AE7A868ACE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Emerging and advanced technologies are transforming industry, creating new fields of commerce, driving innovation, and bolstering productivity. Emerging and advanced technology and information occupations are projected to grow by 377,500 jobs per year on average between 2022 and 2032, much faster than the average for all other occupations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H20486D8075ED4CE497178A4B6B789EE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As of 2024, more than 400,000 computing and technology jobs remain unfilled in the United States. These unfilled jobs present a significant opportunity for individuals to advance in the 21st-century economy. It is projected that there will be 660,000 new jobs in the technology and computing sector by 2032. However, the availability of emerging and advanced technology education at the time of enactment of this Act does not equitably provide all students in the United States with the tools to fill these technology sector jobs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98099C8B04B84977B2324F55FDC2ADE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Given the rapidly increasing interest and deployment of artificial intelligence and other new technologies in the workplace, knowledge of, and the skills to use, emerging and advanced technology is increasingly essential for all individuals, not just those working or planning to work in the technology sector.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB1462F8FEF64E5EBBE0FE166EC83C74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing students with emerging and advanced technology education in elementary school and secondary school is critical for student success, and strengthening the workforce of a 21st-century economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5027225C5A304D5C9FB3CF2BE2ED122A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>While an estimated 90 percent of parents want technology, such as computer science, taught in their children’s schools, just 44 percent of all middle schools and 57.5 percent of secondary schools offer high-quality technology instruction that includes programming and coding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H653A8CD8AAB14E83AE4521E4893A2D33"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Lack of universal emerging and advanced technology education is evident in the lack of a widespread tech industry, which is overwhelmingly concentrated in a few cities nationwide. Emerging and advanced technology education is limited to affluent schools and students, placing low-income, minority, and rural communities at risk of being left behind.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H95360E5117E943A2B304D9171D55D1D9"><enum>202.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="HACF415215FB647CDA4CB0B1E97404341"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Computational thinking</header><text>The term <term>computational thinking</term> means the wide range of creative processes that go into formulating problems and their solutions in such a way that the solutions can be carried out by a computer, and may involve some understanding of software and hardware design, logic and the use of abstraction and representation, algorithm design, algorithm expression, problem decomposition, modularity, programming paradigms and languages, issues of information security and privacy, the application of computation across a wide range of disciplines, and the societal impact of computing.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD90A50151A6E4B7AA7A56E58DC598495"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4B26A27C97C1432BAFC04AFED9ACE945"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State educational agency, as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12E7B406BCFB45ECB6745E14A6B49B85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local educational agency, as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EF94D6E0C1149C193E0F32132B5C679"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an eligible Tribal school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD13777836986436CAC80E63929992654"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a community college, which shall have the meaning given the term <term>junior or community college</term> in section 312(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89AAF9E3274E45528F902CAF19BFA7D3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a technical college or postsecondary vocational institution, as that term is defined in section 102(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE6197A78E3B4DD7A1BFF13D9B0F32ED"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a labor organization (as defined in section 102);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07134084B7424A029AE556E184C15D08"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a State agency with responsibility for a workforce development program, as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C6F20F665CE4B288BACA99BB3C0EF18"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H993ABE68843F4C99BDC0B854DACF0061"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible tribal school</header><text>The term <term>eligible Tribal school</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1194EA7A36CB455C82E1B3D198A4AA4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FE602F208314C0BB35BE6A60CB676E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a school operated pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H588933579C90410E8C7862F320ED4C8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a tribally controlled school (as defined in section 5212 of the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2511">25 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H394AD48EF953476A90C46B7832AD025F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Emerging and advanced technology education</header><text>The term <term>emerging and advanced technology education</term> includes education in any of the following: computational thinking; software design; hardware architecture and organization; theoretical foundations; use of abstraction and representation in problem solving; logic; algorithm design and implementation; the limits of computation; programming paradigms and languages; parallel and distributed computing; information security and privacy; computing systems and networks; graphics and visualization; databases and information retrieval; the relationship between computing and mathematics; artificial intelligence; quantum computing; applications of computing across a broad range of disciplines and problems; cloud computing; and the social impacts and professional practices of computing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16C3267981474F0D8A8B9B5308652DBF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H998DC51B79AE4EADBCCEAA96BCABFE2D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text>The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means an eligible institution as described in section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8591411228544ED29A2B439C06912C68"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Poverty line</header><text>The term <term>poverty line</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H846E2B92078246099A71E69F76F80BB1"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Programming</header><text>The term <term>programming</term> means a hands-on, inquiry-based way in which computational thinking may be learned.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72C8BBE24DA24FA594FCA0B0EBC560A5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A03214BF3724E80803FF259929D0242"><enum>(10)</enum><header>STEAM</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>STEAM</term> means the subjects of science, technology, engineering, arts, and mathematics, including emerging and advanced technology.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA7F4602D02D44C4CB8E8095004E5C3BD"><enum>203.</enum><header>Department of Education grants</header><subsection id="HA98479D90DBF4E849B40A85FABE9EA29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of grants</header><paragraph id="H3D9A56B074D148DF8265C8A98571D50D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to support the expansion of emerging and advanced technology education. From the amounts appropriated under subsection (g), after reserving amounts under subsection (e), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2215397CA68445CB5FF75E07754F412"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reserve 50 percent of the remaining funds to award grants to eligible entities that propose to use grant funds in accordance with subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE28D53EED1794F86B631A4A58E302712"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reserve 50 percent of the remaining funds to award grants to eligible entities that propose to use grant funds in accordance with subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB061C99A117146729EC9FF5E93C847A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consortia</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may apply for a grant under this section as part of a consortium of one or more eligible entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D1D71924FD443888CD36B543483E05D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of not less than 3 years and not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FF343003FF0436BA9E1EC14E21A9A3A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6EDFA7DCFE14062970C9C81F5D77F77"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information and recommendations included in the reports prepared under section 103; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05EF27666236499A80054865CBC1842F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">structural and other barriers facing specific demographic groups, as informed by the reports prepared under section 103.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07A74B040EF145BDB8F29BDDFA413E53"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Multiple awards</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33BD63D7CCAE479F9305A4002FD0EE8E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an eligible entity may receive only 1 grant award under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B27729ACA9448529D3A97729EEB64E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Part of consortia</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB2549B3BEC44D02B8537DC62D05C40D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may receive more than 1 grant award under this section if the eligible entity is part of consortia that receive the grant awards.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB88BD225C7FB43E9BC94E302EDEEC6AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Lead fiscal agent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives more than 1 grant award under this section as part of consortia, may be the lead fiscal agent only on 1 grant award under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC0D416D621C410AA11CFF334A32888D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04BC320C83994981B3AC226DA1B8E352"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCACA8936365946F6830596903C96B93A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that proposes to use grant funds in accordance with subsection (c) shall include in the application under paragraph (1), at a minimum, plans for the following:</text><subparagraph id="H17A2A7BE8BD146559539F2C288084F49"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Every high school student served by the eligible entity to have access to emerging and advanced technology education not later than 5 years after receipt of grant funds.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62086052657B4E6B8C818C8E635DC346"><enum>(B)</enum><text>All students served by the eligible entity to have access to a progression of emerging and advanced technology education from prekindergarten through the middle grades (as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)) that prepares students for high school emerging and advanced technology education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B04CE6F15554A75BE837F712B4B152E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Expansion of overall access to rigorous (as defined by the Secretary) STEAM classes, utilizing emerging and advanced technology as a catalyst for increased interest in STEAM more broadly, and reducing the enrollment and academic achievement gap for underrepresented groups, such as minorities, girls, and youth from families living at, or below, the poverty line.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF81DF3F92034148AD2A8D5EECE023BE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Continuous monitoring and evaluation of project activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB8A678773CC42ADB718CAAF354F6B0E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effectively sustaining project activities after the grant period ends, and the length of time which the applicant plans to sustain the project activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8913C4115C9D47658767EC53A72AB6D3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Disclosure of how the eligible entity will engage with industry to inform the project activities, and with which entities from industry they will engage.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAE613D0EA1E4E1CA82E1DBCC509DAF9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Leveraging of permissible activities described in subsection (c)(2), if relevant to support and enhance program activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62C25D51DD374CA18394824A034AEDE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant funds for emerging and advanced technology education</header><paragraph id="H80B15BF443934A82B949D282B8E8CB32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required activities</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a)(1)(A) shall use the grant funds for each of the following activities:</text><subparagraph id="H67ADC65659674E5CB9E6069367B1F06B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training teachers to teach emerging and advanced technology, including providing professional development opportunities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H851C48D3248840F5BE8B37D4A3066C58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Expanding access to high-quality learning materials and online learning options, including equipment and other related technologies and access to broadband internet that are necessary to fully perform in the area of emerging and advanced technologies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6980AE70FBE44991B35D5626EDDFB937"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Creating plans for expanding overall access to rigorous STEAM classes, utilizing emerging and advanced technology as a catalyst for increased interest in STEAM more broadly, and reducing course equity gaps for all students, including underrepresented groups, such as minorities, girls, and youth from low-income families.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42319F94783440D88166FD998988DC22"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Ensuring additional support and resources, which may include mentoring for students traditionally underrepresented in STEAM fields.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CFA6B72F6BF478A8BF808F6446C89C5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Ongoing industry engagement to receive feedback on curricula and the emerging skills needed of artificial intelligence-related jobs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54AC86F3301A43829964DB0B4B6B0CD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Permissible activities</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a)(1)(A) may use the grant funds for 1 or more of the following activities:</text><subparagraph id="HFBF7D5C1ED174A2C8B8B8A7D1EE30C3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Building effective regional collaborations with industry, nonprofit organizations, State boards and local boards (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)), institutions of higher education (including community colleges, technical colleges, and minority-serving institutions), and out-of-school providers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12FA84A9EB034D49AB5586D427DFEF57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recruiting and hiring instructional personnel as needed, including teachers and paraeducators (which shall have the meaning given the term <term>paraprofessional</term> in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)), including through support for the workforce development system (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)) in the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9C9AB4F933B4DE9A9163E0365939C80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Preparations for effectively sustaining project activities after the grant period ends.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B4A101A8FFC4D4180F6B7CD42133648"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Disseminating information about effective practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD05D07B88D6E46569DA7F689672864EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 15 percent of a grant awarded under subsection (a)(1)(A) may be used to purchase equipment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ACE74C265654E6FAB3015C57092460D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant funds for emerging and advanced technology teacher development and recruitment</header><paragraph id="H6047A773F8044748BF6AD99C129D974B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a)(1)(B) shall use the grant funds for emerging and advanced technology teacher development and recruitment, which may include professional development opportunities, loan repayment, or tuition reimbursement for service as an emerging and advanced technology teacher, or any other program designed to develop and recruit emerging and advanced technology teachers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD28986008FA54D5E98085B9E9992A7DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fulfilling obligation</header><text>If an eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a)(1)(B) uses the grant funds to implement a loan repayment program or program for tuition reimbursement for service as an emerging and advanced technology teacher, the eligible entity shall fulfill any loan repayment or tuition reimbursement obligation made to a teacher in exchange for service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67CA5A9E757847838D237E7BED1DBA26"><enum>(e)</enum><header>National activities</header><text>The Secretary may reserve not more than 2.5 percent of funds available for grants under this section for national activities, including technical assistance, evaluation, and dissemination.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H894E452DC2964747BADF8CDDD87644A2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall authorize third-party evaluations of grants awarded under this section to help build an evidence base of effective programs that advance a 21st-century artificial intelligence workforce. Such evaluations shall assess the scalability of activities funded by such grants to support the 21st-century artificial intelligence workforce.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9B17B624C8DB4156BC609AC63C9DAB39"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $160,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC047060D25C84243A631545C35891446"><enum>204.</enum><header>Department of Labor grants</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34E3A6B470D24CE1A48EA22D23E6BE07"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants authorized</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0CD7E73618E34558925785E4DF013295"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall award grants to eligible entities to support workforce training for workers most impacted by artificial intelligence. From the amounts appropriated under subsection (f), after reserving amounts under subsection (d), the Secretary of Labor shall award grants as described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7210AD6F3C62462B885C2EC92D62439F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consortia</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity may apply for a grant under this section as part of a consortium of eligible entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BBE3E7D98FF4E18B8B58099476DF199"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of not less than 3 years and not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EE6C93F38674D6FA605147DBC8CF4F2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary of Labor shall consider—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEE5D356D1A504E8DBD01F7103A559E87"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the information and recommendations included in the reports prepared under section 103; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAE563F443189468EB589B59AECB8EB29"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">structural and other barriers facing specific demographic groups, as informed by the reports prepared under section 103.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B68D7B0EDF3444A921F9EA58B9642A6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary of Labor shall give priority to eligible entities that are labor organizations representing workers in industries or occupations identified in the report under section 103(b)(2), or consortia of eligible entities that include such a labor organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6EF8E2660134F07861A1C9DEE9AA995"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant funds To serve individuals seriously affected by AI</header><paragraph id="HDB4F4FD1282840CE8E64AFCE61EF9CB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Target population</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to serve individuals who have a high school diploma or its recognized equivalent and—</text><subparagraph id="H8FDCFB8E01AD45038DF6CC279A4BACB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are employed in an industry or occupation projected, pursuant to the report under section 103(b)(2), to have the most growth in artificial intelligence use, which is likely to significantly impact the job opportunities or wages of workers; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDEC326B43954F31840B160384C10AEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not earlier than 1 year prior to the date of enactment of this Act, involuntarily separated from an industry or occupation projected, pursuant to the report under section 103(b)(2), to have the most growth in artificial intelligence use, and are eligible for unemployment insurance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11CB9A6F293C4FAF8B5096C57FE98B32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In serving the target population described in paragraph (1), an eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds for 1 or more of the following purposes:</text><subparagraph id="H2F10FDC81E2843AF823B9E7E06F5FB6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Providing training to such individuals, including skill certifications, or by supporting other programs that directly enable such individuals to enter high-skill, high-wage jobs in in-demand sectors, including emerging and advanced technology sectors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H855191E49A134B019E927275CED0AA39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Providing training to such individuals, including continuing education certificates or programs aiming—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB73246E47A1C4EBBAAC2659A8D82DA22"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to update workers’ skills related to advanced and emerging technology; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF17AF1837EE2448F88D499A2787B14DF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support maintaining or advancing in high-skill, high-wage jobs in in-demand sectors, including emerging and advanced technology sectors.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0408ACDBB697422CB90BCE82EC5C65DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary of Labor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary of Labor may require, including, at a minimum each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H2F5045A852664D4D9B9536F33E1F0C0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of project activities that will be carried out using grant funds, how such activities will serve the target population described in subsection (b)(1), and how such programs will support the growth of the 21st-century workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC444CBFC17FF4CA5AFB60CA550603883"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A detailed description of how the eligible entity will engage workers and utilize input from workers in the design of project activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2B08119F0474FE3A754A88237DF5642"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A detailed description of how job quality and wage considerations, alongside skill development, have informed project activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25BBCAF74AEB45B6B060DDB4820066FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan for continuous monitoring and evaluation of project activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC95A1774114628B14CEBF02AB7D269"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan for effectively sustaining project activities after the grant period ends, and the length of time which the applicant plans to sustain the project activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B89F9ED6E9C4C8C97A4158519D7F8D7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assurance to provide performance data, as described in subclause (I) through (VI) of section 116(b)(2)(A)(i) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3141">29 U.S.C. 3141(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECD83B5C3ED547FBB7E73EEDDD3C7359"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National activities</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may reserve not more than 2.5 percent of funds available for grants under this section for national activities, including technical assistance, evaluation, and dissemination.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF17D2645D2484E91AC53290E7BEA2BF6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABC20978FF4A484BB1517F0A02DCB665"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Labor shall authorize third-party evaluations of grants awarded under this section to help build an evidence base of programs that advance a 21st-century workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E5278C8079B42D09701FD8D7026335E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scalability; worker engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The evaluations described in paragraph (1) shall assess—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A165E6F1A2F44A7B2DF6329381CAEDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the scalability of activities funded by the grants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DD48397F58C459A867302F11C08A756"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the effectiveness of worker engagement in the design of project activities in improving training relevance, completion rates, and employment outcomes for the target population.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H385DA58D88EE4745A018E2D823668C09"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $90,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H660E971ADE504647B2D5DAA8D03EC73C"><enum>205.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="H887E03CACD0843F2A68FA69C032495D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grantee reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H831329CCA1C64052BF66B91663AD188D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that receives a grant under section 203 shall submit to the Secretary a report, not less than twice a year during the grant period, on the use of grant funds that shall include data on the numbers of individuals served through activities funded under such section, disaggregated by race (for Asian and Native Hawaiian or Pacific Islander individuals using the same race response categories as the decennial census of the population), ethnicity, gender, and eligibility to participate in the school lunch program established under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1751">42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF747AC5AD194AB6817ADAD19C12A381"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that receives a grant under section 204 shall submit to the Secretary of Labor a report, not less than twice a year during the grant period, on the use of grant funds that shall include data on the numbers of individuals served through activities funded under such section, disaggregated by race (for Asian and Native Hawaiian or Pacific Islander individuals using the same race response categories as the decennial census of the population), ethnicity, and gender.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB79253D25EC42268FF46FE94A5FF02C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report by the secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the first grant is awarded under this title, the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor shall submit to Congress a report based on the analysis of reports received under subsection (a) with a recommendation on how to expand the programs under this title.</text></subsection></section><section id="H94E91EB4EE7F4CD7851956E593F85971"><enum>206.</enum><header>Amendments to the Education Sciences Reform Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 153(a)(1) of the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9543">20 U.S.C. 9543(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H4A098DE1C6B646FA8EE59D7F09DE19E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (N), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H61BB4F2881524EB5A07D2BF2EE2F0C9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE0C93EFB04BE486D8D72B532F13AE138"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC65B531524414995970E80887FB6749B"><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6E8F6388F74242938CCB516268D287F6"><enum>(P)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the existence of emerging and advanced technology education (as defined in section 202 of the <short-title>Workforce of the Future Act of 2025</short-title>) in elementary schools and secondary schools, and the degree of competency in emerging and advanced technology fields among such students;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

