<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB149830270F94D8B8D80B6C5F161C7C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6586 IH: To authorize the Secretary of Defense to establish a pilot program to assess the efficacy of providing junior enlisted members of the Armed Forces a monthly coupon for use in procuring food at commissaries.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Defense to establish a pilot program to assess the efficacy of providing junior enlisted members of the Armed Forces a monthly coupon for use in procuring food at commissaries.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC4CF28EA1B04F13971F296CB7721273" style="OLC"><section id="H225F43F83F674146BD974A0CBF2A6424" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H9C054B28EDF74CE4BACAEED33576D94F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>members of the Armed Forces and their families deserve access to affordable and healthy food options, including during their duty day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92288B4163DF48D1A768F49179624049"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there has been increased awareness about the challenges members and their families face in accessing affordable and healthy food options;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF2C58187BBF45628A5F843DF9BCB387"><enum>(3)</enum><text>those challenges have been especially acute for unaccompanied junior enlisted members who live in government-provided quarters on military installations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFA741FED0C6424E90AAAEF582DA0737"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of Defense should explore a variety of proposals for expanding the accessibility of healthy and affordable food options to members, especially members who live in unaccompanied housing on military installations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8B4D583EBCA3402687B17B2A6FC5DF30" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to provide coupons to junior enlisted members to purchase food at commissaries</header><subsection id="H97AE1AE0B1674A0AAB27D8E82105534E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may conduct a pilot program to assess the efficacy of providing junior enlisted members of the Armed Forces a monthly coupon for use in procuring food at commissaries.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB70D0FF308A47B9B48F90AE110338D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of installations</header><paragraph id="H4FFEAA1134F3480CA853178C9CA363CC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may conduct the pilot program authorized by subsection (a) at 2 military installations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98E5FC731C7240D08BFE4377ECC9121D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting installations for the pilot program authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider installations with—</text><subparagraph id="HFD889D568D7845629F0F756E9E57DADA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>large numbers of enlisted members who live in unaccompanied housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DFBF2BD16E04A82968DEF46B5EBFD46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the largest ratios of enlisted members to commissioned officers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H423AAB1FDFAA42F4927B698E1987EF8A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>unaccompanied housing that provides access to functioning kitchens that residents may use to prepare meals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE6DCB81DC7148EF9E80787AB46B047E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>commissaries that are experimenting with or expanding their selection of nutritious and minimally processed ready-made and easy-to-make food options;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3B5BD5B0456483D8615B4B4751AB3EB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>low rates of attendance at dining facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65A233C2F49D47178E51274187D8DE83"><enum>(F)</enum><text>low customer satisfaction ratings for dining facilities, including installations with complaints about dining facilities submitted through the Interactive Customer Evaluation system of the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CAF88C057274F3A8CE9BF9B06C0EB5A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>commissaries located within easily accessible distances from unaccompanied housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H265FDD8B0C6641A08E2D36115C97F30F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coupons</header><paragraph id="H9CE286416A0D4F8A8330D9C4A45F8BCA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may determine the amount of the coupons to be provided under the pilot program authorized by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EF9C0D1E6CC4FD6A8BBF9DF0FB6F8C3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use for food at commissaries required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A coupon provided under the pilot program authorized by subsection (a) may be used only to purchase food at commissaries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49B3A8E8848E4BF189B224E2ED1BFAF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text>A coupon provided under the pilot program authorized by subsection (a) may not be used to—</text><subparagraph id="H0C40FF85CE9B4C1183BE0000D41A7866" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchase alcoholic beverages or tobacco; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26995B2FA9A84896BC5CF6D909692E59" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pay any deposit fee in excess of the amount of the State fee reimbursement (if any) required to purchase any food or food product contained in a returnable bottle or can, without regard to whether the fee is included in the shelf price posted for the food or food product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E223A869F914FA7BF2220353531D126" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Supplement to other food assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A coupon provided to a member under the pilot program authorized by subsection (a) shall supplement and not supplant—</text><subparagraph id="H55D6241122794050B1790EB3D317DD41" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the basic allowance for subsistence under section 402 of title 37, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5158E7AAC410447B9284A89A7B2D19C4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any program to provide meals or rations in kind for which the member is eligible.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FD19E57F6834D3B911D8401614A2DB4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duration of pilot program</header><text>The pilot program authorized by subsection (a) shall terminate not later than one year after the date on which the pilot program commences.</text></subsection><subsection id="H69F4F79924EE46DE80B482F7FFD34092"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report required</header><paragraph id="HBDB2433CBF074F61A1E8B7B50CDC5740" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the termination under subsection (d) of the pilot program authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report detailing the results of the pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE249AEC3919041F48E0B9D8145DA79A2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall include an assessment of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA9E11D8FCB1F4E83A90D2EB1281EF2C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The use of coupons by members who received coupons under the pilot program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H594F11FD6D724F5FA6442897B01FD9BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The satisfaction of and feedback from such members relating to the coupons.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA73A8BF1C7914C5AAAFB164A65E5D7B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The impact of providing the coupons on—</text><clause id="H65DFEB6F4BD44F578A696EA7A91B3579" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rates at which such members used commissaries; and</text></clause><clause id="HDFA4ED2214654D408B3DCDD390F44C82"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rates at which such members used dining facilities on their installations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD146B833CC804249B36BC40E612E14A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Historical rates of use of dining facilities on installations and historical customer satisfaction metrics for such facilities, including the number of complaints with respect to such facilities submitted through the Interactive Customer Evaluation system of the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5615D49E73D74A0A9B6F42ACB2800DA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The efficacy of the pilot program in—</text><clause id="HA6758DE7700940EBA4284821A78F92DF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing food insecurity rates among junior enlisted members;</text></clause><clause id="HE02D1DA92C9C442E9288AC9016745028"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increasing the availability of nutritious food options for such members at commissaries; and</text></clause><clause id="HEFE5A7B889EA427090465526FD2D9EE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>increasing the availability of nutritious food options for such members generally, including such members living in unaccompanied housing.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B3393CD0D02462DB30E3FB3170E0CC7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HDD796E01BC3947FCA177F23025516A4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAB6F63E2A6349689E9C9D5EDA02ECF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coupon</header><text>The term <term>coupon</term> means a voucher or monetary benefit for a member of the Armed Forces that may be used only at a commissary for the purchase of food.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H481C0D587DC4493E95A2D6335283CE97"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Food</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>food</term> means any food or food product intended for home consumption, including a ready-made food item.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

