<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H28E68B7EBFB54F7BA0BF5EADD2027C98" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6499 IH: Assessing Safety Tools for Parents and Minors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6499</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Trade Commission to submit a report on industry efforts to promote online safety for minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDD89F6FD33A84EDD81480913376BCCC5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAC80A7266CD34F8DAD063162609F92EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Assessing Safety Tools for Parents and Minors Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H5F8C7846BBAA4FEDA27ADD4ACB1814CF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Industry review and report</header> <subsection id="HE09CFEFE63834D158CF1877029EA6C5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in consultation with industry, parents, experts in communications technologies and parental controls, experts in privacy, mental health experts, and other appropriate entities as determined by the Commission, shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H517CAA1D44064D2999D65D9BE1B88110"><enum>(1)</enum><text>initiate a review of industry efforts to promote online safety for minors through education, parental and child safety tools, age-appropriate labels for content, privacy and other safety settings, or other relevant technologies or initiatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CD26D08EF3B45F198DCCE5CC97FAD02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examine the effectiveness of industry efforts identified in paragraph (1) to mitigate online harms for minors and provide recommendations for industry, Congress, and agencies to improve online safety for minors.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H385D2BC78E46412293AE674EE129A5B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report with the findings and recommendations resulting from the review described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2D3A84F0D177423A86B2A82922AF94FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>This Act is exemption from subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the Paperwork Reduction Act).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD6CCF8BFDFC4D0B81B2C79CF7ACB97C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HA1AA86C55B7F4B15A28F3AD48C455350"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB360825208E94694B38F6157846C794A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <term>minor</term> means an individual under the age of 17.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

