<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82E8ACB02157463399B23310707FF357" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9255 IH: Timeshare Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9255</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish requirements with respect to the sale of timeshares to improve acquisition transparency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC4E865B7045C4072BB8814A12BFD43EE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC6F65B80D8074F4A80E4AD8910B26B71"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Timeshare Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCA22FC7E4B5C4EB7928CA9A171916B42"><enum>2.</enum><header>Timeshare acquisition transparency</header> <subsection id="HEC984EDCD95546D8BDDB014900E1E0E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for a timeshare company to enter into a timeshare agreement with an individual for the sale of a timeshare unless—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE3DC60ED11014036B0C3E90EC1451DA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such agreement incorporates—</text> <subparagraph id="H851E74700249489B977765D80A5A9E59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a single document, an itemized specification of all the costs required to acquire and maintain ownership of the timeshare, including ongoing fees;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27A235C5F4674F10B2FCA66A9831C4C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a specification of each fee that may be altered by the timeshare company and an explanation of the notice, including the timing of such notice, that will be provided to the individual with respect to an alteration of each such fee;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7A1EA9572CA4EBDA661530CCF7E0354"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a specification of each option available to the individual for ending ownership of the timeshare; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87ECB8D82C3E4C9D95AE07CCB4025E5A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a provision stating that the individual may terminate the agreement, without penalty, during the 14-day period beginning on the date on which such individual enters into such agreement; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4B7BC19AB264552AB8A61DCC5D5E964"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the individual, prior to entering into the agreement and free from the supervision of an employee of the timeshare company, is provided an opportunity to review all documents associated with the agreement, including documents containing the specifications and provisions described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H84C0D28C08F7432BB6D11EEB2716444B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H09815B86BF8241FA886F18101B0CCEB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practice</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B579649EA0148C18719DFFE3CFD8E31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> <subparagraph id="HAE8F30CD78314401ACDE93BB502A4B24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61BB4FBDBA5742B5BC2BDFBE0D5E30EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates subsection (a) or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30B314A722BF43DCA293642E39A25BF5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0DC9936031ED4632BBD40FF89033E1CE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such rules as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H579E00B083554201938E3EA5943335C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (a) shall apply to agreements entered into on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDCE9FDA72A4640A3A86E4BA56E0FC664"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be interpreted to preclude a State from imposing or enforcing any requirement relating to the sale of a timeshare that provides greater protection to consumers than the protection provided by the requirements of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD9B37AEB638843BABCE60817DC987E69"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H014B8509BBCE4BEA97BB19F9D302BBCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEEB4CC6023E4020AD2B83A2BB5F3D87"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timeshare</header><text>The term <term>timeshare</term> means an interest purchased in any arrangement, plan, scheme, or similar device (not including any exchange program), whether by membership, agreement, tenancy in common, sale, lease, deed, rental agreement, license, right to use agreement, or by any other means, whereby a purchaser, in exchange for consideration, receives a right to use accommodations, facilities, or recreational sites, whether improved or unimproved, for a specific period of time less than 1 full year during any given year, but not necessarily for consecutive years, and which extends for a period of more than 3 years.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17A8B356A1EA4F55A2A1CC12174A761C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timeshare company</header><text>The term <term>timeshare company</term> means any person that sells, offers, arranges, or otherwise engages in the business of providing a timeshare to a consumer, directly or indirectly, for monetary consideration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

