<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-NEW26234-F13-KT-8XT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 748 IS: Condemning the Department of Justice and Internal Revenue Service settlement agreement in Trump v. Internal Revenue Service, under which $1,776,000,000 in taxpayer money may be used to financially benefit individuals who assaulted law enforcement officers on January 6, 2021, and President Trump, his family, and his political allies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning the Department of Justice and Internal Revenue Service settlement agreement in Trump v. Internal Revenue Service, under which $1,776,000,000 in taxpayer money may be used to financially benefit individuals who assaulted law enforcement officers on January 6, 2021, and President Trump, his family, and his political allies.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 18, 2026, the Justice Department, Internal Revenue Service, and personal counsel to President Trump agreed to a settlement that requires the Federal Government to establish a $1,776,000,000 <quote>Anti-Weaponization Fund</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the distribution of the $1,776,000,000 in the <quote>Anti-Weaponization Fund</quote> will be determined by a panel of 5 members appointed by the Attorney General and eligible for removal by the President <quote>without cause</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the panel described in the previous proviso <quote>shall have the power to determine its own procedures for submitting, receiving, processing, and granting or denying claims</quote> and is not required to make those procedures public;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a document published by the Department of Justice on May 19, 2026, and signed by Acting Attorney General Todd Blanche further states the United States is <quote>FOREVER BARRED and PRECLUDED from prosecuting or pursuing</quote> claims against President Trump, <quote>related or affiliated individuals (including, without limitation, family or others filing jointly),</quote> or related companies and trusts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 19, 2026, Acting Attorney General Todd Blanche testified before the Senate Appropriations Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies, and did not rule out using the <quote>Anti-Weaponization Fund</quote> to make payments to individuals who attacked the Capitol on January 6, 2021, including individuals who were found guilty of assaulting law enforcement officers;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas, at a May 19, 2026 press conference, Vice President J.D. Vance similarly stated that the <quote>Anti-Weaponization Fund</quote> could be used to make payments to individuals who attacked the Capitol on January 6, 2021, including individuals who were found guilty of assaulting law enforcement officers;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Andrew Paul Johnson, who was pardoned by President Trump for his criminal conduct on January 6, 2021, was sentenced to life in prison after being found guilty on 5 charges of child sex abuse after trying to keep his minor victims silent by promising to share millions of dollars in restitution he expected to receive from the Trump Administration; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in addition to Andrew Paul Johnson, at least 20 other individuals who were pardoned by President Trump for their criminal conduct on January 6, 2021, have since been charged with, convicted of, or sentenced for, additional crimes, including conspiracy to commit murder, production and possession of child pornography, reckless homicide, burglary, and online solicitation of a minor, but still may be eligible to receive payments from the <quote>Anti-Weaponization Fund</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate condemns—</text><paragraph id="iddf8e7c0c33074784a5c246d77c6bec86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use of public monies to financially benefit President Trump, his family, his associates, or his political allies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec2074b47b6c4ba4afbd0c25663b0f52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the effort to provide immunity from prosecution for tax crimes to President Trump, his family, his political allies, affiliated individuals, and related companies and trusts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6148627689de44d3b51805d3867bbb12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing payments to individuals who attacked the Capitol on January 6, 2021, including individuals who assaulted law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

