<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6110535FAE8C4DAC8177B7C24D64D1B6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7363 IH: ICE Out of Our Faces Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7363</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the Department of Homeland Security’s use of facial recognition.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H93DF0A6768E04F7AAA4224F6773FA97E" style="OLC"><section id="HDBE46CDBF22A412BA72C004110ACADD2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ICE Out of Our Faces Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC95EDDA9E96248459AC6ED89094C0746"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3158F2D362644D27A65CFAD68C62A816"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biometric surveillance system</header><text>The term <term>biometric surveillance system</term> means computer software that performs facial recognition or other biometric recognition in real time or on a recording or photograph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75BCE5055E3F41EA9CA441723483B23E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered immigration officer</header><text>The term <term>covered immigration officer</term> means any individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="H46F98E7B09104AEF86C870B525C9BEB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>authorized to perform immigration enforcement functions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H494EC2E9FA784AA89601EBBCE35DB4BC"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3660EA92659547908F83CFC2BBD6FB8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an officer, employee, agent, contractor, or subcontractor of U.S. Customs and Border Protection;</text></clause><clause id="HD037C5E830564663A9BDDD088D1E4016" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an officer, employee, agent, contractor, or subcontractor of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement; or</text></clause><clause id="H49F0E4CD665546BFA607C2F0897A3943" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an individual authorized, deputized, or designated to perform immigration enforcement functions pursuant to section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18E568CB106F4E6E93C030A2CFAC68B9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Facial recognition</header><text>The term <term>facial recognition</term> means an automated or semi-automated process that—</text><subparagraph id="H34B2DA31D2C24265B2D8054E45E3A0CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assists in identifying an individual, capturing information about an individual, matching an individual to a list or otherwise generating or assisting in generating surveillance or identification information about an individual based on the physical characteristics of the individual’s face; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H167442F7EDB94AA4BA7DDD345B03040F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>logs characteristics of an individual’s face, head, or body to infer emotion, associations, activities, or the location of an individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC0ED52E4B4C42A3813D90C35815A89E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other biometric recognition</header><text>The term <term>other biometric recognition</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H374181C72CAA41E2BABE56CDCFBD1287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an automated or semi-automated process that—</text><clause id="H326625740F6644C79A41101D74B76C5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>assists in identifying an individual, capturing information about an individual, or otherwise generating or assisting in generating surveillance information about an individual based on the characteristics of the individual’s gait or other immutable characteristic ascertained from a distance;</text></clause><clause id="HD8AB66A97E6442A09E1B4E541D5D8239"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>uses voice recognition technology; or</text></clause><clause id="HC5766B7797F5445081696B46287A3A01"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>logs characteristics referred to in clause (i) or (ii) to infer emotion, associations, activities, or the location of an individual; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8628BE775F32488EB2779550FE54FDE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include identification based on fingerprints or palm prints not ascertained from a distance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF11A9BF37F4613B816894D280F1200"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Voice recognition technology</header><text>The term <term>voice recognition technology</term> means an automated or semi-automated process that assists in identifying or verifying an individual based on the characteristics of an individual’s voice.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC67987E81DC94FCBA4CABCCF7833ACA7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of biometric surveillance by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection</header><subsection id="H6916854DC3BB4677BFA338BEC195C1A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any covered immigration officer to acquire, possess, access, or use in the United States—</text><paragraph id="HA0CCC75A84174FF88DB3DCEDD060ABC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any biometric surveillance system; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC43389E6757F42969F8243CFB92F1AE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information derived from a biometric surveillance system operated by another entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08952065B91E4C5AB049D50928104005"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Biometric data deletion</header><text>All information collected by a covered immigration officer for use in, or derived from, a biometric surveillance system, including information collected before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall be deleted not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H705B7A2A01A84317B529E5E50A7A0539"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judicial investigations and proceedings</header><paragraph id="H9519B6918AF643C48C0FA1D17AD698CE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admissibility</header><text>Except in a judicial investigation or proceeding alleging a violation of this section, information obtained in violation of this section is not admissible by the Federal Government in any criminal, civil, administrative, or other investigation or proceeding.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B2717FBB73B4D3185B458FB3C1E1466"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><subparagraph id="H887DC55BF6B942B88D8F94832FF799C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A violation of this section constitutes an injury to any individual aggrieved by such violation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7AF446149B849CAB6CF611DEA2BD442"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Right to sue</header><text>An individual aggrieved by a violation of this section may institute proceedings against the Federal Government whose covered immigration officer is alleged to have violated this section for the relief described in subparagraph (D) in any court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CE00900F65F43E39D26B3992BEC7712"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Enforcement by state attorneys general</header><text>The chief law enforcement officer of a State, or any other State officer authorized by law to bring actions on behalf of the residents of a State, may bring a civil action, as parens patriae, on behalf of the residents of such State in an appropriate district court of the United States to enforce this Act, whenever the chief law enforcement officer or other State officer determines the interests of the residents of such State have been or are being threatened or adversely affected by a violation of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H621795F29E764E9D9B238A3DB30B1EF4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action authorized under subparagraph (B) in which the plaintiff prevails, the court may award—</text><clause id="HCED931B0B68A438AB08520917AD3AECB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>actual damages;</text></clause><clause id="H4EE60F52786E453BB85D97498672C37B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>punitive damages;</text></clause><clause id="H6083FA520BCB4D248011747042103762"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reasonable attorneys’ fees and costs; and</text></clause><clause id="H6C0A1278338D4ADB88DE97CF3FB4F5A8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other relief, including injunctive relief, that the court determines to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBB86427F0FB43E89C13ED72EBB37DAC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>Any covered immigration officer who violates this section may be subject to retraining, suspension, termination, or any other penalty, as determined in an appropriate tribunal, and subject to applicable due process requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H173B052326704BC1AC69C161C9A3B71A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preempt or supersede any Federal, State, or local law absent actual conflict with the limitations on covered immigration officers imposed by this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

