<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB791D718F2974B57A547299EFCED9701" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7751 IH: Parks to People Active Transportation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7751</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260302">March 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a program to make grants for the improvement or construction of greenway paths, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCD8A0EC9D2954ED1B0C0758D3A467A46" style="OLC"><section id="H083B7E992888463B93A4D894F3B2AB78" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Parks to People Active Transportation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF95137EC5B2A46D18F923C03F945224D"><enum>2.</enum><header>National and regional greenways program</header><subsection id="HEA27A05070894232A0E302BD2D61A783"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program to make grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible organizations to improve or construct safe and connected greenway paths between communities that are designated as regionally or nationally significant by the Secretary under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H33F9FDA69E754BCBA5FA8884D7E5305A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regionally or nationally significant greenway paths</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under this section, the Secretary shall establish a national greenway paths network. The national greenway paths network shall contain regionally or nationally significant greenway paths designated by the Secretary that—</text><paragraph id="H9A8F912CDE494E369F5FA5C1A800B7AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>cross multiple local jurisdictions or State lines;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA295CE48015744A3984CF2598D265133"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce congestion and single-occupant vehicle trips, improve safety and access to jobs, and lower emissions for criteria pollutants (NOx, VOC, PM) and greenhouse gases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE46D336F1E4F4C6CA3A41B7F022CCACB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support community goals and objectives in areas covered by metropolitan planning organizations; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5595C8F3FD6D4F239A08FB54DB707E7A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>meet any other criteria the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H427DA23208AB4100AD0CD28C68CAFE08"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="HA76DCFE73F2A4070B242558F0E0E948C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, an eligible organization shall submit to the Secretary an application in such manner and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9CE9D586E54A90ABADCFDCFC22EAD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible projects partially on Federal land</header><text>With respect to an application for eligible greenway projects that are located in part on Federal lands, an eligible organization shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the appropriate Federal agency with jurisdiction over such land to be eligible for a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B7F102534CF454F8F0B815DBB1A845A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a grant for construction of a greenway path under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><paragraph id="H09C2D1CB26EC467FA047559E03C7AEE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the proposed eligible greenway project is likely to provide substantial additional opportunities for walking, bicycling, and recreation, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H746C30D2A3D64F2DBA9629986CA777E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>creating greenway paths connecting multiple communities, counties, metropolitan regions, or States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A943804FC974185A8750D73A5D9F0F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrating greenway paths with transit services, where available, to improve access to public transportation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11E617A380844F05A95BC396D5D5C003"><enum>(C)</enum><text>integrating greenway paths with existing parks, recreation or scenic areas, adjacent waterways, or transportation corridors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H332FF0A0D4E34E36AE31E63D756BCAC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether the eligible organization proposing a project demonstrates broad community support through—</text><subparagraph id="H4325A5714CF9473ABD479C93ED36D361"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prior public input in the development of a plan for the proposed project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3578A5D9729641A8AD07EE09170D9A79"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the commitment of any project sponsors and community leaders, including elected officials in the jurisdiction in which such project is located, partner organization leaders, and private or nongovernmental organizations in the area in which such project is located, to the success and timely implementation of an eligible greenway project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H97C4F93D88884F9B8D7E4373C615F5C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible organization provides evidence of commitment to traffic safety, regulations, financial incentives, or community design policies that facilitate significant increases in walking and bicycling.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3B9BEEBB5C645889804C89A1721A0A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible organization demonstrates commitment of State, local, or eligible Federal matching funds, and land or in-kind contributions, in addition to the local match required under subsection (g)(1), unless the applicant qualifies for an exception under subsection (g)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H748A8153CADB48C79A0C833A4A28E580"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible organization demonstrates that the grant will address existing disparities in bicyclist and pedestrian fatality rates based on race or income level or provide access to schools, jobs, services, transit, or recreational opportunities for low-income communities and communities of color.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE4AABAFFABC40109E31B3CB4F80B975"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>Whether the eligible organization demonstrates how investment in active transportation will advance safety for pedestrians and cyclists, accessibility to schools, jobs, and transit, accessibility to national, State, or local parks, economic competitiveness, environmental protection, and quality of life.</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CDA5AD064314438921A446D7D1DE6E9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section may be used—</text><paragraph id="HE98F9E56EFE443FF8A4D7E2FBEA3FBD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve or construct a greenway path; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB246266237B1491F88FA5FECB01483FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to acquire real property necessary for the improvement or construction of a greenway path.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE904852C537480D9D8FABBDB45FDF13"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Set aside</header><paragraph id="H35454412DA9345D08D25F013F51976DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Planning and design grants</header><text>Each fiscal year, the Secretary shall set aside not less than $5,000,000 from the funds made available to carry out this section to provide planning grants for eligible organizations to develop a local or regional greenways and paths plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC58594BEE3154982934B6B4567DA1CAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Each fiscal year, the Secretary shall set aside not more than $3,500,000 of the funds made available to carry out this section to cover the costs of administration, research, technical assistance, communications, and training activities under the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA637601785C44D04BEC6D7C1FC19F318"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Grant timing</header><paragraph id="HF51FA2577B83420EBC43FE2731B6796B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Request for application</header><text>Not later than 60 days after funds are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a request for applications for grants under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67D2023C64EC4C6785B428332CF49B40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header><text>Not later than 180 days after funds are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall select grant recipients for grants under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52C362E84A204FC8A143B5D5B2CFD83C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal share</header><paragraph id="H3734627D6BAF47469B8D6FB378D84A6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Federal share of the cost of a project under this section shall not exceed 80 percent of the total project cost.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD24B2EABE424D13A95268A2A6A544E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="H2DDB6E9ACDCE4CE592925DAB132C8CE5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Disadvantaged communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For projects serving communities with a poverty rate of over 40 percent based on the majority of census tracts served by such project, the Secretary may increase the Federal share of the cost of a project under this section to 100 percent of the total project cost.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H806C46FEB91F4AD8A0E07CDB7494ABFC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rural areas</header><text>For projects serving rural areas, as such term is defined in section 101 of title 23, United States Code, the Federal share of the cost of a project under this section shall be 90 percent of the total project cost.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25A4DA82B2F04B50AEE07FE0B787F9D5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HD2BBBF2064C9420DA8FBD7F0EFB0BDBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2028, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the information described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF51F2D8372D945AF8DB07F76E3E37A74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2030, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing the information described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43487D6E036A41F6B163EC103F38DC83"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report information</header><text>A report submitted under this subsection shall contain the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF470331055A046E4A1212F5E75C37CCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of grants made under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F996D5621D54533996756C364245BDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Best practices of recipients in implementing projects funded under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE323D3304F7C413190A41B4F551B2DE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Impediments experienced by recipients of grants under this section in planning for and delivering projects under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB77A817BB5D54101B7F8DC2B5C35E743"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $300,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection><subsection id="H39786F8228C34EF98206B27D40C66523"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HFAA7289F6281474E8882F0882CDCF009"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active transportation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>active transportation</quote> means alternative methods of transportation to motor vehicles, including walking, bicyling, or utilizing assistive mobility or micro mobility devices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE286D436EB84F15AA3E181268C8D341"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Greenway path</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>greenway path</quote> means a hard-surfaced or wheelchair-accessible facility built for active transportation, including a walkway, bikeway, or shared-use path that connects communities, cities, counties, metropolitan regions, or States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF33890FA2D7640BBBD900990A61A9FB6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community</header><text>The term <quote>community</quote> means a geographic area that is socioeconomically interdependent and may include rural, suburban, and urban jurisdictions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50B8E5C7B49B4C3795CC0C43E223095B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible organization</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0C7C9D886B804EC2A25718F5F811E838"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a local or regional governmental organization, including a metropolitan planning organization or regional planning organization or council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BC682700B3141F990399CB1A75AFA5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a multi-county special district;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8BCF329E8F642629A9168902308BC05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State (including the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and any other territory of the United States);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33D9BC39B9B84E34BB4B7D8E8A768245"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a multi-State group of governments; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H368C396C61C745E2830755C2807C8B3E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C9FD013EEC8447CB9EDCDCB76695FA2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible greenway project</header><text>The term <quote>eligible greenway project</quote> means an active transportation project, or group of projects—</text><subparagraph id="H7F1C05EC0AF94809BED94AE52A474FD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is designated as a regionally or nationally significant greenway path under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H619E305CB06B4818A407FC11B9E2587D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within or between a community or group of communities, at least one of which falls within the jurisdiction of an eligible organization, which has submitted an application under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35E9A6C28C6D47CD880F6514D6EBF81A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that has—</text><clause id="H1E597845904344EA884978D8A7D34159"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a total cost of not less than $15,000,000; or</text></clause><clause id="H09F9444F18B34FCD814BD701DB8C1183"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to planning and design grants, planning and design costs of not less than $100,000;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AB941A3324F4D40B87605282A77B34E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that construct path segments that close local or regional network gaps or are located within underserved areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AE7656E62744E848B6B1E2533DDDFD4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>that support an accessible public realm, connect to public transportation, support opportunities for economic development, or promote health and safety; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29E1F863C1154F0C93932607D9C6A567"><enum>(F)</enum><text>that connect communities to public spaces and parks, enhance ecological connectivity, support land conservation and access, or support sites for remediation and restoration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CBF1039E4084EB999EB9894D3D56BB7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 4(e) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF6CE0638CF7459FA90F4A5F9DBDE57C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H630CBBEF95E34783B7076EE7305B2E2C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Total project cost</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>total project cost</quote> means the sum total of all costs incurred in the development of a project that are approved by the Secretary as reasonable and necessary, including—</text><subparagraph id="H37BED4C4809F4607AE68147C73473712"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the cost of acquiring real property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H493E88E9CBD04C35A449CC13700CF2B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the cost of site preparation, demolition, and development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D034FF442584C2C93A48BF580D6D186"><enum>(C)</enum><text>expenses related to the issuance of bonds or notes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22167A9FF8EE499E85EF74CA32ED78FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>fees in connection with the planning, execution, and financing of the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB00EAC33C38248D29915EB7E57191BCF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the cost of studies, surveys, plans, permits, insurance, interest, financing, tax, and assessment costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD96EB865BB1842DF84D6DB0CE7A7C9C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the cost of construction, rehabilitation, reconstruction, and equipping the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H841179AC3926439FAB9C3C7C7F746D86"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the cost of land improvements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H570DFC16F5FA4F268227AF3A97A36D90"><enum>(H)</enum><text>contractor fees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94197E2DAD1F429C9B1FDE9EF89D58A5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the cost of training and education related to the safety of users of any greenway path constructed as part of an eligible greenway project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4B58BF354974670BB00D53B62EAC7BA"><enum>(J)</enum><text>any other cost that the Secretary determines is necessary and reasonable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

