<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26101-C37-0L-330"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 593 ATS: Honoring the victims of the 2025 Potomac River mid-air collision.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 593</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the victims of the 2025 Potomac River mid-air collision.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 29, 2025, a United States Army Black Hawk helicopter and a passenger aircraft, operated as American Airlines Flight 5342 from Wichita, Kansas, to Washington, D.C., collided in flight above the Potomac River near Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this tragedy took the lives of all 64 passengers and crew aboard the airliner and the lives of the 3 crew members aboard the helicopter, including individuals from Connecticut, Delaware, Georgia, Indiana, Kansas, Maryland, Massachusetts, Minnesota, Mississippi, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Rhode Island, Tennessee, Virginia, and several foreign countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 11 young United States figure skating athletes, along with their parents and coaches, were among the victims of the collision;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 3 United States Army soldiers, who selflessly chose to serve and defend their country, lost their lives in this tragic accident;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 78 agencies and organizations responded in the aftermath of the January 29, 2025 mid-air collision, including first responders of the District of Columbia Fire and Emergency Medical Services Department, the Metropolitan Police Department of the District of Columbia, the Metropolitan Washington Airports Authority Fire and Rescue Department, the United States Coast Guard, the Maryland State Police, and other local, State, and Federal agencies, all of which acted promptly and selflessly in responding to the disaster and assisting in the recovery efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Federal, State, and local officials have cooperated to conduct a thorough investigation of this incident;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas countless individuals suffered the loss of a spouse, parent, sibling, friend, family member, or loved one; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the lives of those lost will be remembered and cherished by those who loved them: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id0f0d666d0db547bba414fbe5bf71540d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the memory of all victims of the 2025 Potomac River mid-air collision near Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport, recognizing their lives and contributions to their families and the United States of America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idef1899887dd145a8b47b6af0d51dce7b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offers sincere condolences to the families, loved ones, and friends of those who lost their lives in this tragic incident;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f838f701bb14ba1a185cdcd45b60df1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges the bravery and professionalism of the more than 1,700 first responders and emergency personnel, servicemembers, medical professionals, and investigators who assisted in the rescue and recovery efforts following the collision; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id370e962bb9cf40319ff095f1b687e5d9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expresses its commitment to honoring and supporting the families affected by this tragedy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51eeb18aa1b648d1b899d63e239ed776"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expresses its commitment to translating the safety lessons learned from the collision into action to prevent future incidents and ensure a similar crash does not happen again. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

