<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF59EA14BC25D42D596D8BDE86C523D13" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7972 IH: Taxpayer Workforce Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7972</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Internal Revenue Service to establish a fellowship program within the Internal Revenue Service to recruit qualified data scientists to partner with tax law specialists and provide insights and identify emerging and complex issues in tax administration, ranging from data acquisition and quality through developing advanced analytics, statistics, and models to improve core tax administration activities in services and enforcement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4E24AA35928644A2B4BE832A91A1D438" style="OLC"><section id="HEC78FF880A404BF88214E695449DDF7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taxpayer Workforce Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA2056545AA6F4742A2551A7AE39BFDE5"><enum>2.</enum><header>IRS Fellowship Program</header><subsection id="H3DEB1DBD510546118FD6FDC9A67BE9A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2026, the Commissioner of Internal Revenue (hereinafter known as the <quote>Commissioner</quote>), after consultation with the Chief Counsel of the Internal Revenue Service (hereinafter known as the <quote>Chief Counsel</quote>) and the Chief Data and Analytics Officer of the Internal Revenue Service (hereinafter known as the <quote>Chief Data Officer</quote>), shall establish within the Internal Revenue Service a fellowship program (hereinafter known as the <quote>program</quote>) to recruit qualified data scientists in the private sector to join the Internal Revenue Service to create and participate in the task force established under subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA3E604325A945208F2EE912A06CEB62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objective</header><text>The Commissioner, after consultation with the Chief Counsel and Chief Data Officer, shall design the program in a manner such that the program—</text><paragraph id="HCCD65D0F31C8490F91B8BF7F4CCFEBE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>addresses such tax cases handled by the Internal Revenue Service as the Commissioner determines—</text><subparagraph id="H0B7F6EEBAF2A410DBC4C1E3452ED3970" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are the most complex, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA5991702CF545D49FEA2D92140669A6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include new and emerging issues, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84FA973C605C487AAC925A826D41BDAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recruits and retains outstanding and qualified tax experts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91019772A6B84AE3978A3286798294A2" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advertisement of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall advertise the program in such a way as to attract qualified data scientists and such other tax professionals as the Commissioner determines are appropriately qualified to handle the most complex tax cases.</text></subsection><subsection id="H58418314D6094F009B3A22B1BF9F1C9F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Structure</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H8AAB7C67AF7A42F98FFF29C19BDCBA56"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The program shall be staffed by not fewer than 10 fellows at the discretion of the Commissioner based on the needs of the Internal Revenue Service and the availability of qualified candidates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB66436EE7ED4352A588240690D8BCF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term of service</header><subparagraph id="H511C7B6D2EB34CA295D12FC04F48F036"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each fellow shall be hired for a 2-, 3-, or 4-year term of service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4805A99168824592AF0C58FFCA5D14CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extensions</header><clause commented="no" id="HC0027AC2B6144AB2A6459250464CBB0E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A fellow may apply for, and the Commissioner may grant, a 1-year extension of the fellowship.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC524DA87194E42518003A72CCCF2BA11"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No limit on number of extensions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be no limit on the number of extensions under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF5339FD2968742BCAC1C38EA1ADE98D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fellowship vacancies</header><text>The Commissioner, after consultation with the Chief Counsel and Chief Data Officer, shall fill vacant fellowships—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBF836E3A7EE34D129831028030687080"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in such a manner as to ensure that the program is staffed with no fewer than 5 fellows, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFD82C5D09C9B407BB1EEC53FCC9E6709"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as soon as practicable after the vacancy arises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A754044814347A794E9EDDBC52C6C17"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Hiring authority</header><text>The Commissioner shall have authority to permanently hire a fellow at the end of the term of service for such fellow.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H382A8F7817F84ACBA2BD8471E7364835"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Task force</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date on which the first fellowship is awarded under this section, the Commissioner shall establish a task force within the Internal Revenue Service and the office of the Chief Counsel in both national and regional office placements that includes the fellows hired pursuant to subsection (d), the purpose of which is to—</text><paragraph id="H43DCBFFEEE0A4A6493A55A4C4BEF553F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop, test, and refine data-driven methodologies to support audit case selection,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B824CFDCF0E4B31812B23F76A178E33"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educate Internal Revenue Service employees on the use, interpretation, and limitations of data analytics, models, and emerging analytic techniques relevant to tax administration,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC3FD42FF329493A8B3F8047699D625D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support, in coordination with examiners and tax experts, the audit of selected taxpayers through advanced data analysis, transaction-level testing, and quantitative modeling,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1560A408F9AB455DAE3AA2161B94C964"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support efforts to address offshore tax evasion and issues implicating the Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act through data integration, anomaly detection, and network analysis,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H235E5DFBEE7D4E5699E302CEB2555FF4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify, mentor, and train junior employees from the Internal Revenue Service with respect to using data analytics and emerging analytic techniques to identify risk and facilitate task administration improvements,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97BA5A1B5D514D9FB572237036001D6D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review existing use cases of artificial intelligence and data analytics with respect to tax administration, provide recommendations to improve on such existing cases, and identify new such cases, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05A35B4E54304C9D82BB53E88BCC35BF" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide data-driven recommendations for improving audit effectiveness and efficiency and for improving improper tax payments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4A570125EC624494A78DF1225D2CA5FD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The task force established under subsection (e) may be composed of both—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H4C7192712C46426C83C3A8B63303996D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fellows, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2C35EAD578B44F28BF64E6778C4574D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>permanent employees of the Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF76538098ED84A90AD862ECFF0E37996"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Pay of fellows</header><paragraph id="HFD60D5FD236A42DA87C39AFE16AC0649"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall determine, subject to the provisions of this subsection, the pay of fellows recruited under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72BF77D6BF034E01AEF54438698C7F1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pay scale</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), the pay of a fellow shall not be less than the minimum rate payable for GS–15 of the General Schedule and shall not exceed the amount of annual compensation (excluding expenses) specified in section 102 of title 3, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB982351AC58E471BB2E18E3B948BBB37"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration of program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) may appoint a lead program officer to administer and advertise the program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H300ED84FFFA64F92813DCDBF6129289B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual review and report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the first fellowship is awarded under this section, and annually thereafter, the Commissioner shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text><paragraph id="H4484985F0435403C9A071EB42EA4FDC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the effects of the program,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B2461B547884144B5AA5E45CE273F1F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the return on investment of the program, including calculations of all costs incurred and benefits incurred, which may include predicted revenue increases based on task force recommendations; tax revenue and penalties recommended, assessed, or collected due to the work of the task force; and operational improvements in taxpayer service,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BD6EACC81474E6E83AE218E27731BA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of the total number of fellows who apply each year, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B3D9BA9D2254090B8E6AEF7E114D667"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for changes to the program, if any.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB42C1FEF907A46F88101D11CD2361544"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Rules and regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner, with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate, other than the Commissioner), shall promulgate such rules and regulations as may be necessary for the efficient administration of the program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEF04B7A27E5D438CA6DECF4083DC3266" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Qualified data scientist defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>qualified data scientist</term> means a specialized professional who has demonstrated skills applying advanced analytics, statistical modeling, or machine learning in complex regulatory, financial, or compliance environments while working alongside tax law specialists and other tax subject matter experts.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

