<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" slc-id="S1-HEN25C85-02D-TY-XWN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SJ 97 IS: Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 97</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Proposing a balanced budget amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="constitutional-amendment" id="H429E990DDEAB4DE58FB0B4060BD59C9D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD62B027883C7490E992AFD4B19E19DE0"><text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification:</text><quoted-block style="constitutional-amendment" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C1C0F2BD3034981B527D76589CBE7E3"><constitution-article commented="no" id="HA4C68B7495934BCA865FF9545E0C5719"><enum> —</enum><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="H1579F91A115C423C8E49065C6BB9DCF6"><enum>1.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenditures and receipts shall be balanced, which may occur over more than 1 year. Expenditures shall include all expenditures of the United States except those for payment of debt, and receipts shall include all receipts of the United States except those derived from borrowing. Congress shall achieve balance within 10 years following the date of the ratification of this article.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="HF7E06A21A7E64F5BAF904EDD67CDEFA6"><enum>2.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For emergency situations, Congress may, for limited times, authorize expenditures exceeding those allowable under section 1, if two-thirds of the House of Representatives and the Senate agree to pass the bill. Debts incurred from such expenditures shall be paid as soon as practicable.</text></section></constitution-article><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

