<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3252F721B9BE468BA2406C405FE79D9F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8264 IH: HBCU Research Capacity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill of Arkansas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Federal Clearinghouse on Grant Opportunities for Historically Black Colleges and Universities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1B195AD9F2354B7DBF7049130E49165D" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H17F0A970A1E849F08C6938D315A0F7CF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>HBCU Research Capacity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC85F6D88D5CB4ADA9EB9F28D8A72BC28"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H8CDAD49EC5A3464EA860624A1E17F09F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Historically Black Colleges and Universities (HBCUs) are a vital source to the Nation’s research and workforce communities. While enrolling 8.5 percent of Black undergraduate students, HBCUs produce almost 18 percent of Black STEM bachelor’s degree recipients, as of 2024.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB42551667D4143C79C5D512F01764BD6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Despite these major contributions, only one HBCU, Howard University, has achieved very high research activity status. Furthermore, HBCUs received less than 1 percent of the approximately $60,000,000,000 in Federal research and development expenditures at colleges and universities in fiscal year 2023.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2BB923B200DB45158F48E7464C54E53B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Due to historical underfunding, HBCUs face cyclical barriers in building research capacity, further limiting grant access, resources, and exasperating issues related to smaller endowments. This makes it even more difficult for scholars to secure Federal research funding.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98F24A2C77B74B49BA5B16060AE809EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In finding solutions to research and development barriers, a May 2024 report by the National Science and Technology Council recommends strategies such as expanding flexibility in funding, encouraging interagency collaboration to share best practices, and reforming merit-review to reduce bias and improve transparency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H88D09CED1F404B4A80FCAE174B39BA46"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Expanding research diversity is strategically important for national security, economic growth, and innovation. Underrepresentation of HBCUs in Federal research funding represents a missed opportunity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2695384E32642FFB70A4CC8C34A07E0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A Federal clearinghouse providing information on grant opportunities and sharing best practices would help address barriers such as knowledge gaps, transparency, and capacity limitations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F07B1857C0843CDA3F4D415B25573BC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Coordinated agency review, gap identification, and reporting to Congress should improve accountability and help ensure equitable access to Federal research funding for HBCUs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42DC25A5C40D419AA3641BE2907FBE59"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Establishing, maintaining, and creating accountability measures for the Clearinghouse is therefore appropriate and necessary to notify eligible HBCUs and guide Federal agencies in supporting HBCU research capacity.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H8E93CA996A9343B09D437869730D5108"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Clearinghouse on Grant Opportunities for Historically Black Colleges and Universities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1060">20 U.S.C. 1060 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA651A65F80E4D67BE1A04D2F7A1E9DC"> <section id="H57427D24C51047819E16EC818A9F00A6"><enum>328.</enum><header>Federal Clearinghouse on Grant Opportunities for Historically Black Colleges and Universities</header> <subsection id="H8899DCB823A04B0991736F637B1D091D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H47EC936DF62B4F16AC33C33D0AB70A5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall establish a Federal Clearinghouse on Research Capacity and Grant Opportunities for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (in this section referred to as the <quote>Clearinghouse</quote>) within the Department.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H10896A550E704CD6B70CFC62EE730D58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall be the primary resource of the Federal Government to identify and provide comprehensive information on Federal grant opportunities for which part B institutions are eligible or are exclusively eligible, delineating between the two categories, that support—</text> <subparagraph id="H99C8CD511B624FF0BA138B6F56087688"><enum>(A)</enum><text>research and development; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA60D935AFCFB4EC5A229E49A4BBE419E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>building institutional research capacity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4AEE9BEDB8C4A96B2DF8D6508582D00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personnel</header> <subparagraph id="H5252D7E3C7864625BDC49A96DB9E5A43"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assignments</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall be assigned such personnel and resources as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out this section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H34435F9C11894313BF1B2710B95B26A8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>The Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration may detail personnel to the Clearinghouse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0020E302D0334D2D938996514ECFAB1E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exemptions</header> <subparagraph id="H1066AF2674A94DE8917D1980CAE2EAE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Paperwork reduction act</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>) shall not apply to any rulemaking or information collection required under this section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4ABFC9D30A4A432488BA60518AC1FDAB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal advisory committee act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply for the purposes of carrying out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H434A734621414255B568CBE36F89A0FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clearinghouse contents</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall include best practices and recommendations for part B institutions to build institutional research capacity and access Federal research funding, including best practices and recommendations from appropriate Federal, State, and local organizations, including from annual Agency Plan submissions described under section 4 of the HBCU PARTNERS Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1063d">20 U.S.C. 1063d</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H8DEAF5BA7F1D47F29D99ACB64873F511"><enum>4.</enum><header>Notification of Clearinghouse</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA0FAB84026E459C87DB408726E68392"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notification of publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall provide written notification of the publication of the Federal Clearinghouse on Grant Opportunities for Historically Black Colleges and Universities (referred to in this section and section 5 as the <quote>Clearinghouse</quote>), as required to be established under section 328 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as added by section 3 of this Act, to each part B institution (as such term is defined in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>)) and to Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA98C3B5D64224E109F49053CDDB0DEEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual notification to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall provide an annual report to Congress on the contents of the Clearinghouse.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB451C3B899448FCA1AE1EE6A592C050"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1F74F08154041818223830D36BF03B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide each part B institution described in subsection (a) with the option to receive quarterly updates of Clearinghouse contents; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB85F197696274162ACE41541BB1C6634"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">send quarterly updates of Clearinghouse contents to each part B institution that chooses to receive the updates.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H63F17BCA3D574E588D6A26FFADBD3F55"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grant program review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall each—</text>
<paragraph id="H824EB78EDB7F4FD6AE4A4C30A13E9BD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review grant programs administered by their respective agency and identify any grant program that may be used to implement best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC93EA1F579E44A90B997B2ED0D536D57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify any best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse for which there is not a Federal grant program that may be used for the purposes of implementing the best practice or recommendation as applicable to the agency; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H76EFA90A302E4A88A866616D95CAF3DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on an annual basis, report any findings under paragraph (2) to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

