<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26586-31L-CS-75P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 756 IS: Expressing support for the designation of June 5, 2026, as “National Gun Violence Awareness Day” and June 2026 as “National Gun Violence Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 756</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of June 5, 2026, as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Day</quote> and June 2026 as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas each year in the United States—</text><paragraph id="idc203f7ede75944f7a6d10d80632262dd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nearly 47,000 individuals are killed and nearly 97,000 individuals are wounded by gunfire;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4136198065f6474aa93af5f8a0dc7532"><enum>(2)</enum><text>nearly 19,000 individuals are killed in homicides involving guns;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97b62eb6b9e54b79acb359da753255c4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nearly 27,000 individuals die by suicide using a gun; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id31a4d37c71d6451bbddd3917e319cc4b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>more than 400 individuals are killed in unintentional shootings;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 1968, more individuals have died from guns in the United States than have died on the battlefields of all the wars in the history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, nearly 15,000 people were killed in gun homicides or nonsuicide-related shootings;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2025, more than 230 people were unintentionally shot by a child under 18;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by one count, in 2025 in the United States, there were at least 406 mass shooting incidents in which at least 4 people were killed or wounded by gunfire;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, nationwide, more than 88,000 military veterans died by gun suicide from 2004 to 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, every year in the United States, more than 4,400 children and teens are killed by gun violence, and more than 17,000 children and teens are shot and wounded;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 15,000 people in the United States under the age of 30 die because of gun violence annually, including Hadiya Pendleton, who, in 2013, was killed at 15 years of age in Chicago, Illinois, while standing in a park;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 5, 2026, to recognize the 29th birthday of Hadiya Pendleton (born June 2, 1997), people across the United States will recognize National Gun Violence Awareness Day and wear orange in tribute to—</text><paragraph id="idcac1de09f4cd4ac88765b4a58909b834"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hadiya Pendleton and other victims of gun violence; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id03e057784bdb4520a8178c86f589885b"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>the loved ones of those victims; and</text>
 </paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas June 2026 is an appropriate month to designate as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id3046b271d2d943afb789bd9617087a7d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports—</text><subparagraph id="idd7a1fcda5558441980da134fb9d2123d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the designation of June 2026 as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Month</quote> and the goals and ideals of that month; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5bde553a6d6e47a9bc9d3e9c087eb1ff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the designation of June 5, 2026, as <quote>National Gun Violence Awareness Day</quote>, in remembrance of the victims of gun violence; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddbc877703da64216a99e334a43a3c4ed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the people of the United States to—</text><subparagraph id="id16edffb5c06f4721801bae1d2726df6e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote greater awareness of gun violence and gun safety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd245eb7472694d3dbb74513458ff29a6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wear orange, the color that hunters wear to show that they are not targets, on National Gun Violence Awareness Day;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5f42aaa2ab74b89b422694e99ddbcb5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>concentrate heightened attention on gun violence during the summer months, when gun violence typically increases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id82ea2c36bca9487190252805c9766c77"><enum>(D)</enum><text>bring community members and leaders together to discuss ways to make communities safer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

