<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3127F54F3FB34BB0BAEB315BBD704921" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7715 IH: Justice for Allie Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7715</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit coercing protected adults to send or otherwise transmit an intimate visual depiction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H55706EAD782849539C6D16AEC836D519" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBE7DF6D904F44D8D816C479B22E1689D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice for Allie Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD3C72879DE4049479A825A55E5807683"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sexual exploitation of protected adults</header> 
<subsection id="H0297E8BBD6654EC1A741E54F8A64474E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/109A">Chapter 109A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H451CF559B2004527B8EBE8FAB82523A3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HD013B5B0D2824C82A68904E245621CFC"><enum>2245A.</enum><header>Sexual exploitation of protected adults</header> <subsection id="H9292465CA1D44976B4A5C80F4BA49BCA"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Offense</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, using the mail or any facility or means of interstate or foreign commerce, knowingly persuades, induces, entices, or coerces any protected adult to send or otherwise transmit an intimate visual depiction (as such term is defined in section 1309 of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6851">15 U.S.C. 6851</external-xref>)) with the intent to harm such protected adult, or attempts to do so—</text>
                            <paragraph id="H5E459DE3EEA94B45BB93CE3AD42588D6">
                                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in the case of a first offense under this section, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both; or</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="HCCD62A5561E4431DBEC160C0BE44FC19">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a second or subsequent offense under this section, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection> 
<subsection id="H363DE0E05AD246E49B5060AC97797C46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8C91CA5ACDC44EE288C8542D4C2280C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>protected adult</term> means an individual who is 18 years of age or older and who is unable to protect themselves from abuse, neglect, or exploitation at the time of offense, due to one or more of the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3B27FF251B9C4BE982D289902F38FF1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Autism spectrum disorder (as such term is defined in the most recent edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, as of the date of the commission of the offense).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30C6CC5D1F9544A1B0582B93A68098A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Intellectual developmental disorder (as such term is defined in the most recent edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, as of the date of the commission of the offense) or an intellectual disability (as such term is defined in the edition of the International Classification of Diseases most recently adopted by the Department of Health and Human Services, as of the date of the commission of the offense).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B057A7247654B61B3B6546452E8A9F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cerebral palsy (as such term is defined in the edition of the International Classification of Diseases most recently adopted by the Department of Health and Human Services, as of the date of the commission of the offense).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF755911DEA574FDD878F746265F3176C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Down syndrome (as such term is defined in the edition of the International Classification of Diseases most recently adopted by the Department of Health and Human Services, as of the date of the commission of the offense).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1CACFECF38EE4E0185EF1B57CF928FFA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Major neurocognitive disorder (as such term is defined in the most recent edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, as of the date of the commission of the offense).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3AF56DC3E7E94B7F8D605E957EE6C0A7"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Dementia or Alzheimer’s disease (as such terms are defined in the edition of the International Classification of Diseases most recently adopted by the Department of Health and Human Services, as of the date of the commission of the offense).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18CEBEE1B92348269F82878772486A05"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Schizophrenia or another psychotic disorder (as such term is defined in the most recent edition of the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, as of the date of the commission of the offense).</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H33CEAEB16F1145B8B29369316CD53D45"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>harm</term> means any harm, whether physical, psychological, financial, or reputational harm.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2CDA2647B2A446B49EBDD498083CFF57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/109A">chapter 109A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item related to section 2245 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H21C9D4947D8D48D98CAD5FD4C1FE86B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">2245A. Sexual exploitation of protected adults.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

