<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB5323D83AC534B09835A22D7790ED9A0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7875 IH: Providing Opportunities for Individuals in Need of Treatment and Support Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7875</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a grant program for providing services to individuals experiencing gambling addiction.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4530D9BE9E204AC4A6C2E17DAB0B15DC" style="OLC"><section id="HB78DDF97BAA3432F89795300C85B3DB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Opportunities for Individuals in Need of Treatment and Support Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>POINTS Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H18FBACE7C9004DD2A7A306168442EAC3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for providing services to individuals experiencing gambling addiction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290dd">42 U.S.C. 290dd et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H12DAA3537ECF4709B88D099417713316" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HA8B49B09913E4E41981041B3CCA2F89C"><enum>554.</enum><header>Grants for providing services to individuals experiencing gambling addiction</header><subsection id="HAED9DC00F3CA46ED9839DD721BAF73FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall make grants to States, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations (as such terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)) on a competitive basis to establish, improve, or expand programs providing prevention, screening, assessment, intervention, and treatment services, including culturally and linguistically appropriate services, to individuals at risk of or experiencing clinical gambling addiction.</text></subsection><subsection id="H078701DFD30D4404B487F0E704FABC16" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization that receives a grant under this section shall use funds received through such grant to, with respect to gambling addiction—</text><paragraph id="H8B1B1C41EA1548DB81D0FE0577ADD610" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide training on screening, brief intervention, referral for treatment, and treatment to health care providers and health paraprofessionals who practice in primary care, behavioral health, or other relevant health care settings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A67703FD7D8473A8C4EAC5C1AA24EEE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement a prevention strategy, including public outreach and awareness, in the State or Indian Tribe that receives such funds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BE45204AEA144EF80DCDE8F27091EED" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide a specialized treatment service, including—</text><subparagraph id="H159C54B6CA4B433985B4C3B31B16C491"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in-person or telehealth outpatient treatment; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AACCBB5F41E4CA28430398BE20C81D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a peer support group, including a program operated by Gamblers Anonymous;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69A3CE86AEFF47E8BD49FDC90F0A3495" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish or expand help lines or such other real-time service for prevention or intervention, including coordinating with the National Problem Gambling Helpline operated by the National Council on Problem Gambling, for individuals in the State or Indian Tribe that receives such funds; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H370DB373AA83401AA1E6214876176507"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement such other innovative prevention, intervention, or treatment services determined appropriate by the Assistant Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC23875055F0C445BAD2D4ADCB03124FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making grants under this section, the Assistant Secretary shall give priority to a State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization that—</text><paragraph id="H373E6D073C9B459F9BFEA2CFCC93CA83"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposes to establish, improve, or expand a program described under subsection (a) that serves individuals who are disproportionally impacted by gambling addiction, including men, youth, Native Americans (as defined in section 103 of the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2902">25 U.S.C. 2902</external-xref>)), members of the Armed Forces, and veterans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABB4CAC339B840368FE1158E4B1BECB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposes to establish, improve, or expand a program described under subsection (a) in a primary care setting;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EBD41037E3E4EE98234151BF2280800"><enum>(3)</enum><text>partners with, or proposes to partner with, at least one community-based organization to address gambling addiction; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB27A82B41DBA45C09B96B21070BBB9C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>operates in a health professional shortage area (as defined in section 332), including a rural target area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H723963BF2C3F43A98CF7FABDAFEC153F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="HFABB7B4FB8144D328101F7101A6959E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization seeking to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Assistant Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Assistant Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52DB454A63324D7C971CB96469A0055C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required content</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At a minimum, an application submitted under this subsection shall explain how the applicant establishing, improving upon, or expanding a program described under subsection (a) would increase—</text><subparagraph id="HDEFE67AD1B444E089471311FAF7CCF82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>access to services for gambling addiction in the communities served by such applicant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3619B6378F3C4E00A5D19E26AC3B1065"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of individuals served by such program in at least one such community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3196F16AED554C77AEC351B61922D8A3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall provide technical assistance related to the services described under subsection (b) to each State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization that receives a grant under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H56BC5B2A5BA54287B4CC86EB352E9514"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HA54F37D29314476FAAF0097595761272"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 29, 2027, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the effectiveness of grants made under this section for establishing, improving, or expanding programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F4C1B513D0C430A805EE8CC4C656BB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committee defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committee</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA49BB37CCF5E4042AB9541A9350875F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09131D74490346C29DD17FE40558D12E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DEFF1AFE836416E83B5D8AD29D71A8C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69CE6DA126C34AD2A811ACE485BFD148"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43A16BD1F2C240A2B01FB315F0D6BB9E" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H0DABBEA39C7942FA8729CF58A8A0CDF3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section for fiscal year 2027 an amount that is equal to 33 percent of the amounts received by the Secretary of the Treasury under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4401">section 4401(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4401">26 U.S.C. 4401(a)</external-xref>), with respect to the 2025 calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H397D3396A0BB43DE86AEEFEC5618EF1A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal years 2028 through 2032, the amount authorized by this subsection shall be adjusted by the percentage increase, if any, in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI–U) published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor for the most recent 12-month period for which data is available.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

