<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BON25543-RTY-1D-5L0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3111 IS: Small Businesses before Bureaucrats Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3111</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251105">November 5, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Labor Relations Act to adjust the dollar thresholds for National Labor Relations Board jurisdiction over certain labor disputes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H748370770F7B4018A89110BAF23BDDE2"><section section-type="section-one" id="H69876FA709E344029E5BEC97C8B23DA8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Businesses before Bureaucrats Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF9BE892886404AACA6B7CB981D055643"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increase of dollar threshold for National Labor Relations Board jurisdiction over certain labor disputes</header><subsection id="H34875BABBC8F4C5B90C1802373E790E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 14(c) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/164">29 U.S.C. 164(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBA4F09D37F494BB79592A76A179B03C0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, except that in the event that such standards used a dollar threshold, such threshold shall be updated in accordance with paragraph (2)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf096d60959bd41248da70145ce8e4f6f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF47AA388339C464B9EEB30A95B725AFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53BFE5AA31454CB3AFE52FDDCF0D0CA3"><paragraph id="HEF83986F2E69415C8FE56470E5D6A9AE" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing by rule under paragraph (1) any dollar threshold with respect to a class or category of employers for the purposes of declining to assert jurisdiction over certain labor disputes involving such class or category of employers, the Board shall establish such dollar threshold at an amount—</text><subparagraph id="HBBD6967122CB4EA2B1F283FA84C5FEBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to calendar year 2026, equal to the product of—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B2BB23D1A454C39844D38DF292BD1FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the dollar threshold applicable to such class or category as of the day prior to the date of enactment of the <short-title>Small Businesses before Bureaucrats Act</short-title>, multiplied by</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC7FF27B73BB484FAF6BE276E17CA88C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ten; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CBDF36A2125456CBE71B684E5F05CB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to any calendar year after 2026, equal to the product of—</text><clause id="HF4F5A60F018B4C6F980547607B2516A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the dollar threshold applicable to such class or category with respect to calendar year 2026 (after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Small Businesses before Bureaucrats Act</short-title>), multiplied by</text></clause><clause id="HA1218B0A051D4B3F983CA454C99FAB8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the quotient obtained by dividing—</text><subclause id="HC67D305C6F6F49C09ABD684FBC23BFE9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Personal Consumption Expenditure Per Capita Index (as published by the Bureau of Economic Analysis) with respect to the calendar year preceding the applicable calendar year for which the dollar threshold under this subparagraph is determined; by</text></subclause><subclause id="H35BC2F479CB34851B3FE7A442CBE5204"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Personal Consumption Expenditure Per Capita Index with respect to calendar year 2026.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id166bc21069414302afb9e482d00239b0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personal consumption expenditure per capita index</header><text>Beginning in calendar year 2027, the Director of the Bureau of Economic Analysis of the Department of Commerce shall annually prepare and publish an index (to be known as the <quote>Personal Consumption Expenditure Per Capita Index</quote>) that reflects expenditures by individuals in the United States on a per capita basis with respect to the calendar year preceding the calendar year in which the Director prepares and publishes the index.</text></subsection><subsection id="H54ACC5BC053946039D5D2AF9977A55BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any decision of the National Labor Relations Board relating to the assertion of its jurisdiction over a labor dispute made on or after the later of January 1, 2026, and the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

