<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H37DC2C6364994009ADE66FE603A7DB57" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7150 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to Congress a quarterly report on housing loans insured, guaranteed, or under laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7150</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260120">January 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to Congress a quarterly report on housing loans insured, guaranteed, or under laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H43B36C17B8164C9996DCD30960BEED2D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8ECA774ECB2E4314823767D004A1D814" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Quarterly report to Congress on housing loans insured, guaranteed, or made under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3736 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H755974394DAB446E8244FA4D96AF4F8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The annual report</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) The annual report</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE768AB98B436402B974E4CDB1F1EC69D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HA22444F797A34A5BAF5D62154D0446A6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H4F216F2517EB443BB8B44F6DC2271AD9"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a quarterly report on the administration by the Secretary of housing loan benefits under this chapter. Such quarterly report shall include, with respect to the quarter that precedes the quarter during which the report is submitted, the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H1B9390DB00AE4008A9ACB76F41202491"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of housing loans insured, guaranteed, or made by the Secretary under this chapter.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2DB9D22DA93140CA93284ECEDBB75176"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of applications for housing loan benefits under this chapter denied by the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC98A15826E0F4C0891FA61581070951F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of housing loans insured, guaranteed, or made by the Secretary under this chapter refinanced under section 3710(a)(8) of this title or section 3712 of this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BAB510213F340EBA40948EEEA9DA185"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of veterans who owe a payment on mortgage associated with a loan insured, guaranteed, or made by the Secretary under this chapter that is at least—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5DFAF77C13B74545B3A392BF7859043F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>60 days late; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H627DDDE248DF4E8A987008A68603EE54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>90 days late.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA81F6CBF7C34EEBB7D7071705446D56" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of full-time employees of the VA Home Loan Guaranty Service of the Department (or any successor office).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill> 

