<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEC8A742B77ED49688C2985A5F5BF34C8" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1323 IH: Recognizing the impact the stigmatization of menstruation has on the lives of women, girls, and people who menstruate, and expressing support for the designation of the month of May as “National Menstrual Health Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1323</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260522">May 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the impact the stigmatization of menstruation has on the lives of women, girls, and people who menstruate, and expressing support for the designation of the month of May as <quote>National Menstrual Health Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas menstrual health is an integral part of overall health because most women menstruate, on average, for 40 years of life between menarche and menopause;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the World Bank estimates that globally, 500,000,000 people lack access to menstrual products and clean, safe water and sanitation facilities for menstrual hygiene management;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United Nations Population Fund recognizes that menstruation is intrinsically related to human dignity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas menstrual health impacts the fulfillment of rights such as adequate and secure housing, education, safe and healthy working conditions, and freedom from discrimination;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas 6,000 women in the United States enter menopause each day;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas access to safe, private water and sanitation facilities is essential for effectively managing menstrual hygiene with dignity;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas cultural stigma and lack of access to menstrual health and hygiene education, sanitation, and infrastructure can limit access to school, employment, and religious activities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas negative stigmas around menstruation can impact girls from the onset of puberty and throughout the remainder of their lives;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas menstruation is a normal and healthy part of life for most women and girls, yet, in many societies, the experience of menstruators continues to be constrained by cultural taboos and discriminatory social norms;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the lack of resources for safe and dignified management of menstruation can cause discomfort and psychological stress and add to the shame and sometimes depression that women and girls experience as a result of menstruation-related taboos and stigma;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas women’s health research continues to be understudied, resulting in a lack of research and education around menstrual and uterine health issues such as fibroids, endometriosis, and polycystic ovary syndrome, impacting millions of women in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas an investment in menstrual health is an investment in gender equity and equality; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas menstrual health disparities impact economic opportunities and empowerment: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H1E88A95C463148CD8B9358032598F1AB"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H0CD24C788C1442048CDCAAA2ADFA8C2A"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H01F001091EA8490C9821D648A1C99F46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of <quote>National Menstrual Health Awareness Month</quote>, which are to—</text> <subparagraph id="HAED4295385744049A7E4A2B54818982C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>normalize menstruation as a healthy biological process and eliminate period stigma;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBA2ED23F96614CFE80BF668BF8929832"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate young people to understand menstrual health management and its impacts on the overall physical health, mental health, and well-being of women, girls, and those who menstruate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H015FA403337D4F3DB9E94B9E708150EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support the development of new supportive standards of menstrual health education and care for menstruating girls, women, and people; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H51D506D0C3044DE4B67722C94254D1B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve access to care, treatment, and information regarding menstrual health, including for conditions such as dysmenorrhea, fibroids, endometriosis, and polycystic ovary syndrome;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD6B814138B44C269EC5715396F84E20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acknowledges the importance of ensuring access to appropriate menstrual products and safe, private sanitation and hygiene facilities in schools and workplaces in the United States and abroad;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H98CCC0BC080D4562A94FAD73C8CB1807"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of promoting health equity and addressing the burden negative stigmas around menstruation have on women, girls, and those who menstruate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H689FE48476984AB9A3DEFC9A693DEDB5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the importance of expanding clinical research and health education on conditions impacting menstrual health such as fibroids, endometriosis, polycystic ovary syndrome, and menopause; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65D99CD034144F9A984D16ED154063E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports the designation of a <quote>National Menstrual Health Awareness Month</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

