<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0EB6A978BD834912B17AE1F5AC6289CE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5845 IH: Las Americas Energy Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5845</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251028">October 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a lending program for Latin America and the Caribbean to reaffirm the United States commitment to sustainable and equitable growth and energy security in the Western Hemisphere.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86DC7B0AF96D40B787E94E8A5F1ADC17" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H729F71F4035F4E3DB0BE2E2B3A1B2928" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Las Americas Energy Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD43280C8EFA84259A0C01C1E4636A325"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; purpose; statement of policy</header> <subsection id="H1B7B750E31B4478BA3E30049D92CDB5C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H1B87C3CCD45644AD90453AB1CBAC3603"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Energy independence and security are critical for a country to maintain its sovereignty, independence, and sustainable economic growth.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6CCDD3F90ED48209E0559FF2ED90F2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The International Energy Agency (<quote>IEA</quote>) defines energy security as the uninterrupted availability of energy sources at an affordable price.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB75365DE270947A1AA318C5F5A4FFEB4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The IEA defines long-term energy security as primarily dealing with timely investments to supply energy in line with economic developments and environmental needs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A594272A2B04E22B58DAF7786A5D8BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The IEA defines short-term energy security as focusing on the ability of a country’s energy system to react promptly to sudden changes in the supply-demand balance.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6E49509E98A14848BBA0C7DDFE6209EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The IEA’s Executive Director remarked in February 2023 that Russia’s February 2022 invasion of Ukraine had sparked an ongoing global energy crisis with serious implications for international energy security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3E90A693B9CA4336AE0AAF82E9A22FE0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), a United Nations body that provides regular assessments on global heating, issued a synthesis report in March 2023, and found that the effects of global temperature changes were “already affecting many weather and climate extremes in every region across the globe,” which has “led to widespread adverse impacts on food and water security, human health and on economies and society and related losses and damages to nature and people.”.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H588B2599C76A457AABD65B06F6A635A4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The IPCC notes that to avoid mounting loss of life, biodiversity, and infrastructure, we must have ambitious, accelerated action to adapt to climate change, while also making rapid, deep cuts in greenhouse gas emissions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EA94D8BD6A3443B92329C8D93C9A117"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The World Meteorological Organization’s State of the Climate in Latin America and the Caribbean 2021 report found that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCFBF2DBA56314354809B872477047992"><enum>(A)</enum><text>widespread drought across Latin America and the Caribbean has had significant impact on inland shipping routes, crop yields, and food production, and consequently led to worsening food insecurity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4B72F190587401BA77E491CBA80CDE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>extreme weather events affected millions of people across Central America, exacerbating food insecurity in countries already crippled by economic shocks, COVID–19 impacts, and conflict; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA0EFB731033A4044BAC8FC2E294724FB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sea-level rise poses a major risk to low-lying coastal zones in Latin America and the Caribbean.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB983EFD715EF453ABA0AC30152EB8600"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United Nations states that facilitating more reliable and affordable access to clean electricity helps governments to improve the quality of other basic services, such as education and healthcare. Electricity access also helps diversify and strengthen local economies. Thus, increasing electricity access could reduce the need to migrate to urban areas and other countries.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5B60744AA2D94796BE80F328F1435D45"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Natural disasters of increased frequency are projected to increase the displacement of people and the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees estimates that an annual average of more than 20 million people have been forcibly displaced by weather-related sudden onset hazards every year since 2008.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A8E757E3BDA4406843D386800CA65E8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Rising commodity and energy prices, as well as other global economic shocks such as those caused by natural disasters, pandemics, and conflict pose a serious security risk that may lead to social unrest and instability in Latin America and the Caribbean.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H49F3A721E1BC496D94B9235B6D110748"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States has economic and national security interests in assisting Latin America and the Caribbean to achieve sustainable energy security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1E195188DDD24615BD980C46F9E8EEE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text>
<paragraph id="H996E31610A3B4AA79AB85ABAB203EE6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to advance United States foreign policy and development goals by helping Latin America and the Caribbean meet its short-term energy needs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9E797B3B8E04D99A26463A844C0461B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote the energy security of Latin America and the Caribbean by encouraging the development of accessible, transparent, competitive, and solvent energy markets and systems that provide diversified sources, types, and routes of energy, as well as by prioritizing clean energy sources that reduce carbon emissions and address the ongoing global rise in temperatures;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD42D2D923D3D4BD1AF0915E07F5BAC6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to encourage United States public and private sector investment in Latin American and Caribbean energy infrastructure projects to bridge the gap between energy security and commercial demand in a way that is consistent with the region’s current absorptive capacity, and that recognizes the importance of building and widening the absorptive capacity of the region;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5E7B936DD4B41D383CAF2DBA632B24E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to help facilitate the export of United States energy resources, technology, and expertise to global markets in a way that benefits the comprehensive energy security of Latin America and the Caribbean; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H74BC857D27CB4B9C96AB6411E8D4E150"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to assist partner countries in developing and strengthening regulatory and investment frameworks that support energy security.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H63877C233C414F078BF73BCA8FC01FBA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sovereign lending program for eligible Latin American and Caribbean partner countries</header> <subsection id="H217C6BE054B34A099BF1A42EF94CE36C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall establish a sovereign lending program for eligible Latin American and Caribbean partner countries—</text>
<paragraph id="H9A80E8F3294843C19A4E964C60E972BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support their short-term energy needs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA09B52F4EDA54908991384DCB4B35BA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fund projects that help them transition to renewable or clean energy that reduces carbon emissions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD8A5BF220F32425998CC71CA9219C300"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fund technical assistance programs that ensure that there is a continuous pipeline of clean energy projects available for investment from the United States, Latin America, and the Caribbean;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B13670E7F1A48E1A99C0EC66EC2C192"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide capital and financing for United States companies to make it easier to invest in renewable energy projects in smaller and developing markets; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC8FE6E52F6E64115A45340F29755751E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to provide financing to partner countries to help purchase battery solutions that contribute to reliable and affordable electricity prices.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAC506B9A0D3A46868C5F20543A99A2E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a loan under the program, an eligible Latin American or Caribbean partner country shall submit to the Secretary of the Treasury an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. At minimum, the Secretary shall require an applicant to provide—</text>
<paragraph id="HCA22D03AAD904231BCAD6D0E6EAD4865"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information about the energy projects that will be supported through these funds, including their economic and technical viability, feasibility to attract funding from the private sector, net carbon impact, the potential to use United States goods and services during project implementation, and enhancement of energy market integration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1C39D9C2C2B473F8BAA49148DF5C56F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>data on how funds will support equitable job creation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1933395D836F45218B4BD0B426565AC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information regarding environmental impact, including on biodiversity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0DBC484CE3E4A2B938B028A2EDCD1A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>data on the impact upon marginalized communities; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5467D76B8794710B4070853BF726409"><enum>(5)</enum><text>certification that no funds shall be used to purchase a commodity from or support in any manner a corporation or state-owned enterprise that has an ownership relationship with the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party, the Government of the Russian Federation, or any other foreign adversary or malign influence.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H102E0F7BDAF8445A9E2491A5511ABB76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In selecting among applications for a loan under this section, the Secretary of State shall give preference to an eligible Latin American or Caribbean partner country that shares democratic values, respect for human rights, and economic freedom, as determined by the Secretary of State, including members of the Alliance for Development in Democracy (the Dominican Republic, Costa Rica, Panama, and Ecuador) and the Caribbean Community (CARICOM).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE51E5C73F0564F188DDD0DBF69258A50"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Loan conditions</header><text>A loan provided under the program—</text> <paragraph id="HCDE658E93FE54986AFA6686CA6E11BCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be—</text>
<subparagraph id="H543D9A20ED36497DA68CD385192D45BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a zero-interest loan, not to exceed 30 years in duration; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBE4A1D15AA24FA7BE267B656D2CED0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a low-interest concessional loan, not to exceed 50 years in duration;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H414286B1626645AFB9DC4FF515E4935E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not contain any requirements that an eligible Latin American or Caribbean partner country engage in austerity measures or policies that increase poverty and inequality, diminish the quality of life, and threaten the immediate access of goods and services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68D2A17B5C0940DF93DDB989999C5C72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall ensure that no funds are used to purchase a commodity from or support in any manner a corporation or state-owned enterprise that has an ownership relationship with the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party, the Government of the Russian Federation, or any other foreign adversary or malign actor; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A92F0D70E6C4C4BA9F9ADF38E503450"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall be subject to such other terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Treasury, in concurrence with the Secretary of State, determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC449FC7FFB7F400985497896B399D787"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="HAFC8BE49B0DC426D966948346BFE2195"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 4 years, the Secretary of the Treasury, in concurrence with the Secretary of State, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report on progress in the implementation of the program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5BF2CE17129746A4BC603A8C9043CBF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HF8E113392A7A4759BFFC13C8F3CFCA80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include a description of how the program strengthens United States national security and economic interests in Latin America and the Caribbean;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDB720B58C76F4F3696FF17A3AD327A5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include an assessment of—</text> <clause id="H2A83BFDED67D40CEB3F8CC8413FA5B98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the status and effectiveness of current efforts by regional governments, multilateral development banks, and the private sector to promote energy security in Latin America and the Caribbean and to transition to clean energy practices;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4783D5BFBA674540A6AA992F7E33703A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>major challenges hindering such efforts; and</text></clause> <clause id="H244C427518BD400D8AA083140F8F6981"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how the United States can strengthen the effectiveness of such efforts;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H780AA3AAB0AE4926B4D6AD755EF7E6CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify how activities by the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and other related agencies can effectively be leveraged to strengthen and promote energy independence and security in Latin America and the Caribbean;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7742B8DCB72B4A449995524C7EE8951B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assess diplomatic initiatives taken to secure specific national commitments by governments of eligible Latin American and Caribbean partner countries to undertake efforts to promote energy security and independence in the region, address corruption and rule of law concerns, modernize digital and physical infrastructure, improve ease of doing business, and finance and incentivize energy security initiatives; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4D02DE1CCF584E078B83FDA6621460E3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>detail coordination of efforts with relevant multilateral development banks to advance energy security and independence of eligible Latin American and Caribbean partner countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8F87C5A61B8D403AB530FB47AB393852"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual audit</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury—</text>
<paragraph id="HF74A166ABA2D4D89A4FDFE9DA568DD9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall ensure that a full audit of the program is performed on an annual basis; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4873448E257D4EAD9794206A05CBD6F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall submit the results of the audit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HED72F2EA305F45519E677A3D929A57F4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031 to carry out the program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H537235C588EC4B64BFD0089BC7A60236"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Eligible latin american or caribbean partner country defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible Latin American or Caribbean partner country</term>—</text>
<paragraph id="H2DAB3F05166344A1ADD02FB8CEEDEE3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means a country that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D252D019E59427C9CD413642EB1F655"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a beneficiary country for purposes of the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2701">19 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC3CEBABB02FC434FA67A39867052A40A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a member state of the Caribbean Community (commonly referred to as <quote>CARICOM</quote>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CA1BABEC966444B8A588DEF8817F9F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a member state of the Alliance for Development in Democracy;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1A71BBFFA4094008AD478D58235B4175"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is a country in the Western Hemisphere that is a party to a free trade agreement or preference program with the United States; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8A3D0A4CBF04549B2DB4EA0C27FEB6E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>is a beneficiary country of the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7891D2B897BC47408D29207CDA420FE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not include any country that—</text> <subparagraph id="H26B6371E5F14443FA974C54E0B01FBA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been sanctioned by the United States; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD1F43060E7094EA3B3C7F0FA1546BBC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of State determines—</text> <clause id="H357B736917C84358B7B3C92270B811A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to be a state sponsor of terrorism; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H57EC23CADD2C4A92B9FC548BCD342A84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to be a foreign adversary, defined as a foreign government engaged in a long-term pattern or serious instances of conduct adverse to the national security of the United States or security and safety of United States persons.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HDF0FCF55314E46D9A814F550965BF8C0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Supporting efforts to increase energy security of eligible Latin American and Caribbean partner countries</header> <subsection id="HDAB0E3D79CF94B59998275C8A2E86AD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall, as appropriate, prioritize and expedite the efforts of the Department of State and those other departments and agencies in supporting the efforts of eligible Latin American and Caribbean partner countries to increase their energy security, including through—</text>
<paragraph id="H18E7E4DCFA3D4577B47EC40C80C79D7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing diplomatic and political support to these governments, as necessary—</text> <subparagraph id="H98A5E26669674DB1BB0D42BD81B652C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to facilitate international negotiations concerning cross-border infrastructure and transactions;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE83FB2C1FE824C1A845953100115C673"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enhance and build Latin America’s and the Caribbean’s regulatory environment with respect to energy; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFB16A0B1A6E4F668BCB4C948076F0C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to develop accessible, transparent, and competitive energy markets supplied by diverse sources, types, and routes of energy to achieve energy efficiency; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C97551AE797433E90BD8164F93B767A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing support to improve Latin American and Caribbean energy markets, including early-stage project support and late-stage project support for the construction or improvement of energy and related infrastructure, as necessary—</text> <subparagraph id="H07BA547C9115477BBE4AED2B8A806552"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to diversify the energy sources and supply routes of eligible Latin American and Caribbean partner countries;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB75E8783818F48A39514AC284B995753"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enhance energy market integration across the region; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7DB0C8A51194095BD1F0BCA23A55EF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to increase competition and aggregate energy markets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HAA84B4B1FE25499B9EC81C9DC0EF45A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project selection</header>
<paragraph id="H7BD4C420DD0144A4ACC383192EE43D35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal departments and agencies described in subsection (a) shall identify energy infrastructure projects that would be appropriate for United States assistance under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC80E310FE124E2CA8D384980FCB76F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Project eligibility</header><text>A project is eligible for United States assistance under this section if the project—</text>
<subparagraph id="H09D95E1B68C64ED2A913B6248909485F"><enum>(A)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H768D279BAE74434EA41E84A9BA786202"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improves electricity transmission infrastructure and power generation through the use of a broad power mix, prioritizing renewable energy or energy efficiency;</text></clause> <clause id="HED2C9D7FC0A94631B44960BEC244B129" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advances energy storage projects, smart grid projects, distributed generation models, or other technological innovations and digitalization of the power sector, as appropriate; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3F7346FC40574538AA4DFD92E385D4B0" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improves energy access for marginalized and underserved communities;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB84A8FD2E1A7475B9ABD48EADF11075A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is located in an eligible Latin American or Caribbean partner country; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF79410534736448B91D3E3BF0D315171"><enum>(C)</enum><text>can be conducted in a transparent and accountable manner that mitigates any risk of corruption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33DEDBF41EB041479C58D4956235029E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>In selecting among projects that are eligible under paragraph (2), the Federal departments and agencies described in subsection (a) shall give preference to projects that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4D5F8EACF6634AE4962C6295B968CF9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>link the energy systems of two or more Latin American and Caribbean partner countries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B767BFE32C04DFDA1E85C702F8F513E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address the impacts of sustained global temperature increases;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE3D385FB9C6B49B491943A43916E5669"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance resilience to sustained global temperature increases and global economic shocks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H469EF20F500242CD998BE80DA90BD738"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are expected to enhance energy market integration;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB9753AAE76194969BAD834EEA587B0BF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>can demonstrate sustainability by attracting funding from the private sector, an international financial institution, or the government of the country in which the project will be carried out;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE294DE682967488CAA7EA0FC61D89505"><enum>(F)</enum><text>have the potential to use United States goods and services during project implementation; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBF5404A311CD4ECF9E5DBA0B7DBFDE8B"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">decrease electricity prices and promote price stability in the face of global economic shocks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3A9F5EDBACB441348DF0194E229E422E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Types of assistance</header> <paragraph id="H6FF91443606F4AE2B6BAA421CB0B1455"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Diplomatic and political support</header><text>The Secretary of State shall provide diplomatic and political support to the governments of eligible Latin American and Caribbean countries, as necessary, including by using the diplomatic and political influence and expertise of the Department of State to build the capacity of those countries to resolve any impediments to the development of projects selected under subsection (b).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC8F92964B8E84D7E80821B7564156739"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Early-stage project support</header><text>The Director of the Trade and Development Agency, in consultation with the United States Agency for International Development, the Inter-American Development Bank, the Caribbean Development Bank, and the World Bank, shall provide early-stage project support with respect to projects selected under subsection (b), as necessary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66D66B84A30445E9962789EDED06CDAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Late-stage project support</header><text>Federal departments and agencies described in subsection (a) that provide late-stage project support shall do so with respect to projects selected under subsection (b), as necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H897C846E39F8416B9B7E707BF32BCDB9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception from certain limitation under build act</header><text>For purposes of providing support for projects under this section—</text> <paragraph id="HB4A5DA60D95E4C83A0E91C81D4A4121B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States International Development Finance Corporation may provide support for projects in countries with upper-middle-income economies or high-income economies (as those terms are defined by the World Bank);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3F8B165E51C04C02A1B40167E8941ED0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the restriction under section 1412(c)(2) of the BUILD Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9612">22 U.S.C. 9612(c)(2)</external-xref>) shall not apply; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC96E88D2E84D4B46A19A697B23986ED6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Corporation shall restrict the provision of such support in a country described in paragraph (1) unless—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3163285F3FE14D26A21594D9861DBC71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such support furthers the national economic or foreign policy interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CF7B570FB254C3385487D2883E2B0C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such support is—</text>
<clause id="H8E2FFFBB80F440679C2EE2EE504EE7D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designed to produce significant developmental outcomes or provide developmental benefits to the poorest population of that country; or</text></clause> <clause id="H59B5625AFE984FFBAECD062B441D9983"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>necessary to preempt or counter efforts by a strategic competitor of the United States to secure significant political or economic leverage or acquire national security-sensitive technologies or infrastructure in a country that is an ally or partner of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7AD1121F44CA49D0B6757D8230D76C0C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Progress reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for seven years, the President shall transmit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate a report on progress made in providing assistance for projects under this section that includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="H462C8E2999D34001890DEB00FD3480BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the energy infrastructure projects the United States has identified for such assistance.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5A318F80512242F79C4F8EF3702742A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each such project—</text> <subparagraph id="HECC2FE28E1B54DA5A7A6E7F69F30F9A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the role of the United States in the project, including in early-stage project support and late-stage project support;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H18AD8FEC88354D1190C38FDDE54C40A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount and form of any debt financing and insurance provided by the United States Government for the project;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD8C96A23674C4B1794F4CE108E9D71F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the amount and form of any early-stage project support; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD257A6D33D5B4FE1801331128FAF3D33"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an update on the progress made on the project as of the date of the report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF533EA7CF85B4FDF9AB3FC1A4B3C2728"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Eligible latin american or caribbean partner country defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible Latin American or Caribbean partner country</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3(h).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

