<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BUR25B83-4H4-7J-J01"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3330 IS: Strengthening Sanctions on Fentanyl Traffickers Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To impose sanctions with respect to persons that contribute to international trafficking of illicit drugs, including companies of the People’s Republic of China that supply fentanyl precursors and certain cartels that traffic fentanyl into the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Sanctions on Fentanyl Traffickers Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc536b4ed60504a8f8fed04509260f4d4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id0053c98c9d284711a555cd66b9c9b872"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien; lawfully admitted for permanent residence; national</header><text>The terms <term>admission</term>, <term>admitted</term>, <term>alien</term>, <term>lawfully admitted for permanent residence</term>, and <term>national</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id04992bce9bc746cc985374bb9594ff2c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id31DBB75F137E4C64BBF5CC02E863F920"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Knowingly; knows</header><text>The terms <term>knowingly</term> and <term>knows</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc93bccd8741e4cefb9f1f0f0fe009415"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id1e883a43bcf645098d378a5d35edc5b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id122ad994b62e41a580eb5a1abae9ea63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States (including any foreign branch of such an entity); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id208e7939b72f44fb817dc765ab3d5833"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id148fc583a61f43e6887fe7c0fe25a496"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prioritization of identification of persons from the People's Republic of China</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7211 of the Fentanyl Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/2311">21 U.S.C. 2311</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id6abf5e946ae0486fa648091bdd551e4a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="id058e7fa8ebb44b7bb03cfd415a55f02f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5847b459661d4b3e8c2f9992c9ddf35e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph (3):</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60A799168A004817906D5F4502207ED3"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d80e0253c5a48dd93c3ccad24777100"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2226ae84f2094538b1055c830dd484c0"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>In preparing the report required by paragraph (1), the President shall prioritize the identification of persons of the People's Republic of China involved in the shipment of fentanyl, fentanyl analogues, fentanyl precursors, precursors for fentanyl analogues, pre-precursors for fentanyl and fentanyl analogues, and equipment for the manufacturing of fentanyl and fentanyl-laced counterfeit pills to Mexico or any other country that is involved in the production of fentanyl that is trafficked into the United States, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3af702517ecd4f4f8b456fdf25567b6f"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any such entity involved in the production of pharmaceuticals; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e7bb60b77d44364ae4c4f00e8dbb41c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any person that is acting on behalf of any such entity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide842cf076d594e53b788a33de53779d6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of prioritization</header><clause id="id2a4e5b900f8549fda697acd87ee05d16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The President shall continue the prioritization described in subparagraph (A) until the People’s Republic of China is no longer the primary source for the shipment of fentanyl, fentanyl analogues, fentanyl precursors, precursors for fentanyl analogues, pre-precursors for fentanyl and fentanyl analogues, and equipment for the manufacturing of fentanyl and fentanyl-laced counterfeit pills to Mexico or any other country that is involved in the production of fentanyl that is trafficked into the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="idfa275044618b49438ed9d54458871532"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the President so certifies to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3047bf01a4724fbc95f96a77285b02a7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Person of the People's Republic of China defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>person of the People's Republic of China</term> means—</text><clause id="id9b5812f4e305478880750a017f735446"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual who is a citizen or national of the People's Republic of China; or</text></clause><clause id="id7e6cfc5435d34a9c9ec4669d2284f780"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the People's Republic of China or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Government of the People's Republic of China.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id041fe696659b468b8b9dbf01604d8bd1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>the date that is 5 years after such date of enactment</quote> and inserting <quote>December 31, 2030</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ide7e67b7fa9e34e4b8f92b40c0dab6b9e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="id0a848a5f5fdf43068e305eaafe9eef82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President is authorized to impose the sanction described in subsection (b) with respect to a foreign person if the President determines that the foreign person—</text><paragraph id="id4302d8351c824924ae6509b713d4e77f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has engaged in, or attempted to engage in, activities or transactions in the People’s Republic of China, including in Hong Kong and Macau, or with respect to persons domiciled in, organized under the laws of, or with their principal place of business in such jurisdictions, that have contributed to, or pose a significant risk of contributing to, the international proliferation of illicit synthetic narcotics or the means of production of illicit synthetic narcotics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa9cae16c0e842189f251d3531821e94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has knowingly or with reckless disregard has received any property or interest in property that—</text><subparagraph id="id8bd2a7eed88a4c84b4d5f438941ca2ca"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constitutes or is derived from proceeds of activities or transactions in the People’s Republic of China, including in Hong Kong and Macau, or with respect to persons domiciled in, organized under the laws of, or with their principal place of business in such jurisdictions, that have materially contributed to, or pose a significant risk of materially contributing to, the international proliferation of illicit synthetic narcotics or the means of production of illicit synthetic narcotics; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddf5deb7e11ca491db3355f96ceef616a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was used or may have been intended to be used to commit or to facilitate activities or transactions in the People’s Republic of China, including in Hong Kong and Macau, or with respect to persons domiciled in, organized under the laws of, or with their principal place of business in such jurisdictions, that have materially contributed to, or pose a significant risk of materially contributing to, the international proliferation of illicit synthetic narcotics or the means of production of illicit synthetic narcotics;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide5bfa9a7c32b4edca88c8d7d11c7416c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is a port or ship owned or operated by the People's Republic of China that, knowingly or with reckless disregard, facilitates the shipment and transportation of illicit synthetic narcotics or precursors of illicit synthetic narcotics (including in such circumstances where those precursors are improperly labeled during the customs process);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id527cc1f3a4834129bc8ea798d62baddf"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is an entity of the People's Republic of China that produces illicit synthetic narcotics or their precursors and, knowingly or with reckless disregard, sells those precursors to persons involved in the proliferation of illicit synthetic narcotics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a36396b5f584fc2bc03e0ae69942934"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is an online marketplace of the People's Republic of China that, knowingly or with reckless disregard, facilitates the sale of, exchange of, shipment of, transshipment of, conveyance of, or payment for illicit synthetic narcotics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f8d54e947b8473f8edb0eac9020a5d8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>is a covered PRC government entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc99568a3c3854cc9a769ba2907f5638a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>is an entity of the People's Republic of China that knowingly or with reckless disregard, provides material support related to illicit synthetic narcotics to a covered PRC government entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb0d69ed50e4438db8c1d4b9b80fd400"><enum>(8)</enum><text>has established an entity that engages in, has engaged in, or is designed to engage in evading sanctions that would otherwise be imposed pursuant to this section; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5cdf65070ac946e09079a039ed6788d9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>is acting directly or indirectly for or on behalf of a person referred to in paragraphs (1) through (8).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5c18c8d2800c47518d236c3e780ffbd4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanction described</header><paragraph id="id30f541a42faf477483750d96668e3861"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanction described in this subsection is the exercise of all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person if such property or interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf34732e7d1c549e5942642549ca82a7c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise the authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to the extent necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c6eb62198eb4de0be1c118d7dfc7c5e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to any person who violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of any prohibition of this section, or an order or regulation prescribed under this section, to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection section 206(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c9af2ef72c340c48782fef8350ea81c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0499555b58c45abafb6992226bf8caf"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32cb77895ef34546add3b9d7bfcf932c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this section shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77e0a44bef144d46891a33b42983af24"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9f468fe4e82417bb275e83e236d670f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence and law enforcement actions</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="idddead8e6fa354b32b2611db651ff9501"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60b319abf5f94c8289326ac08a2bbaa2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any authorized intelligence or law enforcement activities of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcd6645b2bc6f4b559f39438857fb2191"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requests by appropriate congressional committees</header><paragraph id="id1fef90c97129400db72f9130ac0133bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after receiving a request that meets the requirements of paragraph (2) with respect to whether a foreign person has engaged in an activity described in subsection (a), the President shall—</text><subparagraph id="id4f809b32c09947c38aaed19fecdd4558"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine if that person has engaged in such an activity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id96331dd2bc2742ffb201ccb2f2f6402d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit a classified or unclassified report to the chairperson and ranking member of the committee or committees that submitted the request with respect to that determination that includes—</text><clause id="id4e44aa038e274597992dafa04222d673"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a statement of whether or not the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions with respect to the person; and</text></clause><clause id="idf9b632042cc94f9691747774d5422f61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions, a description of those sanctions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc9150b38f6944d6871a3e596bf0ae5a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A request under paragraph (1) with respect to whether a foreign person has engaged in an activity described in subsection (a) shall be submitted to the President in writing jointly by the chairperson and ranking member of one of the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c378f42c12a42e689da42de341071ff"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="id9ca75b1c69cc469eb680c93794bc11fc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id28a9e931202f40f3a28d3cb6b64479e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07257064ac6c4aaa8ca34524cd0c926f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Select Committee on Strategic Competition between the United States and the Chinese Communist Party of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id29c7d05833b6466a8adf0d85576eb1dc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered PRC government entity</header><text>The term <term>covered PRC government entity</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="id674d9673ec504b7ba94b4c390f7f0cc7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Government of the People's Republic of China, a government official of the People's Republic of China, or any entity or instrumentality thereof, that is identified by the United States Government as knowingly or recklessly facilitating the flow of illicit synthetic narcotics into the United States or otherwise providing material support to a foreign person described in subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbc17406c94347beadab0ec11a48e979"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any subsidiary, affiliate, or successor of an entity described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb65479f88b344a8bea2c6c1d675bbad"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person owned or controlled by, or that provides material support to or for, or receives materially support from an entity described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc49c85585c2542f8af927d90c0a9c473"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Illicit synthetic narcotics</header><text>The term <term>illicit synthetic narcotics</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id447101994aaf463db2ae7d9c9deb6369"><enum>(A)</enum><text>controlled substances, as that term is defined in section 102(6) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802(6)</external-xref>), with the exception of—</text><clause id="id71329fa79ca24711810c8541c7419658"><enum>(i)</enum><text>substances of natural origins; and</text></clause><clause id="id5cf37c27427b4a579d962641d460e140"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>medications that are lawful under the laws of the United States and the Drug Enforcement Administration has provided an import permit to the importing organization for the import of such medication;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id291143ade86c4e98a123a2f40a983c5c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>listed chemicals, as that term is defined in section 102(33) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802(33)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida8bce63f4ea74048a76d88dd3eb89517"><enum>(C)</enum><text>active pharmaceutical ingredients or chemicals that are used in the production of controlled substances described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35a840202bcd4f768743b5b9bd215097"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to significant fentanyl trafficking organizations</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2923abe7484e4e3aae122e88e7bb7431"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States sanctions imposed on the transnational criminal organizations listed in subsection (b) provided for in the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1901">21 U.S.C. 1901 et seq.</external-xref>), as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, shall remain in effect except as provided in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ebd7a40626c4cca8dda136d8d378abb"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transnational criminal organizations</header><text>The transnational criminal organizations listed in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="id8a24745ec3cf458ea75d3ed26e0bbca4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Sinaloa Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida3b53037dad746cba3ebbd12747d7b24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Jalisco New Generation Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f0d97ffab674a35a75d7379dfdc403e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Gulf Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id966c25d2f9b64ed2b876bc20d6b476b9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Los Zetas Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85247e5964a541368e2d70587ad00009"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Juarez Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcce4aac5ee5f45008b250b5f3759ae02"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Tijuana Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb24d6e77a5cb4f009d2a24cdd2ed12e7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Beltran-Leyva Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b6076f23c7042f9bb19331c227a9da0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>La Familia Michoacana.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61f7974e8cb34f65b434cbf6c0534d14"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of certain sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may terminate the application of any sanctions described in subsection (a) with respect to any transnational criminal organization listed in subsection (b) if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notice that such transnational criminal organization is not engaging in the activity that was the basis for such sanctions.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3cc906238e894c03bb5ed7f781c74b04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idc1a3849140d947c3bb54683e43481195"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id394b077c64ba43f296fc940fe894010e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="id2e2b1e9ff79b449184bda82c05e0edcb"><enum>6.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons involved in global illicit drug trade</header><subsection commented="no" id="id8d0e031e69cd4575b1bdb6d58cd19008"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose any of the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person determined by the President—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id4146e020a2f741f89d0c4ecb6b1e3e76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to have engaged in, or attempted to engage in, activities or transactions that have materially contributed to the international trafficking of illicit drugs or their means of production;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id9340922fcb5a459ea0488a9ed83b033b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to have knowingly received any property or interest in property that the foreign person knows—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idbcff5acd0bb34318a211894944fa3b45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constitutes or is derived from proceeds of activities or transactions described in paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id354d74852bfa4121aee13a1badf4943d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was used or intended to be used to commit or to facilitate such activities or transactions; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id3955aeccc84444009da0722cf11dae53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to be a leader or official of any sanctioned person or of any foreign person that has engaged in any activity or transaction described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="id80E390776CAB4DA1BED62A13697AD20D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="idbad41c1bef9b437ebbd0b208fb0196bf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President may, pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the sanctioned person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PH06AD34046A3E4775BEFEA8F77603855C"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Banking transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may prohibit any transfers of credit or payments between financial institutions or by, through, or to any financial institution, to the extent that such transfers or payments are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and involve any interest of the sanctioned person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PHE839607806344081A38D20CAFE4CF59A"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Loans from United States financial institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may prohibit any United States financial institution from making loans or providing credit to the sanctioned person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PHFB880DE1C08641F380A01D622592602E"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Foreign exchange transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may prohibit any transactions in foreign exchange that are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and in which the sanctioned person has any interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PHC995E76A02A04E2F92C5DD5E2707679B"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on investment in equity or debt of sanctioned person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may prohibit any United States person from investing in or purchasing significant amounts of equity or debt instruments of the sanctioned person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="PH28648A2CB6BF4F0B87A1A4133D839C41"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibitions on financial institutions</header><text>The President may direct that the following prohibitions be imposed with respect to a sanctioned person that is a financial institution:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="PH4E5A1826E80F4DF6ABBC920DA041547C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition on designation as primary dealer</header><text>Neither the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System nor the Federal Reserve Bank of New York may designate, or permit the continuation of any prior designation of, the financial institution as a primary dealer in United States Government debt instruments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="PH2168E4EDDAC641B2B8AE5E49E831DD8D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on service as a repository of government funds</header><text>The financial institution may not serve as agent of the United States Government or serve as repository for United States Government funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="PHFC7E2FBD7203400FB12B8A7CD263CF6A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Procurement ban</header><text>The President may direct that the United States Government may not procure, or enter into any contract for the procurement of, any goods or services from the sanctioned person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PHAC9A3A2126D941F78A2C923E63F6E122"><enum>(8)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Barring of corporate officers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may direct the Secretary of State to deny a visa to, and the Secretary of Homeland Security to bar from the United States, any alien that the President determines is a leader, official, senior executive officer, or director of, or a shareholder with a controlling interest in, the sanctioned person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="PH4B2F9E94468A4088ABE4DEBCFBBBAF94"><enum>(9)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions on principal executive officers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may impose on the principal executive officer or officers of the sanctioned person, or on individuals performing similar functions and with similar authorities as such officer or officers, any of the sanctions described in paragraphs (1) through (8) that are applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idB1A1E3A1010D4AA4AFD1DCF8761CDB76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain sanctioned persons</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idff7b747c5a2049eb865cf8c4c52eabd6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (3), an alien with respect to whom the President imposed sanctions under paragraph (1) or (8) of subsection (b) shall be—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id75a2bc7d8a974e3daee749f2ecdae0c3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idb598b6ae4df4432792f6ddcf0001a0dd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idb8a7c60d37c64a1da0ce9704d8a69218"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id58f6873bf5c24e2d80d1040a958767ce"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="idea44dad2dbc44f19b9f6755e0d9a4456"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of any alien described in paragraph (1) is subject to revocation regardless of the date on which the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="iddfb9474b213d4d3d8cc0157ff9782df1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause commented="no" id="idc2167789459e4a52af3ec28f877d0719"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idb1b18e57367c41beadea11d63c9c6467"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the possession of the alien.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id97E572D00BBD4F36A1D6220AD03D5121"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Paragraphs (1) and (2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien described in paragraph (1) if the President determines that the admission of the alien would not be contrary to the interests of the United States, including if the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, determines, based on a recommendation of the Attorney General, that the admission of the alien would further important United States law enforcement objectives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6efd532b848542d19eb0b54d5038d7fa"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="idedd798c06ac04fb2a5ec4cedb96db78a"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9abc6c06e9ff485693232cbf2498260b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any sanctions imposed with respect to a foreign person pursuant to this section shall terminate on the date that is 6 years after the date on which the sanction were imposed.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79bd00d4211e4d72b653a611e3c0686e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc88c29f9677348eaa5cf7a7bd5a2475f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the termination of sanctions under paragraph (1) if the President certifies to Congress, not later than 30 days before the termination of such sanctions, that the continuation of such sanctions is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04e55016354647f2b960ed1df870a4d4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Renewal of waiver</header><text>The President may, on a case-by-case basis, renew a waiver issued under subparagraph (A) for additional periods of not more than 2 years each, for an indefinite number of periods, if the President, prior to each such renewal, certifies to Congress that the renewal is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf163ef357af24651861084810ffd526f"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52bb3c6974eb4359aee517ab598faf20"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id61e4f0d302f545bb92c31e65c350f166"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this section shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6b0b39240142454b86b18373672d9cba"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ea03f9ffdd24a0ea8c7c8cdc89a1ea7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence and law enforcement actions</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="id7cf3e181403e4a69bb4c95d44cbc158e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideea96934210c4f57bfdbd9437e101037"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any authorized intelligence or law enforcement activities of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idE71990C0218949AB9002268D02520EE4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id7149e32f98a64740a69e8804002bd8cc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Entity</header><text>The term <term>entity</term> means a partnership, association, trust, joint venture, corporation, group, subgroup, or other organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id5e510413659f42b0bfbad3913b013907"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> includes—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idC2043EA64DDB473AADA8267CBE3D0E50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a depository institution (as defined in section 3(c)(1) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(c)(1)</external-xref>)), including a branch or agency of a foreign bank (as defined in section 1(b)(7) of the International Banking Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/3101">12 U.S.C. 3101(7)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id901FCD59434F4B34BCB2E3081ED1F667"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a credit union;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id8EFBA5B14F8C477FB98421F68C679E58"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a securities firm, including a broker or dealer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idD92AA75FE9874E50A7FB01A408952AB2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an insurance company, including an agency or underwriter; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7D6B36BE881A4B6F9A63FFEBE58F9B1E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other entity that provides financial services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="idcb09bdcdc438433d8d0055a1b5e6c6a9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Means of production</header><text>The terms <term>means of production</term> includes any activities or transactions involving any equipment, chemical, product, or material that may be used, directly or indirectly, in the manufacture of illicit drugs or precursor chemicals.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id814e48a7ec2d494fa2baacedba70ac1d"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Proliferation of illicit drugs</header><text>The term <term>proliferation of illicit drugs</term> means any illicit activity to produce, manufacture, distribute, sell, or knowingly finance or transport narcotic drugs, controlled substances, listed chemicals, or controlled substance analogues, as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id53af765ee124478ab9c197f5b94c97e3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sanctioned person</header><text>The term <term>sanctioned person</term> means any person with respect to which sanctions are imposed under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id97f5d588a76549b69e6cad9bb25570dd"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States financial institution</header><text>The term <term>United States financial institution</term> means a financial institution (including its foreign branches)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="idB344A1DE31CF47478D6A8E1F6DF8685A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="idDB9A4248A7CD44D7B1C353385900439A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

