<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ALL26173-965-RF-S69"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4394 IS: Promoting Police Leadership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4394</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to improve the COPS program with respect to training command-level personnel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Police Leadership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="iddd1d84867d5745e4812104a2d8db58ba"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commander curriculum development</header><subsection id="idc5524606c11a4b7e85f7e408deb3580c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 901(a) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="ide369f49380b649ceab586b66835b5419"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (32), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd38b3631d1c440787ea9ebc2668d6c4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (33), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb42f233d06b047da9b5cecc502d85fe8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0bb7f9a694344abda06a2b4772a6e4d9"><paragraph id="id2eb01a448d35479ea018bb46025a63de"><enum>(34)</enum><text>the term <term>command-level personnel</term> means law enforcement officers employed by a State, local, or Tribal law enforcement agency whose responsibilities include managing, directing, or overseeing law enforcement operations within a geographic subunit of the jurisdiction in which such agency has primary responsibility for law enforcement activities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf5b188a1d3904e7eb95f4acb500db3a2"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>COPS program</header> <text>Section 1701 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
        <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id01d7379e67234238add329bb969a5949">
          <subsection id="id66360768554f48be816ff3c619efc720">
            <enum>(q)</enum>
            <header>Training in improving police command-Level personnel leadership, management, and
              effectiveness</header>
            <paragraph id="id758deb1995a947208a1c5dcb59f38237">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>Training curricula</header>
              <subparagraph id="idb43bac95055f48e6bc6f3989f5d7e2b2">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Attorney General shall develop training curricula or identify effective existing training curricula for command-level personnel relating to—</text>
                <clause id="id42e1a7c4e6854a359fd879fd7b4ec478">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>leadership and strategic thinking;</text> </clause> <clause id="id918b703892874b3c8a922b67aa9ffc1d"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>critical incident response and management, including understanding, preparing for, and responding to the effect of critical incidents on officers and communities;</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="id80cb6c835898479e95e02535d9789293">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>risk management;</text> </clause> <clause id="id4f4857ea4d08437289b9f7f738cad89b"> <enum>(iv)</enum> <text>officer wellness;</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="id59d9cf5f20fb4cd1a6e3b4705511e90c">
                  <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>data analysis and data-driven policing tactics;</text> </clause> <clause id="idedf0d8a8353d46839e840ce1a85221db"> <enum>(vi)</enum> <text>evidence-based decision making; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="idc48cbbef2f064466985e9835bca11e57">
                  <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text>building community trust.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id23f93ae3b0a14c00a43f09ff1ad4eace"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Requirements</header> <text>The training curricula developed or identified under this paragraph shall include—</text>
                <clause id="id120c64b42c654ed880304c7e3543610c">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>primarily in-person instruction and peer-to-peer learning;</text> </clause> <clause id="id3e6f412cf6fe49868a33c1a91021639d"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a framework for a practical, evidence-based problem solving component under which participating command-level personnel—</text>
                  <subclause id="iddd86541ef2c14fc1aeb6f4298c288923">
                    <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>identify and develop a proposed solution to a leadership, operational, or management challenge relevant to personnel in the command-level personnel’s employing law enforcement agency;</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="ida04817a2893945f986393a2fa0eac051">
                    <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>receive feedback from curriculum instructors and other participating command-level personnel to refine the proposed solution accordingly to meet the needs of the law enforcement agency and community served; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                  <subclause id="id221cc414f3c6488791bb8fff94667c52">
                    <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>present a final, implementable product emphasizing evidence-based strategies to program instructors and the command-level personnel’s district or geographic command; and</text>
                  </subclause>
                </clause>
                <clause id="id343b6edb706d403fa66a9bd82eb810f7">
                  <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the incorporation of pre-course and post-course assessments to measure knowledge acquisition and leadership competencies relevant to the training curricula.</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="idca7eec83605e4c7daee639b18c162d02">
                <enum>(C)</enum>
                <header>Consultation</header>
 <text>The Attorney General shall develop and identify training curricula under this paragraph in consultation with relevant law enforcement agencies of States and units of local government, universities with appropriate law-enforcement or leadership programs, and any other entities the Attorney General determines appropriate.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id4ff19d9c1b1b4e1ea6ac6508e284ca46">
              <enum>(2)</enum>
              <header>Certified programs and courses</header>
              <subparagraph id="id19b38c5a8ffa433a8f8f0d91072c08bf">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which training curricula are developed or identified under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall establish a process to—</text>
                <clause id="id3697f9043313485b87ccd161c7dbe111">
                  <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>certify training programs and courses offered to command-level personnel which incorporate 1 or more of the training curricula developed or identified under paragraph (1), or equivalents to such training curricula, which may include certifying training programs or courses offered on or before the date on which the Attorney General establishes the process; and</text>
                </clause>
                <clause id="id5040ee757e6b42d6a59c2244ca551897">
                  <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>terminate the certification of a training program or course that fails to meet the standards developed or identified under paragraph (1).</text>
                </clause>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id4a3c376bbce543e58b4b558fa44c7dbc">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
                <header>Partnerships with educational institutions</header>
 <text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which training curricula are developed or identified under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall develop criteria to ensure that entities which offer training programs or courses that are certified under subparagraph (A) collaborate with educational institutions to evaluate and continuously improve the curricula and coursework of those educational institutions.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id90a95458fb5c4b8dafa26cdcea0527af">
              <enum>(3)</enum>
              <header>List</header>
 <text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Attorney General completes the activities required under paragraphs (1) and (2), the Attorney General shall publish a list of law enforcement agencies of States and units of local government employing law enforcement officers who have successfully completed a course using the training curricula developed or identified under paragraph (1), or equivalents to such training curricula, which shall include—</text>
              <subparagraph id="idf91700e2348444cdafe41df73bddb74c">
                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the total number of law enforcement officers that are employed by the law enforcement agency; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph id="id65d6483a856d486da591fdadf5621ab6">
                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the number of law enforcement officers who have completed such a course.</text>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
 </subsection></section><section id="id31fefd7490c8422da122c646d2d4a738"><enum>3.</enum><header>Attorney General reports</header><paragraph id="id401f3f6fc0a7480f982e520101247c2c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the activities carried out as a result of the amendments made under section 2.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide69ded71d8964f08af0644889ae89907"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, at a minimum, information on—</text><subparagraph id="idcd759e09f4064a9a9d234f0596906ac0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>steps taken by the Attorney General to develop or identify curricula under section 1701(q)(1) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, as added by section 2;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0144f3f2590b48a7831bdc0776072648"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any assessments conducted or identified by the Attorney General on the effectiveness and utilization of curricula developed or identified under section 1701(q)(1) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, as added by section 2;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id916eab0746484108b623cc9db4c4f3ad"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for curriculum updates and improvements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id105d06229ee743adb7a7d5ee3789a5c0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>barriers to training implementation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="ide03cb3802c9a40de957dac88d17b71f8" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb62b3b60f0ba4a1ca3e642152c722131"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a review of the actions taken by the Attorney General pursuant to this Act and the amendments made by this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf7204befa1744ba1935d1fab847f7fd1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to Congress a report on the review conducted under paragraph (1), which shall include a description of—</text><subparagraph id="id23e1a0bd4e614d189b51be47050b8343" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the process for developing and identifying curricula under section 1701(q)(1) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, as added by section 2, including the effectiveness of the consultation by the Attorney General with the agencies, associations, and organizations identified under that section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d12911d7d1f452aaaaadd83639de978" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the certification of training programs and courses under section 1701(q)(2) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, as added by section 2, including the development of the process for certification and its implementation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idb90082090d59498dbff0207818df307c"><enum>5.</enum><header>State certifications and training standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, shall be construed to preempt or replace the authority of any State or local government, including any Peace Officer Standards and Training entity or similar certifying body, to set and enforce certification, training, or qualification standards for law enforcement officers.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

