<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E84396209084AB49A40B8FD7EA3B5AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8295 IH: Protecting Families from Fertility Fraud Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8295</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to criminalize abuse with respect to assisted reproductive technology.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEE6B1A788941425694BC21195FA82762" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFE1B6C20FF894E5A8CD760E589F1410B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Families from Fertility Fraud Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HFA4A6B381A1E48A0974E8C3D23C47ABC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Abuse with respect to assisted reproductive technology</header> 
<subsection id="HF7EC088D483D4CB8932D3C6111148C6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/109A">Chapter 109A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4855F53211C44B2681672A448D961EE6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H7414DC2D00E34CCD9C2B509DC5925655"><enum>2249.</enum><header>Abuse with respect to assisted reproductive technology</header> <subsection id="H491A0921F20C47669358E22D255F5928"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Offense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, in any circumstance described in subsection (b), knowingly misrepresents the nature or source of DNA used in assisted reproductive technology (including any treatment or procedure that involves the handling of human oocytes or embryos such as in vitro fertilization, gamete intrafallopian transfer, and zygote intrafallopian transfer) or assisted insemination (including any procedure that involves the handling of sperm including intrauterine insemination) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H231AE16308A241819F3531185BBE9EDE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Circumstance described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text> <paragraph id="HE21D9247EB5248E5B4CBE192D22AF078"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant or victim traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08F38EE98B77446B8C1C24D9D2CE7599"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the defendant used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E82C91C884E4106BAA4685AD18E3BDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2A8C1A930DF4A4DBD208CD506351A1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the defendant transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFD8294EBF3B444F8940D6A0A4216DF3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any instrument, item, substance, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6868CF25219F4484BAA124551FFC9A4B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14BEC26912634BC4A1D489F0C1D1D2AD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7B79177F4A554565B517DF2C6D35ECA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case in which DNA testing leads to the identification of a person who has violated subsection (a), no statute of limitations that would otherwise preclude the prosecution of an offense under subsection (a) shall preclude such prosecution until the date that is 10 years after the date on which such person was identified.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HE655BCBE43C44EDAB1D3D6C50822F0EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Racketeering activity</header><text>Section 1961(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>section 2249 (relating to abuse with respect to assisted reproductive technology),</quote> after <quote>(relating to nuclear materials),</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H86C5C0D5C00846BFA82CE22D2C6A994C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/109A">chapter 109A</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7D8611FF807341148C03D0F734774DC8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">2249. Abuse with respect to assisted reproductive technology.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

