<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H48E5532BC7FE4BD883514DA7CC9CCF6B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5945 IH: USS Frank E. Evans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5945</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the inclusion on the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Wall of the names of the lost crew members of the USS Frank E. Evans killed on June 3, 1969.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE69875ECB781473599C47C6822E0522C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD138F6676D86486AB44B307EB350058E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>USS Frank E. Evans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H38546E5B24BB4591889123051479B2AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion on the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Wall of the names of the lost crew members of the USS Frank E. Evans killed on June 3, 1969</header> <subsection id="H49DB8587BCC44B58AEF94A4FD0CB8D10"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall authorize the inclusion on the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Wall in the District of Columbia of the names of the 74 crew members of the USS Frank E. Evans killed on June 3, 1969.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H07B1E7D0B78447FC9C5AFCD30B75BAE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall consult with the Secretary of the Interior, the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Fund, and other applicable authorities with respect to any adjustments to the nomenclature and placement of names pursuant to subsection (a) to address any space limitations on the placement of additional names on the Vietnam Veterans Memorial Wall.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H95E04F0EEAC340F1A21C423B726436E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of commemorative works act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/89">Chapter 89</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Commemorative Works Act</quote>), shall not apply to any activities carried out under subsection (a) or (b).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


