<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3F4BBB7F775642189037CE6DA8FF05B2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9307 IH: Web of Biological Data Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9307</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000139">Mr. Van Epps</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a centralized resource for access to data to facilitate biological research through enabling advanced computational methods such as artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H89220D11D2824F3D9965893DF28C8DF5" style="OLC"> 
<section commented="no" section-type="section-one" id="H448815EE44CD49EEAC397964C4CF9D70"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Web of Biological Data Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5778B457CB304228ABBDD64FB4857C9F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Web of Biological Data</header> <subsection id="HF615833BE3144ED5BE248B1020C7F458"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE9BAA844E7FC4DA2B3B3F8FE6DD854D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory board</header><text>The term <term>advisory board</term> means the advisory board established under subsection (h).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8654FC921DC4E5E96DFE22EA377EE71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Laboratory selected under subsection (b)(1)(A).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0118954D99934FC393037B2ACEB19319"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text>The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7EF8BAE3DB046378EA7B577860FFD90"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE999D6447CF4E0B90562FEB45D85151"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Web</header><text>The term <term>Web</term> means the Web of Biological Data established under subsection (b)(1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H15E3BC08F9714B1EBB803347DC411846"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H602ED0893AAA46A3901C6D0C12B22EEF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7853F3F7B72549AB85E3405DB1D344AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through a competitive process, award a grant to a National Laboratory to establish a centralized data resource, to be known as the <quote>Web of Biological Data</quote>, to facilitate biological research through advanced computational methods such as artificial intelligence; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0055B488BE148D49E406DB777019388"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a research and development program to further data science relating to generating, storing, curating, and managing biological data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA09F002316A426385A26FE11621F487"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The Web shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H2AAFE0C878CB491E917B20F443C1CE11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as a single point of entry for researchers to access different sources of biological data, especially those funded by the Federal Government, by directly hosting data or providing access to existing databases;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31864B4A5A404383AC9BD0774D1BB5FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have metrics and metadata to indicate data quality, including usability, interoperability, and completeness; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H194FF231C0D3493CA13F0B710E34913E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include tiered levels of cybersecurity safeguards and access controls to protect different types of biological data assets hosted in or connected to the Web.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C0DF2154C444763B488274D87F3DC0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of Director</header><text>As part of establishing the Web, the Director may—</text> <paragraph id="HFC49F7A8EFE14A0BB3F085A31EF81571"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enter into data sharing agreements, memoranda of understanding, or other relevant contracts with other Federal departments and agencies to integrate biological datasets into the Web that are not hosted by the Department of Energy;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB19A1DA125EF47129804255C64EE2D30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enter into cost-sharing agreements with nongovernmental entities to fund the Web;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71CFD171F8764D44B868C817386E9B26"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish partnerships with other Federal departments and agencies, academia, industry, and international partners and allies to optimize usability and performance of the Web; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D478BA3B25748848E2BBFA37FE46A15"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carry out any other activities determined necessary by the Secretary to advance United States biological data curation and sharing.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD2BAD4C6002D4C799221E975FC154F87"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives an implementation plan for the Web that describes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6D9A0271C45D4CC994413F016D272349"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how the Director and the Secretary shall implement this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06D1B26AD7B244BA971B69D30BA880EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan for working with Federal departments and agencies—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6F3E4BAEECC455A80BB6812F095B3ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to acquire data that was collected through Federal funding; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A61FDA94D3B4E3AB126D82A08BF6BDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to digitize biological samples that are currently owned or funded by the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD03F8169FE8C441184178DEE409B5365"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the type of initial projects that shall be pursued under the program established under subsection (b)(1)(B);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CD7C6EF115C4D449A88209DD3D25F91"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan for exploring and implementing cost-sharing agreements, including with philanthropy and industry, to assist in cost-sharing for the Web;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF009378C22294BE298A08820C7485EB1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a cybersecurity plan for the Web; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CD593233D8F438189E3E1A387E7BD19"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the Director will leverage partnerships with other Federal departments and agencies, academia, and industry.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDF433A9CC155443A9A2555419B5E1501"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Phase I</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3EF3E5745EA44B31A20E9960CD75758C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>test an initial version of the Web, which shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD265633E19F744ECA057321B53C8FA2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>focus on specific biological data subtypes selected in consultation with the advisory board, representatives from other Federal departments and agencies, and external stakeholders from industry and academia;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53109A73679C4676B3C69A2B7F1D1077"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a single point-of-entry interface for biological data that—</text> 
<clause id="HC48A2D83106A4EE9A757CD773C19F33F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>optimizes user experience and data management;</text></clause> <clause id="H4F28E6BE1B1642258DDA901DCEC1F5EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is built around human-centered design principles;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDB1D81DFEA1E47B9A5C424DE8262049C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is built with the capability to expand to other datasets and biological datatypes beyond the initial version; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9B584B8277474C98979CFA947F40C9D7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is built with tiered security access;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CD2BD5CFB2A482E8AF31AF50D1B32EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include initial frameworks, developed in collaboration with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, for application programming interfaces focusing on hosting an initial list of biological data subtypes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF9EA87FEE1954C91AFC56700415C86CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include appropriate cybersecurity and access safeguards to protect data accessible by the Web, including limiting access to adversarial countries and countries that do not participate in reciprocal data sharing, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H373F33B2F7204CBA96CF3970E4B35FA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as part of developing the initial version of the Web described in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H85DF8725FF924C1CBD8D3DB02CF071CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with Federal departments and agencies to acquire data that was collected through Federal funding;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB6A3E6BCFC3846A4BEC9E9ABEE2564A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop cost-sharing agreements, including with philanthropic and industry members, to fund the Web; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9926B5C6814D401F9614B9CDEEAA20AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>work with biotechnology stakeholders to test and evaluate the initial version and implement any needed changes to ensure usability;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E684B511E684C8689C69BDCD6C49A3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>select initial research projects to fund under the research and development program established under subsection (b)(1)(B); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD95FD045702D4713B398C906A6EC8D90"><enum>(4)</enum><text>submit a report to the committees described in subsection (j) on the implementation of this subsection and plans for carrying out subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5C7704B911244FFB071D80C5539E62D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Phase II</header> 
<paragraph id="H3AE00A45FFEA4AF2B51D13BF389F191B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall expand the Web—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H816925D27153401699559685525A1DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be accessible to United States researchers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB40AF54C6B3453FBA1F7412872BAD57"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to accommodate different types of biological data; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99E13E51ABD34616B83F97CB1224498E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be capable of adapting and expanding based on the emergence of new biological data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4900323C440D483FB4EC1A211DED88E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Features</header><text>The expanded version of the Web described in paragraph (1) shall have the following features:</text> <subparagraph id="H6B92BD761DE54A9E830534441E1610F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A fully realized single point-of-entry interface that—</text> 
<clause id="H9ED13944D0A04964B95200B873D99AE6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is connected to any dataset or database that hosts federally funded data;</text></clause> <clause id="HCC702974BDAB4FAABCBEC85240BBC631"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>hosts biological data not already stored by other Federal databases; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFF6C315D960A458BBF3C3F78B3B093DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>hosts relevant bioinformatic tools for optimized access and analysis.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BC19FA8CF4144F99DF29BE6952D7CDD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A full suite of interoperability frameworks associated with different types of biological data, metadata, and appropriate ontologies.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71D8E8E17F3E4FDDBA418F57EE68EA9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An online interface that optimizes usability, including the ability to rapidly search through metadata across databases.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92EE52B0FC8D4343849916397BC90AC9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Incorporation of human-centered design principles into user interfaces.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9466468F35C94B98AEF3A48BCA2D7214"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A standard quality and format for the hosted biological data that is appropriate for training artificial intelligence models.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E105394D3F84CC892D49CD2D076D2C3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Restrictions on data sharing with countries described in subsection (e)(1)(D).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FE33947271D44A2860E017401E382C4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Appropriate cybersecurity requirements and tiered safeguards related to the sensitivity of data to prevent misuse of data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B53E976336E40A58A7B044EAB29193E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other activities</header><text>In the 3-year period following the 2-year period described in subsection (e), the Secretary shall continue—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5497B1D55D8446A1B7DC7D7122CC7935"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out the activities described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2) of that subsection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB80251D02C9A4D08A68299E0A9AFDE08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out the research and development program established under subsection (b)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H213C136C7E11474E8E256251C2CFBED8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Independent assessment of cybersecurity</header><text>The Director shall seek to enter into a contract with an external entity to conduct a biannual independent assessment of the cybersecurity safeguards and access controls of the Web.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H35A789A184FE47D482ACA82A1C3D2C7B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Advisory board</header> <paragraph id="HB194A6F7DAC94A60B387C6B5FF0D2FEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Secretary selects a National Laboratory under subsection (b)(1)(A), the Secretary shall establish an advisory board to oversee the implementation of the Web and ensure that the Web maximizes the usability of biological datasets across sectors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46A801E8673847F8B75F0DE7C7566DB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Chair of the advisory board shall be the Director.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFB72D068DBF4316BE2DA1112C9ED1D3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The advisory board shall consist of 11 additional members, of whom—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H368C441AA8EE412D80225A2DC7BB09D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>4 shall be representatives of industry;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A61D3DBA5094816B2303D8B1FA54B9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 shall be representatives of academia;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B9CA1000D2F4A81A21A012A26D94B1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>2 shall be representatives of National Laboratories (excluding the National Laboratory selected under subsection (b)(1)(A)); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80D039C28F2F45F788E47F1BF9024171"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">3 shall be representatives of relevant Federal departments and agencies, as determined by the Director, of whom one or more shall be a subject-matter expert on biosecurity research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A841F66B0F340F1B8C84D5E94FB95B4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>FACA exemption</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the advisory board.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2BEEC475F8E740ADBAA876D289755DB5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In developing the Web, the Director shall collaborate with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H303F43A131FD484C8F1153170D84634F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal departments and agencies involved in biosafety and biosecurity capabilities to assist with implementation of proper cybersecurity and biosecurity safeguards;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF14E81D52D84270BCA4159721BB00CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the National Artificial Intelligence Research Resource of the National Science Foundation to ensure integration of well-curated biological data with cutting-edge foundational artificial intelligence tools;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9667BBDFC784DF88B4406D8D6C24DDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards and Technology to ensure that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB1C9D8D34F2A4352BD3EBDC9FC3E57B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the data included in the Web is formatted in a way that is appropriate for training artificial intelligence models; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9138FC7EAA77440981BC1AD25A37745E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>associated application programming interfaces and ontologies are sufficiently adaptable to changes in biological data;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE9E8F76706342FE920FB9B80562FD19"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the National Library of Medicine to ensure compatibility and interoperability between the National Center for Biotechnology information databases and the Web;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC959BE87FAB4261B8F84F89ADAEC4B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a nongovernmental group that is qualified to implement an online interface that maximizes usability by the public and human-centered design; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAB18CFBDA0944EBA404AC926D8E3831"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other Federal departments and agencies determined relevant by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD36AB636CFF4F1BB190CD8AC78C3333"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives a report describing—</text> <paragraph id="H85C56EE485BC4918B6F003FEB49A0BF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>progress made in developing the Web, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2E53371D862F443385CAA7F00D27C97F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the quantity of data stored directly on the Web and accessible through application programming interfaces;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5B48D4AA62548008F9A13F03AA7B7F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collaborations with other Federal departments and agencies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BE49060164D403FB0617FFB578DC184"><enum>(C)</enum><text>user engagement;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB974AA7C922840A4980BB3EC8C6676DE"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8E3243979E4F4181A3D8AD0CD39C9F76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any cybersecurity vulnerabilities identified by an assessment carried out pursuant to subsection (g); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6678EE4880D04406BC3519153AF2E271" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>actions taken to address those vulnerabilities; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA170196AF6104A2E844F36DDC9B0B332"><enum>(3)</enum><text>plans for maintenance, expansion, and development of the Web in the subsequent year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0313CBF564504BC7A3AFFFC70E0FEE3D"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated—</text> <paragraph id="H1BD59839CFB34C46A31CB31539403C14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$30,000,000 for the period of the first 3 years following the date of enactment of this Act to carry out subsection (b)(1)(B);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H464A19CEAC87480AA874FE1768205D89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$310,000,000 for the period of the first 3 years following the date of enactment of this Act to carry out subsection (e); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79E753F0BC914A6A94725383EC401643"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on completion of subsection (e) and the submission of the report described in paragraph (4) of that subsection, $80,000,000 for each of the subsequent 2 years to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H314DBDB6737D475CAB3A46B1A34FA0E9"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede, modify, or waive any applicable requirement relating to privacy, informed consent, human-subjects protections, data use limitations, or protections against unauthorized disclosure, misuse, or reidentification applicable to biological data hosted in or accessible through the Web.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

