<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC25FFA3049594C49831627C8DAB9CD2E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 843 IH: Supporting the designation of October 30 as the “International Day of Political Prisoners”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 843</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of October 30 as the <quote>International Day of Political Prisoners</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas there are an estimated 1,000,000 political prisoners across the world, including cases of journalists, academics, political opposition activists, dissidents, antiwar campaigners, and human rights defenders being detained, arrested, imprisoned, convicted, and otherwise punished for political motives without connection to any credible offense;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas authoritarian and repressive regimes around the world, including the Republic of Belarus, the People’s Republic of China, the Republic of Cuba, the Arab Republic of Egypt, the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Republic of the Union of Burma, the Russian Federation, and the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela, have engaged in systematic imprisonment of independent voices;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024 and 2025, the United States Government, through bilateral and multilateral negotiations, secured the release of several dozen political prisoners from the Republic of Belarus, the Russian Federation, and the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on October 30, 1974, Ukrainian and Russian prisoners of conscience in the Soviet Gulag initiated the tradition of marking the annual Day of Political Prisoners in the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (USSR) to draw public attention to the plight of those imprisoned for their political or religious beliefs and to express solidarity with them; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in subsequent years, the Day of Political Prisoners on October 30 was marked by hunger strikes by prisoners inside the Soviet Gulag and by public demonstrations of solidarity in cities across the USSR: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H207F03058FE4402FB55EB24F5DE1F29C"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H8ADBAFE0073A4944B584726C6D02AE20"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H29930C221E134A35AE6CF8F649906134"><enum>(1)</enum><text>deplores all forms of political repression and imprisonment and conveys its unwavering solidarity with all those imprisoned around the world for peacefully expressing their political or religious beliefs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE42FB930FD8A4C6FBB0B3B294DFA31AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports efforts by the United States Government to condemn political imprisonment, hold accountable those regimes responsible for persecuting and imprisoning dissenters, raise international awareness of political prisoners, and secure their release through bilateral and multilateral negotiations with other states, and urges it to continue such efforts in the future; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H354647DD3EA6445BBB6F70E5511BE3FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the designation of an <quote>International Day of Political Prisoners</quote> in the United States.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

