<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-MDM26606-VYN-GM-L6L"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 663 IS: Honoring the service and sacrifice of the Ohio Air National Guard airmen who were killed in the Boeing KC–135 Stratotanker crash in Iraq during Operation Epic Fury.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 663</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the service and sacrifice of the Ohio Air National Guard airmen who were killed in the Boeing KC–135 Stratotanker crash in Iraq during Operation Epic Fury.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on March 12, 2026, a United States Air Force Boeing KC–135 Stratotanker crashed in western Iraq during a refueling mission conducted as part of Operation Epic Fury;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas all 6 servicemembers who were aboard the aircraft were killed in the crash;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Captain Seth R. Koval, Captain Curtis J. Angst, and Master Sergeant Tyler H. Simmons from the Ohio Air National Guard’s 121st Air Refueling Wing were among those who lost their lives in the incident;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the people of Ohio are devastated by the loss of these brave airmen and mourn alongside their families, friends, and fellow servicemembers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 121st Air Refueling Wing maintains an exceptionally high operational tempo and has long been recognized for its readiness, professionalism, and ability to deploy rapidly in support of United States military operations around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 121st Air Refueling Wing was recently awarded the National Guard Association of the United States Distinguished Flying Unit plaque in recognition of its combat readiness, flying safety, and outstanding operational effectiveness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the airmen of the 121st Air Refueling Wing were selected to be forward deployed in support of operations in the Middle East because their unit consistently demonstrates the highest levels of readiness and reliability;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the KC–135 plays a vital role in United States military operations by conducting mid-air refueling missions that allow fighter aircraft, bombers, and other military platforms to remain in the air longer and conduct missions across vast distances;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas mid-air refueling is one of the most technically demanding and dangerous tasks performed in the United States Air Force, requiring extraordinary skill, discipline, and trust among pilots, boom operators, and their crews;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the boom operator aboard the KC–135 is responsible for carefully guiding the refueling boom to connect with another aircraft in flight and safely transfer thousands of pounds of aviation fuel, often operating with little margin for error;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the brave airmen aboard the KC–135 were performing this critical mission in support of ongoing United States military operations designed to defend United States interests at home and abroad;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these servicemembers gave their lives in defense of the freedoms and liberties of all Americans;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the servicemembers aboard the KC–135 were serving their country honorably and courageously in support of these operations when they made the ultimate sacrifice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these airmen are patriotic American heroes who answered the call to serve and willingly placed themselves in harm’s way to defend the United States and its allies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the entire Nation mourns the loss of these airmen and stands united in prayer for their families, loved ones, and fellow airmen during this time of grief; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the sacrifice of these brave airmen will never be forgotten by the people of Ohio or by a grateful Nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id8fc35389b9094589a3daced253559c6f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the lives, service, and sacrifice of the Ohio Air National Guard airmen from the 121st Air Refueling Wing who were killed in the Boeing KC–135 Stratotanker crash in Iraq during Operation Epic Fury;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0eb609fb3ef94f208e5ac0054649b0b3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses its deepest condolences to the families, friends, and fellow servicemembers mourning their loss;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id907cd4af0287437897a0ed0ba9e17ede"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the critical role of the 121st Air Refueling Wing and all Air Force tanker crews who perform the difficult and dangerous mission of mid-air refueling in defense of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb438b741ea94a19810695c1f1352fe6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>affirms that the people of the United States will always remember these brave airmen and remain grateful for their sacrifice in service to their Nation.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

