<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H492554954EF34DF99D5E566549946C07" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6004 IH: Sgt. Alfredo Freddy Gonzalez Memorial Veterans’ Hospital Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6004</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251110">November 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to construct a hospital under the jurisdiction of the Department of Veterans Affairs in the Rio Grande Valley sector, Texas.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7D61DF596FC04016A50FFB60DF4BC4AF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD1D86CE93919476BBE700C57759C7948" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sgt. Alfredo <quote>Freddy</quote> Gonzalez Memorial Veterans’ Hospital Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HED8DD35E545D490D8179CBC60B1EDA03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to construct Department of Veterans Affairs hospital, Rio Grande Valley Sector, Texas</header> 
<subsection id="HB7B4D9B066F047E299AA6731B3C3B626"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations made in advance for such purpose, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may construct a hospital under the jurisdiction of the Department of Veterans Affairs in the Rio Grande Valley sector, Texas.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H6A57A783673244F39B36C93040950117"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Name of hospital</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The hospital authorized under subsection (a) shall, after the date of the enactment of this Act, be known and designated as the <quote>Sgt. Alfredo <quote>Freddy</quote> Gonzalez Memorial Veterans’ Hospital</quote>. Any reference to such hospital in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be considered to be a reference to the Sgt. Alfredo <quote>Freddy</quote> Gonzalez Memorial Veterans’ Hospital.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

