<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E8B11D301ED4CD3ADA405B2BB2CE472" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1177 IH: Impeaching Peter B. Hegseth, Secretary of Defense of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1177</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Peter B. Hegseth, Secretary of Defense of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEA6131766C2F4762AB88B50FB40DC307"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HD1A5C9087E3C4B00A16B7336A4208107"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Peter B. Hegseth, Secretary of Defense of the United States, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following articles of impeachment be exhibited to the Senate: </text></section><section id="H1F3E08708AE24EB3B21FB548308C0F9E" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Articles of Impeachment Exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the Name of Itself and of the People of the United States of America, against Peter. B Hegseth, Secretary of Defense of the United States, in maintenance and support of its impeachment against him for high crimes and misdemeanors.</text></section><section id="H8CC10F68162D4DD5B6E12426065BA23E" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article 1: Unauthorized war against Iran and reckless endangerment of United States servicemembers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In his conduct of the office of Secretary of Defense of the United States, Peter B. Hegseth, in violation of his constitutional oath faithfully to execute the office of Secretary of Defense and, to the best of his ability, preserve, protect, and defend the Constitution of the United States, and in violation of his constitutional duty to take care that the laws be faithfully executed, has engaged in high crimes and misdemeanors in that—</text><paragraph id="H19ECD3B17E70466FBCC120ADB05C70DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lacking lawful authority, and in direct contravention of Article I of the Constitution, which vests in the Congress the sole power to declare war, and the War Powers Resolution, Peter B. Hegseth has willfully participated in and directed the initiation and escalation of armed hostilities against the Islamic Republic of Iran—which is a brutal regime that terrorizes its own people—without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization by the Congress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62FB7D4359DC47F4997C477BC9B54F49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has failed to seek or obtain meaningful consultation with Congress prior to such actions, thereby usurping legislative authority and undermining the separation of powers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F13B584DBF04C2AB81022E13A6EA1EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has authorized, supported, and advanced military operations lacking defined objectives, lawful authorization, or clear strategic necessity, knowingly exposing members of the Armed Forces of the United States to substantial and foreseeable risk of injury or death;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H683E5D62C7C44E9FB0FBAF840535E446"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has endorsed and facilitated operational plans involving extreme and unnecessary risk to United States personnel and interests, including potential ground operations within Iran, thereby recklessly endangering the lives of American servicemembers deployed in combat operations and stationed throughout the Middle East; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC95A5E540A04D95801F7197EC9D6BCE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has demonstrated a willful disregard for the Constitution, abused the powers of his office, and acted in a manner grossly incompatible with the rule of law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF3F8122203344C8581BC829FE89E333E" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore Peter B. Hegseth, by such conduct, warrants impeachment and trial, and removal from office.</text></section><section id="H6612277FDAA6413CBC87AD5D191293E7" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article II: Violations of the law of armed conflict and targeting of civilians</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In further violation of his constitutional oath and duties, Peter B. Hegseth has engaged in high crimes and misdemeanors in that—</text><paragraph id="H4287F4F85CE346DF9AFDC388D45A6234"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has authorized, condoned, or failed to prevent the use of military force in a manner inconsistent with the law of armed conflict, such as operations resulting in large numbers of civilian casualties and the destruction of civilian infrastructure in Iran, including a girls’ school in Minab;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5856D6218842441BBFF960C677E12EDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has undermined or disregarded established rules of engagement designed to minimize harm to noncombatants, including illegal <quote>double tap</quote> strikes in the southern Caribbean; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64EF7D8E29504F679A7DE83CC0DED819"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has engaged in conduct that raises serious concerns of violations of the Geneva Conventions and other binding legal obligations of the United States, including by stating that the United States shall give <quote>no quarter, no mercy for our enemies,</quote> which is an unlawful command.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9B999F5433A1468588B71FED813A5800" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore Peter B. Hegseth, by such conduct, warrants impeachment and trial, and removal from office.</text></section><section id="H9B6DAE67766D487A92260DBABD29EA39" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article III: Negligence and reckless handling of sensitive military information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In his conduct of the office of Secretary of Defense, Peter B. Hegseth has engaged in high crimes and misdemeanors in that—</text><paragraph id="HD69C8E386B23474E9EAF1E9BBE057807"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has demonstrated gross negligence in the handling of sensitive and classified military information, including through the use of unsecured communications systems like the Signal app to transmit or discuss operational details in flagrant contravention of United States law and military standards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H858668A3E1094D6B9E062294B1CC9832"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">he has compromised operational security and placed United States personnel at risk through this careless and improper conduct.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC1ABA49145904A14BD27A1B25DE381B5" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such conduct constitutes a betrayal of the trust placed in him and a dereliction of his duty to safeguard national security.</text></section><section id="HC5D0343C97124B6C8197CA3DE7022E58" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore Peter B. Hegseth, by such conduct, warrants impeachment and trial, and removal from office.</text></section><section id="H560BDFD63ED44F27AC23DCB81A39A3C9" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article IV: Obstruction of congressional oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Peter B. Hegseth has directed or engaged in efforts to obstruct the constitutional oversight responsibilities of Congress by—</text><paragraph id="H001BDB8D50534FBAA6D5D44A8CFA63E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">failing to provide timely and complete information regarding military operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C0F2004DB95479AB594CFD23E359506"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withholding material facts relating to civilian casualties and operational conduct in Iran, Venezuela, and other military theaters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3CD32070484B2E94259FD1A2F4E9BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interfering with the ability of Congress to exercise its constitutional responsibilities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC8A2C474D8A84D1DABADA0C260667850" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore Peter B. Hegseth, by such conduct, warrants impeachment and trial, and removal from office.</text></section><section id="HC1B8F52F81D942EE8DF489DABD1D92A5" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article V: Abuse of power and politicization of the Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Peter B. Hegseth has abused the powers of his office by—</text><paragraph id="HA59E13E44475454B866340645386EDE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using his position to influence military decisions for improper political purposes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6E59F77D0D842329BBC0DCD2C125D27"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intervening in military disciplinary or personnel matters in a manner inconsistent with established law and practice, including targeting and launching bogus investigations against specific elected officials for the express purpose of political retribution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30C3421F67AB439D9A4845242A53AD3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undermining the principle of a nonpartisan and professional Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H764097D975294B6F943F5869E1B6BEDD" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore Peter B. Hegseth, by such conduct, warrants impeachment and trial, and removal from office.</text></section><section id="H72F07E72BEC6459E9246BC1DE65C5581" section-type="undesignated-section"><enum/><header>Article VI: Conduct bringing disrepute upon the United States and its Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through the cumulative conduct described in these Articles, Peter B. Hegseth has—</text><paragraph id="H2F47E796F45743F583C52B6971BC1D80"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acted in a manner contrary to the public trust as Secretary of Defense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BAEF4011C14444592117D9A8A9D994F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shaken public confidence in the integrity and ability of the Department of Defense, including by undermining United States commitment to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and United States credibility around the world;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EE1BA89905A4EE4854D20E00E6255F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">brought disrepute upon the United States, its Armed Forces, and the Department of Defense by violating its laws and the codes of conduct bestowed upon public servants; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91F699401FF442FE945A1D6C1786FC55"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">degrading the readiness and cohesion of U.S. Armed Forces by—</text><subparagraph id="H6CAAD5B4CF1B4B7D93FC6C6AB7CA635D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">denigrating women, LGBTQ+, and people of color serving the United States, including by forcibly separating transgender people from service; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H933F6E656CD941848B71BBBD9A5476C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>personally intervening in promotions to deny the elevation of qualified Black and women officers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2935AEE3CA544B338E75A388DB745D0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>attacking women’s physical qualifications, restricting their access to reproductive care, and undermining systems to address sexual harassment and assault in the military; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2545AC5F9C034CE681C88DA76DF82464"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promoting standards of appearance that disproportionately penalize Black servicemembers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H6D32F5C824C04FC7BCC4D2C1EAE316AA" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore Peter B. Hegseth, by such conduct, warrants impeachment and trial, and removal from office.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

