<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H37705FEAFDEB457580DAA0A764062B40" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7563 IH: Rare Earth Magnet Market Revitalization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7563</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the importation of certain rare earth magnets from covered nations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2FE51A1F56C64C318CB3F24DC882AFCA" style="OLC"><section id="HE5B84893B594420EBDFFD797605D904D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rare Earth Magnet Market Revitalization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H64FF20A16AB342C68516DF21F08EC614"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H61C0617ECA134BD49D4BDA97447E7B31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H1526FFACC98646BAB84311909C9EF618"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Price and market manipulation by the People’s Republic of China has reduced the incentive for private investment in rare earth magnet processing, refining, and production in the United States and partner countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A353368E33046FDAAEB02A15820B083"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This has created unacceptable vulnerabilities to the supply chains for commercial and military products that rely upon rare earth magnets.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9346B0B955424AAC984665A192E238BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Commerce should be empowered to ensure that United States-based manufacturers acquire rare earth magnets from United States or partner sources to the extent they are available.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2F07714FEE0C4E56BE9976C6BB157FFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on importation of rare earth magnets</header><subsection id="H9CBF208AF0874E5ABE3198066D25215B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Secretary of Commerce, shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that, except as provided in subsection (b), no articles are imported into the customs territory of the United States that—</text><paragraph id="H8EA5CB82F2D547E9BBA3077DBAA88D55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are rare earth components or rare earth magnets originating from one or more covered nations; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C7820056D094D24A5A7113664D9AF33"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate rare earth magnets originating from one or more covered nations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AA2063EF3534C478E98953CEA77B51F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H5D7E5780FBEB49C49F92B664A5BF2BF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nonavailability</header><subparagraph id="H9F8C06B1DD374B7CAE23AE57DAFD420B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall waive the prohibition under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis upon certification by the importer that—</text><clause id="HD48455CC4E77463AA53E5FCB995CC22F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to the importation of rare earth components or rare earth magnets, such articles cannot be practicably sourced from a country that is not a covered nation; or</text></clause><clause id="H2D0F4C56D31842E98CF3A2D4071ED014"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to an article incorporating rare earth magnets, such article cannot be practicably assembled without the incorporation of rare earth magnets originating from one or more covered nations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09E53DB12A174764984A309744570662"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Override</header><text>The Secretary may elect not to waive the prohibition despite a certification under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that alternative practicable sourcing is available for the relevant article or articles.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0102B46E56F48C7A33421C27208CA52"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may waive the prohibition under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis if the Secretary determines that such waiver is in the national interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FBD02754CE84F2EA6490C7E59367D21"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish, on a publicly available website of the Department of Commerce, a list of each importer that has received a waiver under this subsection, along with the amount and type of rare earth magnets imported pursuant to such waiver. The Secretary shall also publish to such website on an annual basis an aggregate report describing the waivers granted during the preceding year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F4302B4DB1443B8BDF1AFA121196EFD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The limitation under this section shall apply with respect to articles imported into the customs territory of the United States after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2433BF03BB54488195359967B12201CA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on exportation of electronic waste containing rare earth magnets</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce is authorized to promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to prohibit the exportation of high-value electronic waste that contains rare earth magnets to the extent that the Secretary determines that such waste could be recycled or repurposed in the United States to extract such rare earth magnets for use in new products.</text></section><section id="H22053533E66A42D0B6777F1ED78463F9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to provide offtake agreements or price guarantees for rare earth magnets</header><subsection id="H2FDD0D7965DC4BBF975F1781BE4B0BDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations and to such regulations as the Secretary of Commerce may promulgate, the Secretary is authorized to provide Federal financial assistance in the form of offtake agreements or price guarantees to any nongovernmental entity the Secretary determines has invested in facilities and equipment for the manufacturing, production, processing, or recycling of rare earth components or rare earth magnets in countries that are not covered nations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6207A6096A69424B88859D7540B6CF92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after making any award of assistance pursuant to the authorization under subsection (a), the Secretary shall publish on a publicly available website of the Department the terms and recipient of the assistance so awarded.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE2573C540264406096496D74ECEF94A2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report describing the manner and extent to which the limitations under this Act have been implemented, the assessment of the Secretary relating to their success at developing a secure supply of rare earth magnets, and any recommendations with respect to expanding such limitations to include all critical minerals.</text></section><section id="HA82BBB4FF61C4E04BB52E84C081AF7E8"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD4769CE5407645AF9CB5AD543F52E729"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered nation</header><text>The term <term>covered nation</term> has the meaning given that term in section 4872 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAF783C4C07E457D97AA8A4630348EE8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rare earth component</header><text>The term <term>rare earth component</term> means samarium, cobalt, neodymium, iron, and boron, to the extent such materials are intended for use in the creation of a rare earth magnet.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67D89E6685ED424FA060ADEB86B3FB7E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rare earth magnet</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rare earth magnet</term> means samarium-cobalt magnets and neodymium-iron-boron magnets.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

