<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2259A5E1C30C4295AA81A07EDA549C08" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5925 IH: HHS Reproductive and Sexual Health Ombuds Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5925</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251104">November 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish within the Department of Health and Human Services an Ombuds for Reproductive and Sexual Health.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDD7C051EE6054D07A08310EAEA87335E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3B68BB730ABF439284201A4EBA249458" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>HHS Reproductive and Sexual Health Ombuds Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0A5FB5F30B974AEA920E5CFE23DF36C5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ombuds for Reproductive and Sexual Health</header> <subsection id="HC806B332DCA24295964E1FD87887F484"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HD8D72E858E6741A69A244F5097D5779F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Position established</header><text>There shall be within the Department of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Department</quote>) an Ombuds for Reproductive and Sexual Health (in this section referred to as the <quote>Ombuds</quote>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB519A0F7861C4ACF82125CE7E35158E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to be appointed as the Ombuds, an individual shall, prior to such appointment, have expertise in sexual and reproductive health and demonstrated commitment to the provision of specified health care services, including abortion and the care of LGBTQ+ individuals, individuals belonging to a racial or ethnic minority, individuals with disabilities, and individuals of low socio-economic status.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H289033245D51471E8F591B0A8C01C5A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting directly to Secretary</header><text>The Ombuds shall report directly to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB454D819B129471DB21638DE54D31136"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Organizational independence</header><text>The Secretary shall take appropriate action to ensure the independence of the Ombuds’s office from other officers or employees of the Department engaged in reproductive and sexual health activities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6A17906E6C7044CF96071E26533A94F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Staffing</header><text>The Secretary shall take appropriate action to ensure that the Ombuds’s office is sufficiently staffed and resourced to carry out its duties effectively and efficiently.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H87658F9CC44740E9BD2BEAF773160ADD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Ombuds shall be as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H5C290071324A43968921303DF378FE33"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To educate the public on specified health care services, including by making evidence-based, medically accurate educational materials available to the public.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA633502907AB4077B947620B5FB0F236"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To analyze data collected by the Department of Health and Human Services about consumer access to specified health care services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H410933A0012D4C1E89AE7539AA9BF3FA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In coordination with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of the Treasury, and State insurance commissioners (or their designees within the applicable agency), to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5C36440B5AED4E4D9B4F0E9F9FBB75B9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">gather information about benefits for specified health care services under health plans and programs specified under subsection (j)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83F49A99F9E343DEB1F9772D66E2C85E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide an analysis of any gaps in such coverage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB58C42036064198A8B2CEF0B098EDCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To disseminate information about how individuals can connect with—</text> <subparagraph id="HB53EBB34F58F475C85EB3B6A15C70676"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health care providers receiving Federal funds under title X of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300">42 U.S.C. 300 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H470992E7C3BB48658F7A9C30F23E47AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>abortion funds; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF9E25D0584645E69A4AFE2E64AC4B22"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other clinics that provide specified health care services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88C12BFBADAF4662B34F9908C0575C6D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To provide the public with evidence-based and medically accurate information related to medication abortions conducted outside formal medical settings.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F32733BEA464C13B2EC0ED3467EBD5C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To collect information regarding, and to address, reproductive and sexual health misinformation being disseminated to the public.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68D0BA2E52934ADDBBABA88360D936A9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To coordinate with the Federal Trade Commission to collect information about, and address consumer protection and data privacy concerns on, the provision of any services relating to reproductive and sexual health.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDF7747E4A604CC2817AA0F7D2CA1E10" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In coordination with entities receiving grants under section 1311(i) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(i)</external-xref>) and other entities assisting individuals eligible to enroll in qualified health plans (as defined in section 1301(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18021">42 U.S.C. 18021(a)</external-xref>)) through an Exchange established pursuant to title I of such Act, to promote awareness of the availability of such plans and the benefits under such plans for specified health care services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H945E37458322420CB93C65DB9C4DC85A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Request for investigations</header><text>The Ombuds may request the Inspector General of the Department to conduct inspections, investigations, and audits related to any of the functions under subsection (d).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB92DE486F07442E49C868570558BE044"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Protection of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Ombuds shall comply with all applicable Federal privacy laws (and the regulations issued thereunder) in the collection, analysis, or release of any information or data, including in any reports issued under subsection (i).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29B6E29AA8684DFFBDAA68CEC1C96433"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Coordination with department components</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after a request from the Ombuds to the Secretary for records of the Department necessary to execute the functions of the Ombuds under subsection (d), the Secretary shall establish procedures to provide the Ombuds access to all such records.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0A5E7CBA79F148C390C239089A91677F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Public outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall take all appropriate actions to advise and engage with the public regarding the existence, authorities, and duties of the Ombuds and the Ombuds’s office.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC05E2E9514674C179D59AFFB458EA560"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual reporting</header><text>Not later than June 30, 2026, and each June 30 thereafter, the Ombuds shall submit to the Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="HA75CACCBF8DD48968A3FCA2B7943B9AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluates the efforts of the Ombuds (or the Secretary, as applicable) with respect to each of the functions specified in subsection (d); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97B4B51D1A28436D95D027DBE686C2E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains such other information as the Secretary determines is appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H52448333407D4AEA9D0E024137AF2A0A"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F58DA4F770C4153BDF17C3B68648817" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>health plans and programs</term> refers to any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H08262395D79D41C4BB8DAA26A76201E2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Each Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7b">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b</external-xref>) but including the program established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF54B802809284534B3EB5A9EAD090FCA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Health insurance coverage offered in the large group market (as such terms are defined in section 2791 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA21FC9377ADB4E71BF9F352F0BD3990C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Health insurance coverage offered in the small group market (as so defined).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE052160278D6406293197B61EE4F7540" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Health insurance coverage offered in the individual market (as so defined).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE944CA0B99EB49FD94AF271142D0D1BB" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Self-insured group health plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78375415BBEF4890AC514CE69E25FCB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reproductive and sexual health misinformation</term> includes any information relating to reproductive and sexual health that is not evidence-based or medically accurate, including inaccuracy in the provision of any related services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H169F378B4C9E4226B7C3CB19813E87F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specified health care services</term> means evidence-based, medically accurate medical, surgical, counseling, or referral services relating to reproductive and sexual health, including services relating to pregnancy and the termination of a pregnancy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4D9D1FB0C8BC4FB4976B802B7F1151E2" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the Ombuds to collect, or as requiring other Federal, State, local, or private entities to provide to the Ombuds, individually identifiable information about individual patients, including protected health information (as defined in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)) or individually identifiable health information (as defined in such section (or successor regulations)).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

