<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H91333F44708644AE89D6348CB0F35DD3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7799 IH: Stop Proxy Organizations Nurturing Subversive Operations and Riots Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7799</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide that 501(c)(3) organizations are liable for the use of funding provided as a fiscal sponsor.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H413F1A0A22264CC4A0777137EC8E6BAC" style="OLC"><section id="HE069B21E8ACE4EFAAD9413A5EF7086B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Proxy Organizations Nurturing Subversive Operations and Riots Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPONSOR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1DDC611BA4E14982916DE03DF73BAE97"><enum>2.</enum><header>Liability of tax-exempt fiscal sponsors for sponsored activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">Section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA060E3F167E84707A0DD62F547BFDBD0"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24832E598E7742A985BAFA94A60DE6D7"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Liability of fiscal sponsors for sponsored activities</header><paragraph id="H1590E52CE99046549A3E89A1C858A785"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If—</text><subparagraph id="HA4224FC8D0824C088612ED739157B8EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an organization described in subsection (c)(3) expends funds for a fiscal sponsorship, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE14564DA235A4C3993CE3207D3578514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a deduction under section 170 is allowed to any donor, or such organization represents to any donor that the donor is entitled to a deduction under section 170, with respect to a contribution to the organization for purposes of such fiscal sponsorship,</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">then the organization shall bear any criminal liability related to or arising from such fiscal sponsorship, and any civil liability concerning a covered activity related to or arising from such fiscal sponsorship.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H518221799E1C42858AAE2BAA54580796"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered activity</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>covered activity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA46F6FA4E5BD46AAA764406D7E649FDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>aiding and abetting an act of international terrorism committed, planned, or authorized by an organization that had been designated as a foreign terrorist organization under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>), as of the date on which such act of international terrorism was committed, planned, or authorized, by knowingly providing substantial assistance, or conspiring with the person who committed such an act of international terrorism,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AB7CB72484C467795294A6626F6AFFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by force or a specified and credible threat of force, or by physical obstruction, intentionally injuring, intimidating or interfering with or attempting to injure, intimidate or interfere with any person lawfully exercising or seeking to exercise a constitutional right, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF439C3B93B1444EEAA01CF56CA69D86B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by using force or a specified credible threat of force or by physically blocking the movement of any article or commodity in commerce to intentionally prevent the lawful movement of interstate and intrastate commerce.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term <term>intimidate</term> means to place an individual in reasonable apprehension of bodily harm to such individual or to another.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71E9DEDF70B84A008779827553101E12"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fiscal sponsorship</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>fiscal sponsorship means</term> a relationship in which an organization described in subsection (c)(3)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5942D0EB77DD4CB2B8EAF77F767E21DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agrees to receive and administer funds on behalf of a project or organization that is not exempt from tax under subsection (a), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D5BFD263DA84B4C8B30BF3F256E0628"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retains discretion and control over such funds to ensure they are used for the purposes for which such organization was organized and operated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A6392184E94E6190716F4790CA0CE3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Presumption of responsibility</header><text>An organization to which paragraph (1) applies is presumed to be responsible for ensuring that the manner in which its funds are used under any fiscal sponsorship complies with applicable laws, regulations, and tax obligations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC4B1C2C09FA4BE8BFC3B3E7DFDE48D2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Defenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The liability established by this subsection does not bar the organization described in subsection (c)(3) from defenses based on exercise of due diligence and reasonable oversight.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

