<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H68F50A8CAB1C49E5A096E10136A5971A" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4313 : Hospital Inpatient Services Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 4313</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to extend acute hospital care at home waiver flexibilities, and to require an additional study and report on such flexibilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H28DAD94F88A54751A910E20CEBE5DAAD" style="OLC"><section id="HF338B1738AEC42F186C111279B5049A6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hospital Inpatient Services Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEE6B956D3B0E45B7B7164034E08779A7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extending acute hospital care at home waiver flexibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1866G(a)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc-7">42 U.S.C. 1395cc–7(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>January 30, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2030</quote>.</text></section><section id="HA92302DFBCBB4A7A85CDBC829FA937EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requiring additional study and report on acute hospital care at home waiver flexibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1866G of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc-7">42 U.S.C. 1395cc–7</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H8FF556BAFEA2475FBE9C262D983C4F4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(E)—</text><subparagraph id="H9D8D056025334ACA96882D7C16448D03" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii), by striking <quote>the study described in subsection (b)</quote> and inserting <quote>the studies described in subsections (b) and (c)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39728BA2CD3744A38DE8C4617D89A6B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new flush sentence:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3F850F8F438341C0BE4769D71093A897" display-inline="no-display-inline"><quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subparagraph">The Secretary may require that such data and information be submitted through a hospital’s cost report, through such survey instruments as the Secretary may develop, through medical record information, or through such other means as the Secretary determines appropriate.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8398ADDF89FE4422987888C42B64561B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H809C6C1846F2481994F69EA033100C0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Study</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Initial study</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A7E3ADCAB4449038D4E556DD3F76079"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting <quote>or subsection (c)</quote> before the period at the end; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8889BD54039436B865E2EDD618DFFAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H579A23FFB6604BC8981F4D4C895E02FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HBA2ED2B9A8144E0195769BFD3A45CB12" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection id="H3EEBCDEFE7D44C8EB31146CF01CBCB0B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Subsequent study and report</header><paragraph id="HDF9D7E5D3FA54D6A81171BCF7BE52F02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2028, the Secretary shall conduct a study to—</text><subparagraph id="HC2EF66619E3F4862BF365CD80810C8B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze, to the extent practicable, the criteria established by hospitals under the Acute Hospital Care at Home initiative to determine which individuals may be furnished services under such initiative; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F1635041D044E069BCA093BD8EC09BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyze and compare (both within and between hospitals participating in the initiative, and relative to comparable hospitals that do not participate in the initiative, for relevant parameters such as diagnosis-related groups)—</text><clause id="H75A46CD2144446509C3D5C53AF79117E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>quality of care furnished to individuals with similar conditions and characteristics in the inpatient setting and through the Acute Hospital Care at Home initiative, including health outcomes, hospital readmission rates (including readmissions both within and beyond 30 days post-discharge), hospital mortality rates, length of stay, infection rates, composition of care team (including the types of labor used, such as contracted labor), the ratio of nursing staff, transfers from the hospital to the home, transfers from the home to the hospital (including the timing, frequency, and causes of such transfers), transfers and discharges to post-acute care settings (including the timing, frequency, and causes of such transfers and discharges), and patient and caregiver experience of care;</text></clause><clause id="HED77A3931C13445198E840D32B1B2FC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>clinical conditions treated and diagnosis-related groups of discharges from inpatient settings relative to discharges from the Acute Hospital Care at Home initiative;</text></clause><clause id="HEE316B283BBA489FAE847D179F243D3B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>costs incurred by the hospital for furnishing care in inpatient settings relative to costs incurred by the hospital for furnishing care through the Acute Hospital Care at Home initiative, including costs relating to staffing, equipment, food, prescriptions, and other services, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="HF110FA6EA0FB40F8B099861BA4338B47"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the quantity, mix, and intensity of services (such as in-person visits and virtual contacts with patients and the intensity of such services) furnished in inpatient settings relative to the Acute Hospital Care at Home initiative, and, to the extent practicable, the nature and extent of family or caregiver involvement; </text></clause><clause id="H22797D5DB8C34A8099244E36F7A58F94"><enum>(v)</enum><text>socioeconomic information on individuals treated in comparable inpatient settings relative to the initiative, including racial and ethnic data, income, housing, geographic proximity to the brick-and-mortar facility and whether such individuals are dually eligible for benefits under this title and title XIX; and</text></clause><clause id="HE0EDD25F70604DBC927918139ABFF582"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the quality of care, outcomes, costs, quantity and intensity of services, and other relevant metrics between individuals who entered into the Acute Hospital Care at Home initiative directly from an emergency department compared with individuals who entered into the Acute Hospital Care at Home initiative directly from an existing inpatient stay in a hospital.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17A1AD1CEBED4592B103B0E1EA68ABCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection bias</header><text>In conducting the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, analyze and compare individuals who participate and do not participate in the initiative controlling for selection bias or other factors that may impact the reliability of data. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA15E7DCA49BB486982AA53E01235CFF7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2028, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H440547C9B0994956B52B88876317C89F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account for fiscal year 2026, out of any amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $2,500,000, to remain available until expended, for purposes of carrying out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H4AD845A9DBDD42DA956A6178ACD075FE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Medicare Improvement Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1898(b)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395iii">42 U.S.C. 1395iii(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$1,403,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$1,400,500,000</quote>.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20251201" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 1, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

