<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H405277B9AECC4737AD6443EFB573C5AE" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1239 IH: Condemning antisemitic hate-filled rhetoric and content disseminated by prominent online personalities, and urging social media platforms and public leaders to denounce and address such conduct.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1239</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning antisemitic hate-filled rhetoric and content disseminated by prominent online personalities, and urging social media platforms and public leaders to denounce and address such conduct.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the rise of digital media platforms has enabled individuals with large audiences to disseminate disinformation, commentary, and political viewpoints to millions of viewers worldwide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas such influence carries a heightened responsibility to avoid rhetoric that promotes hatred, violence, or discrimination against any group, including Jewish individuals and communities;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas antisemitism has surged in the United States and globally in recent years, fueled in part by online disinformation, conspiracy theories, and extremist rhetoric;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas antisemitic incidents have significantly increased, including a 344 percent increase over the past 5 years, and a 893 percent increase over the past 10 years, and online platforms have been identified as a major vector for the spread of such hatred;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Hasan Piker, a prominent online streamer, has often used antisemitic rhetoric, including expressing support for Hamas, a designated foreign terrorist organization;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in August 2019, during a stream on Twitch, Hasan Piker stated that <quote>America deserved 9/11</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Hasan Piker referred to Orthodox Jews as <quote>inbred</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Hasan Piker downplayed sexual violence committed by Hamas, a designated foreign terrorist organization, against innocent civilians on October 7, 2023, stating, <quote>It doesn’t matter if f-ing rapes happened on October 7th […] that doesn’t change the dynamic for me at all</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Hasan Piker has expressed support for Hamas on multiple occasions, including on April 14, 2026, stating, <quote>Hamas over Israel every single time</quote> and doubling down on claims in multiple media appearances that Hamas is <quote>a thousand times better than Israel</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Candace Owens has employed rhetoric that has included conspiracy theories accusing Israel of controlling the United States Government, promoting false claims that Jews are taught by ancient religious texts to hate non-Jews, and casting doubt on the truth of the stories of Holocaust survivors;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on February 1, 2026, Candace Owens posted on X an antisemitic claim that the United States is controlled by <quote>satanic pedophiles who work for Israel</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, during a podcast appearance on December 8, 2025, Owens repeated false claims that Jews are killing Christian children as part of religious rituals and that Jewish texts and traditions promote the sexual assault of children, which is an antisemitic trope constituting a blood libel;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in July 2024, Candace Owens called the horrific medical experiments committed by Josef Mengele on Jews during the Holocaust <quote>bizarre propaganda</quote>, continuing that <quote>some of the stories, by the way, sound completely absurd</quote>, downplaying and rejecting the veracity of these crimes;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on February 21, 2025, Candace Owens hosted E. Michael Jones, who claimed on her platform that Hollywood <quote>created the Holocaust narrative</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the amplification of antisemitic narratives online can contribute to real-world harm, including harassment, intimidation, and violence against Jewish individuals, institutions, and communities; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas public officials, leaders, and technology companies have a responsibility to confront and condemn antisemitism in all its forms, including when it appears in online discourse and influencer-driven media: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H40C438A994B94D81AB43E49C823CF425"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H46A09DA71D754B519531ABB69A27B17F"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That it is the sense of the House of Representatives that—</text> <paragraph id="HFE736E2EE0B146459A71E7C8F2D77AC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>antisemitic rhetoric and conspiracy theories disseminated by influential online personalities, including Hasan Piker and Candace Owens, are dangerous and contribute to a climate of hatred and intolerance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85CFFE987C7B493AAA544DD1F8F590D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>individuals with online platforms have a responsibility to refrain from promoting or amplifying antisemitic narratives and disinformation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H900D2741A3DE49A4861F243E39BFE79C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>social media and streaming platforms should take appropriate steps to enforce their policies against hate speech and prevent the spread of antisemitic content;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A3197686E304A0D9146546B4B1C0F4D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>public officials and community leaders should unequivocally condemn antisemitism, including when it is propagated by high-profile media figures and influencers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2518AB74E8E64F6187992B3349DB5096"><enum>(5)</enum><text>efforts to downplay or excuse antisemitic rhetoric under the guise of political commentary should be rejected; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H143C9B6254F0427B8487681EBD595BCC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United States reaffirms its commitment to combating antisemitism, and ensuring the safety and dignity of Jewish individuals and communities both online and offline.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

