<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT25A19-T9G-S5-PVP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3183 IS: Healthy Lungs for Heroes Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3183</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to improve safety standards for wildland firefighters, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Lungs for Heroes Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id882a9987c08d470584a84e88a564aa78"><enum>2.</enum><header>Safety standards for wildland firefighters</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19c1d49e0ccf44a387e920a3ed30c4af"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id165e0dae84a748a6bcadb84917fd38e9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered permissible exposure limits</header><text>The term <quote>covered permissible exposure limits</quote> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d212b989e024dd995825abbd5ea6d5e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the permissible smoke exposure limit established by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb723d492bcc744588f25b09edee57731" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the permissible occupational smoke exposure limit established by the Occupational Health and Safety Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide47b7e62a5d04816838a1ed110040634"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ece5d52c69f4567a72cca3d0f14fc26"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id60d5ce9890fd4506ae25c103d4ef58cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary, with respect to wildland firefighters under the direction of the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb6a50e611d4d4f88a8ffded5a040b9be"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to wildland firefighters under the direction of the Secretary of the Interior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b458d731eb14a8ca9ac5b629b54be60"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wildland firefighter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>wildland firefighter</term> means any person who participates in wildland firefighting activities under the direction of the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior, including under a contract with the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18c0b67da47c4ef8811ca1d75cb713e0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Safety standards</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e7a0c3a6bb340b8a42b7b841db405be"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida4cb6d438e104e9198f65b4df5c165b3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the National Wildfire Coordinating Group, the Secretary of the Interior, and other appropriate Federal agencies, shall develop a strategy to make commercially available appropriate respiratory personal protective equipment for wildland firefighters and supporting staff in settings in which smoke exposure surpasses covered permissible exposure limits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0202849dab794f86b653f3c9ba6cadb1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary, in consultation with the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, shall determine appropriate respiratory personal protective equipment for wildland firefighters and supporting staff in settings in which smoke exposure surpasses covered permissible exposure limits; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5529c3ad4f7c484b8257b4e66743139b"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary concerned shall require each wildland firefighter and supporting staff to use the respiratory personal protective equipment determined under subparagraph (B) in settings in which smoke exposure surpasses covered permissible exposure limits.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide537994390a34a82a93b1985a3631c9d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f88bd84e3174db3af793611f22ebaf2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in consultation with the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1aa15a51b58d4cf7998f1e23f1165f19"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">periodically review standards relating to personal protective equipment and other safety standards for wildland firefighters and supporting staff, including the respiratory personal protective equipment determined under paragraph (1)(B); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id971e7d6f99b04ddf85ec0a3403abd39b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop an appropriate permissible exposure limit or occupational exposure limit for wildfire smoke for wildland firefighters and supporting staff participating in settings described in paragraph (1)(A) if the Secretary determines that the covered permissible exposure limits are not tailored to those settings; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id763a7e5e153840ccbed60dbbd142a2ed"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate into the standards described in subparagraph (A)(i), by reference, the most recent edition of standard NFPA 1984, entitled <quote>Standard on Respirators for Wildland Fire-Fighting and Wildland Urban Interface Operations</quote> (and any subsequent editions), as necessary, for the safety and personal protection of wildland firefighters and supporting staff, subject to the limit described in subsection (a)(1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbb61a07410242de8dda713b5f9f3587"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for each fiscal year.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

