<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F645D6671DE4127911CC4B15C37183E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7538 IH: Migrant Child Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7538</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to establish strong requirements to ensure safe placements for unaccompanied alien children.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB4D46EBFFA4C4B138E62849EBDDAEDC1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3A217875DBB54C489DB98ECDA152CB8C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Migrant Child Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6F66604B339B4BB4A2D434DE4AD80BE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring the safety of unaccompanied alien children</header> <subsection id="H30C42F141D4C40969C5BB615D1E1F4C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 235(c)(3) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB56945E4A5A440BE9F2D3C932CED5827" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H8E1B7748BFF54729B483D8C14A4565A9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Information about individuals with whom children are placed</header> 
<clause id="H499428D38B8741209270DA9C8E7733FB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Information to be collected by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and provided to the Secretary of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before placing the child with a sponsor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide to the Secretary of Homeland Security, regarding the sponsor with whom the child will be placed, all information related to the individual that the Secretary of Health and Human Services possesses, including the following information:</text> <subclause id="H38A0AF07DFEA4EA48F86D3615AB6D39D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The name of the individual.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4C58015E505A43DB92F7021E15BC092B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The maiden name of the individual, if applicable.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF480300A653B4AE883BAB636A86CFA00"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Any former name or alias of the individual, if applicable.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H264F53E623514E838C1341DF61C8273D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The social security number of the individual.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFE2724AB4B454C3BA3306205BE5B8680"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The date of birth of the individual.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6064517B15744FB9B2675520B6E2ED22"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The birthplace of the individual.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC3803F34F46344DDA12E2425CC16B843"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The location of the individual’s residence where the child will be placed, including proof of address.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8AD01DD4FA394F9BA89C822B7D997E28"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>The results of background checks of the individual and each additional adult household member of the residence where the child will be placed.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFB0EA36EB4654B40A7F92DB52E406037"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>The immigration status of the individual.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H9A9BEF56AA724609986E8C514230A30A"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Contact information for the individual, including a phone number.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HADCF2D9D8D214F64981BAEC1AADD7106"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>Whether the individual is a relative or legal guardian of the child, and if so—</text> 
<item id="H3A6B58CBC683467D8B09E9DF10E408D0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>documents to prove that the individual is a relative or legal guardian of the child; or</text></item> <item id="HCEC6022F7AC94F339AB79A57C9B62030"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the results of a DNA test administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services proving that the individual is a relative of the child.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCECAC03FD1CA49BFBD8343ED3835B6EE"><enum>(XII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other information the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines appropriate.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HCF207F59156F4EDEB7C673090309C476"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional pre-placement safeguards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before placing the child with an individual, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H35A8A682B9634A4284CA723074668071"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conduct at least one in-person home visit at the location where the child will reside to confirm the safety, suitability, and stability of the placement environment;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H68F9E9406FED4A168DE29B40CCF17FEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>require the sponsor, if the sponsor is not a citizen of the United States, to consent to placement on an appropriate electronic monitoring system, which may include global-positioning-system monitoring, for the duration of the child’s immigration proceedings or until otherwise determined by the Secretary; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H578E8818571B4A5295BADF0EF6381E26"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the individual to execute a bond, in an amount determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security, but not less than $5,000, conditioned upon ensuring the child’s appearance at all required immigration proceedings and compliance with any related reporting requirements.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6F52A5EDA7CF42DABF0803A23999A7B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Activities of the secretary of homeland security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving the information described in clause (i), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, without unnecessary delay, determine the immigration status of the individual with whom a child is to be placed and notify the Secretary of Health and Human Services. If the individual is determined to be unlawfully present in the United States and not currently in removal proceedings under the immigration laws, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider the initiation of such proceedings consistent with applicable law and the Secretary’s enforcement discretion.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4C7067ED501143349A2A9E1FE798DD32"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>No waiver</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services may not waive the requirements under clause (i).</text></clause> <clause id="HCDD6956E336F4611ABA831C96BF4A0A9"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Reports to NCMEC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall report as missing to the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children the name (and any other information in the possession of the Secretary) of any unaccompanied alien child, with respect to whom, not later than 120 days after placing the child with the sponsor—</text> 
<subclause id="HB2D75DE326F9439E9A7CB02F1A886778"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary could not contact the sponsor for the purpose of a follow-up or well-being check; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H47FE13B574B749558495FBE8D2AE1267"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the sponsor did not contact the Secretary for the purpose of a follow-up or well-being check.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H6C21631573C343169E21B99086229F43" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Information provided to State or local health or welfare agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after placing a child in a residence, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide to the appropriate State or local health or welfare agency the information provided to the Secretary of Homeland Security under clause (i) and any other information in the possession of the Secretary related to the child.</text></clause> <clause id="HB47EA2C905EE4F009F70200033BB0545"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Parental contact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall attempt to contact the parents of each unaccompanied alien child, using any information in the possession of the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD4EF2852088A4F298A551A14FFF76694"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any unaccompanied alien child (as such term is defined in section 462(g) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)</external-xref>)) apprehended on or after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

