<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5338B7A69D184D3AA124AA03AA65BE37" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9178 IH: Less Tax Paperwork for Digital Asset Owners Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9178</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000067">Mr. Yakym</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce certain tax compliance burdens with respect to digital asset ownership, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF1D91968F87E4D8481668CBC6A316F0D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2EE0AC7F9E8943D1B418A6268F362762" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; etc</header> 
<subsection id="H98DBB04225624373A9D331181672271D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Less Tax Paperwork for Digital Asset Owners Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H37367D303F6F4FCE9724B0B50CAACB14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H77033C3DD0504F008644D84DBF4FFD10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="H2EE0AC7F9E8943D1B418A6268F362762" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; etc.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="HE96A3D3CABCB45ED999EE2F4BD65B193" level="section">Sec. 2. Treatment of de minimis digital asset network fees.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H2FCDE4F907D14C50B286F80FA3FD9EBD" level="section">Sec. 3. Simplified accounting for gain and loss on widely traded digital assets.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H47731E5E2582434CA04B8C75294BDF03" level="section">Sec. 4. Treatment of U.S. dollar stablecoin transactions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H18A4969250CE4E2C90358714DC70FC3A" level="section">Sec. 5. Broker requirements.</toc-entry> <toc-entry idref="H69F30C2EB31444E889EFDF09E1809499" level="section">Sec. 6. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> <section id="HE96A3D3CABCB45ED999EE2F4BD65B193" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of de minimis digital asset network fees</header> <subsection id="H6C7CFCC92D2349EB86928FE7C281254D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part III of subchapter O of chapter 1 of subtitle A is amended by inserting after section 1043 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9DB4725B8C184519818049AD0CF2B9D3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H7AC7042B3E34443287408E397BFEF769"><enum>1044.</enum><header>De minimis network fee exception</header> 
<subsection id="HDC7380BE66BE4CA782D9DEC9180A5801"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No gain or loss shall be recognized on the disposition of a digital asset in payment of a de minimis network fee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE1247EFA379B4C32A12673573C05152B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>De minimis network fee</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H435436089B0F4DF6B0AEFE6B230970D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>de minimis network fee</quote> means an amount paid or incurred in a digital asset transaction to validate another digital asset transaction if the aggregate amount so paid or incurred with respect to the validation of such other digital asset transaction does not exceed $10.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1369AD5C8A874AF8B2F9F6DCF9B07F65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Network fee</header><text>The term <quote>network fee</quote> means any amount which would be a de minimis network fee if paragraph (1) were applied without regard to the dollar limitation specified therein.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD47C49858C98491F8402BD3CA739D15A">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Disposition of digital asset used To pay network fee</header>
 <text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H5280594BF4D44DA28E2085DAC84D5349"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>a disposition of a digital asset shall not fail to be treated as a payment merely because such asset is not received by another person, and</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H455D649D81A74EEC8577666E0CEC607D">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>any payment of a network fee using a digital asset shall be treated as a disposition of such asset in exchange for consideration equal to the fair market value of such digital asset.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE93DC4C0314F49AC94098B15192FD4A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of unrecognized gain</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of any network fee which would otherwise be taken into account in determining the amount of gain or loss on the disposition of any asset, in determining the amount of any deduction, or in determining the basis of any asset acquired, shall be reduced by the amount of any gain not recognized by reason of subsection (a) with respect to the disposition of the digital asset used to pay such network fee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE088647E2E6F4EA79371FDAC4B47A841"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exclusions</header> <paragraph id="HD3C79D0D4B024BE6B4D5491E073102CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Trade or business</header> <subparagraph id="H2CD778B474A14BB1AE5FE036E2A9C8B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to the disposition of a digital asset by—</text> 
<clause id="H5E059523DD80406C843E6E12EBED15D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a trader, broker, or dealer in digital assets,</text></clause> <clause id="H7C985AD8E5DC47C693B58760C8A73A1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a person in the trade or business of batching or facilitating the validation of digital asset transactions on behalf of others,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HACA95A5F802848D281D468A92A1C8CD9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent provided by the Secretary, any person in a trade or business which is substantially similar to a trade or business described in clause (i) or (ii), or</text></clause> <clause id="H00A9D613FA8B48CF87D453DAAAF36D25"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any person that engaged in more than 5,000 digital asset transactions during the preceding taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA00216B488EA40D9BFD5B36595C190AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administrative convenience exception</header> 
<clause id="H84A00BF8586449DAA83EB284495740F1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any taxpayer that demonstrates to the Secretary that such taxpayer is of a type with respect to which not applying subparagraph (A) will not result in a substantial Federal revenue loss.</text></clause> <clause id="H345B3B49423E499EB00DED77EB68C445"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall issue guidance that—</text> 
<subclause id="H6BB0F6E72E674E569ADDBFF0A23C73CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identifies different types of taxpayers with respect to which not applying subparagraph (A) will not result in substantial Federal revenue loss, and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8F160B12C0BE43FCABEBDCF238C9648F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>specifies with respect to each such type of taxpayer the information that such taxpayer must provide to make the demonstration described in clause (i).</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HBE7E0D8BC0B0476FA86787CDF87F9D64"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Certain factors required to be taken into account</header><text>The guidance issued by the Secretary under clause (ii) shall—</text> <subclause id="H1B82948CBE9642CA96093E095E7DF7BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for purposes of determining the classification of types of taxpayers, and whether any Federal revenue loss from not applying subparagraph (A) with respect to any such type of taxpayer would be substantial, take into account the method or methods used by such type of taxpayer for selecting the digital assets used to pay network fees and the average holding period of such digital assets by such type of taxpayer, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H659DFADF4EC2417DB59A76BD00847CAB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine Federal revenue loss by reducing such loss by a reasonable approximation of the additional administrative costs of the Department of the Treasury, and the additional compliance costs of such type of taxpayer (and any person who would be required to make additional information return reporting with respect to such type of taxpayer), which would be imposed if subparagraph (A) did not apply to such type of taxpayer.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C1D5CBB64494FC6BFE5A8D6089528A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain accounting methods</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to any digital asset—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H44A182E02E8243788F8E671492593650"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to which section 475, 1051(a), or 1256(a), or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BEC505C877D4F73846F2D547C0B6C90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, to which a mark-to-market method applies under any other provision of this subtitle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE38152ED9F5B4ADE837396DBF61C9980"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or guidance to prevent the abuse of this section through—</text> <paragraph id="H8200E6A99F2E41B0805ABD92679475F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>transaction structuring for the purpose of qualifying for the exclusion provided in subsection (a), and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED0737AB83EA4624B2D42281E847458A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the receipt of any value other than the validation of a digital asset transaction in exchange for a network fee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1758A4EDE6904F74ADF6DC370EDDFDDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part III of subchapter O of chapter 1 of subtitle A is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1043 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD2168FBAAD554793A3D28B78744F8182" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H9DB4725B8C184519818049AD0CF2B9D3" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H7AC7042B3E34443287408E397BFEF769" level="section">Sec. 1044. De minimis network fee exception.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCC48DEA865A8434EBD0BF2C30D4AEE81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to the disposition of assets after December 31, 2027.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H2FCDE4F907D14C50B286F80FA3FD9EBD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Simplified accounting for gain and loss on widely traded digital assets</header> <subsection id="H333366BF0B1B433FBE2B492FF717B2DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part IV of subchapter O of chapter 1 of subtitle A is amended by inserting before section 1052 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCEAC56D58D70438891E46FCF3EC9F02C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HB312ED008B094EDC966EDFEDF5975051"><enum>1051.</enum><header>Election to apply simplified accounting for gain and loss on widely traded digital assets</header> 
<subsection id="H01062F1364584D7D896F4A8F16E12B5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any designated type of digital asset with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year—</text> <paragraph id="H3B1C1F8D4F9640E4BD7234E66032CE87" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such taxpayer shall recognize gain on such designated type of digital asset for such taxable year equal to the excess (if any) of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H09117969187F48F680F14964A15C8D3A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sum of—</text> <clause id="HD53C4C5AD5E44F6EB0391A7A7DFABAB8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate amount realized by the taxpayer on sales or exchanges (including nonrecognition transactions) of widely traded digital assets of such designated type during such taxable year,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0E924EAFADD5401CACFFADE68B7ED9EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of dispositions (including nonrecognition transactions), other than sales or exchange described in clause (i), of widely traded digital assets of such designated type, the fair market value of such widely traded digital assets (determined as of the time of such dispositions), and</text></clause> <clause id="HABAB6DA5FC674F97BE70B895B360C3F7" commented="no"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the fair market value of widely traded digital assets of such designated type held by such taxpayer as of the close of the taxable year, over</text>
                                    </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54CD0246810F4556B93379BFD4555857" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sum of—</text> <clause id="H0AE5AA4347B94A72A0DAC8806C937A6E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the fair market value of consideration provided by the taxpayer for the acquisition of widely traded digital assets of such designated type during the taxable year,</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE047542E875440A0823EE6C5D812EC33"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of any disposition described in subparagraph (A)(ii), any amounts which would have reduced the amount realized by the taxpayer on such disposition if such disposition had been a sale or exchange,</text></clause> <clause id="H25A0CCFADB464610BBFA4AC0E1652C43" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of the acquisition of widely traded digital assets of such designated type during the taxable year the basis of which in the hands of the taxpayer are determined by reference to the basis of such assets in the hands of the transferor, the basis of such assets in the hands of the taxpayer immediately after such acquisition, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA7D212CD97404275A3450B0B6F91DCA9" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the fair market value of widely traded digital assets of such designated type held by such taxpayer as of the close of the preceding taxable year,</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9614C5C4942B439DB9D29C44AD3FB375"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such taxpayer shall recognize loss on such designated type of digital asset for such taxable year equal to the excess (if any) of—</text>
                                <subparagraph id="HEFAEC23CF6A045E6A44F4AFCB81D4EFF">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the amount described in paragraph (1)(B), over</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H832254DC220F4FA4A03CDD46596A5234"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount described in paragraph (1)(A), and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C54DC2A3B71462A8276775D695BD505"><enum>(3)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (1) and (2), such taxpayer shall not recognize any gain or loss on the disposition of widely traded digital assets of such designated type.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5ECA03F205B740DAB84393164269D468"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designated type of digital asset</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0018F3DED8EE4C049635FB684F5AC56D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>designated type of digital asset</quote> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, any type of widely traded digital asset with respect to which such taxpayer elects the application of this section for such taxable year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4049C739E9034FBA93EC345719355677"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Type of widely traded digital asset</header><text>Widely traded digital assets shall be treated as being of the same type if, and only if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD4FFDB007FC546BA8B8403C151B6DC49"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such assets are fungible, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1E50963CAEBC48ACA6C35AEC67E671CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such assets are determined under rules provided by the Secretary to have values that are directly linked or highly correlated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B956E7962974851A27A9BFB7D52F089">
                            <enum>(c)</enum>
                            <header>Gain or loss treated as short-Term</header>
 <text>Any gain or loss determined under subsection (a) shall be treated as short-term capital gain or short-term capital loss, respectively.</text>
                        </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5D3535DFC224DC89FCAB2C4A3E84AE3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Treatment of lending transactions</header> 
<paragraph id="H449F837D10E242AA9636E450E62755E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain lending agreements</header><text>In the case of any transfer of widely traded digital assets to which section 1058(a) applies, such assets shall be treated for purposes of this section as continuing to be held by the transferor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CA72B7D0DB8409A9509EDDFAB6C5511"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other lending transactions</header><text>In the case of any loan of widely traded digital assets which is not described in paragraph (1), except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, such assets shall be treated for purposes of this section as continuing to be held by the lender.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0967C74CD9B44D56AD03AB29D6D9F5D6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Election</header> 
<paragraph id="HF1E784DF987D4A37B60FAD7DDB4554FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application of election</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An election under this section with respect to any designated type of digital asset shall apply to the first taxable year which begins after the date on which the taxpayer makes such election and to each taxable year thereafter unless revoked as provided in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0AB6F37F5F1476EA9DC67CD46875695"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Partnerships and S corporations</header><text>In the case of any partnership or S corporation, the election under this section shall be made at the partnership or S corporation level.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A3FD7DA2DEA424EA8CEF44EB7540E15"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revocation</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD28AA2A218584082AF56DA8820EC17E2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A taxpayer may revoke an election under this section with respect to a taxable year which—</text> <clause id="HF6A6D80BE4164FA485E2E2260EAD66C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has not begun as of the date on which such taxpayer requests such revocation, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAD8F9C62515040618ADC010523C2C18C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not one of the first 5 taxable years to which such election applies.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29F31A04A9254D59B0F1AEBCF239305D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deemed revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any designated type of digital asset which has ceased to be a widely traded digital asset, the election under this section with respect to such designated type shall be treated as revoked with respect to the first taxable year beginning after the date on which such designated type ceases to be a widely traded digital asset.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H476D63AFEB1644C48EC64DD2E657B769"><enum>(C)</enum><header>5-year waiting period</header><text>In the case of any revocation under this paragraph with respect to any designated type of digital asset, the taxpayer may not make an election under this section with respect to such designated type if such election would apply to any of the first 5 taxable years to which such revocation applies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H918EC35C28DD4A1B9378AA241BF7D22D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rule for traders making mark-to-market election</header><text>If a taxpayer has in effect one or more elections under this section with respect to designated types of digital assets and such taxpayer makes the election under section 475(f)(3) with respect to any taxable year, the taxpayer shall (notwithstanding subparagraph (A)) be treated as revoking all such elections under this section beginning with such taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC915AB2A39484FD582CC51A50733724B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transition rules related to election, revocation, and certain transfers</header> 
<paragraph id="H49037EE03FDF4E52BD02D2D8202B9B49"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transition rule for election</header><text>In the case of an election under this section, with respect to any designated type of digital asset, any widely traded digital assets of such designated type held by the taxpayer shall be treated as sold for fair market value on the last day of the taxable year preceding the first taxable year to which such election applies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H563AAD54F5734AD1939CD34BE44EA888"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition rule for revocation</header><text>In the case of a revocation of an election under this section, proper adjustment shall be made in the amount of any gain or loss subsequently realized for gain or loss taken into account under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D6C322E29954002A08AE5DB5F88AA3A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transition rule for certain transfers</header><text>In the case of any transfer of a widely traded digital asset which is a designated type of digital asset with respect to the transferor for the taxable year in which the transfer occurs, if the basis of such asset in the hands of the transferee is determined by reference to the basis of such asset in the hands of the transferor, the basis of such asset in the hands of the transferor (solely for purposes of determining the basis of such asset in the hands of the transferee) shall be treated as being equal to the fair market value of such asset at the time of such transfer.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H33385D3A16404BE5964B5A538ACF99B7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Coordination with certain other provisions</header> <paragraph id="H9EF6E459206545AD9D0E7E88ABC8B733"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determined without regard to wash and constructive sale rules</header><text>Sections 1091 and 1259 shall not apply to any transaction with respect to which gain or loss is not recognized by reason of subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EAFD91535B046ECB8A11DCB03242A4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with related party transaction rules</header><text>Section 267 shall not apply with respect to a sale or exchange of property if the transferor has an election in effect under this section for the taxable year with respect to such property.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6239F63DB6E461F8C43B283E9CC12DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonrecognition provisions to not apply</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any transfer of a widely traded digital asset which is not a designated type of digital asset with respect to the transferor for the taxable year of the transferor in which the transfer occurs but which is a designated type of digital asset with respect to the transferee for the taxable year of the transferee in which the transfer occurs, if the transferor and transferee are described in section 267(b) (applied without regard to section 267(c)(3)) or section 707(b)(1), gain or loss shall be recognized on such transfer notwithstanding any other provision of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC25C2ACD912341579ADB60698D7B5367"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Clarification that certain transfers are treated as dispositions</header><text>The following shall not fail to be treated as a disposition for purposes of this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB67E11036FFB4F4D896A2356566BCC95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The distribution of any digital asset from a trust to a beneficiary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H00378462A86846FC90A007C16D18F7A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The transfer of any digital asset from a decedent (whether or not incident to the decedent’s death).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDACCE9E3DF18464B9A9C3F172971C881" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or guidance relating to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDC3E55295509439D9F523C4C90AA317E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the form and manner of making an election or revocation under this section,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BFFA243D3194DF592E8F374A71B75D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adjustments necessary by reason of such election or revocation,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D3A9D20557949FB86AC2540F74B3303"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adjustments to reporting requirements relating to widely traded digital assets with respect to which an election is in effect under this section,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF67186BC35954CB1B67E96D7D7989EDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the treatment of a derivative of a designated type of digital asset, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFC1DA3DC7C942C7887C6344443DDE54" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>preventing abuse of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1D37F9AD5CF04A5D9DF0C17AB548C2A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part III of subchapter O of chapter 1 of subtitle A is amended by inserting before the item relating to section 1052 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBA48CDC333DF446980BF1A9C5C6DE7E7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HCEAC56D58D70438891E46FCF3EC9F02C" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HB312ED008B094EDC966EDFEDF5975051" level="section">Sec. 1051. Election to apply simplified accounting for gain and loss on widely traded digital assets.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBF093191C91F47D886E8DBA014223080"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2027.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H47731E5E2582434CA04B8C75294BDF03"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of U.S. dollar stablecoin transactions</header> <subsection id="HE8DFB8C1BF514B77AB0A192A04B9F145"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part IV of subchapter O of chapter 1 of subtitle A is amended by redesignating section 1063 as section 1064 and by inserting after section 1062 the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7C11ADE5C08448C886C52BF112594407" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H4BDA29A6F2DA44B891C5BC7338A78004"><enum>1063.</enum><header>Certain U.S. dollar stablecoin transactions</header> 
<subsection id="HD3DA11D9169E4374A555B87B95256B34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment of acquisitions of U.S. dollar stablecoins</header> 
<paragraph id="H5467A8FFB4CA48A2A58A49EE73826297"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The basis of any qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin acquired by a taxpayer in any sale or exchange shall be the redemption value of such stablecoin. The preceding sentence shall not apply if it is unreasonable under the facts and circumstances to conclude that the value of the consideration provided for such stablecoin in such sale or exchange is not less than 99.5 percent of such redemption value.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC021F33E910464CA381174252AE4A16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of consideration provided in exchange</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title, in the case of any consideration other than money provided in exchange for a qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin, the income, gain, or loss resulting from the provision of such consideration shall be determined by treating the value of such qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin as being equal to the redemption value of such stablecoin. The preceding sentence shall not apply if it is unreasonable under the facts and circumstances to conclude that the value of such stablecoin is not less than 99.5 percent, and not more than 100.5 percent, of such redemption value.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6DEE670E8E0C4E96B855283C88103B45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of sale or exchange of qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins</header> 
<paragraph id="H5D3F1E9BE4264CA7B9C0DCD2655ECA57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination of gain or loss</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the taxpayer’s basis in any qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin was determined under subsection (a)(1), gain or loss on such taxpayer’s sale or exchange of such stablecoin shall be determined as though such stablecoin were sold or exchanged for the redemption value of such stablecoin. The preceding sentence shall not apply if it is unreasonable under the facts and circumstances to conclude that the value of the consideration received for such stablecoin in such sale or exchange is not more than 100.5 percent of such redemption value.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE24D9ED6BDA94DF0A9482237518BF5E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of consideration received in exchange</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title, in the case of any consideration other than money received in exchange for a qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin, the cost of (and amount paid or incurred for) such consideration shall be determined by treating the value of such qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin as being equal to the redemption value of such stablecoin. The preceding sentence shall not apply if it is unreasonable under the facts and circumstances to conclude that the value of such stablecoin is not less than 99.5 percent, and not more than 100.5 percent, of such redemption value.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFEAC738B4E144E9E9CA0B8BFD9F43726" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<paragraph id="H0A0227E5832A4275A17259FAC9205539"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year if such taxpayer is—</text> <subparagraph id="HA4B33B761C024B7E8BE98CD7EF90269C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a trader, broker, or dealer in qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H74424CDFC7894802A63163056845983D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent provided by the Secretary, any person in a trade or business which is substantially similar to a trade or business described in subparagraph (A), or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3139DE5C045847898453BE0596C750AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other person who in the preceding taxable year engaged in more than 5,000 transactions to which subsection (a) or (b) applied, determined without regard to—</text> 
<clause id="H2699BC936925432BA28EA1EB2167392E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any such transaction which is predominantly with respect to a trade or business (other than a trade or business described in subparagraph (A) or (B)), including the acceptance of qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins at redemption value as a payment for goods or services in such trade or business and the use of qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins at redemption value to acquire goods and services for use in such trade or business, and</text></clause> <clause id="H86622AE2E114410AB8A919F7100321A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any such transaction which is a sale (for money) of a qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin at or below redemption value.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5300134E681849C9998A8A15E309C16F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functional currency other than the dollar</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to any taxpayer or qualified business unit (as defined in section 989(a)) that uses a functional currency other than the dollar.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H367E2897958B4E65BFE6E170BBEAD823"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Related parties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any sale or exchange between persons described in section 267(b) (applied without regard to section 267(c)(3)) or section 707(b)(1)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H96226B937508465F8B19F06D2F3094E9">
                                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>subsections (a)(1), (a)(2), and (b)(2) shall be applied by substituting <quote>100 percent</quote> for <quote>99.5 percent</quote>, and</text>
                                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD0C9CDAE517E4226AAC7CE6558BBC052"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsections (a)(2), (b)(1), and (b)(2) shall be applied by substituting <quote>100 percent</quote> for <quote>100.5 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H85E78CE2826A4E50AC0D4E6D365C7B05" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Redemption value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>redemption value</quote> means, with respect to a qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin, the dollar amount for which the issuer is obligated to convert, redeem, or repurchase such stablecoin.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H05F9E277377F4166BA50622F72620BC6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance—</text> <paragraph id="H492D9C6CC8224CA1AAEAF97FE79A9AC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describing the factors considered, and documentation or substantiation required, with respect to the facts and circumstances tests described in subsections (a)(1), (a)(2), (b)(1), and (b)(2),</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89C830791BC14EF88A54746EE77AD4F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing for the application of subsection (c)(1) with respect to a portion of a taxable year if the taxpayer only regularly purchases, exchanges, or sells qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins for profit for a portion of such taxable year, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD9D0FD0A49F74A568FA7E851FF341F96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to prevent abuse of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8322D61CF8B144BFB0D71DBC9A7FDD74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part IV of subchapter O of chapter 1 of subtitle A is amended by redesignating the item relating to section 1063 as an item relating to section 1064 and by inserting after the item relating to section 1062 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7DD85086CE64483FAAFE516F693D09CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H7C11ADE5C08448C886C52BF112594407" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> <toc-entry idref="H4BDA29A6F2DA44B891C5BC7338A78004" level="section">Sec. 1063. Certain U.S. dollar stablecoin transactions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H3B2A7FE3335548F7ABE8CFC42B8A0204"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H18A4969250CE4E2C90358714DC70FC3A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Broker requirements</header> 
<subsection id="HD3AD6D9F3EF6430D83A2A696B21B0610"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="H4DDEC195C3F242839686A2BC7F165B2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins acquired at redemption value</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6045">Section 6045(g)(3)(D)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H624AE5386F3A41DFAA266C13A3563B1E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H3A8F400D02CC4A18ABD2D08BC2819749"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Specified digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specified digital asset</quote> means any digital asset other than a qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin the customer’s basis in which at the time of acquisition is at least 99.5 percent of such stablecoin’s redemption value (as defined in section 1063(e)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA019DC410CE3422692F6BFAAF6783E31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<subparagraph id="H95FCF036F3EC499EA3E0E72497A246FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6045">Section 6045(c)(1)(D)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>digital assets</quote> and inserting <quote>specified digital assets</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EA8DB1780F640F8B1333506B30F9A83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subparagraph (B)(iv) and subparagraph (C)(iii) of section 6045(g)(3) are each amended by striking <quote>digital asset</quote> and inserting <quote>specified digital asset</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BAD85C7645E49FD944AE274681D7D77"><enum>(C)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6050I">Section 6050I(d)(3)</external-xref> is amended by striking <quote>(as defined in section 6045(g)(3)(D))</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF6899E8E29C3486BA46B3557FE4E10F8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Special rules for digital assets used To pay de minimis validation fee</header> <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6045">Section 6045(g)</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
                <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6ED314E957F54B96AB06646DDD95FAF5"
                    display-inline="no-display-inline">
                    <paragraph id="H01E6D269B3E64416855F5BB58BC300EF">
                        <enum>(7)</enum>
                        <header>Special rules for digital assets used to pay de minimis validation
                            fee</header>
                        <subparagraph id="H8FF2BDC14EFA4D1B8F415D3764ADF342">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
                            <header>In general</header>
 <text>Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of the disposition of a digital asset with respect to which no gain or loss is recognized by reason of section 1044(a)—</text>
                            <clause id="HBED00CE8CA844A0DB383DF9D73CB2B69">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clause (ii), subsection (a) shall not apply to such disposition, and</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="HF4CC11E0FD524E2E8588EFDB3B434262">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the broker shall include in a return under subsection (a) such aggregate information relating to such dispositions of the taxpayer as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate, including for purposes of verifying the taxpayer’s basis in digital assets held by the taxpayer.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="H874F9BAC33FC47609BC77BCACD40D77B">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
                            <header>Application of de minimis exception</header>
 <text>If the broker has been notified by the taxpayer or the Secretary that the exception described in section 1044(e)(1)(B) applies to such taxpayer, the broker may treat such exception as continuing to apply with respect to such taxpayer for any calendar year (hereafter in this subparagraph referred to as the <quote>current calendar year</quote>) unless—</text>
                            <clause id="HA27380A3355C4D0880A75D8A6B8B2D3C">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>such taxpayer had more than 5,000 digital asset transactions with such broker during any of the 5 preceding calendar years and the taxpayer has not notified the broker that such exception applies to such taxpayer for the current calendar year,</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H3C0F16B466094C1B9E6FD4041A16197F">
                                <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>such taxpayer or the Secretary notifies such broker that such exception does not apply to such taxpayer, or</text>
                            </clause>
                            <clause id="H40700A12DB7B426BA3C829F06D9C55D8">
                                <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>such broker otherwise knows, or has reason to know, that such exception does not apply to such taxpayer.</text>
                            </clause>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9613F039B1F422586CD51AAFF66AD05" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules for simplified accounting for widely traded digital assets</header><text>Section 6045(g), as amended by subsection (b), is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9068F1C72A6348D0B759CBAABFA46A85" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H073F5101EB704CD19A715B75C43C75E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Special rules for simplified accounting for widely traded digital assets</header> <subparagraph id="HD0E5F6C273B6484FA0D97895D3679BC4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of widely traded digital assets with respect to which an election under section 1051 applies—</text> 
<clause id="H0A0AD44C3FD14CDCBEE7754E3FE062CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clause (ii), subsection (a) shall not apply to dispositions of such assets, and</text></clause> <clause id="H8646E9D710B44595B9DEC3D5FDF473DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the broker shall include in a return under subsection (a) such information with respect to each desginated type of such assets (within the meaning of section 1051) as the Secretary may provide, including—</text> 
<subclause id="HA168FE25B7D342B8B47C1836BAEA0EA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>aggregate reporting with respect to sales, exchanges, dispositions, and acquistions of assets of such designated type (including net gain or loss thereon),</text></subclause> <subclause id="H03CB51C946E14DCBBBD926A4676979F7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the fair market value of assets of such designated type held by the taxpayer as of the beginning and end of the calendar year, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC5C8F3C3072E449CA2B7FD52CC6A73F8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require with respect to assets of such designated type for purposes of the administration of section 1051.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E609EB362144B83A8065C977F8AE63D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination of election based on broker notification</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the broker shall take into account any election under section 1051 (and any revocation of such election) if (and only if) the taxpayer or the Secretary notifies such broker of such election (or revocation) or such broker otherwise knows, or has reason to know, of such election (or revocation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC09AD621AC0D47A3BF292C5F19E16BA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to returns required to be filed, and statements required to be furnished, after December 31, 2027.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H69F30C2EB31444E889EFDF09E1809499"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">Section 7701</external-xref> is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5278CBE61B0E4A3BB989252668C81CCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (p) as subsection (q), and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H562819B05F3541D6A0189D572E065044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (o) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9F8D2C1AF45C4558B98E91186959D916" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HD9C13867EA504840BE1C5C9A10DE33BF"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Definitions related to digital assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title—</text> <paragraph id="HE8541287477C4768A74C5760EB0ECAC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>digital asset</quote> means, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger or any similar technology as specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66F07D7B985C428E81B68D0805C7ADD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Traded digital asset</header><text>The term <quote>traded digital asset</quote> means, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, any digital asset if—</text> <subparagraph id="H099D48832214485AAA876245A2B484D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such asset is fungible,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94034B326A5C4F77BAF1DD956D4084C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>quotations of such asset are readily available on an exchange (or, in the case of an exchange that does not provide quotations, such quotations are readily ascertainable), and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCE66B121C15E48089638A8D14A4794AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such asset is either—</text> 
<clause id="H45125366A5404963BF985CCC4F313337"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not a tokenized digital asset, or</text></clause> <clause id="H02741455EE244A8E90FC28C71907B1EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a wrapped digital asset with respect to which the reference digital asset is a traded digital asset.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FB7825694B74FA5B51B5407F17958E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Widely traded digital asset</header> 
<subparagraph id="H91DA5FFFAC5940CCA97AF52A69EE87F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>widely traded digital asset</quote> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year and except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, any traded digital asset if—</text> <clause id="HBBBA742B20814C18B2D768B24B3CBB81"><enum>(i)</enum><text>quotations for such asset were readily available on an exchange for the entire calendar year which ends in or with the taxable year preceding such taxable year,</text></clause> 
<clause id="H10A52418DAF24B7BA4757AB1F3E3014F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the market capitalization of such asset exceeded $500,000,000 at substantially all times during such calendar year, and</text></clause> <clause id="H93B3171A6DF347FFB36D1ACC5C6013D8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not more than 10 percent of the units of such asset were owned, directly or indirectly, by the taxpayer or any person described with respect to the taxpayer under section 267(b) (applied without regard to section 267(c)(3)) or section 707(b)(1) at any time during such taxable year or such preceding taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED2FA76B486E4FA0BFB2B750A54C5F0D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for wrapped digital assets</header><text>In the case of any wrapped digital asset, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, such asset shall be treated as a widely traded digital asset if, and only if, the reference digital asset with respect to such wrapped digital asset is a widely traded digital asset.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91A98F8CAAA54BA89556A9600059D09C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority to ensure reliable price discovery</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B), the term <quote>prevent abuse</quote> includes the exclusion of assets that lack reliable price discovery or that the Secretary determines are at risk of price manipulation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D493166E5044E0589B132C3B429436B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Authority to adjust requirements</header><text>The Secretary may, by regulation, provide requirements that apply in lieu of one or more of the requirements of clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that due to changes in market conditions (including by reason of the enactment of Federal digital asset market structure legislation) that such alternative requirements would more effectively or efficiently identify traded digital assets for which there is consistent and reliable price discovery.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF9E5BA46309743A4B75C6C0FF8790F67" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any calendar year after 2027, the $500,000,000 amount in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text>
                                <clause id="HC253C4CF92E54E259F5924632109CBC4">
                                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text> </clause> <clause id="HA291EEB3A74744B685119EC323776CC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2026</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any increase determined under the preceding sentence which is not a multiple of $100,000 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF66CCEBBE3FE40D5984CB68FF8ED9714" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tokenized digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>tokenized digital asset</quote> means any digital asset (other than any qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin) if more than an insignificant portion of the value of such digital asset is related to anything other than the operation of the cryptographically secured distributed ledger on which such digital asset is recorded.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EFA9872E867458DB7FF8BD978E63698"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Wrapped digital asset</header><text>The term <quote>wrapped digital asset</quote> means, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, any digital asset if such asset—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9526ECA173E14CE0BE4E409D7E35954D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is redeemable on demand, on a one-for-one basis, for another digital asset, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H662DB6EB82864EA4998FEDCBEE52E500"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger other than the cryptographically secured distributed ledger on which the digital asset referred to in subparagraph (A) is recorded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBFA5DCB03F894C72ACE5F93B2CAA2109"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reference digital asset</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7DB86D823CB642728176B181FDFE0960"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>reference digital asset</quote> means, with respect to any wrapped digital asset, the digital asset referred to in paragraph (5)(A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB0683763EEB45668B21E857F8B8F6A9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for rewrappings</header><text>If, but for this subparagraph, the reference digital asset with respect to any wrapped digital asset would be a wrapped digital asset (hereafter referred to in this paragraph as the lower-tier wrapped digital asset)—</text> 
<clause id="H1918D916081F49F3B6EDE9E141116073"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) shall be applied with respect to such lower-tier wrapped digital asset, and</text></clause> <clause id="H18D012C9576B4568BCEBDC69B53AB84B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reference digital asset with respect to such lower-tier wrapped digital asset shall be treated as the reference digital asset of such wrapped digital asset.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1A23A14742E4D148A80086A59B9249A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Multiple wrappings</header><text>If, after the application of subparagraph (B), the reference digital asset with respect to the lower-tier wrapped digital asset is a wrapped digital asset, such subparagraph shall be reapplied by treating such lower-tier wrapped digital asset as the wrapped digital asset.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AB7B44B05ED4DEEBCF91F8F3A41F657"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Stablecoin</header> <subparagraph id="H8018B1F733BD488598DA2B6ACF6590B6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin</quote> means any U.S. dollar stablecoin which is issued by—</text> 
<clause id="HEF508CD6CBE04443B24BC283F383C65D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a permitted payment stablecoin issuer (as defined in section 2(23) of the GENIUS Act, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph), or</text></clause> <clause id="H4E77441722514F61A90C2E43DE86576A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a foreign payment stablecoin issuer (as defined in section 2(12) of the GENIUS Act, as so in effect) which is permitted under such Act (as so in effect) to offer, sell, or otherwise make available such U.S. dollar stablecoin in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97F952E17BB04ECAB3ED2795635B4161"><enum>(B)</enum><header>U.S. dollar stablecoin</header><text>The term <quote>U.S. dollar stablecoin</quote> means a payment stablecoin as defined in section 2(22) of the GENIUS Act (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph) applied by substituting <quote>dollars</quote> for <quote>monetary value</quote> each place it appears in such section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC21988905CE149FC9F63F77E6B109A99"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication of list</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the extent feasible, regularly publish a list of qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE031715434244AECBDF42B600CC23FE5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limited authority to treat stablecoins as money</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to (except as otherwise expressly provided in this title)—</text> <clause id="H6C95C0063FBD4118ADF0B467A1EFA993"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treat qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins as dollars, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7F3FD4AB2CF040F5B9CD09516973F6B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>treat other stablecoins as currency if such treatment would increase Federal revenues.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H076275F23C754F739AAED2087614E5EB"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Digital asset transaction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>digital asset transaction</quote> means any transfer of a digital asset recorded on the cryptographically secured distributed ledger (or similar technology) referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61B3D8053F0F45BFAA098D53858E3B9E"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Validation</header><text>The term <quote>validate</quote>, and any derivative of such term (including <quote>validation</quote>), when used in connection with a digital asset transaction, includes the processes of proposing transactions for validation and verifying the validation of transactions.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

