<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFE339BA8FAF5452D93F83C937F00D61A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6647 IH: Drone Safety Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6647</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000398">Mr. Kean</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for collaboration between NASA and the FAA relating to research on unmanned aircraft systems and advanced air mobility, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD76CED0E074A44869497BFE0D5E926B2" style="OLC"><section id="HD6D8B02355614924A14D3577B1D9C382" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drone Safety Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3D001984D28C4425B35C2B924A2E82EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system and advanced air mobility</header><subsection id="HBB8906A0B7AD43C384F6F4D4BE8861DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that research and development related to autonomous aviation is vital to ensure United States competitiveness as the National Airspace System evolves from trajectory-based operations to collaborative and highly automated operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A79063AA1C1452BBB5A7D65CC721851"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Administrator shall, in collaboration with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, and appropriate representatives of academia and industry, continue its research on unmanned aircraft systems and advanced air mobility, including research related to UTM and autonomous capabilities, as practicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9E38BFF18794BDA9F995F62C04F3E89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on the progress of the research under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB9830E1896AA477898B148D74AADF87B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H9F8CD3B2B2E34A11AA3744185A248F82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AC4FF8020C047ECB63B85C4465F3C05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advanced air mobility</header><text>The term <quote>advanced air mobility</quote> means a transportation system that is comprised of urban air mobility and regional air mobility using manned or unmanned aircraft.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H535F7BE0E5D244C68DCDFBEFFD487C17"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1ADF9FF4BC354186B0778827C30E7E88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54172F2290CB420490CB99AAA6D863E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8667CDEF6E7C40798C60B9CE01BB0479"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional air mobility</header><text>The term <quote>regional air mobility</quote> means the movement of passengers or property by air between two points using an airworthy aircraft that—</text><subparagraph id="HDBB9A6FA5A1E4A23B012B59D2E66DE18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has advanced technologies, such as distributed propulsion, vertical takeoff and landing, powered lift, nontraditional power systems, or autonomous technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CC8F1DBE46844418D8289F6DB5268CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a maximum takeoff weight of greater than 1,320 pounds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA1F78BCB3D349DAA102503BB627350D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not urban air mobility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D9C2CACA51845189A1185A284D5CBC9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The term <quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4224F1135DD4426A88157BEF4FD5300"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Urban air mobility</header><text>The term <quote>urban air mobility</quote> means the movement of passengers or property by air between two points in different cities or two points within the same city using an airworthy aircraft that—</text><subparagraph id="H5D4AE805EF3043518293DC16BFAD38DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has advanced technologies, such as distributed propulsion, vertical takeoff and landing, powered lift, nontraditional power systems, or autonomous technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B19A28E35E84BB69A85174F339B09B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a maximum takeoff weight of greater than 1,320 pounds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7769261F7C6F4A7E812297A0CC5EB9B2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>UTM</header><text>The term <quote>UTM</quote> means an unmanned aircraft system traffic management system or service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


