<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A4C23D5D73A46B99E3AD06DBC4405D7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7539 IH: Safety and Accountability in Freight Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7539</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration to conduct a study on chameleon carriers in the United States and plan, develop, and test an advanced automation tool to help enforcement personnel detect chameleon carrier applications under the registration process of the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H4502332B9D6C436D88952CC176626279" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9718D84471184D7A826D99C3EE73C287" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety and Accountability in Freight Enforcement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC413B495519B45B8B19D491B5A78B462" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on chameleon carriers</header> <subsection id="H7058E65F3B484635B4AC043D75BB019A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that contains the results of a study that examines chameleon carriers on United States roadways.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H809E5D6D75AD4225A5CDC56AB7CA8A93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H440B963BAEAF436B958794DFFBB1B8E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estimated number of chameleon carriers on United States roadways at any given time;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67F6275C48254D989765A17967ACDBCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the prevalence of chameleon carriers on United States roadways since the issuance of the report of the Government Accountability Office titled <quote>Motor Carrier Safety: New Applicant Reviews Should Expand to Identify Freight Carriers Evading Detection</quote>, issued March 22, 2012;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9107586AF63A4B0DAC30EA3722332847"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the estimated number of fatalities caused by chameleon carriers since the report described in paragraph (2), including the number of fatalities broken down by State;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H189D82E3B6C24004A3F617AFADAA6EF5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the estimated number of serious bodily injuries caused by chameleon carriers since the report described in paragraph (2), including the number of serious bodily injuries broken down by State;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F13B01E99E2472DA7BFB80DFF7EFAE5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the estimated amount of property damage caused by chameleon carriers since the report described in paragraph (2);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09F06FC48C534E2DBC394F7A6C8CEC71"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an identification and analysis of the methods and techniques used by chameleon carriers to evade Federal enforcement, including how such methods and techniques have evolved over time;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC48961C42A34ED588FA7219C203FEF1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an identification and analysis of the existing monitoring and enforcement capabilities, along with any shortcomings, of the Department of Transportation to detect and mitigate chameleon carrier activity, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD61D2B18D0C447C78FC620CC3001F6AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the registration processes for Department of Transportation numbers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8AC5604CDA24ACD834BDF820C8942A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the existing software capabilities of the Department of Transportation to detect chameleon carrier applicants;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5142109916A429383AF047B71893455"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for improving data fields within the Motor Carrier Management Information System; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45B20E5F63C84FF88EABB3996C811281"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any existing penalties laid out under Federal statute and regulation for chameleon carriers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64E4889BA4044C91B623C233D625B840"><enum>(8)</enum><text>any other relevant priorities deemed necessary by the Department of Transportation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8D9C195036349D39F31E115DA191ADA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>any legislative recommendations to address chameleon carriers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB181EBE199F1439A8AD052D0ECF9E4FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out the study under subsection (a), the Comptroller General may collaborate with other Federal agencies, State and local governments, institutions of higher education, and private sector entities.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H49E5968ED8424511BE5F54793A296D8E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Advanced automation tool</header> <subsection id="H55A439A10225489A93D31F30FB14C4C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration shall develop, test, and implement an advanced automation tool to help Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration registration personnel detect chameleon carrier applications under the registration process for Department of Transportation numbers.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H25AA838EDA5143788FA95C28B00108A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration</header> 
<paragraph id="H365B9D1EF851421281B5B0EAFAC17EB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the tool under subsection (a), the Administrator may collaborate with other Federal agencies, State and local governments, institutions of higher education, and the private sector as necessary to develop and test the advanced automation tool.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D4E600407E14F488464C26A15D64B58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator and any Federal agency the Administrator determines is relevant shall enter into a memorandum of understanding to share information needed to implement the requirements of the tool under subsection (c), which may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7C46C59B435F4ABC8440BAABFB3C3447"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Treasury;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H355488C0DEF24C6F8A52BAD29966BDB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H343F580CC5F14C7E9BF5E438B020BD6A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Postal Service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0042D3E111544BDBC26C1DE7845E025"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H890BFD49D02B4741AF30A92C8F073F8D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBBE1CBE742084619807F22BFBD55F8AB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Department of State; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBFFA1A4524A4D32861C05B5BDB4A79D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>relevant operating administrations within the Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39AC71AE0B19410F8E4A7E1626916ABD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with any relevant State agency to share information needed to implement the requirements of the tool under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3882749C96BE4AFC9E0D68008FD16FD0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The advanced automation tool developed under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HCCB43F7448134028B1F5A0EE863CD12A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ability to detect chameleon carrier-like characteristics that support evidence of substantial continuity between entities, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDD5EE1DD2FC34A909EA486097DB638B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the new or affiliated entity was created for the purpose of evading statutory or regulatory requirements, a Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration order, enforcement action, or negative compliance history;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17E26742BA254139AB9BF503E48C89B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the previous entity's safety performance history, including, among other things, safety violations and enforcement actions of the Secretary, if any;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E39D70D1E39435AA3F562C26A9C4D42"><enum>(C)</enum><text>existing or inactive Department of Transportation numbers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F5987E15094420A8A36C288FAA4923C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consideration exchanged for assets purchased or transferred;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9D9C26C858A34D0C8F7B3533DAA03DA1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>dates of company creation and dissolution or cessation of operations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3855B36760B14717A280D0B2F70AD99F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>commonality of ownership between the current and former company or between current companies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C04669C1A7A4464A4491F48749DB752"><enum>(G)</enum><text>commonality of officers and management personnel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3EB54033321447B8F5AF06D0499011A"><enum>(H)</enum><text>identity of physical or mailing addresses, telephone, fax numbers, or email addresses;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83BB3FAFEA404EC79646C9107993E725"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identity of motor vehicle equipment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3003E8FD9823415FB5D9A4507D3D4D33"><enum>(J)</enum><text>continuity of liability insurance policies or commonality of coverage under such policies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA574719AE3F24AA4AC0A122C02EABC8E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>commonality of drivers and other employees;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6DBD35B581441C5A0B41056B28D2711"><enum>(L)</enum><text>continuation of carrier facilities and other physical assets;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C9FA0A54A0346A0AE3C582B8342383D"> <enum>(M)</enum> <text>continuity or commonality of nature and scope of operations; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB3509FD0772465C8868E5A7DBABEE5A"><enum>(N)</enum><text>advertising, corporate name, or other acts through which the company holds itself out to the public;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAB997E1E1704930A2FD6287B29109DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the ability to detect lapses in insurance coverage;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF4B6F3B9FDA4D64BF6567B430BD702B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the ability to compile evidence of the chameleon carrier-like characteristics under paragraph (1) relevant to the determination of a registration application for Department of Transportation numbers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3D884F21B1184556A12D58A6EE6564B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the ability to provide automated decision support relevant to the determination of any registration application for Department of Transportation numbers, while keeping responsibility for final determinations on employees of the Administration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE01A7F705F5C43F2B43E6881222E17AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the ability to automate information sharing between Federal agencies; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H946EB74A96874E3FA5276F1DEBA2E7ED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other relevant priorities determined necessary by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA3A779F54421460DAC4F326ED3D43BE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appeals for redetermination</header> <paragraph id="H3A389F7F095240208B8410CF0375ED6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the tool under this section, the Administrator shall develop an appeals process under which persons denied a Department of Transportation number on the basis of a flag by such tool may seek a review of the denial.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43E221778FC549DE9B020142AD87A6F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>In establishing the tool under this section, the Administrator shall provide for a process under which a person denied a Department of Transportation number as described in paragraph (1) shall receive a notification of such denial that includes the factors flagged by the tool and provides instructions to such person to correct the application for such number not later than 30 days after receipt of the notification.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H685A908BFCAA43AF837A9950F3C90918"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing of redetermination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appeals process developed under paragraph (1) shall provide for a redetermination on the amended application for a Department of Transportation number to take place not later than 30 days after the receipt of the information described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H98DD213E72084F49B513DED1486BD2CA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall brief the congressional committees of jurisdiction on the issue of chameleon carriers and any ongoing efforts or progress that the Administration has made to combat such issue or meet the objectives of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF573B5BA58E4454DB5DB01A8EAB6AC09"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to allow the final use of an automated decision by the tool created under this section for Department of Transportation number registration.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC5CA2FCFDAF46B1A04B4938334BB4D4"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Data privacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the tool under subsection (a), the Administrator shall ensure that data used by such tool is not disclosed for a purpose not described in this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8930D00E77E645239C96B5659A843824"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Audit and report on effectiveness</header> <paragraph id="H1B0CDAFCECAE41DE8834466FE8B2D5A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of implementation of the tool established under this section, the inspector general of the Department of Transportation shall submit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of such tool.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E5B22177A994A19A9641520D92FC731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall contain—</text> <subparagraph id="HFD8EE7CE5AF34632B00137C04703928A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of an audit of the effectiveness of the tool established under this section;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HACB816ACC4F948C0A60773C87EB61124"><enum>(B)</enum><text>empirical data on outcomes of the use of the tool, including the number of flagged and rejected applications for Department of Transportation numbers, any reduction in severe crashes, and the number of errors and application redeterminations under subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCC33A5FB8FA46E3A74EB593D2B78359"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any recommendations to improve the effectiveness of the tool.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H089FA9BBF71F4529864012437BDE7BC6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition of chameleon carrier</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>chameleon carrier</quote> means a motor carrier, intermodal equipment provider, broker, or freight forwarder, or an officer, employee, agent, authorized representative, or other affiliated party of such an entity, that has, directly or indirectly, operated or attempted to operate a motor carrier, intermodal equipment provider, broker, or freight forwarder under a new identity or as an affiliated entity to—</text> <paragraph id="H2DF882B0E19040EBB3301F1FB43959EC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>avoid complying with a Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration order;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5918D7494B304995A0C77EB6EA8C5452"><enum>(2)</enum><text>avoid complying with a statutory or regulatory requirement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H148AC0157FA04E4EBB1247AB87606CEB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>avoid paying a civil penalty;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H430DF380F02B4AC89C3B37D976CA88E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>avoid responding to an enforcement action;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15D0EB7F2DBB484CBE788ACAA3306917"><enum>(5)</enum><text>avoid being linked with a negative compliance history;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71122D743CAE402FBB5D4CC99808DA39"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">avoid or evade increased insurance premiums, policy cancellations, or underwriting restrictions by obtaining or attempting to obtain insurance coverage under a new or materially different identity, ownership structure, or corporate form;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDDADEEDD87E4B7FA0F78C68BD130B9D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>misrepresent ownership, control, management, or operational continuity to an insurer, broker, or underwriter for the purpose of securing lower insurance rates or favorable coverage terms; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CF35D73F3244281ADDF2D7740EFBA37"><enum>(8)</enum><text>reincorporate, re-register, or otherwise reconstitute a carrier entity following the denial, nonrenewal, or cancellation of an insurance policy due to safety, claims, or compliance history.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

