<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26435-8K9-X0-1K7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 733 ATS: Expressing the sense of the Senate that public servants should be commended for their dedication and continued service to the United States during Public Service Recognition Week and throughout the year.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 733</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the sense of the Senate that public servants should be commended for their dedication and continued service to the United States during Public Service Recognition Week and throughout the year.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the week of May 3, 2026, through May 9, 2026, has been designated as <quote>Public Service Recognition Week</quote> to honor employees of the Federal Government and State and local governments, and members of the uniformed services, for their contributions to the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Public Service Recognition Week provides an opportunity to recognize and promote the important contributions of public servants and to honor the people who serve the United States at all levels of government and as members of the uniformed services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas millions of individuals serve the public in government service and as members of the uniformed services in every State, county, and city across the United States and around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public servants provide crucial services to millions of people across the United States, supporting local programs and contributing to local economies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas public service is a noble calling involving a variety of challenging and rewarding professions and highly skilled and trained individuals offering their knowledge, effort, and skills in support of the public; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States is a great and prosperous country, and public service employees contribute significantly to that greatness and prosperity: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id32707cb7e20d4a709f89ba5b937af315"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commends the dedication, professionalism, and patriotism of the public servants of the United States who fulfill their constitutional oath and deliver essential services to the people of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbeb3e4344d7b40f691a510b929af9007"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the indispensable role of public servants in strengthening the economy of the United States, protecting the safety and security of the public, safeguarding individual rights, and sustaining the foundations of democratic self-governance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d58a62b96484d318cb63b690aad2a9d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the contributions of all public servants during Public Service Recognition Week, May 3, 2026, through May 9, 2026, and throughout the year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01c31d872ebf4725b3a42370520f78db"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls upon the people of the United States to observe Public Service Recognition Week with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities that honor and acknowledge the service of those who work on their behalf.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

