<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53AFE10D73684365935971DDBD13111E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9405 IH: Esther Coopersmith Award Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9405</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish, at the Department of State, the Esther Coopersmith Award in recognition of a distinguished diplomat advancing sustainable peace and security.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF200DBCC698742AE823CA96382B1C781" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H0129EC573312405F82A6D184ADC01CB8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Esther Coopersmith Award Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0DD63DDD77D14F2AAD34B51CC51012B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HE9D8150109734DBB98FCC01759F66BD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United Nations Secretary General’s 2025 Report on Women, Peace and Security notes an estimated 676,000,000 women and girls lived within 50 kilometers of a deadly conflict event during 2024, which is the highest number since the 1990s.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76CE87636FB04E94961C8A0D4ED1F56F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The meaningful participation of women in conflict prevention and conflict resolution processes—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3086B3016364A268652AF87CB53A77D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promotes more inclusive and democratic societies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1E1236DD300F4C43A167A56529ABFACC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is critical to the long-term stability and security of those countries and regions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H814282341C0C48CC9B2BC172C94B5D6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2017, President Trump signed the bipartisan Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/68">Public Law 115–68</external-xref>), which codified decades’ long efforts to strategically address material threats to United States national security by supporting United States leadership in improving the participation of women in peace and security processes, conflict prevention, peacebuilding, and decision-making institutions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B9A1FFC4CF04423861FC13435BB7388"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2018, President Trump signed the bipartisan Women’s Entrepreneurship and Economic Empowerment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/428">Public Law 115–428</external-xref>) to recognize the vital contribution women’s full and unfettered economic participation and inclusion plays in fostering global growth, prosperity, and stability.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H918318753350454587BD4E069C13D55B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In October 2023, President Biden released the United States Strategy and National Action Plan on Women, Peace and Security to better equip United States national security agencies with the tools to address shifts in geopolitical challenges and advancements in technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B86D1FB1F514E6890F228282A48E04E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Executive Order 13595 (76 Fed. Reg. 80205 (December 19, 2011); instituting a National Action Plan on Women, Peace, and Security)—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24E21E52CED14062BBAB4C840155DA8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">institutionalized a United States Government-wide effort promoting women’s participation in conflict prevention, management and resolution, and post-conflict recovery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF25AD81671374B7A88D0617B5E852D76"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">noted the responsibility of all nations to protect their populations from genocide, war crimes, ethnic cleansing and crimes against humanity, including when implemented by means of sexual violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H36240F44BC404F8C9D648CCEF9CFCD19"><enum>(7)</enum><text>For 70 years, the late United States diplomat Esther Coopersmith leveraged creativity and innovation to build bridges and forge common understanding, which contributed invaluably to United States peace and security.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE38A2C76486549279D2237EF32FA1759"><enum>3.</enum><header>Alignment of award recognizing United States diplomatic efforts within United States law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 614 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4013">22 U.S.C. 4013</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and the rights of women and girls</quote> after <quote>freedom of religion</quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H35C3594D22AB499080734FFA224A6AA2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of the Esther Coopersmith Award for Advancing Peace and Security</header>
<subsection id="HE614DADBDF504E2C857087692EDEFEB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish an annual individual or group performance award, which shall be known as the <quote>Esther Coopersmith Award</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2564866138749D5BD9DC159CFF44FFF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recipients</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recipients of the Esther Coopersmith Award shall—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF6ED0448DB746BABAA7A723263678C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be members of the Civil Service or of the Foreign Service who have made meaningful contributions advancing the purposes of the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/68">Public Law 115–68</external-xref>) or the Women's Entrepreneurship and Economic Empowerment Act 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/428">Public Law 115–428</external-xref>) to sustainably prevent, mitigate, or resolve conflict, violence, or instability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B279DB40560423FAC9ED49354CAEB45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include one honorable mention recipient annually; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD177E57796BF4BC7AED361786008DAF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>meet with the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB95A119C6B074DEFB00AE17957810604"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Efforts To be recognized</header> <text>Recipients of the Esther Coopersmith Award shall be recognized for actions promoting women’s leadership in efforts, such as—</text>
                <paragraph id="H14408F701B0D4DC8801E5F80C1094691">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>integrating the perspectives and interests of affected women into conflict-prevention activities and strategies;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H064A4AFE1C8C433FA40646D79AE5B0FA">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>encouraging partner governments to adopt plans to improve the meaningful participation of women in peace and security processes and decision-making institutions;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H36B9D8441BC046DEAB5C7C876B16F308">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>promoting the physical safety, economic security, and dignity of women and girls;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H15085DA0B39145009D503CE57976C38F">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>supporting the equal access of women to aid distribution mechanisms and services; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBF1D227159764238A0B656ECF29F9ECA">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>supporting foreign capacity to collect or analyze data for the purpose of developing and enhancing early warning systems of conflict and violence.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H509424ED29DF4C16B2A4B80971B44CEC">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Representation</header>
 <text>In accordance with section 5(a)(1) of the Women, Peace, and Security Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152j-1">22 U.S.C. 2152j–1(a)(1)</external-xref>), the Secretary of State shall support recipients’ official travel to attend a major global security conference to support the alignment of global efforts advancing peace and security.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="HA6392B048C764CA68CD1196A2B78BF8A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary of State shall—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E3EE4577DA644F98F205218E359D060"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate the Office of Global Women’s Issues to administer the Esther Coopersmith Award; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A6F5D871DF549729C87F5FB501418C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive input regarding award recipients through an award review panel composed of Assistant Secretaries of State and Chiefs of Missions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEB904927C35B45918022699D20AC353E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mandatory training</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In accordance with section 6(a) of the Women, Peace and Security Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2152j-2">22 U.S.C. 2152j–2(a)</external-xref>), award recipients and honorable mentions shall present their work virtually to—</text>
<paragraph id="H03F785CAA2554E93B0A799988CEA07D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Chiefs of Mission Conference; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6666CBC90B7D4AD48FBB2CFFA9D26E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at least 1 entry level training course (such as the A–100 class) for incoming Foreign Service officers.</text></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H1051027413C44344B024B9B7BEA64ADC"><enum>6.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report</header>
<subsection id="HD67A5BD962284CE09F619358065F2914">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text>Not later than 90 days after the Secretary of State selects recipients pursuant to section 4, the Secretary shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that describes the efforts undertaken by the recipients to promote women’s roles in supporting peace and security.</text>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H3126E38406634C8AA3DC2A35890B0C60">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Matters To be included</header>
 <text>The report required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9DEAE4318A514F69B476306EA451045B"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>describe United States' interests in resolving the conflict, instability, or violence addressed by the recipients;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H48B012CED2024B318031032FB82A0E59">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>describe the recipients’ actions and resulting outcomes, including those taken by a United States Mission, Department of State bureau, foreign government, or other stakeholders;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H16F503D47253458CB60BAD8B20375314">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>assess areas for potential further action and lessons learned; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H11A8A7A60EF44BC1928E42C47990097C"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>identify steps to be taken by the Department of State to replicate or carry forward work initiated by the award recipient, if applicable.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section>
<section id="H94C8534CE48340868B7E25623B0693C5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendment made by this Act, shall cease to have any force or effect beginning on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

