<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26196-P6R-XW-1PJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 643 IS: Designating March 12, 2026, as “Detransition Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 643</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating March 12, 2026, as <quote>Detransition Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas gender ideology has resulted in irreparable harm to individuals, especially minors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas no child should be pushed into irreversible chemical and surgical procedures, sex change interventions, or receiving hormones or puberty blockers;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the influence of social media and other online platforms has perpetuated harms that gender ideology poses to children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas medical interventions by healthcare professionals, under the guise of <quote>gender affirming care</quote>, have damaged the healthy bodily and hormonal development of children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many minors seeking to transition have a history of 1 or more mental health disorders, including gender dysphoria, anxiety, depression, body dysmorphia, eating disorders, and suicidal thoughts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Department of Health and Human Services, <quote>Sex-rejecting procedures on children—which include puberty blockers, cross-sex hormones, and surgical operations—expose them to irreversible damage, including infertility, impaired sexual function, diminished bone density, altered brain development, and other irreversible physiological effects</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2013, the rate of gender dysphoria in children has dramatically increased;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas about 42,000 children and teens across the United States received a gender dysphoria diagnosis in 2021, which is nearly triple the number of gender dysphoria diagnoses that occurred in 2017, according to Reuters;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas at least 121,882 children ages 6 to 17 were diagnosed with gender dysphoria from 2017 through 2021, with similar data from diagnoses covered by Medicaid, according to Reuters;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas at least 14,726 of minors with gender dysphoria diagnoses started hormone intervention from 2017 through 2021, according to Reuters;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas over 5,700 of the 13,994 minors across the United States who received medical intervention for gender dysphoria over the course of 4 years were operated on, according to Do No Harm’s <quote>Does My Hospital Transition Kids?</quote> database;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas approximately 225 children’s hospitals in the United States provide some version of <quote>gender affirming care</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many of the individuals who underwent these transition procedures, like detransitioner and activist Chloe Cole, ultimately pursue the process of detransitioning; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Detransition Awareness Day has been nationally recognized since 2021: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id48b355cf5e83475aa904f6519ba86db3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates March 12, 2026, as <quote>Detransition Awareness Day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id868442611fe548379cf164aebf76e506"><enum>(2)</enum><text>celebrates and commits to fostering the biological reality of young men and women.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

