<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV25M76-MV6-PW-7LT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3344 IS: Prohibiting Unauthorized Military Action in Venezuela Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3344</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the unauthorized use of United States Armed Forces in hostilities with respect to Venezuela.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prohibiting Unauthorized Military Action in Venezuela Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1fa03f24e7dd4be3b4df73b89877ae23"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of United States Armed Forces to conduct hostilities with respect to Venezuela</header><subsection id="id43644168dd2d47ab9d2f8084ea8fe974"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available for the Department of Defense, or for any other department or agency of the United States Government, may be used to conduct hostilities with respect to Venezuela, except—</text><paragraph id="idb870c564ac6f4fe2a3222507ceae73a7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pursuant to a specific statutory authorization enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id626b8828cd1f47979687a36162b8a48f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pursuant to a congressional authorization consistent with section 2(c) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc42ee762f4ec409395e7a7736b475f95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the United States from—</text><paragraph id="id0e902998f9cd4e83b5382c9a17599af0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acting to defend itself or its citizens from an armed attack or the threat of an imminent armed attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id435afc96460646569fa8444362330c29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acting to defend the United States Armed Forces or United States personnel from an armed attack;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8c6cb9e6add401f9029bec00596d439"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conducting lawful counternarcotics operations that do not constitute hostilities; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2651d21f27314931b64889b6562e627a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing humanitarian assistance to the people of Venezuela.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa2fac19a20c457890e75d2099a1c0f4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hostilities defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>hostilities</term> means any situation involving any use of lethal or potentially lethal force by United States forces, whether such force is deployed remotely and irrespective of the intermittency thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="id99e924b9520d422ab2cf092c604c410c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relation to the War Powers Resolution</header><text>Nothing in this section supersedes any requirement of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1541">50 U.S.C. 1541 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

