<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A9C21D3E929413D8FCEA62D4275F2C8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5965 IH: Student Veteran Work Study Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5965</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a pilot program to extend eligibility for a certain work-study allowance paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to certain individuals who pursue programs of rehabilitation, education, or training on at least a half-time basis, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAAF9022971EF43659244724AB24475AC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6BB4104B807E4C78A7698D5151E7A0E8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Veteran Work Study Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H372E0416C9514E01AB489097343C3911"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program to expand eligibility for a certain work-study allowance paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to certain individuals who pursue certain programs on at least a half-time basis</header> <subsection id="H2AEAA3A071C94FDE92039F39D7BB76C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary shall expand eligibility for the work-study allowance under section 3485 of title 38, United States Code, to individuals who are pursuing programs of rehabilitation, education, or training specified in subsection (b) of such section at a rate equal to at least half of that required of a full-time student.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H48E0401465C149C8B5CE3B7532D6E8E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship to other work-Study individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure the provisions of section 3485 of title 38, United States Code, apply with respect to the individuals specified in subsection (a) of this section in the same manner as to the individuals specified in subsection (b) of such section 3485, except with respect to the requirement of at least three-quarter-time student status.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7856D28D80224409A92181A9BBFB24F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out the pilot program under subsection (a) during the five-year period beginning on the date of the commencement of the pilot program.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1F845A2615764A9BB8EBA60CFC04C635"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual report regarding veterans who participate in work-study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report regarding veterans who participate in work-study. Such report shall include the following elements:</text> <paragraph id="H3E6E015539694895AE68F855643CA974"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of such veterans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9BFDBEA424B4D85B77C62773DC03995"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The percentage of such veterans who obtain a four-year degree.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E4184BDB9BC46ED867DB8584834E536"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of such veterans who obtain full-time work at the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA9DC1B9C8ADF4A65B8C013E80D403BD2" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section> </legis-body></bill> 

