<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA4CC152AD65E431A94EFF470C71ADF53" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6089 IH: Biomanufacturing Excellence Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6089</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Biopharmaceutical Center of Excellence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0BE5FB7DC66F49A097060762EB04530D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3F3259E52E3C42C4814B46426FCD56B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Biomanufacturing Excellence Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9209AFFAFFB84C779346548212AB6CC4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE760A076A0A340D89C60E27A127C5E82"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBCA5345461C246C88CE06F9A0DAD9B65"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Biotechnology is the designing and engineering of biological systems. Biotechnology allows scientists to grow everything from medicines to crops to materials, enabling <quote>biology by design</quote>. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD20902DAF8A6412E9635BFA964A41175"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Biotechnology holds the potential for the United States to transform its military capabilities, strengthen food security and agricultural resilience, and cure life-threatening diseases, but it holds that same potential for other countries. The countries that master biotechnology first will gain the ability to shape how those technologies are used for decades to come.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28262958A11F4DA1B7826895850E55A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Biotechnology unlocks the capabilities of producing medicines via biological systems, known as biopharmaceutical manufacturing. Biopharmaceutical manufacturing will enable better and less invasive treatments that extend and improve lives. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H33B941655756414694A6F46793C56CD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>By investing in biomanufacturing, the United States Government would reduce dependency on foreign supply chains.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54C1A49F1F00434492CC251DB401AFE1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>For United States manufacturers, the biggest roadblock to commercialization is proving that their products and processes can scale and produce a return on investment. Biomanufacturing requires flexible and affordable infrastructure for development, to ensure that innovative products can rapidly move from the lab to commercial-scale production.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9F45BB2F4354ABFA4BFEE2BFCF9A5D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E828160C06C435D929C4AAE072575B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to realize the potential of biotechnology, the United States Government should establish a biopharmaceutical manufacturing center of excellence;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71A363B3F7624D13A491598BE802FB16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the center should facilitate and accelerate manufacturing innovation, support good manufacturing practices, and provide for collaboration among public, private, and nonprofit institutions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC18600A801334F3583BEA48D29E5C9A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the center should also facilitate training for workers to operate biotechnology tools and equipment and to bolster talent throughout the biotechnology sector. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HEDF66D652225440685C32D3CACA08DB3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of National Biopharmaceutical Center of Excellence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/271">15 U.S.C. 271 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CBC15D06A274F34A65F0127DDF0D2D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating section 36 as section 37; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H888AEA9FF06340B5930763D5BC4EB8F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after section 35 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2398F7318E8345789FF52176FB6F7695"> 
<section id="HC1A156A542D04836AF6B60E68CC87772"><enum>36.</enum><header>National Biopharmaceutical Center of Excellence</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4222D9C3F37C43A4A4DEE7E3DB2E2A34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of Center of Excellence</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B3D29316ACE454E9FA35CC456222039"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall award a grant to or enter into an other transaction agreement with, on a competitive basis, an eligible entity to establish and operate a center of excellence to be known as the National Biopharmaceutical Manufacturing Center of Excellence (in this section referred to as the <quote>Center of Excellence</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12714B1E1D4E430AB7E2695B0FEF24F9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of the Center of Excellence include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H339EFD0A684A4489A79CCE45EBEBF080"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advancing the science of biopharmaceutical manufacturing, especially with respect to products of particular importance to the national security, health security, or economic security of the United States, including by—</text> <clause id="H67091D72C2A149C6B8E4A51362A04198"><enum>(i)</enum><text>developing and demonstrating flexible biopharmaceutical manufacturing technologies and systems;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA4EB5827C57B48F4A7CEC6D9B15A5817"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improving upstream and downstream processes for multiple biopharmaceutical manufacturing platforms or product modalities;</text></clause> <clause id="H85100C95DE584C9E9976F4F7DF18AA59"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improving biopharmaceutical manufacturing equipment and capabilities; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF834CEEA6D984A83AA7B84D540F8F5F8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>reducing supply bottlenecks and strengthening supply chain self-sufficiency through demonstration of innovative technologies;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC9888D03D4048BCA1CE7C825C9DC8BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting good manufacturing practices, quality by design, and standardization of chemistry, manufacturing, and controls to ensure effective and efficient manufacturing and to improve the regulation of innovative methods of manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8764942DADD4E268D4E9E9C9044BF3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advancing workforce training and development by working with educational and community partners to bolster biotechnology talent;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87A824254AFC4C7C8DB396CFB442B567"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing the science of and deploying the infrastructure for innovative biopharmaceutical manufacturing by engaging with—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96EA9C2782FB4145AC3E166138B7FA70"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">institutions of higher education;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBCC4A9354D2B4A6FA72EAD2D165ED213"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">small, medium, and large pharmaceutical manufacturers;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2FD7DCAA0EE4A6897C9C98C8FA80D69"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal, State, and local government agencies and institutes; </text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7ED19ED1EC424FDAA6E22C4A9B763ECC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">non-profit organizations;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CF580F070CD433285E7CD3C31198054"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">professional organizations; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1543BF3C4954D4DA450011DF12FD356"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other entity the Director considers relevant; </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF13DD02B9304673AF9B183BB1EA62AF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sharing with the head of any Executive agency that oversees the planning, management, or coordination of Federal activities relating to biotechnology research generated by the Center of Excellence, including data regarding best practices for biopharmeceutical manufacturing; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBC421C25DA54AA1ADE4132C38A12C54"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other objective the Director considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB81AB21D91B24ED2A9ECA2FA9ABEF035"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall award the Center of Excellence funding for any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HED393A76B9874EF59D67FF29AC50E40B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To facilitate the construction of facilities necessary to accomplish the objectives described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1EACA8A320154785B42B37C310C416DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To conduct collaborative research on new technology for scaling biopharmaceutical manufacturing in the United States for commercial production.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2E31D7EF686402CB85739781A867A9E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To facilitate workforce training programs for biopharmaceutical manufacturing.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DAECB2D51214248AF967D2755A45BE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To fund relevant research and programs for the development of biopharmaceutical manufacturing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H213FC50B351146B496F1F1D5031AC912"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application; award</header> <paragraph id="H3B046EAF0DA44B08B93E8F6DE22328E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director shall solicit applications from eligible entities specified in paragraph (2) and award to or enter into with one such entity a grant or other transaction agreement to establish the Center of Excellence. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H16E9FD056C10462DBC3FD26E139F98EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity is eligible to submit an application pursuant to paragraph (1) if—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCCD14B181EE0483BB6AB0CE7D4C7C974"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity is—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H384FA25BAA3A49979A5780A010221826"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public-private partnership;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F4CCC05FF0E4139A6360501A192EFF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93E3FFED37AD4C07934B724A90EAFBDD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a consortia of entities specified in clauses (i) or (ii); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E7A25B3E67241BC9D4F98CF31D6F7A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity is not a Federal entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F259799205A4D0FBB4C5A24BBF066BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Content of application</header><text>An application submitted by an entity pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H6169B427EEFB4D64A92B58C5B8F305C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>examples from the entity of previous research, development, implementation, and demonstration of innovative practices of biopharmaceutical manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27F8FC66EACA44F590569DE5405B87A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the manner by which the entity plans to advance the science of biopharmaceutical manufacturing, especially with respect to products of particular importance to the national security, health security, or economic security of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2431A39B520D4A38B8E99D29C219ADCC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the manner by which the entity plans to incorporate good manufacturing practices, quality by design, and standardization of chemistry, manufacturing, and controls, and similar guidance to ensure effective and efficient manufacturing and to make innovative methods of manufacturing more understandable to Executive agencies that are tasked with regulating such methods;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDCAF9CF5A364FE2B1979274FEC8D4E6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>examples of trainings facilitated by the entity that prepare workers for the biotechnology sector;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E47C105617941F785A381116C2E2D23"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any existing partnerships with educational or community partners that help facilitate workforce training for the biotechnology sector;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6237E010AC549F69E7AE950E5A43561"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of any experience participating in or leading biopharmaceutical manufacturing partnerships, including those with institutions of higher education, pharmaceutical manufacturers, non-profit organizations, and governmental agencies—</text> <clause id="HFB0EB3602DA545E5849A0841E40D0C98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to organize and conduct research and development aimed at—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84BB15B028EE46288BCDDD8CD3ED6541"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating and standardizing new and more effective technology;</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03B391E418B74FC0B6D3B00788C6A725"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing best practices and sharing knowledge about such technology;</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H087866F6F3E44224A3595C7DF0356199"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creating intellectual property; and </text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAEF7ED9E0CB46F18B00583302CB53E7"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintaining technological leadership in the United States;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H75E425AF97F344F38336F2AFBE52DC1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to support the deployment of innovative practices and infrastructure of biopharmaceutical manufacturing in the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="H315BBF4B64B54BFFBEA54866E9B94C3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to support developing a skilled workforce ready to use innovations in the biopharmaceutical manufacturing sector; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAD5E9A9363E4AD5B29DA706D5E8E8B7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of how the entity intends to utilize any funds authorized under this section to build or expand facilities and infrastructure to achieve any of the objectives described in subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99D70375CE854457B7BD2391B03E3320"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection Criteria</header><text>In selecting an applicant for a grant or other transaction agreement under paragraph (1), the Director shall consider the following:</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H226AF9F43AF340C8BE0273C672D5D3CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The potential of the applicant to establish a Center of Excellence that would achieve the objectives set forth in subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H013FBB7BAA3A4CC382CE9DED19B925DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The past performance of the applicant in biopharmaceutical manufacturing workforce development and the potential of the applicant to support workforce development activities in various regions throughout the United States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93E7493DA1214C68B24D337BFFF5BD6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the applicant proposes to leverage the activities of other biopharmaceutical manufacturing innovation, development, and scaling initiatives.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F3D650E25DC49A5AC84D8DCCB691695"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the proposed location for the Center of Excellence is proximate to other biomanufacturing infrastructure, training facilities, or industrial clusters.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3436AE70C67B494295A9A9D25B9D029B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The time the applicant estimates is needed for the Center of Excellence to be fully operational and to start delivering impact.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA46C545459D546FE9D37F9B4C710B340"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of co-investment committed by Federal, State, private, and other sources to establish the Center of Excellence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H074D9623DC2944A893BD25F56C1EC37F"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any additional criteria that the Director considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF37C8F526F8429BA4023A4350ED981D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reports</header> <paragraph id="H05AB62D9F6B54FCB94333A95F3119690"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which the Director awards to or enters into with an eligible entity a grant or other transaction agreement to establish the Center of Excellence under subsection (b)(1), the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing the progress on establishing the Center of Excellence, including—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H72005CCD45A444F1959F9FABE8B8DB66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the construction of facilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59846307D736472580DC93633C8C3136"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any activities, partnerships, and collaborations by the Center of Excellence; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97D7E54BA3EC4445847E4541E3B10AAF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other information regarding the formation of the Center of Excellence that the Director considers relevant. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H664859EF3F524039B921532872C9D075"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which operations at the Center of Excellence officially begin, the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H180F28798C454107A2A43CD0B74B3BA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the activities, partnerships, collaborations, and findings of the Center of Excellence; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2FFB6FE7895460A82D841EFEFC0B73F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other information regarding the Center of Excellence that the Director considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57727FDF054D4E97B20509423F4D3098"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date on which operations at the Center of Excellence officially begin, the Director shall submit to Congress a report describing—</text> <subparagraph id="HCF5FAEDA6AEE460B869A092D519F61CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities, partnerships, collaborations, and findings of the Center of Excellence; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F78BCA2229B42729C395FA01FC6CFB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other information regarding the Center of Excellence that the Director considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2EDF6B8527C4108B629ED53E6FD0568"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall make the reports required by paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) available to the public in an easily accessible electronic format on a website of the Federal Government that includes information on biotechnology.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98F9E71473A34A92A0E717CEDF29C219"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Intellectual Property</header><text>The Director shall ensure that, prior to commencing operations, the Center of Excellence, in consultation with similar existing institutions, such as Manufacturing USA institutes (as defined in section 34(d)), establishes intellectual property guidelines for research conducted within or in collaboration with the Center of Excellence.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE71C89E0F3224B2DB9EFD1977DD90083"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Director to carry out this section $120,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9045C37D7426492C955AC845E92C09D2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H90A770E9D1C74EA388B374503AE6FF38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biomanufacturing</header><text>The term <term>biomanufacturing</term> means the application of biotechnology to manufacturing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32B2DD1AE93F4F7BAEDC6A0E7ECD41E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biopharmaceutical</header><text>The term <term>biopharmaceutical</term> means a pharmaceutical drug product manufactured using, extracted from, or synthesized from living cells or biological organisms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB8B8956F62E44BD5B6060B37CDBB3B6D"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Biotechnology</header><text>The term <term>biotechnology</term> means the application of science or engineering, directly or indirectly, to—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC23B7ACFF25D4AC9960BB90942AC45A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a living organism;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3C4F8EE2A7C46C98A886F5813F22688"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a part or product of a living organism; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FFCA960E8D44067B7C5461A319F2603"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a modified form of subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C895EDD5E974389902F50CB110FAAAD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>Executive agency</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DC6FCF3BD074FC289D891998F617520"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given that term in section 105 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB04D32311F05430097124EC5312BB53C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the Executive Office of the President and the Office of the Vice President. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC89BFAB5C154F36BF0EE503F2920434"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

