<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA26251-43N-V9-N4J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4098 IS: Artificial Intelligence-Ready Data Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4098</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish standards and guidelines to make open Government data assets artificial intelligence-ready, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artificial Intelligence-Ready Data Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id7cbe7eaf779a420bad141fe0cd9ae72e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of standards and guidelines to make open Government data assets artificial intelligence-ready</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/271">15 U.S.C. 271 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce9831f109144fc0947a1655f0f611bf"><section id="id0dccf7d2a35843a88c9a866a2ebfe33c"><enum>37.</enum><header>Standards and guidelines to make open Government data assets artificial intelligence-ready</header><subsection id="id66c8207a06634063a6a6d5295e4b43c8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the head of any other Federal agency the Director considers appropriate, develop standards and guidelines to assist Federal agencies with making open Government data assets (as defined in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code) artificial intelligence-ready.</text></subsection><subsection id="id377430bb3ac1431081849b2a3652a20d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida033260ebfa04670a91b693470153402"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Adaptability and interoperability</header><text>In developing the standards and guidelines under subsection (a), the Director shall set baseline standards and guidelines for all Federal agencies that, to the greatest extent practicable, allow for the heads of the agencies to adapt and extend such standards and guidelines to meet the needs of agency-specific missions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1704233b45de4cb49c0cd3e79a6b3d60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The standards and guidelines required by subsection (a) shall—</text><subparagraph id="idf005da789e0546b8a972b5f45c486b04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommend improvements to the availability and utility of open Government data assets for the development of artificial intelligence (as defined in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>)) by private or public sector entities, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e31b39449c344aca5b2f656e5bc91c3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the training of artificial intelligence models or systems;</text></clause><clause id="id6110340bf06a402aad7b93031046c861"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>best practices for data quality, data stewardship, metadata, and documentation; and</text></clause><clause id="idd64e189cd40b42e4b3a442fcc0ddf517"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ways to manage intellectual property concerns when Federal data is combined with proprietary data;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2194feb5170b401884958fc2c631e6b7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify, or recommend methods for identifying, other data assets (as defined in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code) generated or maintained by Federal agencies that should be made available for the development of artificial intelligence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8767b101a42c46e3aac576956bbc6a6c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommend measurements for evaluating the effectiveness of Federal agency action pertaining to subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id52612633333e4e7d929c61bb272e580e"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial Intelligence-Ready Requirements for open government data assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standards and guidelines developed under subsection (a) shall require open Government data assets to be, to the greatest extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="id71bf250657894bedb5c6d44a00730adc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>artificial intelligence-ready, defined based on the needs of artificial intelligence developers and information provided by persons engaged with artificial intelligence that is received through the notice and comment procedure outlined in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40978127bdcb402a8a786ad190e47182"><enum>(B)</enum><text>available for download—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26064362d27f4e38a11f4740ce57bbe1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on a publicly accessible website or other convenient method;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a7d03508bf24ac4a4d5370798e12817"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by web-scraping; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2b729a2d51e64ae1abde82f091f222df"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by any other method the Director considers practicable and beneficial;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id407bdaac5a4941b8b8d0a2f6fefbf4a9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>accurate as of the date of the publication of the open Government data asset;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7ac897fc1bc41468a3ec8f27ad62b83"><enum>(D)</enum><text>human-readable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id91302e5ef3774fe484b0e5ef11e47d2c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in an open and machine-readable format, accompanied by publicly available software tools that can decode or process the data; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id600d6b4ca4404a04ad2183095c02e1b8"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">secure and protective of individual privacy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc76d6d1192aa4be98d6093fdb4b8960d"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Public notice and opportunity for comment</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7574104b00704ec1a8c40b6b50ee9a5a"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the standards and guidelines under subsection (a), and in considering revisions to the standards and guidelines under subsection (d), the Director shall—</text>
                            <subparagraph id="id4244b10254dd468094abfcce0e243753">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>publish in the Federal Register—</text> <clause id="id26876bec603947f985a3fcd1ecfc86d8"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>proposed standards and guidelines; and</text>
                                </clause>
                                <clause id="id9f265cc3107c448eb6bcb88d6ec2fc1d">
                                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>a request for feedback, including on the recommendations described in subsection (b)(2);</text>
                                </clause>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idd14c36360b8f4b11a1f0a996112cd278">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>provide the public with an opportunity to comment for a period of not less than 60 days;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="idc1a798a23c5946c3a8b32fd47a198d8d">
                                <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>ensure public comments are available for public inspection; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph id="ida780b181323b41bc8eee3495c7185dc5">
                                <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>demonstrate consideration of the public comments received under this paragraph in the development of the standards and guidelines under subsection (a) or the revision of the standards and guidelines under subsection (d).</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
                        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70a9965a6c2c4d7fb3269f75ade17993">
                            <enum>(2)</enum>
                            <header>Timeline for publication</header>
 <text>The Director shall publish—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69f2fe59f30646fba0506c5b2531b020"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the standards and guidelines developed under subsection (a) in the Federal Register not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section; and</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                            <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9d18eca159f43c991936cc54db6b00b">
                                <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>any revision to the standards and guidelines under subsection (d), or a notice that public comment had been considered and proposed revisions are not beneficial or necessary, in the Federal Register not later than 60 days after the Director has completed the review required by that subsection.</text>
                            </subparagraph>
                        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="idf3d2fb976a0c49bf967abe22ff10e4f4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Updates to the standards and guidelines</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the Director submits the standards and guidelines to the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy under subsection (e) and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Director shall consider, in accordance with the notice and comment procedures under subsection (c), revisions to the standards and guidelines required by subsection (a) to improve the utility of the standards and guidelines.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2b73ad321c3a4f71a777ddfcbf6912cc"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission to the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy</header><text>The Director shall submit the standards and guidelines developed under subsection (a), and any revision of the standards and guidelines under subsection (d), to the President for issuing requirements in accordance with section 701 of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" id="id4511348e3f8c43cbb8c4950ac0780f1d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Implementation of standards and guidelines to make open Government data assets artificial intelligence-ready</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6611">42 U.S.C. 6611 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="idD8FAC8958ADA4FFEB660941BD9A9DF3B" act-name=""><title id="id1D5FEB265B674B8FA78242332910EB46" style="OLC"><enum>VII</enum><header>Implementation of standards and guidelines to make open government data assets artificial intelligence-ready</header><section id="id769c4c7b369044c6b56e7d7d75ff94b4"><enum>701.</enum><header>Implementation of standards and guidelines by Federal agencies</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14f8ec71599948b0a249aaa31668b687"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving the standards and guidelines from the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology pursuant to section 37(e) of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act, the President, acting through the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall issue a requirement that the head of each Federal agency adopt such standards and guidelines.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f930f98c782408f80415eb60d849ce1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the President, acting through the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, issuing a requirement to the head of a Federal agency under subsection (a), the head of such agency shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0a51c83962054283abc951cca42ee76b"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adopt and adhere to the standards and guidelines issued by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddaca49110ddb43e0ad82a7b2e1123c46"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that any agency-specific adaptations of the standards and guidelines remain interoperable with the data systems of other Federal agencies to support interagency collaboration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58af5127f5764edfa0072504aa700f79"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that major information technology and high-performance computing acquisitions explicitly account for any requirement contained in the standards and guidelines.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id35c7cdd50f594dbebad25b3cd488eab4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence and machine learning readiness of national oceanic and atmospheric administration data assets for operational forecasting</header><subsection id="id249f6a547397497384f7e012f1ec5a51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>After the adoption by the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere (in this section referred to as the <quote>Under Secretary</quote>) of the standards and guidelines described in section 701 of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976, as added by section 3, the Under Secretary shall ensure the data assets of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administration</quote>) support the integration of artificial intelligence and machine learning into the operational forecasting activities of the Administration, specifically for—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2079987665ea4bbab77bf55175a45f3d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>model analyses, forecasts, and reanalyses;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id141753c09df541c6a4c0db1e285eee4d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in-situ and conventional observations;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a16fb02acd4421ca951d2a5a03d9247"><enum>(3)</enum><text>satellite datasets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idedccfb71c5a4482d9eaa236a340b0321"><enum>(4)</enum><text>environmental observations that are critical for forecasting.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id95425a949b8b4d3cacb9bf61e4e48482"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual briefings</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of adoption described in subsection (a), and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Under Secretary shall brief the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives on the progress made by the Under Secretary in implementing subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

