<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0795BD82ADFE47F48627C5B8D3FDA61A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7458 IH: Domestic Opportunities for Resource Exploration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7458</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260210">February 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify notice requirements for mineral exploration activities on certain public lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6066E5FE476D4D209EA8AD389A569133" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0C1C0B0C8B8A46A18184C13A6CF34017" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Domestic Opportunities for Resource Exploration Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Domestic ORE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3869BD0DB26E45B0B7428B12D1F7780B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notice for mineral exploration activities with limited surface disturbance</header> <subsection id="HD2923E3F55044B7EB744C58750A1E743"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 days before commencing an exploration activity with a surface disturbance of not more than 25 acres of public lands, the operator of such exploration activity shall submit to the Secretary concerned a notice of such exploration activity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9B46DA402A6C4B80A290B47F1104B696"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>A notice submitted under subsection (a) shall include such information the Secretary concerned may require, which may include information described in section 3809.301 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HAA11355135684622BD045F47104D1C02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the Secretary concerned receives a notice of an exploration activity submitted under subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H10392CAB604940D2A5FF3E03FA50B83A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allow the exploration activity to proceed if—</text> <subparagraph id="H772F20D6EB564FBF844AE3DEA79FC125"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the surface disturbance of such exploration activity will not be more than 25 acres of public lands;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19ABCE39DE42441FA3A869EFD7264F7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary concerned determines that the notice includes the information required under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF0796CA4CB240D98B77BCEEF33434A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the operator provides financial assurance that the Secretary concerned determines is adequate; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F543861350045CCBA4830A736666290"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the operator that information is missing from the notice and specify any information that is required to be included in the notice under subsection (b).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59439930E9E344EC89E8AC23DC1EF3D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3CDAD7D730064C65A604E5D56CE850E9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Casual use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>casual use</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3809.5 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7DF357D30A140E0B21B2B2EEAF58628"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exploration activity</header><text>The term <term>exploration activity</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E78A3B2A7E0450AB1CFE6A63B516532"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means creating a surface disturbance greater than casual use that includes sampling, drilling, or developing surface or underground workings to evaluate the type, extent, quantity, or quality of minerals present;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF6D9EC53D514A1F883A8A003BB2293B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes constructing drill roads and drill pads, drilling, trenching, excavating test pits, and conducting geotechnical tests and geophysical surveys; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4E78F67BCC3C4356B4C16CB88BD3966B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include an activity in which material is extracted for commercial use or sale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7326B386C9DB484BAD7930A84AC85D16" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mineral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mineral</term> means any mineral of a kind that is locatable under the Act of May 10, 1872 (Chapter 152; 17 Stat. 91).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7AF24DC24B047F386F1A87E2FD0506B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Operator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>operator</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3809.5 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0D31A80D691493AA66C45EFD08EC9F8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Public land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>public land</quote> means land owned by the United States that is open to location under the Act of May 10, 1872 (Chapter 152; 17 Stat. 91).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF19E483875504B0CAECE990FCE2DF48B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H1B2ABFAF76524113AA425920594FCDB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to land administered by the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of the Interior; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD81E0F3EDEF64E10B611D686D6109556"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to National Forest System land, the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

