<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT25A04-3NV-YP-RTP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3287 IS: Fair Allocation of Interstate Rates Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3287</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the allocation of costs for certain electric transmission facilities to consumers in a State the public officials of which did not expressly consent to the transmission facility, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HFA3691379AD1416AB7EC58E6890FC0B6"><section section-type="section-one" id="H9FF073E6821C499CAB6966717539F6DF"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Allocation of Interstate Rates Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9C1419170FA0460E90839A310071A214"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rates and charges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 205 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824d">16 U.S.C. 824d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99DC9A37379E40FCA7092976D9BE99D6"><subsection id="H143AC60E539A4268BDD29F0E3E502F73"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prohibition on allocation of certain costs</header><paragraph id="id5e522328cb8641388f46e87f1565a538"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id82edd62ebab04211bb6ea3f78a11c79a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered policy</header><text>The term <term>covered policy</term> means a policy of a State, including any policy of a local political entity of a State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7c9b61602e7f477d890b55caa2977d48"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered transmission facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered transmission facility</term> means any facility, line, equipment, or system used for the transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce that is planned, constructed, or operated in whole or in part to implement a covered policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7069153AC76744579A3B96605A279D23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (3), a transmission provider providing electric service to consumers in 2 or more States may not allocate costs for a covered transmission facility to a consumer served by that transmission provider if—</text><subparagraph id="H2860360AED1C457CB425C3105D46E05B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the basis for construction or implementation of the covered transmission facility is, in whole or in part, to implement a covered policy of a State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4B403DDAA6D49B699C75A06523CB3E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the consumer is not a resident of the State the covered policy of which is the basis for constructing or implementing the covered transmission facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FC3D0653793484580ED686A2895A773"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>A transmission provider providing electric service to consumers in 2 or more States may allocate costs for a covered transmission facility to a consumer described in paragraph (2)(B) if the State in which that consumer is a resident, or a designated public official of that State, expressly consents to such allocation of costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC83CFC9EEF6407286292673D188F9D9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Presumptions</header><text>It shall be presumed that—</text><subparagraph id="H157DF50B6D944828833CF6F5F98FF7A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the benefits of a covered transmission facility accrue solely to the cost causers of that covered transmission facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B148D4971D94A8EBA98877AC53695EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any consumer who is a resident of a State that implements a covered policy that is, in whole or in part, the basis for constructing or implementing a covered transmission facility is a cost causer for purposes of subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC35C97063E343569F00355EF1D0ACF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any consumer that does not reside in the State described in subparagraph (B) is not a cost causer for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8693E44F39D04D3283A66EB0331F0BB2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Commission shall issue such rules and regulations as are necessary to implement this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

