<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25980-J06-0W-6RX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3361 IS: No Palaces Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3361</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 40, United States Code, to require approval by the National Capital Planning Commission of certain improvements to the White House or the grounds of the White House, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="iddf2d034436894019a6465d48e952f514" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Palaces Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf8eb9775e249459eaebeefe8f68b60d8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to the White House or the grounds of the White House</header><subsection id="idf3298c6d996140b2965db55609925147"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consultation between agencies and Commission</header><text>Section 8722(b)(1) of title 40, United States Code, is amended, in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>, before initiating any demolition activities with respect to an existing structure,</quote> before <quote>or before making a commitment</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb8c832d02e914273afe116b2297f3344"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modifications to the White House</header><text>Section 8722 of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideac56440ce9e4031bc8881ec1453c1ba"><subsection id="id520821f013994d90909a15a648024179"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Approval of improvements to the White House or grounds of the White House</header><paragraph id="ide366f4c317424900bfa8ca2d4b2302b8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approval of National Capital Planning Commission required; joint resolution of disapproval</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87041a7b6d4b40a1aaa1957ebfc6deed"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf82834a95e2942cb8b31c43d022f5176"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consideration period</header><text>The term <quote>consideration period</quote> means the 60-day period that begins on the date on which the National Capital Planning Commission approves the proposed improvement under subparagraph (B)(i)(II) (excluding days either House of Congress is adjourned for more than 3 days during a session of Congress).</text></clause><clause id="idd4521c2bc17546e1b0da641ddfece640"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><text>The term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution that is introduced during the consideration period, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the proposed improvement approved by the National Capital Planning Commission on ____.</quote>, the blank space being filled in with the date on which the National Capital Planning Commission approves the proposed improvement under subparagraph (B)(i)(II).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8afea63628c04a15ae3e8ebb9ca92526"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A building or site improvement to the White House or the grounds of the White House may not be carried out unless—</text><clause id="id78e9c10418bf467898c3fdf8176ae341"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Executive Office of the President, or the head of any Federal agency acting on behalf of the Executive Office of the President—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc49b01989c24e51aee6f34f85472c63"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completes the concept review (as described in the Submission Guidelines of the National Capital Planning Commission) with respect to the proposed improvement; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72605abc5bec42548e9c14b3b31ce358"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">obtains the approval of the National Capital Planning Commission with respect to the proposed improvement; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idc2353a5e141a41a2b458057859052029"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a joint resolution of disapproval is not enacted into law in accordance with subparagraph (B) on or before the date of the end of the consideration period.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63e655af9a3a40c78b405e57b8297037"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Procedures for consideration of joint resolutions of disapproval</header><clause id="id2d5947c048ac48e292935ef2bbe5a593"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>A joint resolution of disapproval shall be referred to the committees in each House of Congress with jurisdiction.</text></clause><clause id="id7d7e82ad6f8b4d57b89ef1bd0c9bc01b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Senate procedure</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id576cede002dc4424b066440a067b8972"><enum>(I)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the committee of the Senate to which a joint resolution of disapproval is referred has not reported the joint resolution of disapproval (or an identical joint resolution of disapproval) by the date that is 20 days after the date on which the National Capital Planning Commission approves the proposed improvement under subparagraph (B)(i)(II)—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1416ed04ef074e8683a349dfaaa44c22"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the committee may be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution of disapproval on a petition supported in writing by 30 Members of the Senate; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d5cda72f00a46f7bfd804f1b7133d4c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the joint resolution of disapproval shall be placed on the calendar.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idd879bc2149e74d0c8882df954f155bb0"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Motion to proceed</header><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63c0de6bb2f24f0ba83dc4a350e18f5d"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the committee of the Senate to which a joint resolution of disapproval is referred has reported, or is discharged from further consideration of, the joint resolution of disapproval—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae3abcef52f649d9885c341776fbd36c"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) for a motion to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution of disapproval; and</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea3fdd00ff5844948643eeb05f4b6033"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all points of order against the joint resolution of disapproval (and against consideration of the joint resolution of disapproval) are waived.</text></subitem></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea075fb346da4d6fb5705267689871d4"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A motion to proceed under this subclause is not subject to—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id18070a5a3ee74f23924e6c4f8918edd2"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amendment;</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf6a07c4bb984b0b8b6e822153f31865"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a motion to postpone; or</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75c4cccea04740c5956056b90df9cbf3"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business.</text></subitem></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb9d43ddc9cb4325845351b8606d08ba"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Motion to reconsider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A motion to reconsider the vote by which a motion to proceed under this subclause is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20a3c9da269a412f9edc4da9d16214f0"><enum>(dd)</enum><header>Motion agreed to</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a motion to proceed under this subclause is agreed to, the joint resolution of disapproval shall remain the unfinished business of the Senate until the joint resolution of disapproval is disposed of.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idc900183141324f7198b3b704577d64e0"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Debate</header><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6cb782508728403db31455d43314b64a"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Time limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Debate in the Senate on the joint resolution of disapproval and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection with the joint resolution of disapproval shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, to be equally divided between Senators favoring and Senators opposing the joint resolution of disapproval.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb778e25316964988abbcc896e2cca9d3"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Motion to limit debate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A motion in the Senate to further limit debate on the joint resolution of disapproval is in order and not debatable.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b311ec469b24acc87af34782d037f2e"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Not in order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Senate, an amendment to, a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution of disapproval is not in order.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id573ebbaa47a94f84b1f6bfea5157a267"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Vote on final passage</header><text>In the Senate, immediately following the conclusion of the debate on a joint resolution of disapproval, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate, there shall be a vote on final passage of the joint resolution of disapproval.</text></subclause><subclause id="id8fa01d385dd44c55a7cbba62d93f4709"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate to the procedure relating to a joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text></subclause><subclause id="id40608da1acb54560ab1bbe44260b3493" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In the Senate, the procedures described in subclauses (I) through (V) shall not apply to the consideration of a joint resolution of disapproval after the expiration of the consideration period.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf2bba3466f0a4a0bae238a76ea107934"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Consideration of joint resolution of disapproval received from other House</header><text>If, before the passage by 1 House of a joint resolution of disapproval of that House, that House receives from the other House a joint resolution of disapproval—</text><subclause id="idd914f63f6b6e41b188467c898b4614a4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the joint resolution of disapproval of the other House shall not be referred to a committee; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id9b9673a8e9974ed88dde84a3fdc0d6dd"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with respect to the House receiving the joint resolution of disapproval—</text><item id="id508e14c2f9664f999606bb3f67e2e739"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the procedure in that House shall be the same as if no joint resolution of disapproval had been received from the other House; but</text></item><item id="idd3b211cdc7714c1abc94fc43dfee9d74"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the vote on final passage shall be on the joint resolution of disapproval of the other House.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id9f2c1c207d7c4fe9baa694d5d5d58d93"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rules of House of representatives and senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subparagraph is enacted by Congress—</text><subclause id="id134577e747e848bca557488fd737ffc9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution of disapproval, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that this subparagraph is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id7f2e258dce23444f81e2cf45c4551d62"><enum>(II)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f963b9f2d3148d7874fde03ae4dba94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8fb451d4eaa46d3a42f100a2df62cd6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Private funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No private funds may be used to carry out an improvement described in paragraph (1)(B) unless authorized by Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ff98c9ecbc04d8280dd116fd59c07ca"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any use of Federal funds to carry out an improvement described in paragraph (1)(B) shall comply with the requirements of section 1301 of title 31.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idb41f3447e7f24c3da1d8697e5e6103d9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id167aee7f20664184904803eb9c957784"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, any member of the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, the Commission of Fine Arts, any member of the Commission of Fine Arts, the National Capital Planning Commission, any member of the National Capital Planning Commission, either House of Congress, or a Member of either House of Congress may bring a civil action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia before a 3-judge panel alleging a violation of this Act (including an amendment made by this Act) for injunctive relief.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id65f85bc652274ce1a1817c43c066fa5c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>Any party to a civil action brought under paragraph (1) may appeal to the Supreme Court of the United States any order granting or denying a permanent injunction pursuant to this Act (including an amendment made by this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3134662c6c4545de8137a1cd284244e2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expedited procedures</header><subparagraph id="id90fb2e05e26649f9a160e15a1f312988"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Expeditious hearing</header><text>The United States District Court for the District of Columbia and the Supreme Court, if applicable, shall expedite the consideration of any civil action brought under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02f9f1df4ce142bda0d2bad64aa1313e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the United States District Court for the District of Columbia or the Supreme Court, if applicable, shall give any civil action brought under this subsection priority on the docket of the applicable court.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2e046297d4cf4a80940d5162c6cd2809"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id94ee4b053a6b4280805308199f928351"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States District Court for the District of Columbia shall issue a decision with respect to any civil action brought under this subsection not later than 30 days after the date on which the complaint is filed.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcbb0ad4abeab4027aa92c829a8cd3cfe"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Filing notice of appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notice of appeal of any order, whether interlocutory or final, entered in any civil action brought under this subsection, shall be filed not later than 10 days after the date of entry of the order.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c11f7817d68455b93473dc544b43a73"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Hearing of appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The hearing of an appeal described in clause (ii) shall be held not later than 45 days after the date of the notice of appeal.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd66c859b59194ac8bc7832fb5cc79322"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Decision on appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A decision in an appeal described in clause (ii) shall be issued not later than 90 days after the date of the notice of appeal.</text></clause><clause id="idfe6b18431fc343dba61bc7a27584ae1e"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Judicial discretion</header><text>The United States District Court for the District of Columbia or the Supreme Court, if applicable, may modify the schedules and limitations described in clauses (i) through (iv) in a particular civil action, based on a specific finding that the ends of justice that would be served by making such a modification would outweigh the best interest of the public in having the civil action resolved expeditiously.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

