<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H040F83A2614B48D7BB424269866CCB32" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7240 IH: Military ADS–B Out Loophole Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to
      revise regulations relating to ADS-B Out transmission exceptions, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC6E9E1C83F1745FA88F04600F46F95BC" style="OLC"><section id="H0D38470F4B01451DBF1454E95B2F8EB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military ADS–B Out Loophole Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H252D18AD043243068232FF1C8728C448"><enum>2.</enum><header>Revision to exception for ADS–B Out transmission</header><subsection id="H53A588452EEA4D96BA57B5BF374A51E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>ADS–B Out reforms</header><paragraph id="H5D8E064BFD5C43EC92BBF2CE87ADBA5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date of enactment of this section, in applying section 91.225(f)(1) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, the term <term>sensitive government mission</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HBDDA71DC84EF4BB7907AE09ABBAEC6D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be narrowly construed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F73C276C304A59991BC521458641A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be limited to the portion of the flight during which sensitive activities are carried out.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1EC7FBA78564627BB7FD1A99DB7A71D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking and administrative action</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BF91C53AA784F92AE4CBB054FA22E65"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEEA58487DE894AD1A2C6523D94F942BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue or revise regulations to update section 91.225(f) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, to comply with the requirements of this section; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21A2F674D4284DCE8CA94485502616CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise any memorandum of agreement between the FAA and any other Federal, State, local, or Tribal agency to conform with the revised regulations described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB6063A975354D23BFE1B2770F192DE0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>If the Administrator fails to issue or revise regulations pursuant to subparagraph (A) or revise any memorandum of agreement between the FAA and any other agency pursuant to such subparagraph, the Administrator shall, within 30 days, submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the status of such regulations, including the reasons that the Administrator has failed to issue or revise such regulations within the period required under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B4D751502464AB9841A1810CB80B4A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO review and report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="H4A9B1D184BD64448956FBAB0A3A4E42F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the utilization of exceptions under section 91.225(f) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), as revised under subsection (a), to determine—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC046C74E29F74C35903F3213533C9040"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the Department of Defense and other relevant Federal agencies or other applicable operators have utilized such exceptions in accordance with relevant laws and regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1BB353B9170F467B82930025DBA58ECF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent of such utilization;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H074697A1BA8B40FA8FFFF4860F2B85B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compare the utilization of exceptions specified in such section 91.225(f) before and after the issuance of revised regulations under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F0440666A7E415F885E21FDD8C63FA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to the Administrator and the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the findings of the review conducted under paragraph (1) and the comparison conducted under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15481737F87C4841906C49AC8DDB6452"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>FAA review of non-Compliant operators</header> <text>Upon submission of the report under subsection (b)(3), the Administrator shall—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="HE59D39F0365E4C309769BC8A68309CA8">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether any Federal agency or other applicable operator that has been found to have not utilized the exceptions under section 91.225(f) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), as revised under subsection (a), in accordance with relevant laws and regulations shall be permitted to continue to utilize such exceptions; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="H3D0DA94272AD473686A2782A3A3E25AC">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after the date on which the Comptroller General submits the report under subsection (b)(3), brief the appropriate committees of Congress on such determination.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="H4CCFAB2C99EE4A4CBF4DE7E886CED4A3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H016492B4B48B489589A302812EB57513"><enum>(1)</enum><header>To the Administrator</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, each Federal, State, local, and Tribal agency that performs sensitive government missions as described in section 91.225(f)(1) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), as revised under subsection (a), shall submit to the Administrator a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H4D565D9E42C24B6E9F3B6A39E9598C2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an attestation that such operations are regularly transmitting ADS–B Out and are conducted with proper consideration to aviation safety; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF267AA2612834A789D947FCA8B1EBAEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a list of operations delineated by flight in which the ADS–B Out equipment is not in transmit mode because the aircraft was performing a sensitive government mission, including the airport, airspace location, date, time, duration, and mission type of each such operation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H76903A74F2CA4C19AA6E4F96E20B6DF9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>To Congress</header><subparagraph id="HC2FD092C85BA49928DE9984B0BFE2098"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, and biannually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the frequency and nature of the ADS–B Out exceptions granted to Federal, State, local, and Tribal agencies under section 91.225(f)(1) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), as revised under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB8130DB77954F1CB9F1E231B5858D00"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The report submitted under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E36CFA1E8804AB2B32107D22C6AC682"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include—</text><subclause id="HACFC3B5D97F84DECBC2ACEC8ABD361E2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>aggregated data on the operations in which ADS–B Out equipment is not in transmit mode by each agency described in paragraph (1); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDF6532BF55EF4BCA8D2483DB9568E08C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a determination from the Administrator as to whether each operation described in paragraph (1)(B) jeopardizes aviation safety; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12BA51D0D72D4657ABE1D51A14A29822"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include a classified annex.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3FA739D8AD9459F97ADDB1D2AAA15AB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special notification</header><text>If an agency described in paragraph (1) operates a flight using an exception granted under section 91.225(f)(1) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), as revised under subsection (a), 5 or more times in a calendar month, or fails to provide to the Administrator the attestation required under paragraph (1)(A), the Administrator shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of such use within 14 days of being notified of such use. For the purposes of this subparagraph, a flight shall be interpreted as the period beginning when an aircraft moves under its own power for the purpose of flight and ending when the aircraft lands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C957E4CD11F4C05B2B1C9339E348429"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual Inspector General audits</header><paragraph id="HABF33F85B64B4326A56B924551BC9645"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this section, the inspector general of the Department of Transportation shall conduct an annual audit of FAA oversight of all operations that utilize an exception under section 91.225(f)(1) of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation), as revised under subsection (a), including Federal agency operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD4453DFC3DD40C5ACDB7CB001DFB8E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In conducting an audit under paragraph (1), the inspector general shall assess the efficacy of FAA oversight related to the following:</text><subparagraph id="HABDB0971B3154145AB9A818B4F6A983F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Ensuring exceptions under such section 91.225(f)(1) (or any successor regulation) are strictly utilized by operators in accordance with relevant laws and regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4F839D33F1C4432852EAF7C2565D5D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identifying and engaging with any operator not in compliance with relevant laws and regulations relating to exceptions under such section 91.225(f)(1) (or any successor regulation).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8428E3732854FD4A5D01E9FF261799F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other factor determined appropriate by the inspector general.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74C50F6D4D3148D0BBB921DFB5D8704B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Briefings to Congress</header><text>The inspector general shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on an annual basis after the completion of each annual audit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEDC0F37D9442472A9BF5F3832C15FF16" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0A7475103D984A04A9ADBE02EEB2E7B6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H349D05B735484731AE3150E24AFCDF7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ADS–B Out</header><text>The term <term>ADS–B Out</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H1B444C61E9324D3EBF5A7CE60C6733C1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has the meaning given such term in section 91.227 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43821B7F52A143B8B290DDA8DF571D6C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">broadcasts information from the aircraft in accordance with sections 91.225 and 91.227 of such title (or any successor regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B774DE483C640839739803208DD2670"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H87D7ACDC667044ADBB0AD3B34CDC5F06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1A7E3656B5E4F5F9335F85402750828"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD943D3A188E44053B385A60E2BB48277"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DA303A2264E4800A21AFD0BDF52512C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF7B7068E54A4B9786749C245B253C59"><enum>(4)</enum><header>FAA</header><text>The term <term>FAA</term> means the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

