<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H06832764B4AB4540A20804CB933F5D1C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6595 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to improve the availability of care for veterans at facilities of the Department of Defense.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to improve the availability of care for veterans at facilities of the Department of Defense.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD2CCAF73BE944AB6B0E7E1495086A225" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1326491D862A473A9F4ED3E7FD064BB0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Improvement of availability of care for veterans from facilities and providers of the Department of Defense</header> 
<subsection id="HA1108C0168AF434CBE6E8E7E4C3D98F8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Action plans</header> 
<paragraph id="HD963EE4897F546B79BB98B594386EB22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pursuant to the authorities under section 8111 of title 38, United States Code, and section 1104 of title 10, United States Code, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall develop and implement action plans at covered facilities—</text> <subparagraph id="H418C58A95C7A4BDE97ADE75A93BB331E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to strengthen sharing of resources between the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs under existing statutory authority;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H586F84DA54DA4A0CAF2138029B16C5F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve communication between the Department of Veterans Affairs and pertinent command and director leadership of military medical treatment facilities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD302FE07B0304928B9589EF030C02719"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to increase utilization of military medical treatment facilities with excess capacity or space;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE6A69185BD4449C9249689E174BCFF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to increase case volume and complexity for graduate professional and other medical education programs of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8BB10900FD464339A76A2133F6C1A3BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to increase access to care for enrolled veterans in areas in which a military medical treatment facility is located that is identified by the Secretary of Defense as having excess capacity or space.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEBD48D6192746B08901214A63B97288"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The action plans required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H24559160A01346B982B1D3F638C6D9F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Cross-credentialing and privileging of health care providers to jointly care for enrolled veterans in medical facilities of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0A8B71A757E64F48B7AC123B3B396C5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Expedited access to installations of the Department of Defense for staff of the Department of Veterans Affairs and enrolled veterans.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H45CDACF069AC43FE87189C4444DC19E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The designation of a coordinator within each covered facility to serve as a liaison between the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs and to lead the implementation of such action plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC4936D79A77B4500B16169AB6D770CCC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A mechanism for monitoring the effectiveness of such action plan on an ongoing basis, to include establishing relevant performance goals and collecting data to assess progress towards those goals.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8191C90DAF4B41E4A3A5B33E35E974FF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Prioritized integration of relevant information technology and other systems or processes to enable seamless information sharing, medical records referrals and ancillary orders and results, payment methodologies and billing processes, and workload attribution when personnel of the Department of Veterans Affairs provide services at facilities of the Department of Defense or when personnel of the Department of Defense provide services at facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0971D5E755A4E0A820068E0A9D9315F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An oversight and accountability plan for the handling of adverse medical events and complaints from patients or staff, including a requirement to track any significant adverse medical events and provide information on such events in the briefing required under subsection (f).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE903DEAA32AE4247B41D61B94BC93CC3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other matter that the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs consider appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H95918B0BFD4345F58FCBBDF0F2059C1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval of action plans</header><text>Before any action plan required under subsection (a) with respect to a covered facility shall be considered complete and submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress pursuant to subsection (e), the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that approval for the action plan is obtained from—</text> <paragraph id="HDEE0A226A9EB421BA1459EAFD9443481"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the co-chairs of the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee established under section 320 of title 38, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14342B95F38E4BBDAEC2D924C20F09A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the local installation commander for the covered facility of the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA64BEC05A9F7449D8D690B60641FC353"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the director of the relevant medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs with respect to any covered facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5808C5BC670348499ECF9BB052C1E326"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements relating to sharing agreements</header> 
<paragraph id="H4B73491740E94D5FA34520ED2F836DEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Lead coordinator</header><text>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that there is a lead coordinator at each facility of the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs, as the case may be, with respect to which there is a sharing agreement in place.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD48149F6ABE1436886896BFF7CA57C2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List of agreements</header><text>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall maintain on a publicly available website a list of the sharing agreements in place between the medical facilities of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEA9587978DBE4033A46F1D3D4E845413"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Patient safety, complaints, and accountability</header> 
<paragraph id="H8BD4ACE3FDA84F40960EACAC67A68514"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secure complaint process</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBC4023740A74FC3B6C285FB87CD74CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a secure mechanism for enrolled veterans to report concerns regarding care received under an action plan required under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF050A6C5B73D4AC68E4B8329DD258E17"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements of mechanism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mechanism established under subparagraph (A) shall protect confidentiality, prohibit retaliation, and ensure transmission of each complaint to both the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEB232AAD89643C08DC91FFC270A6731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Documentation and review</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H868A4319FA4641EAA36855C369FF2B3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall maintain records of all complaints, adverse events, and safety incidents involving patients or staff pursuant to the action plans required by subsection (a).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0599A20A4DF94F2FB026B6DEF8C535BC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The records maintained under subparagraph (A) shall be jointly reviewed on a quarterly basis by designated officials of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9ABBFB9769643ED8BF16DB5E2F6658B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification and investigation</header><text>Any allegation of abuse, neglect, or misconduct involving personnel of the Department of Defense in the treatment of a veteran under an action plan shall be promptly referred by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Defense, and the commander or medical center director, as applicable, of the facility concerned to the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FBCFEB93C924191B06E9FBA5C87E455"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Interim protective measures</header><text>Pending resolution of any investigation relating to conduct under an action plan, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may suspend referrals of veterans to the provider or facility concerned.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0347208F5A7345B28470D83F33960AF1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days following the completion of the action plans required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit such plans to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3348A6619FC24FA68342F91E24E077E6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual joint briefings on action plans</header><text>Not later than one year after submitting the action plans to the appropriate committees of Congress pursuant to subsection (e), the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall provide to the appropriate committees of Congress a briefing containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC86D34079CB34930A1693D71D00C91FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a status update on the progress of implementing the action plans required under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H121A22CC221C4C93924E8167B8F8792C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for developing subsequent action plans for each facility with respect to which there is a sharing agreement in place;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5042FBEF7604E6997D548313C6B9557"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of patients served pursuant to the action plans, broken down by facility and service type;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02994806E3614B70BAE55B432F9190C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of health care providers who were cross-credentialed or privileged to jointly care for beneficiaries in medical facilities of the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs pursuant to the action plans, broken down by facility and service type;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H952C2E2B0F5F4A51AB728FBC1F315983"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the costs incurred and reimbursed between the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs pursuant to the action plans, including an accounting of the use of the DOD–VA Health Care Sharing Incentive Fund established under section 8111(d)(2) of title 38, United States Code, if applicable;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0360C1E3E88B4404AF4216AE788AFFD7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a summary of the effectiveness of the mechanisms developed pursuant to the action plans related to oversight, accountability, data-gathering, and performance goals as well as any recommendations for improving such mechanisms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA87D19661628440C960BAC4021538885"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a summary of any patient safety incidents or complaints and associated resolutions as well as any recommendations for improving the patient safety and complaint resolution process under the actions plans; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89B063CC98A94C3A9F8471EADF54110C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a summary of the integration of information technology and other systems pursuant to the action plans as well as barriers to further integration and recommendations for improving such integration.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H086F4D1194744583875188D11506C6D0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to allow the Department of Defense or the Department of Veterans Affairs to require a veteran to seek care at a facility of the Department of Defense or to allow military medical treatment facilities to be used as a facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs for purposes of determining eligibility of veterans for care from a non-Department of Veterans Affairs provider under the eligibility access standards developed under section 1703B of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBC59E43A87DE40A8BA03FEB68B7488E5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on September 30, 2028.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD97D63C018704354ACF8C26EBAB946A8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H95EABF2DFB104646882545924E5DA752"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC8782AAEB36F4835886C964385BE63A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE85BC7F5460B4340BE25D665FFBA6980"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H450B586BD07A453DB30F24084450288C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H68FED481200B4985AEDFC9D5DFFDBB45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a military medical treatment facility (as such term is defined in section 1073c of title 10, United States Code); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA6CC07BBC8C4117A0FC9E21CE92FEF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a medical facility of the Department of Veterans Affairs described in section 8101(3) of title 38, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C58893048AD4E7CA133287782F14F41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>enrolled veteran</term> means a veteran enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs established and operated under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD14D2BA6B3274A7B8825E4A5E835C0FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>sharing agreement</term> means an agreement for the sharing of health-care resources between the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 1104 of title 10, United States Code, or section 8111 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1120A62D80C42ED96CA690EF9A3F52A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body></bill>


