<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26531-95S-WY-9VM"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 729 ATS: Recognizing and honoring Meriwether Lewis and William Clark, and the Corps of Discovery, for their expedition to explore the Louisiana Purchase.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing and honoring Meriwether Lewis and William Clark, and the Corps of Discovery, for their expedition to explore the Louisiana Purchase.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 14, 1804, Captain Meriwether Lewis, Captain William Clark, and the Corps of Discovery departed from St. Louis, Missouri, embarking on a journey that would span more than 8,000 miles across the American continent;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas May 14, 2026, marks the 222nd anniversary of the departure of the Corps of Discovery from the St. Louis region to explore the vast territory acquired through the Louisiana Purchase;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the expedition endured extreme hardship, including harsh weather, dangerous terrain, disease, hunger, and isolation, while displaying extraordinary resilience and determination;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Corps of Discovery produced invaluable maps, scientific observations, and geographic records that deepened the country's understanding of the American frontier and laid the groundwork for future settlement, commerce, and development;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the expedition strengthened the sovereignty and strategic position of the United States in North America during a pivotal period in the early history of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Lewis and Clark Expedition stands as a lasting symbol of the American spirit of exploration, courage, and national ambition;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas generations of Americans have continued to draw inspiration from the perseverance and vision demonstrated by the Corps of Discovery;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as the United States commemorates the 250th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence, the Lewis and Clark Expedition reminds Americans that the Founding generation passed to posterity not only a set of principles, but a country to be explored, strengthened, defended, and passed on; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 222nd anniversary of the expedition’s departure provides an opportunity to reflect upon the character, sacrifice, faith, courage, and determination that helped build the United States into a great nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf5e146db798240449b1e86986e93aad6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the enduring legacy of the Lewis and Clark Expedition and recognizes its profound importance to the history, development, and identity of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b7eb5bd64fc4f8b981e5247e03240cc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the extraordinary courage, endurance, and patriotism of Meriwether Lewis, William Clark, and the Corps of Discovery on the anniversary of the launch of their historic expedition from St. Louis, Missouri;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb115d6c22d31437c893a1fe7e9f15196"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the Lewis and Clark Expedition as one of the greatest feats of exploration and national achievement in the history of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd349f8635017463790df465e745ced5f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commemorates the vision of President Thomas Jefferson in commissioning the expedition following the Louisiana Purchase, which doubled the size of the United States and helped secure the continental future of the United States by executing the principles of <quote>manifest destiny</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2679f7b2584f4125bd3d1076a15964b6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acknowledges the indispensable contributions of every member of the Corps of Discovery, including the assistance provided by Sacagawea, York, and other members, which aided the expedition along its journey;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id86c42a1b427d4229838b61aaf46e21d3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recognizes that the expedition helped establish the geographic, commercial, and strategic foundations for the expansion of the United States from the Mississippi River to the Pacific Ocean;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id207a43b82c87417eb0ad899e0f548649"><enum>(7)</enum><text>celebrates the enduring connection between the Lewis and Clark Expedition and the State of Missouri, the State from which the Corps of Discovery embarked into the western frontier;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ae45ed3f4bd413baa8aa5e5cf19ffff"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recognizes that the spirit, self-reliance, perseverance, faith, courage, scientific curiosity, and confidence in the promise of the United States displayed through the expeditious remains central to the character, heritage, and soul of the country; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf92a34e9f8ba4610b4813d07b89b966f"><enum>(9)</enum><text>encourages all Americans to study and reflect upon the legacy of the Lewis and Clark Expedition and its lasting significance in the history of the United States.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

