<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD0ADC24D3A34543B3BDF1F18C3AE02B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7606 IH: Powering Productivity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7606</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260220">February 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To study and accelerate the more productive use of energy resources within the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFE5ED8AC47C141EBABD04284A7D8014B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5D5E4BD7BD164A0E809EAB4863560A26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Powering Productivity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H336D82BB177649B5AC69CED2995E83F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to improve the energy performance, transparency, and decision-making of the United States by modernizing how the United States measures and accounts for energy productivity and related impacts.</text></section> 
<section id="H692B3D48BA54400CB14053247F62A389"><enum>3.</enum><header>Energy productivity assessments</header> 
<subsection id="H43BBB3096C914462BEBDFA2EE81DDAA3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National energy productivity baseline</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Task Force, shall publish a comprehensive baseline assessment of energy productivity in the United States, which shall, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph id="H731CB56479D841E1B4DD733AB1EE1969"><enum>(1)</enum><text>define a framework and methodology for measuring energy productivity as the relationship between energy inputs and the economic or societal value of the work performed by those inputs, at the national, regional, and sectoral levels;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4115DB5C4EDD4AF5B8D218BED524F2FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate current energy productivity performance at the national, regional, and sectoral levels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF84596C2C468426DA1A563416D5896FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify barriers to improved energy productivity across economic sectors; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83AA061B92EE4213800F2DD17A7438BE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>highlight opportunities for improvement through technology, policy, behavioral, or structural interventions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBF989A6D3C594DD2975D92019C4A4CD8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Periodic energy productivity indicators quarterly report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon publication of the baseline assessment under subsection (a), and at least quarterly thereafter, the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration shall publish a report on energy productivity in the United States, to be known as the <quote>Energy Productivity Indicators Quarterly</quote> or <quote>Energy Productivity-IQ</quote>. Each Energy Productivity-IQ shall measure energy productivity using the same measures of economic output, by sector and nationally, as those used in the labor productivity estimates published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics in its Productivity and Costs reports, or any successor publication that reports such estimates. The Administrator of the Energy Information Administration shall coordinate with the Secretary of Labor to align, to the extent practicable, the publication schedule of the Energy Productivity-IQ with the publication schedule of the Bureau of Labor Statistics Productivity and Costs reports, or any successor publication that reports estimates of labor productivity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6CC1421B508B4108A8A8441DE4395E5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comprehensive energy productivity and competitiveness assessment</header> 
<paragraph id="H8A7D091095FA41558ED42A910A135549"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and every three years thereafter, the Secretary of Energy shall produce a Comprehensive Energy Productivity and Competitiveness Assessment using existing Federal modeling tools and data systems. The assessment shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H91CB63E8F060462AACF061CF6627A976"><enum>(A)</enum><text>quantify the direct and indirect economic, environmental, health, and societal impacts of achieving accelerated energy productivity improvements, relative to a business-as-usual scenario, at the national, regional, and sectoral levels;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE2604864F4B1403F9314A97C09F54822"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyze potential policy pathways to enhance competitiveness, reduce energy costs, increase resilience, and support job creation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6BC3A869EC04FF1831383C42663FFFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluate how such improvements affect national and regional well-being, including reductions in pollution, energy costs, public health burdens, water use, and economic vulnerability;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C21CA511F904906B5B63BFA3D9F9709"><enum>(D)</enum><text>detail how improvements in energy productivity in the United States affect competitiveness in key economic sectors, including manufacturing, services, and other energy-intensive industries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA4FC3D1AB2349B58445D1074AE8119A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>evaluate risks associated with delayed action, including stranded asset exposure and competitiveness losses; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F96B2EE3337429DAB72B9DB690F3227"><enum>(F)</enum><text>include, as appropriate, recommendations for Federal policies, programs, and research priorities to support sustained energy productivity gains; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CDA3C2E434F406596A80107A3BD4047"><enum>(G)</enum><text>include, as appropriate, supporting data, modeling scenarios, investment implications, and additional information to support increased American competitiveness through improved energy productivity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77E125D379FB49C08DAD1409E71DBB21" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of lifecycle factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out each assessment under this subsection, the Secretary of Energy shall consider how lifecycle factors associated with energy production, delivery, and use affect energy productivity, system costs, resilience, and economic competitiveness, including through impacts on—</text> <subparagraph id="H7EA3DDD991964ABAB468392D76ECD338" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">water resources, including withdrawals, consumption, and water quality;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56C9349CA7D64ACF86898CEF05B9477A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public health outcomes, including exposure to pollution and associated health burdens;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H098213458787463EA6FB413A1DB6AE5A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>material use, supply chain constraints, and waste generation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5BC0D63F2E1413C8DF38AA1F00E7AB2" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>emissions and other environmental impacts that materially affect economic or societal outcomes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96753AADA0D347C6A0AE47C879884EEB" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>direct and indirect economic impacts, including effects on energy costs, productivity, employment, and regional competitiveness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H11C3D264D3E2466F8586F7C22C8A5557"><enum>4.</enum><header>Development of energy productivity and cost task force</header> 
<subsection id="HD6530E53A3E2475FB50C8DDBC71FF39D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall establish an advisory group, to be known as the <quote>Energy Productivity Task Force</quote>, which shall be led by the Secretary of Energy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD2CFED4DA12E486EA12F34C0690D085A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="H12A58CE787B2411787CC859DF7CEF118"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal agencies</header><text>The Task Force shall include representatives from the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCEB552C33CE04C0498203205B8B383CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of Energy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0F307541F654C1B92F039B08A905FC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department of Commerce.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H591274766C334E8CA4674EA49F41F500"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Environmental Protection Agency.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65444620EF5041A1A9AFCBA000E545E5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Energy Information Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEBEDC7BB5AA6420EAD29028B069CAE51"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD1AEB49D80B4F759F711AA5001B2CBB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H874EF809210B4FA5A40AC104500D9E95"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The United States Geological Survey.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D5F4098C3904C75969BB3C60B67DF2B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBF1D6AE924B4CF7861BF3C4A8849C6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53FD753914334F0EAB694CE6E870C7C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independent experts</header><text>In addition to the representatives from Federal agencies described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall appoint independent technical experts and stakeholders from industry, academia, and public-interest organizations, which shall consist of stakeholders that represent—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H78E7FDA4E93944929346126C7D30A655"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the electric power sector;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H891A2C332C524BE2B5C63AAEA45B79D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the renewable energy sector;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EBFB3D52B404749B4FC9154471AC631"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the nonrenewable energy sector;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39FB4D4C3F4F45F9B900D689C640BC25"><enum>(D)</enum><text>consumer advocacy groups;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD3F395EAEC34CCCBC5D644EADF24CFC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>energy-intensive industries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9054677A1CA746A886659CB5965645B5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>environmental and public interest advocacy organizations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA54524313BAD47F780112BEEEF91EE22"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17C62C2ADBFC4C79A5B6801F9ED55B76"><enum>(H)</enum><text>academic- and National Laboratory-based researchers with expertise in—</text> 
<clause id="HEC460A9B0D064A23A5C51EE4565B6DF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>energy and economics;</text></clause> <clause id="HA3E9C4CF8348494F8B7FF8177771F1EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>climate and economics; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H950CE7D88DB64B178B907761267D971C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>environmental systems and economics; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H140FB735DFF848A2B514287C27581DEB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any other sector or organization the Secretary of Energy determines relevant for the purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1E90D3A10FFA4A0195ED1051B558DEC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1013 of title 5, United States Code, the Task Force shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD9E59F0D99E049BD85081530A28335B6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H22EA209435184D2C9C8E5F3875AD2405"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Energy productivity</header><text>The term <term>energy productivity</term> means a measure of how efficiently an economy, region, or industry uses energy to generate economic value.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7790ED2479F34D5D973E31B579A6E0FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>The term <term>Task Force</term> means the Energy Productivity Task Force established under section 4.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

