<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA892463E7A14428786CA692FAB56D3BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8567 IH: Undoing National Lead Emissions through Authorizing Directed Education from DOT Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to establish an education program on unleaded aviation gasoline, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H87A478A7B16941AF94694B443762FE17" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9BCDC6A40E8E46FF92136DC6AF351588" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Undoing National Lead Emissions through Authorizing Directed Education from DOT Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UNLEADED Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5A35372247DE46B3B53B02AA9638CB89" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Education program on unleaded gasoline</header> <subsection id="HD7A5914FC6D34B848F7165DF97601864"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall establish and disseminate an education program to provide general aviation pilots, flight schools, airport managers and operators, aircraft maintenance technicians, fixed-base operators, and other members of the general aviation community with information about new unleaded aviation gasoline authorized for use in aircraft and aircraft engines by the Administrator.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDAD5729348FB42F6AD0ADC9A2F531914"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="H05DB166F2BBA4A788B387082CD667108"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the education program under subsection (a), the Administrator shall publish on a website of the Administration, or a public website, information about unleaded aviation gasoline authorized for use in aircraft and aircraft engines, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D5D574ABD6E48C79992622DFCFB0F8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information about the compatibility of such gasoline with aircraft and aircraft engines;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85BF581958B04DE5BEBB6B0A1AFDBE64"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of all variations of unleaded aviation gasoline undergoing evaluation and authorization for use by the Administrator;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD02F631D29A945A7873532F5A7C8CE72"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent feasible, information about when unleaded aviation gasoline products become available for purchase;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03186172632A4B2AB6FE2DC06C0C731F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of any relevant information, including supplemental type certificates, required for a general aviation pilot to use such gasoline;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2C3C5A4B44044FF971F46515FA37BC7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>educational information on unleaded aviation gasoline safety; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5998574915B44C47A7D1B4B7B6276056"><enum>(F)</enum><text>information about the availability of any Federal initiatives or incentives (including tax credits) relating to such gasoline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C9BABF22C4D46A7BDA4003C090CFA9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization tracking mechanism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make the information described in paragraph (1)(B) available through a publicly available and continuously updated authorization tracking mechanism.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFB609E31AA64594B99BBC2414044C2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Administrator shall continuously update the information described in paragraph (1) and ensure such information is made available to—</text> <subparagraph id="H17A73D258BAD4B658AC6EAD397266021" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>flight instructors, pilot schools, and other pilot training providers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD233B500B7FC496C944719138F05B654"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fixed-base operators and the employees of such operators;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5ED3A8DECFAA45A09756AA15C41096F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">general aviation aircraft users, aircraft owners, aircraft pilots, and aircraft operators; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7FD3BFAD07FF49E18B2B27923C1C3D30"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the general public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H154E41C97C304CEF8484E3A1C9D826FF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall coordinate with general aviation industry, fuel providers, and fixed-based operators to facilitate annual education and training for leadership and staff of fixed-base operators to ensure that individuals assisting with transporting and handling unleaded aviation gasoline are informed of fuel type differences and the impacts such fuels have on airplanes.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1D500234F307479A9F46B859B80E7CB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing partnership</header><text>The Administrator may use an existing partnership, including the EAGLE Initiative, to carry out this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H95E78CC547804F64BD398169F7F9AF03"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The education program established under subsection (a) shall terminate on December 31, 2036.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H79D2A476D544491BB1003818CEA77DB8">
                <enum>(f)</enum>
                <header>Briefing</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the Administrator establishes the education program under subsection (a), and periodically thereafter until the termination date described in subsection (e), the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee of Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a briefing containing the status of, and any findings with respect to, such program, including the following elements:</text>
                <paragraph id="H7A6DA6BE9906417C8ED043D6406D3C13">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A year-to-date frequency of updates to the Administration website and information rollout to flight schools and fixed-base operators.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HA1ADB674D8814CF7A54CA6DE93D4C01D">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The progress of unleaded aviation gasoline currently undergoing an evaluation and authorization or approval process by the Administrator for use in aircraft and aircraft engines.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H34E1843D84124B38812110044B5F30E1">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimated total number of gallons of unleaded fuel sold per year compared with the number of gallons sold per year of 100LL.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

