<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25A72-NS8-L6-KW0"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3262 IS: To require the Secretary of Defense to develop and implement a strategy to field an integrated air defense system to bolster the capability of NATO to defeat unmanned aerial systems and deter Russian aggression, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Defense to develop and implement a strategy to field an integrated air defense system to bolster the capability of NATO to defeat unmanned aerial systems and deter Russian aggression, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id0662f3b5e0c249cc9436904721b9c262" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Integrated NATO air defense against unmanned aerial systems</header><subsection id="id2d07e7defab943d5a691e91fac1b3975"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall engage the Secretary General of NATO and relevant policymakers of NATO countries to develop and implement a strategy to rapidly field a multi-layered, integrated air defense system that would bolster allied air defense capabilities to defeat unmanned aerial systems and deter Russian aggression against NATO, particularly against the alliance’s eastern flank members, including Estonia, Finland, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, and Romania.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbaa9c2af67704f5da94bf0a380ee5a56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="ida3bfaad22a78425195f83fff863c2055"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify existing gaps in the defense efforts of NATO against unmanned aerial systems, particularly with regard to—</text><subparagraph id="id7d6411ac198d4be3ab3fa2a737070881"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impediments to using mass-produced, low-cost effectors, such as improved ammunition and rockets, against low-cost unmanned aerial systems, which risk requiring NATO to use expensive, high-cost weaponry, thereby depleting NATO stocks in a non-economical manner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe55946240c140fb93feb8e101877e0b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impediments to using next-generation technologies, such as artificial intelligence and high-power microwave weapons, to better coordinate defense responses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee94bbb8c63f4180b13dd2766fa5ed8b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impediments to allied command and control, multilateral coordination, leveraging of shared facilities, and enhancing operability;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id932443bc7ab145c483ae7bc946263c56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe current United States contributions to NATO air defense and identify future actions to be taken over the next five years by the Department of Defense—</text><subparagraph id="id18bda221f6884720a5963ddcbe95fb21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to enhance the ability of NATO to produce, at scale, low-cost effectors, such as improved ammunition and rockets, to defeat low-cost unmanned aerial systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc391b21870824e21bd01e38f030e9228"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enhance the ability of NATO to develop next-generation technologies to defeat low-cost unmanned aerial systems, particularly artificial intelligence and high-power microwave weapons, to better coordinate defense responses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9981ecb6631d4d0b9515c11d0a16b3cf"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to expand the production by NATO of mass-produced, low-cost unmanned aerial systems, including through cooperation with Ukraine, given Ukraine’s demonstrated expertise in the production of low-cost unmanned aerial systems; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id105a250f4b344ae8a3713c0de3c779e9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describe actions that NATO and specific NATO allies, including the United States, should take over the next five years—</text><subparagraph id="id658c21b3e0db4e2f88378af4002f57f0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to solve the impediments described in subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9007f36fecfe499d9380425992584c58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to achieve the goals described in subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc3d89a0fd8d54807b080eb9fb9f0f66e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees the strategy required by subsection (a), including an identification of—</text><paragraph id="idc3575703b6694b72a7f8d5645479d8f6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any changes to funding or policy required to bolster NATO's multi-layered, integrated air defense against unmanned aerial systems; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idedd545a8c490492f828e9e6ed14a40b1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any additional resources required to carry out the specific initiatives described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4fe809c3c9b6439e85dfe0387216427f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim report on implementation</header><text>Not later than March 15, 2027, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the progress made in implementing the strategy required by subsection (a), including any gaps in resources or authorities identified in the ability of the Department of Defense to implement the strategy.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idddbb2b1dd6224dce8d2e65a383bb25fe"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4528f89589644991aae73c386d386df4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddd16e6a7223649c189110c168e1ef1c0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the congressional defense committees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc8fcf79b7e864b52aeb741ecf42db476"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ea7772bdd0b40769b2a623a5945f85d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NATO</header><text>The term <term>NATO</term> means the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

