<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09DAB101B999403080622F773F594F23" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6662 IH: Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Credentialing Integration Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of
                    Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Mrs. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr.
                    Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of
                    Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of
                    Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which
                was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed
                    Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be
                subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such
                provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to jointly select a joint uniform credentialing and privileging system for medical providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H11CAEF5AF14E43A5946B07D0D7C9634F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6FFB70EE84CD47B181BE62D420903A21" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Defense and Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Credentialing Integration Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB4666C4E0A78462A80B8A8763034EBD2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Joint uniform credentialing and privileging system for medical providers at the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="H7FEB9B5062B845A2AF091D42A1D8D429"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Domestic Policy Council, shall jointly submit to the Committees on Armed Services and Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the medical provider credentialing and privileging systems in use by each Department. Such report shall include each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA100E7EC953B4E11BA82AA245E97A072"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the scope and scale of each system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D293B9EFED34BC5B05BC9D70AF37B1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the type of data stored on each system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85868BB71F3D4E8DB1F2A63457B9A871"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the portability of provider credentialing and privileging information under each system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC2FFE517C1D4C668FF6A36D455CA954"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of the interoperability between provider credentialing systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA23A1CA668554A9787D6ADD440A4CEB4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the risk management system, adverse actions, and governance of each system.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F4277B5F3F2437DB4489477FFF77A77"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of the limitations and gaps in the interoperability and administration of each system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7EE24501884474990DCBC3CF6F5C92A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Recommendations for scaling each system and addressing gaps in the interoperability and administration of such system, with the goal of achieving a single, uniform system to be used by both Departments.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H73BF6899453A4C21B3CABB266E4D3CB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Domestic Policy Council, shall jointly select one system from the systems in use by the Departments to serve as the joint uniform credentialing and privileging system for both the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H05E33DBB25AF4E5EAD5C0B9D93D3BABF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capability of system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that such joint uniform credentialing and privileging system has the capability to import and share provider credentialing and privileging information.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E6A933C05DF4F0E8BD065A124D8E38E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Certification of implementation</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2028, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly submit to the Committees on Armed Services and Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a written certificate that such joint uniform credentialing and privileging system has been implemented and is operational.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

