<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H91472768D5AC439B9901B8224074ECD8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9274 IH: Gun Violence Prevention and Public Safety Database Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9274</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to establish a gun violence prevention and public safety database.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H37605B69058642458BB34952F23E5988" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE20F72CDEE3347A5B8F05F4E69D321F5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gun Violence Prevention and Public Safety Database Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H29AC178AF77B4275961967AEAF0EA803"><enum>2.</enum><header>Gun Violence Prevention and Public Safety Database</header> 
<subsection id="HFFBE3D24E9C145DF8541BC9D3664C327"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall establish a publicly accessible database on the internet website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention of research relating to gun violence in the United States meeting the criteria described under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6F5762BA5843413AB5ADDB23D7D71178"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for research</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall publish on the internet website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention a clear description of criteria for research to be included in the database established under subsection (a). At minimum the research—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4CBC09F8968F49C28F06BE582116EB08"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to baseline evidentiary requirements shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H64F96CD8B0EB4CC385775BA76FED2792"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be data collected that presents an original analysis, systematic review, or data-driven findings;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB45790250CE24B76B200F0C28B9B58AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describe the data sources or evidence relied upon; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF0F1E470F1C4B2098F0667F203CD691"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include a description of the methodology sufficient to understand how conclusions were reached;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E64128D40374F058884738F022AD2C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be published in a peer-reviewed journal, issued or commissioned by a Federal, State, or local government agency, or be produced by a research organization with an established review or editorial process; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A698E55366F47BB8156AA06B852A0E4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall include any other information determined by the Director pursuant to subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H312621C3568D4F6082DF68BF13FEAC65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>Any research included in the database established under subsection (a) shall include to the greatest extent possible—</text> <paragraph id="H528DB46CE21F4DB08D457B36529658B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of the entity authoring such research; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB258F0D0026742A6A2AD8B850B480CF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disclosure of any funding source or sponsorship of such research.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0429B98369474C7C9860CFBA0C0AF466"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Resources</header><text>Research included on the database established under subsection (a) shall at minimum include research relating to gun violence from the—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3DF167BA0E8E424B8A5E6E621A702871"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">National Vital Statistics System;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A0EA002A6E4413E91A9C77D44D7CCA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>National Violent Death Reporting System;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB4E95ED15DE405F93A9DDDC048FE1C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>National Electronic Injury Surveillance System-All Injury Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H025FAD5D75164166B21D6B9923647733"><enum>(4)</enum><text>National Hospital Ambulatory Medical Care Survey;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA45CABD35014602B4EEAC7C0C7E5009"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Behavioral Risk Factor and Surveillance System; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1CE4550FCDC4F99AD6262DF1BC8922C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Youth Risk Behavior Surveillance System.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H9D837B1CB760406F805603AFABBFCC8B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall update the database established under subsection (a) every six months pursuant to the criteria described under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9D015F58861B4951803B7BF03CE0E98C" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Federal funds made available to the Department of Health and Human Services, including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Institutes of Health, may be used to conduct or support research with respect to gun violence.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H75C91923072845E29BE196FBD27E2867"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each fiscal year 2026 through 2030 to carry out this Act.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

