<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H173E26370940430B8FF7279CA17ACFFE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9403 IH: Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps Pay Oversight for Workforce Evaluation and Retention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to update guidance for the Junior Reserve Officers&#8217; Training Corps (JROTC) program to evaluate the effects of the JROTC instructor pay scale on recruitment and retention.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF19E8CB8B30941D483EE0C20688E1E2B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H353C61D15C8E43638DDDC74DD2D41A5E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps Pay Oversight for Workforce Evaluation and Retention Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>JROTC POWER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H01EA6A2757574CDBB0B5A5F8A7100731"><enum>2.</enum><header>Update of guidance and evaluation of Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps instructor pay scale</header> <subsection id="H253FB06F79714CAE9ADD43971A2E80E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Update of guidance</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries concerned (as that term is defined in section 101(a)(9) of title 10, United States Code), shall update Department of Defense guidance governing the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps (JROTC) program to include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H00311C81B2E84462B062A2B8FBE7B4EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation plan to assess the effects of the JROTC Standardized Instructor Pay Scale (JSIPS), or any successor pay system, on recruitment and retention of JROTC instructors; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0433F4EEBDF44BEBC6F0FF990B5D067"><enum>(2)</enum><text>standardized metrics for measuring JROTC instructor recruiting outcomes and retention rates across the military services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3AECDB28B7A84B83A918262F7277895E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required metrics</header><text>The evaluation plan required under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, metrics relating to—</text> <paragraph id="H291C7CC7677F4DC4A5F4A6B2D2C5892D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>instructor vacancy rates and time-to-hire;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC0450F2326F49E3AF251E6AFFC03E63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>retention rates and length of service;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39528DD0641E4F60923C0E51BC648417"><enum>(3)</enum><text>geographic variation in recruiting and retention outcomes, including high-cost-of-living areas, rural, urban, and geographically isolated locations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC22EF7C873B148399082CEE0071FC93F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>comparisons between outcomes under the legacy pay system and the JSIPS;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2049B029AEAF4674871508AD54741B70"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the identification of recruiting efforts used to attract instructor applicants, including data on how applicants learned about available instructor positions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE3BAB74FE3C54FC0B31AFA78DE349004"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the number of applicants who begin, complete, or withdraw from the instructor hiring process, including the interview and background investigation stages;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FD92CADFDD74DFFB12681E0DFBC0C76"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the number of applicants who accept or decline instructor position offers, including to the extent practicable, information on the reasons offers were declined; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB738BAF6CEA648A7969BBCBADCAA430F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>any other matters the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7BDCB21377104A9E95EC0F90CF4E726B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than one year after the issuance of the updated guidance under subsection (a), and annually thereafter for two years, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4ACB14D82DD2432FB80C9AFD9075484E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the updated guidance and implementation status;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB67185D4DF1640818783FD7BE16A363A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>baseline data and metrics collected using the metrics developed under subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38A2B5F1A3C34BD3B2FA2399C1D167CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the effects of the pay scale on recruitment and retention; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B23B23BE47F4677909F3FABB8A2DD04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any recommendations for legislative or administrative action.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

