<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCG26421-9XG-D0-WJC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4774 IS: Fraudulent Artificial Intelligence Regulations (FAIR) Elections Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4774</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the distribution of false AI-generated election media, to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to prohibit the removal of names from voting rolls using unverified voter challenge databases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="ideae64fd5e22e465da548d41e6003e0bb"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fraudulent Artificial Intelligence Regulations (FAIR) Elections Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF9B7D02C738C4C44818C8942F1BCB28D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on false AI-generated election media</header><subsection id="id8cb5efd195bf452ca03d58c1103bd7e2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d1cee752fec4aae95ba6d7ec3174ff9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable Federal election</header><text>The term <term>applicable Federal election</term> means any general, primary, runoff, or special election held solely or in part for the purpose of nominating or electing a candidate for the office of President, Vice President, Presidential elector, Member of the Senate, Member of the House of Representatives, or Delegate or Commissioner from a Territory or possession.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id497289892b914f4db63d2fdda9b6fac1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election official</header><text>The term <term>election official</term> means any individual legally authorized to perform duties in connection with an applicable Federal election, including workers, volunteers, poll workers, and authorized poll observers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c8fb28327cd461780fdd2fecf938547"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">False AI-generated election media</header> <text>The term <term>false AI-generated election media</term> means text, image, audio, or video that—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id49acb90e332043c6bbd4234e0b350dfb">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the product of a computational process that uses machine learning, natural language processing, artificial intelligence techniques, or other computational processing techniques of similar or greater complexity; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="idff3d5343c2e847e3a3ae3d08373fd6bb">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>either—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3e9c467c45944ac59eab14bdf830018e"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contains materially false information relating to—</text>
              <subclause id="idbe86d3ca94d24a6f860d5d0b1acec472">
                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>the time, place, or manner of holding any applicable Federal election; or</text>
              </subclause>
              <subclause id="id95565826b94f49919be667fe353adde7">
                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>the qualifications for or restrictions on voter eligibility for any such election; or</text>
              </subclause>
            </clause>
            <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
              id="id692c5589fce54b13b136c9a4a38c00e4">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>falsely depicts an election official.</text> </clause> </subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77CCB65049EA4408AFAF2BFFD48F9F60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), a person may not—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0aa90d7721204a46bc5c88635e49b14e"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly distribute false AI-generated election media described in subsection (a)(3)(B)(i) if such person—</text><subparagraph id="idce337a72697248e49e4b62d2e3a3c7c6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>knows such media contains materially false information described in such subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id232a4fde8a2f4eaa88f6edf7c02bcea7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the purpose of impeding or preventing another person from exercising the right to vote in an applicable Federal election; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id539a73a299bd40368c29f34060cab2ee"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly distribute false AI-generated election media described in subsection (a)(3)(B)(ii) if such person—</text><subparagraph id="id4BF881DC166548039FB3C97372F34781"><enum>(A)</enum><text>knows the depiction of the election official in such media is materially false; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB7AED3FE587A4337958E53E13FD0E407"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the intent to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab14731d6d734a3bb66c8a4ac5694278"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intimidate or harass an election official; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ab7db447c504397a1cc447c11154a94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deter another person from exercising the right to vote in an applicable Federal election.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD16D8C44B5EF40B486E63897BE659C40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inapplicability to certain entities</header><text>This section shall not apply to the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H9D5DC6F0DBE547E2A858414CCBDA520E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A radio or television broadcasting station, a cable or satellite television operator, programmer, or producer, or a streaming service that broadcasts false AI-generated election media prohibited by this section as part of a bona fide newscast, news interview, news documentary, or on-the-spot coverage of bona fide news events, if the broadcast clearly acknowledges through content or a disclosure, in a manner that can be easily heard or read by the average listener or viewer, that the information contained in the media and described in subsection (a)(3)(B) is false.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H14B25BB2486A441FB4A32031D3DED406"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A regularly published newspaper, magazine, or other periodical of general circulation, including an internet or electronic publication, that routinely carries news and commentary of general interest, and that publishes false AI-generated election media prohibited under this section, if the publication clearly states that the information contained in the media and described in subsection (a)(3)(B) is false.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFBBD78143A64FAFA683FD7E65966DB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Attorney General may bring a civil action against any person who violates subsection (b) in an appropriate United States District Court for such declaratory and injunctive relief (including a temporary restraining order, a permanent or temporary injunction, or other order).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84d758cc247348c79d43b6eafedac2b9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on removal of names from voting rolls using unverified voter challenge databases</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb21e09ea38d74c39adf754b674ed2e7d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20501">52 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 8 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6DEDE897FC774FBFA168CBC65A85871B"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8c0d4a6196942219f712e413d88c184"><enum>8A.</enum><header>Restrictions on removal of voters from official lists of voters</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08395de87e634edcbdc6f12780051afc"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A State may not remove the name of any registrant from the official list of voters eligible to vote in elections for Federal office or take any action with respect to a voter eligibility challenge unless the registrant or voter is determined to be ineligible to vote based on—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id2a4b6f3200f24d7498f273bd6d4a653d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>source information received from governmental entities and obtained by such entities in the course of carrying out official actions or duties; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb655c59aa1dd48959358491caddb76a6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">source information approved by the Attorney General as sufficient to protect the integrity and completeness of voter registration lists.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45ad352a09c0409fb80aec6a085c83c2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval of voter information data</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3f8ea06dcbd4861a50d2bb346f41afa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the members of the Election Assistance Commission, may approve source information under subsection (a)(2) if such information meets the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="idc7bfac93898a4f68a8e5883f2ea56186"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The source information contains qualifying data sets that allow the State to match the individual identified by the source information with an individual on the official list of voters eligible to vote in elections for Federal office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7619da1c869e4c00b4d0c34ceb37a67d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The source information is updated not less than monthly.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id796de10136254a27933065c3c6c00cfe"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The source information was not obtained in violation of section 1030 of title 18, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Computer Fraud and Abuse Act</quote>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea08d55a1b1c44f78f5cea64382e358f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifying data sets</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(A), the term <term>qualifying data sets</term> means the following sets of data with respect to an individual:</text><subparagraph id="id99d1a74f26464ef2ac6ccda45ef3955c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Last name, first name, and full social security number.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idafa6c24efc6746f08485bac02aeaa442"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Last name, first name, and driver’s license or other unique identifying number assigned by the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id675a863689a44617afe1b9657316ae3d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Last name, first name, last four digits of a social security number, and date of birth.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7fb9694195674d3a83319ba13c4001bf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Last name, full social security number, and date of birth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac0dbb1370be4a9ba65158375e2329fd"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with other methods</header><text>Nothing in this section be construed to preclude—</text><paragraph id="ID57EB6F1D27AD490D900D4373745A71D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the removal of names from official lists of voters on a basis described in paragraph (3)(A), (3)(B), or (4)(A) of section 8(a);</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70f9efbd0b6241c2b2541cb0710eea30"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the removal of names from official lists of voters on a basis described in section 8(c); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="IDD0DD22003C3C477ABC27122F5D2D981D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>correction of registration records pursuant to this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id6a6fd0bfffde48aca825ef2c0851faff"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 8(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id2a35a151b4ce4056be2ba0c1623bd982"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>provide</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to section 8A, provide</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea47885b841b4ffb92aff95344864b3a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>conduct</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to section 8A, conduct</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8332e4f3929a49abadf17cf8ba0bded4"> <enum>4.</enum> <header>Private right of action against Federal government for use of Federal data in determining eligibility to vote</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54007148089048dfbbc316f9a4e9475d"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Government shall not compare any information held by the Federal Government with respect to an individual against information held by a State or local government with respect to such person for purpose of eligibility to vote in elections for Federal office.</text>
      </subsection>
      <subsection id="id914750e001424336bda2c7b4a935f190" commented="no">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Private right of action</header>
 <text>A person who is aggrieved by a violation of this section may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court for such declaratory or injunctive relief as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text>
      </subsection>
 </section><section id="id030b5e5c4252450b86914588131bd27a"><enum>5.</enum><header>GAO study and report</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95e1b0326e32440594615a189d80a9ec"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Study</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0e5d42757874526ac18ccec7c346bb6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the effect of the use of Federal databases, including the Systematic Alien Verification for Entitlements (<quote>SAVE</quote>) system of the Department of Homeland Security, for purposes of removing the names of individuals from the official list of eligible voters in elections for Federal office.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0248106654204b4a934dc4df3d8ba14f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters studied</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall study—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id122441ce3b4a4350ab2c4c414d810443"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether such uses suppresses the right to vote;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id476f5db38c5f45e4b710f4bde7b8c72f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the accuracy of the process for identifying individuals who are not eligible to vote in elections for Federal office; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9ebcc5214f94313b0c45649237c48e1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of instances in which such processes have incorrectly removed an eligible individual from the official list of eligible voters in each State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbf259e66b17045c4b46a4ba17dff560a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate and the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id231d51dde59b4b9ebdefa2065e09d4c7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, or an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

