<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDF47D3CD3BE843C1A4A4DE298A3A63C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 7158 IH: Expanding AI Voices through Capacity Building Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7158</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260120">January 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support a broad and diverse interdisciplinary research community for the advancement of artificial intelligence (AI) and AI-powered innovation through partnerships and capacity building at certain institutions of higher education and other institutions to expand AI capacity in populations historically underrepresented in STEM, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3891477CA74341EB99244F602AEE9FE5" style="OLC"><section id="HADFD88CAF12C48449F601EB192DDA774" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding AI Voices through Capacity Building Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Expanding AI Voices Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBA72A295794E48DDB26A0BB9DB24636B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expanding capacity in artificial intelligence science</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5401 of the National AI Initiative Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9451">15 U.S.C. 9451</external-xref>; enacted as part of title LIV of division E of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>) is amended by—</text><paragraph id="H5B5B9313B313477AB1D4EECC70B95C33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0523A636CBA440AB0640ED9A7547DDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H1253C5D8E790486DA417508B16E77AAB" style="OLC"><subsection id="H8548F208314848A491E8934B36340E62"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expanding capacity in artificial intelligence</header><paragraph id="HD5092D110BE44E919F259DFD4B3BCA67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with the heads of Federal agencies the Director considers appropriate, shall make awards on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis to eligible institutions of higher education specified in paragraph (2) or eligible nonprofit organizations (or consortia thereof) to broaden participation in artificial intelligence research, education, and workforce development by increasing the ability of the United States to increase capacity and partnerships for artificial intelligence research and development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE19AB5337EEF430DA1EB18D89172AC79" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible institutions of higher education specified</header><text>Eligible institution of higher education specified in this paragraph the following:</text><subparagraph id="H34AD85C4B4FD45409DAFB691B07080FB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An institution of higher education, that, according to the data published by the National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics, is not, on average, among the top 100 institutions in Federal research and development expenditures during the 3-year period prior to the year of the award concerned.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFB70EA889C84B6D813571411FAA16EE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A historically Black college or university.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA1657657AA94A68AFE6E9AEA842C825" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A minority-serving institution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60DD3AE771FE413EAD11E1BC59D35037" commented="no"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Tribal College or University.</text>
                            </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E309AEBB01A43059A60E4BC8203C4A4" commented="no">
                                <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>A consortia of any of the entities specified in subparagraphs (A) through (C).</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28997721D6D848509ADA99977F358494" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaborations</header><text>A consortia receiving an award under this subsection may include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD003654CA8F44A0AA3A475C1B0922FFA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Mutually beneficial partnerships with institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, Federal agencies, State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, and private sector entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF7D9A7442584E7D9679A5A858CD7404" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing partnerships with artificial intelligence research institutes established as part of section 5201 of this Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9431">15 U.S.C. 9431</external-xref>) or recipients of other relevant awards made by the Foundation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9FD39F695E74EA8A185DDAC1A64830C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the activities under this subsection, an eligible institution of higher education or eligible nonprofit organization (or consortia thereof) shall carry out one or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H4E5D299786D4472890836971EF28FAF6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Development or expansion of research programs in artificial intelligence and related disciplines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14B650E07D5544F4B226CD95864B7DB4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Faculty recruitment and professional development in artificial intelligence and related disciplines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B5969DBFB3B49888100A4784016892A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Bridge programs focused on preparing post-baccalaureate students for graduate programs in artificial intelligence and related disciplines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADF267CE9E4E40FC8842DEE1889B16ED" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Provide or broker access to research resources, including computing resources, networking, data facilities, and software engineering support for artificial intelligence research and development.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B1CDC02264D4691ACDED8BB84D0C121" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Community building activities to foster mutually beneficial public-private collaboration with Federal research agencies, industry, Federal laboratories, academia, and nonprofit organizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3907204D7C2A4A9F83830DF5CBDFEE82" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Development and hosting of intra- or inter-institutional workshops to broaden workforce participation in artificial intelligence research and development.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H384BE0D838C34A039C82A182B625D9CF" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Activities to integrate ethical and responsible practices and principles into education programs in artificial intelligence and related disciplines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H728ED27D60624D16B00E91471E8BF92B" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Other activities necessary to build research capacity, education pathways, and workforce development pathways in artificial intelligence and related disciplines.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E3E02EC53A54C479E783D0EB584AB5A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation shall—</text><subparagraph id="H873B615A03444F66A10A464C084E5588" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct outreach to eligible institutions of higher education and eligible nonprofit organizations to apply for awards under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CC70D2779884D5E9688EAEEC2C2A41F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engage participants from all regions of the United States, especially individuals from underserved communities and groups historically underrepresented in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H254A25DFE86B4589A77AC58DC0939C5B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duplication</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall ensure awards made under this section are complimentary to, and not duplicative of, awards made under existing programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA905AE95E0CE4D2C833026B5F3AF5F1F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Additional considerations</header><text>In making awards under this subsection, the Director of the National Science Foundation may also consider the following:</text><subparagraph id="H3198698D8B62427783A158CE6F47FED0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which eligible institutions of higher education and eligible nonprofit organizations applying for awards under this subsection support students from diverse backgrounds, including first-generation undergraduate students.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C62BF1837F64407BD3EB98BBDCCA50C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The geographic diversity of such institutions and organizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92A6EF126B5A46349585AC0D751D94D1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Relative resource constraints of such institutions and organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBBDF74446EF4FC9BAB5432B59FF9ED8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HFCF9CAB9225F43088F74372C3EF1DB4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Historically Black college or university</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>historically Black college or university</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>part B institution</quote> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CC8E40CB4764D3592C83C478454F8BD"> <enum>(B)</enum> <header>Minority-serving institution</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>minority-serving institution</quote> means a Hispanic-serving institution as defined in section 502(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)</external-xref>); an Alaska Native-serving institution or Native Hawaiian-serving institution as defined in section 317(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>); or a predominantly Black institution, Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution, or Native American-serving nontribal institution as defined in section 371(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(c)</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FE73452B9894DB8AE295781F8E2B5CE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nonprofit organization</quote> means an organization which is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3880D4724E4D4E0499429C8FC559C947"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Tribal College or University</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

