<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7737092AF22643B5B4A803C9AC1ABDD0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6972 IH: Reporting Accountability and Abuse Prevention Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6972</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title X of the Public Health Service Act to require grant recipients to comply with all applicable State and local laws requiring notification or reporting of child abuse, child molestation, sexual abuse, rape, incest, intimate partner violence, or human trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H85A12F217A3B424ABD7CD51C1B5BFEDB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3C161BAD7A9F4937B1DE0694F0C9CC30" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reporting Accountability and Abuse Prevention Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HE49875CDE59A46ACAD3165D3F885E595"><enum>2.</enum><header>Compliance by projects funded under title X with State and local sexual abuse reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title X of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300">42 U.S.C. 300 et seq.</external-xref>) is amending by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H250166445A1642F99A629A3F6ABB1F47" style="OLC"> <section id="H86E8EDCA8C6B4138BEA0B8B8A62E86EF"><enum>1009.</enum><header>Compliance with State and local sexual abuse reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="H917A0A5FE1F74E4DBBB39831142C981F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition on the award or renewal of a grant under this title for any project or program, the Secretary shall require the grant recipient to comply with all applicable State and local laws requiring notification or reporting of child abuse, child molestation, sexual abuse, rape, incest, intimate partner violence, or human trafficking (in this section referred to as <quote>State notification laws</quote>).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4CA6618488C344C1B1C46F6D668227B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required compliance</header><text>In ensuring compliance with subsection (a) for a project or program, the grant recipient shall provide to the Secretary appropriate documentation or otherwise demonstrate to the Secretary’s satisfaction that the grant recipient—</text> <paragraph id="HFDBA7F719687466FB4410278C4295C51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has in place and implements a plan to comply with State notification laws, including, at a minimum, policies and procedures that include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1C54D569BD2247E19D5E6DEDE457161E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of obligations under State notification laws of the project or program, or of each organization and individual carrying out the project or program, including any obligation to inquire about or determine the age of a minor patient or of a minor patient’s sexual partner;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4305A3A809BC4042B69969E6F84CFBC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>timely and adequate annual training of all individuals (whether or not they are employees) serving patients for, or on behalf of, the project or program regarding—</text>
<clause id="H624C423552C541358D5CEC5C6B3DE464"><enum>(i)</enum><text>compliance with State notification laws;</text></clause> <clause id="H0C9B49550EBB454884A64078D28D2F17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>policies and procedures of the project or program with respect to notification and reporting of child abuse, child molestation, sexual abuse, rape, incest, intimate partner violence, and human trafficking; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H930BD896B9C54E55A840584A89079755"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>appropriate interventions, strategies, and referrals to improve the safety and current situation of the patient;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1771C433C9F743DA9CCF590AF50478F0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>protocols to ensure that every minor who presents for treatment is provided counseling on how to resist attempts to coerce the minor into engaging in sexual activities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A1E3A38C4794598A26885A55FB039EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a commitment to conduct a preliminary screening of any minor who presents with a sexually transmitted disease, pregnancy, or any suspicion of abuse, in order to rule out victimization of the minor; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD34B04306B0340FC87C19657350A15C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintains records that demonstrate compliance with each of the requirements set forth in paragraph (1) and—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6DB80A0498D94739B555E3317A417A5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>indicate the age of minor patients;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0ABECF1FAB0C486993971836568D1492"><enum>(B)</enum><text>document each notification or report made pursuant to State notification laws; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB383EDA246B04CF19A4F2DF80CCF06D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>indicate the age of the minor patient’s sexual partners if such age is an element of a State notification law under which a report is required.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H419508516EEA4E99BB97B6FB589A06C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition on the award or renewal of a grant under this title for any project or program, a grant recipient shall agree to allow the Secretary, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Comptroller General of the United States to review the records maintained by the grant recipient, including any contractor or subgrantee of the grant recipient, for the purpose of ensuring compliance with this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7689B83884D64EC3A61A5C818640D372"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties for noncompliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD29C6A96628040359BB165FA0E6BB891"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Secretary finds that a grantee under this title has violated subsection (a), (b), or (c), work with the grantee to remedy such noncompliance; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H68B922D3454744E79D07E8CBF0E352BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if the Secretary finds that the grantee commits a subsequent violation of subsection (a), (b), or (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="HBACD85881EF440BD9ACE115A701D6C3F"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>seek repayment of all monetary Federal assistance received by the grantee under this title on or after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Reporting Accountability and Abuse Prevention Act of 2026</short-title>; and</text>
              </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H139C43A572A746408929D17CF360CD30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not award or provide any assistance under this title to the grantee for a period of at least 36 months following the date of finding that the grantee has committed such subsequent violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

