<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26441-6C8-PK-L6C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 685 ATS: Designating April 22, 2026, as “National Assistive Technology Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 685</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating April 22, 2026, as <quote>National Assistive Technology Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas assistive technology is any item, piece of equipment, or product system that is used to increase, maintain, or improve the functional capabilities of a person with a disability or an older adult;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas an assistive technology service is any service that directly assists an individual with a disability or an older adult in the selection, acquisition, or use of an assistive technology device;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, in 2024, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reported that 1 in 4 individuals in the United States, or almost 70,000,000 individuals, have a disability;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, during the 2022–2023 school year, the Department of Education reported that there were more than 9,500,000 children with disabilities;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reported that, among adults 65 years of age and older, 2 in 5 have a disability;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas assistive technology enables individuals with disabilities and older adults to be included in their communities, including by making their classrooms and workplaces more inclusive;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas assistive technology devices and services are necessities, not luxury items, for millions of individuals with disabilities and older adults, without which they would be unable to live in their communities, access education, or obtain, retain, and advance gainful, competitive, and integrated employment;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the availability of assistive technology in the workplace promotes economic self-sufficiency, enhances work participation, and is critical to the employment of individuals with disabilities and older adults; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas State assistive technology programs support a continuum of services that include—</text><paragraph id="id4eb4324fe6c14138bb4e325b8b4e4bdf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the exchange, repair, recycling, and other reutilization of assistive technology devices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida4ac742ea7dc4be48506972d2e3863b7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>device loan programs that provide short-term loans of assistive technology devices to individuals, employers, public agencies, and others;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7457496b16643ae800a4955f3a52f33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the demonstration of devices to inform decision making; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id617f6c0c2f6e4f6fae3c9e8e9e411d76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State financing to help individuals purchase or obtain assistive technology through a variety of initiatives, such as financial loan programs, leasing programs, and other financing alternatives that give individuals affordable, flexible options to purchase or obtain assistive technology: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id923e6457c1d04df194a656c10d8fa617"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates April 22, 2026, as <quote>National Assistive Technology Awareness Day</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf11b5cd2e32544cdb64f34edfd53eedc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends—</text><subparagraph id="idc49a9a6a3a9f49dea7dee3c237390d72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistive technology specialists and program coordinators for their hard work and dedication in serving individuals with disabilities in finding the proper assistive technology to meet their individual needs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabecd19f635d440d80c2cf4c21db43fc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>professional organizations and researchers dedicated to facilitating the access and acquisition of assistive technology for individuals with disabilities and older adults in need of assistive technology devices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

