<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF759E6CBAAA64B9B8F76DF42BC6C2315" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6883 IH: Reproductive Coercion Prevention and Protection Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6883</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001237">Ms. McDonald Rivet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To define reproductive coercion as a form of domestic violence, to provide Federal judges the authority to intervene in certain cases of domestic violence, and to create a private right of action for victims of domestic violence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC1F1CB2114DC4461A622A06E644D0338" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8F16C885C906460F9264C0B3893EBA40" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reproductive Coercion Prevention and Protection Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H9A016D5BFECD44578440315800744CB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H740C04F902F54CC2B2153F70A6A79B95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the National Coalition Against Domestic Violence and the National Domestic Violence Hotline, between 10,000,000 to 12,000,000 women and men become victims of domestic violence each year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB59C57D303DE4668A00BD038F853F72E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A person can experience domestic violence though either intimate partner violence, such as with a current or former dating partner, or non-intimate partner violence, such as those with whom the person has a familial relationship.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43881471EACF4A37878110452B34677A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Intimate partner violence has affected both women and men across the United States. For example, roughly 20 people every minute are physically abused by an intimate partner in the United States. In particular, women between the ages of 18 to 34 experience the highest rates of intimate partner violence of any group, with over one third of murdered women in 2021 were killed in relation to intimate partner violence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B49D32EE73F4BFABCD2B430DC66B897"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Reproductive coercion is a form of intimate violence by an intimate partner, dating partner, domestic partner, or spouse against a person that involves behaviors to exert control over a person's reproductive autonomy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC8D0EC2B2814BA2B9B0E16BD09F43EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Reproductive coercion affects people across a wide array of socioeconomic and demographic backgrounds.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2135E50B61A44B77B8F0996AAF72C2A2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Common forms of reproductive coercion include sabotaging contraceptive methods and coercing or forcing a person to either become pregnant or terminate a pregnancy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3802C7B9FA874BCCAABE410A2832FF63"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Studies indicate that eight percent to sixteen percent of adult women in the United States have experienced some form of reproductive coercion. For example, one-quarter of abuse survivors report that their abusive partners have forced them to become pregnant. Additionally, over two-thirds of women in physically abusive relationships also experience sexual assault by the intimate partner, and those women are at heightened risk of homicide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E6661761A3E4048A70D6D08FB8CCCFC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Homicide is a leading cause of mortality for pregnant and postpartum women in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H685555113581402C8304D5A0D94FBD9C"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Persons experiencing reproductive coercion are traveling across State lines to neighboring states to access reproductive health care, including when they lack access to reproductive health care providers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD38290384083428988B3788CB3258674"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Due to State-level reproductive health care laws, some private companies have adjusted corporate policies to provide, among other provisions, travel reimbursements for employees who need to access out-of-State reproductive health care.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C43637F40884922A68C6A633CCEA52E"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many health insurance plans and medical providers commonly offer mail-order delivery of birth control, ensuring timely access to medication without the need for in-person visits. Concerningly, persons experiencing reproductive coercion have reported instances where an intimate partner sabotaged or destroyed their mail-order birth control.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H807AF67803F743BAADE3BF79C179A861"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Health care insurance markets may cover or operate across multiple States and may be impacted by different State regulations concerning reproductive health care and services.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HCDAB3593CC6D429DBA546DD6250187D8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reproductive coercion</header> <subsection id="H09EE8DB0C97542D892600A62D9591B5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the <short-title>Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994</short-title> (34 U.S. Code 12291 et seq.) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0104080904174298BD137C63DDBFB7EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 40002—</text> <subparagraph id="H10D29647E7D94C6C9B47B8CFE0CAF96C"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in paragraph (12), by inserting the phrase <quote>, including reproductive coercion</quote> after the phrase <quote>coercive behavior</quote>;</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48DC3C5C74CA494AB2FDC5422E6D66FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF5697D3CF37045D6A6EA10AFD589E98E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HF1C2CD36E3EF46B3B751943D6460A2C6"><enum>(53)</enum><header>Reproductive coercion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>reproductive coercion</quote>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7F03BF350A8E41C09EDC2A5DE3E07997"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means control over the reproductive autonomy of another through sexual assault, force, threat of force, or intimidation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78D6C3E4108D4C0392B6FA06E739D758"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text> 
<clause id="HC11E531DB9ED4B3897AD926C804979EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pressuring or coercing another to become pregnant or to terminate a pregnancy;</text></clause> <clause id="H77E2F85030444F76B9543C70FC1F689D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deliberately or physically impeding, manipulating, or sabotaging contraception use or access to reproductive health information; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2D686940578643A89598F3B6D6D7A75E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using coercive or manipulative tactics to control, or attempt to control, a pregnancy outcome either by the continuation of a pregnancy or the termination of a pregnancy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B9DD01C988848C583B73E853FA10ABE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding after section 40221 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H99C9CED47B6B4F4190E9ABF73FF8422C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HC036C56A574E491BB57D77AC1FAC827F"><enum>40222.</enum><header>Civil action for reproductive coercion and domestic violence</header> 
<subsection id="HDBD59E7EB5D2408984814E4353A12FE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual alleging that a covered defendant, in the circumstances described under subsection (b), engaged in domestic violence may bring a civil action against such covered defendant in a court of competent jurisdiction for damages under subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9A263C140BB248EEA3219E355DE193D3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Circumstances described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1817D5B2824243D59B539BE43DE13D13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the covered defendant or victim traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using means, channel, or facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA82E9D60AE949CB9C7D2176C1F3A8B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the covered defendant used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of foreign commerce in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC3939D829B7409091D3078A01F741F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAFA72C108B44F0C8A7DBA38EBDA0434"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the covered defendant transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in any manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6767FCFA2E244AFC93C1651E4BD56FAE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any instrument, item, substance, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H37F088251C7C4E6298076688467A1FEB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0259C02C3C504ED6B01F5CFB735C4798"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8473DBFAF07409A80225DFADDA2B1D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Damages</header><text>In a civil action brought under subsection (a), the court may award—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFAB505F2516479496DE93E690DDC463"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actual damages;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE77667AFAA754E6C81438659E63E2D78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>punitive damages; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DF6B4AC00E44AA3A72D075C3E6858FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other relief the court determines appropriate, including injunctive relief. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAB35D55D82CF42879CAE3836BA819345"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4E3593F010894C4096368C29BE33B173"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modify, limit, or supersede the ability of a State court to grant or take away custody of children, property, or pets shared between the parties to the case; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D1486FA296C45978480970AA10A68ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>modify, limit, or supersede the jurisdiction of a State court; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E77C684DE5242098B3EF783902E8593"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modify, limit, or supersede a State definition of domestic violence or reproductive coercion for the purpose of State law or any remedy available under State law; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D0DA5AA6B4D4650B3AB6E8D3B79185A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>limit the ability for an Article III court to remand an entire case or portion of a case to a State court based on the case’s jurisdiction where appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H768E63BCAE66420981CBAFA90FC9C906"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HE70DB13335084ECEB1A86C7793912F9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Domestic violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>domestic violence</quote> means any violation of the law of the jurisdiction where the conduct occurred or the victim resides, by a covered defendant, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H25A2438069E04271BF25DB3D5C924220"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the use or attempted use of physical abuse or sexual abuse;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD9DB274351C4FA0A17A5F6887BEB5FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a single instance or pattern of reproductive coercion; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H165117CCA1484FDABA5E079ADA267C1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any coercive behavior committed to gain or maintain power and control over a victim, including verbal, psychological, economic, or technological abuse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42DD729AF3E24A3D9556E2EBF952F578"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Covered defendant</header> <text>The term <quote>covered defendant</quote> means, an individual, who with respect to a victim—</text>
                  <subparagraph id="H2E8CB11B7A96429CA2A8FE20B5A1E3B5">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>is the spouse, intimate partner, dating partner, or domestic partner or a previous spouse, intimate partner, dating partner, or domestic partner;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H842754FEEFA94A79A9901728E5CAFE51">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>is a person similarly situated to a spouse or previous spouse;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31F7D5BEA29D404FA215538E76638D6A"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>is cohabitating, or has cohabitated, with the victim;</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                  <subparagraph id="H4660D3B6193F47EB8FA89EA70AC791B0">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>shares a child in common with the victim; or</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H054A9C22BBDF40C6A193B71709091F89"> <enum>(E)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a non-intimate partner with a familial relationship, including a grandparent, aunt or uncle, parent, brother, sister, or in-law.</text>
                  </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

