<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H58295C7887C14E36B8ADE8A61981FD87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8671 RH: Bank Fraud Technology Advancement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 612</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8671</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–704]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 7, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal banking agencies to conduct a study on the use of advanced technologies in fraud detection and prevention, with particular attention to community financial institutions, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HC7426B5A6B9D4F439ED2BCB2AB07A45B"><section id="H9B3DF4566CA44340815BD3AF42B8196D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bank Fraud Technology Advancement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2EFD595CD6E14CA18ABE7C25BE3960A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3877C27880F34B2A9836AB652DA84878"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced fraud detection technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>advanced fraud detection technology</quote> means emerging technologies used to detect, prevent, or mitigate financial fraud and scams, including artificial intelligence, machine learning, predictive analytics, behavioral biometrics, network analytics, data fusion tools, distributed ledger-based monitoring tools, and blockchain tracing tools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51DA7CA2B25445508642F832223A818E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>artificial intelligence</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3216B732DE0F4B85A94AD525ADD46B33"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Credit union</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>credit union</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>insured credit union</quote> in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A9AC3AE70EF45759DD9EE64DB0667B1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal banking agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal banking agency</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H47B88D58D1324924ACF65481777E2C8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA476D0B872314207A2086152EA3C3390"><enum>(B)</enum><text>means the National Credit Union Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H179A708FBCB7471CA22617995A33280D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Insured depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>insured depository institution</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4205F24304D444C9B52C29DFB888CB4E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Machine learning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>machine learning</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H128BE0DB4E1A4F30AA60DA465B812934"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on advanced technologies in fraud and scam detection and prevention</header><subsection id="H1C906353F0FA4ACE8B42EC6D92121E0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal banking agencies, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, the Federal Trade Commission, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Federal Communications Commission, and other appropriate Federal and State government agencies, including appropriate law enforcement agencies, shall jointly conduct a comprehensive study on the use of advanced fraud detection technology by insured depository institutions and credit unions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H502F030C4ECE4A21AAA1993A78A1B955" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required elements</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall evaluate the following:</text><paragraph id="HAB0C8BFC160F4EBFACAFEB2399DB6E47" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Current use and effectiveness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The current use and effectiveness of advanced fraud detection technologies, including–</text><subparagraph id="HDC21A7B597544F9497D02A7F1B79ECF8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which insured depository institutions and credit unions of varying asset sizes deploy advanced fraud detection technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C09149A6EDB4C9DABD4AED399738B22" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measurable outcomes relating to fraud detection, prevention, loss reduction, loss mitigation, privacy, and consumer protection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC3840F800F54F2990FCD8AAE2206905" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">barriers to adoption and considerations of interoperability, data access, liability, error rates, and regulation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6E5980EBE4F4C42926AB8C0A77565A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how various fraud detection technologies differ in use, effectiveness, costs, benefits, and considerations under subparagraphs (A) through (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC85222DF3AAC4EBD88E5F747A4FA443C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community financial institution access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Community financial institution (that is either an insured depository institution or credit union) access to advanced fraud detection technology, including—</text><subparagraph id="H52E02B013A35432B9F78C66C90D78CBC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">challenges faced by community financial institutions in accessing or deploying advanced fraud detection tools, including unique challenges faced by various types of community financial institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C30DB5DA0DB4215AD336382C8C3DA57" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether economies of scale disadvantage smaller community financial institutions in general, or certain types of smaller financial institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B9B1184C5E34C42BAA6C138CDF10E3E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>options to facilitate shared services, utility models, managed-service providers, or consortium-based fraud detection platforms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43235888E1B04FDBA3CE2C9A1E20EFDB" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations to ensure regulatory guidance is appropriately tailored to avoid discouraging adoption by smaller community financial institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H443ABBD2FCFB4CC286A2E599CDBACB96" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence and machine learning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Artificial intelligence and machine learning, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB8B2205416B347698CEA557615BD8966" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use by insured depository institutions and credit unions of artificial intelligence and machine learning models, applications, and tools in detecting fraud patterns, anomalies, synthetic identity fraud, and real-time payment fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB142CEEA3CA444B58627B581529A9F01" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">governance frameworks used by insured depository institutions and credit unions to manage fraud model risk, explainability, and validation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H765D7DDE544E4D12A1459F9C7D8D08AD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">steps Federal banking agencies can take in coordination with other relevant government agencies and the private sector to ensure access by insured depository institutions and credit unions, including community financial institutions and their third-party vendors, to such models, applications, and tools.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB62A27335C34073A85B9B386BC0E439" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information sharing and public-private partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information sharing and public-private partnerships, including—</text><subparagraph id="H4B022F02FCA4433F965FB331E6339523" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effectiveness of existing information-sharing frameworks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2629ABF3560F45BC8EC8A23703D1978C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether expanded public-private partnerships or centralized fraud utilities would enhance detection capabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0A141B8CDE045DCAC276B7863B880DA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the feasibility of a voluntary fraud analytics consortium accessible to community financial institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F0C64E9EE9A49D7AB9C8306F82EA329" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>privacy, data protection, and cybersecurity considerations associated with expanded data sharing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3E9EE5B413B4957B41A1F48096F8A19" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Payments system risks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Payments system risk, including—</text><subparagraph id="HEFB6CB6FAF634590AAC9AA6524AD2C36" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fraud risks associated with electronic funds transfers and checks; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C5250CBB8AF44E4BFA23873F0EA9772" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether advanced analytics can reduce fraud while preserving settlement finality and payment system stability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9831819E6EC45EAAC1A3CF68C1C8FED" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regulatory and supervisory considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulatory and supervisory considerations, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2FC167A3692C467BB26F136B17623B58" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">what benefits and risks arise from existing supervisory expectations with respect to innovations in fraud detection and prevention, including whether existing supervisory expectations create barriers to innovation while maintaining relevant safeguards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC37667F280A344C194548236BB2C21B3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the need for interagency guidance, regulatory clarity, or safe harbors to support technology adoption in a manner that promotes fraud detection and prevention consistent with consumer protection, privacy, safety and soundness, and national security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A780C13282A42C192919961A45F0647" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>opportunities to harmonize expectations across Federal banking agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73C51B9D9055431BA81C09443A252E89"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether additional training for Federal banking agencies staff is necessary to promote effective regulation and supervision of financial institutions’ use of advanced fraud detection technology, especially for community financial institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80017F1C38774487ADAAEB03FA6309C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report and recommendations</header><paragraph id="H40422A5703DD43FFAE60E4BAF41EE070"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal banking agencies shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under this section, and make such report publicly available.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DFA5B95A8DB461FBC345AD7C61311D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Classified annex</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report under paragraph (1) may include a classified annex, if applicable, provided to the committees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EFBA6EC687847C79413D951F5654221"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include legislative, regulatory, or supervisory recommendations that promote fraud detection and prevention consistent with consumer protection, safety and soundness, and national security, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H3F2532CB57184E7688B7331B674140C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proposals to support shared fraud detection utilities or consortium-based analytics platforms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CB9435D5DD74A66B904AE081A80A08F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance or safe harbors to encourage artificial intelligence use in fraud prevention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF5C50127B8B4015BF9DCABF44F33326"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pilot programs tailored to community financial institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF404E1700BC435887DFAF9F19359D9F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations to strengthen public-private information sharing consistent with privacy and civil liberties protections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0DEB6E8DA0B64153BFE3C8B4A54D1854"><enum>4.</enum><header>Community Financial Institution Fraud Technology Pilot Program</header><subsection id="HC20A4F34774341EFB655C56358C96020"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after submission of the report required under section 3(c), the Federal banking agencies may jointly establish a voluntary pilot program to facilitate community financial institution access for insured depository institutions and credit unions with less than $10,000,000,000 in total consolidated assets to advanced fraud detection tools.</text></subsection><subsection id="H52D0D7F2D4E54FB0AE38C414EC443809"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program features</header><text>The pilot program described in subsection (a) may include—</text><paragraph id="H7E10E08D8E4F46ACBA0ECE4A7545308A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>pooled procurement or shared services models;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F8753EF364476782E3A1B1C8A4E36B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>model validation assistance or technical support;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2E66D78B6AC4380B931778B0F4052CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>standardized vendor risk management templates;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD52014E3A7B44563A902B624D695F0B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>regulatory clarity regarding model governance expectations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3AD85CBE8F4845AF405FE9B7B10DD7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>collaboration with the Department of the Treasury and law enforcement to provide anonymized fraud typology data feeds.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2B6D7066ED34F7B92F1EAF527110E75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset and report</header><paragraph id="H3AA909BCA07F40B798E194A9CBBE1E74"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>Any pilot program established under this section shall expire not later than 3 years after submission of the report required under section 3(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51F8724C18EC48B3ABA2CEF09F7334C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the expiration of all pilot programs established under this section, the Federal banking agencies shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, and make such report available to the public, containing—</text><subparagraph id="H002A0C0C523641FC806C71371566F77C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all findings and determinations made by the Federal banking agencies in carrying out any pilot program established under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C37737762D048D28817B80400E28E83"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any legislative, regulatory, or other recommendations the Federal banking agencies may have based on such findings and determinations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4664D63E488C41D98C991C9EDDB902CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Classified annex</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report under paragraph (2) may include a classified annex, if applicable, provided to the committees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

