<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE72BE31AC0E5462EB9A6A525ECD43DFA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8453 IH: Rural Child Care Facility Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8453</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a low-interest loan program to support the renovation, retrofit, expansion, and adaptation of structures to increase the availability of child care in rural communities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3F1FF9728235486CA05AB3FCEB9394AA" style="OLC"><section id="H0D84DA72127B40319D3DAE907E1DD0F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Child Care Facility Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1AC2A85F5687419FBD027EEB234F125E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Low-interest loan program to support the renovation, retrofitting, expansion, and adaptation of structures to increase the availability of child care in certain rural areas</header><subsection id="HB0C2AA1327B04E9795EC9AA1CAF6886E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary may, subject to this section, make a low-interest loan to a covered child care provider in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF8B0838234754AD99753D3AD44D42E9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB113797CE35B4D7A905D206BFA5E1621"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered child care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered child care provider</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9A646F3E91584E1E890DBDAED4DC7FB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a child care service provider who—</text><clause id="HDC008DCF32034CA09C3C9775239A3E2D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is primarily engaged in providing child care services for children from birth to compulsory school age;</text></clause><clause id="H910AA9FB2F394941AAB141685DAECA40"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE77C20883F454DBE9E3778F16DB3AFB2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provides child care services for school-age children outside of school hours or outside of the school year; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3C81193EB5DE4C6EB7C56BAFDDEF150A" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>offers pre-school or pre-kindergarten educational programs;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAA6C2AD9235D4AB8BD6772D72B19AC75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is in compliance with the licensing requirements for child care services providers of the State in which the provider is located; and</text></clause><clause id="H8A6DD37514F349A9AB043F409E0DD058"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has conducted a criminal background check that meets the requirements of section 658H(b) of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858f">42 U.S.C. 9858f(b)</external-xref>) with respect to each employee and regular volunteer of the provider; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35DF0A367EF94B71BB1F667DF2619648"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other child care service provider that the Secretary deems to be qualified to receive a loan under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56B939CD4F144240BA57E25127F77FC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child care desert</header><text>The term <term>child care desert</term> means a census tract in which—</text><subparagraph id="H2707C5048E2E4C50B6A4344A554662C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of residents who are children is not less than 3 times the number of children for whom the licensed child care providers in the census tract are capable of providing child care; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AFD8FFAC2434D2B905C729C08CBA7BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there are no licensed child care providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C466328449B4B15BEA3D77B971B9A92"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rural community</header><subparagraph id="H9836670B0D26456BB1A9042336075170"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>rural community</term> means any census designated place with a population of less than 20,000, subject to subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53469FF9DF3E47B3A6E87CAFF8244D3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority to modify definition</header><text>The Secretary may, as the Secretary deems necessary, modify the definition set forth in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA15390C3B5A943CA9FE2BA12F59CB1C9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Low-interest loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-interest loan</term> means a loan which bears interest, at a rate fixed at the time of each advance, equal to the Treasury constant maturity rate, as published by the Department of the Treasury for a maturity comparable to the term of the loan on the business day that precedes the advance date, plus 1/8 of 1 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5306912FC50F4138B9BDE849100512A5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Deputy Under Secretary for Rural Development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82E36C4253AA4C6C84FB7ABAE6902D7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity desiring a loan under this section may submit to the Secretary an application for the loan, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBD517B2235934855B8AA879B1EBE10D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application processing</header><paragraph id="HE171EAFF31C4485C8EEE2C170C76A355"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice of application status</header><text>Within 30 days after receipt of an application for a loan under this section, the Secretary shall provide to the applicant a written notice as to whether the application is complete or additional information is needed to complete the application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE24EB12BF9443E5B2926F7992B323A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of approval or disapproval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 90 days after receipt of an application for a loan under this section, the Secretary shall provide to the applicant a written notice as to whether the application has been approved or disapproved.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64826FBB76BE4B4AA93C50F72A77927B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>The Secretary may approve an application for a loan under this section for a project if the Secretary determines that—</text><paragraph id="HA5665B2F35BF4445BCD1A20324C98AFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the applicant is a covered child care provider; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06F5A13D84274ECC883924A8095B6CF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the application demonstrates that completion of the project will increase the availability of child care in a child care desert in a rural community.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD50746E23A7D44DE91C5960790FF3FD5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of loan</header><paragraph id="H32FC580495EB4FAD8052D718F62AC680"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity to which a loan is made under this section may use the loan to facilitate the renovation, retrofitting, expansion, and adaptation of a structure to increase the availability of child care services in a rural community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H376DBFF6E21C42B7A6FD56BD49282065"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on use for pre-development activities</header><text>Such an entity may use not more than 10 percent of the loan to facilitate the pre-development phase of a new facility, including planning and design.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H805D5324E68C4884952A2D03492756E0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Loan term</header><paragraph id="HDA9B34E02CE14B43AF514A4B8C09868F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A loan under this section shall be made for such term as the Secretary may determine, which shall not exceed 25 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E0A8365F1584D60891CC18501CBB875"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repayment schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a repayment schedule for a loan made under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCE400FB93434EDD8E463E7558414A83"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a written report regarding implementation of this section, which shall—</text><paragraph id="HAE2E6AA2109B4D3B98398E0F3C2775E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specify the number of loans awarded under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9822578C0B349AFB5D0C13955F00D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe the activities funded under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DF4D9F5685148B59768F846820A8F14"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the number of child care slots created as a result of providing loans under this section, including the number of child care slots serving children from low-income families or children who are dual language learners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D8FE3E64F67419CA5ACE94CFB3BA660"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the number of child care slots at risk of elimination due to a child care center closing or proposed price increases, that have been preserved as a result of providing loans under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7FE47328106426E9806FCD1DD6F6B38"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the number of staff employed by covered child care providers to whom a loan has been made under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBF76331792B471EB284D7548FC41FAE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include demographic data about the communities served by the covered child care providers to whom a loan has been made under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EF2F1020F7741DB8C2FF17890762E2A"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify the number of providers of pre-kindergarten child care services to whom a loan has been made under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

