<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE9D1670BCE3C4041B5D08A54E37AB31F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7372 IH: Safety is Not For Sale Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7372</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260204">February 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that lifesaving motor vehicle safety features are offered independently of convenience and luxury features, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDB7EA7E68FA84BC89C057B0D920656D0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD25A1D2467C54EF8850AB24F86419D60" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety is Not For Sale Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA916150CA1D74A579DEA10D8EB0C205C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on certain sales practices with respect to optional safety features for motor vehicles</header> <subsection id="H4AD94C4F17404E7CBCA797BF760A256C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph id="H943F78DC1BBE4007AB6729DF5C5C7D80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person may not offer for sale or lease to a first purchaser an optional safety feature unless such person—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HABF1876B76F548E58F2640ADC9A5568E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offers such optional safety feature for sale or lease—</text> <clause id="HB72B6BA9948340CEA9007D7789D80D77"><enum>(i)</enum><text>separately from any non-safety feature; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFFA9AE436D1C44CB82C1AEFB0E2E120A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as standard trim equipment; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E73FBB072154AB8823367E0B0D03588"><enum>(B)</enum><text>clearly and conspicuously discloses to the first purchaser the cost of the optional safety feature separately from any non-safety feature.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC7B2D583C384426984D2D6E6927AE212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEE49EF460BA84BCD9E4396110819DBC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Commission</header> <paragraph id="H231CDF7A47394D5DAAB4FE2EFC05B9B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A61E1D168A2479BBAF1233E77F269DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce subsection (a) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE072BC7B3BCF44B3A6812E987B972705"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H93E9E6D99E2F4EDCB267F51A7245170E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Actions by States</header> 
<paragraph id="H4B55D5EEF42745E68E914E0A082E62AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (6), in any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of that State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of subsection (a), or a regulation promulgated under such subsection, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States or other court of competent jurisdiction to—</text> <subparagraph id="H10CCB3D1DDAC4876838D52E056CB2AF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin that practice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA69EF6636FF46138DEA191213778EA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such subsection, or such regulation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74C44D95F8104E7598715CA29386EE33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain civil penalties;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7BE0CF7B91345929ADA54AD336CDE72"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H777150C49C224977A768BA496367952F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>obtain such other legal and equitable relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72EA5DC2922646578719E21F2D7C309C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of Commission</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE8612A2364CA40C287FB8B940D3C65C8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice</header> 
<clause id="H6B3E16B50B9142ADB2BF8B5CE719BB60"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (iii), the attorney general of a State shall notify the Commission in writing that the attorney general intends to bring a civil action under paragraph (1) by not later than 60 days before initiating the civil action.</text></clause> <clause id="H2F7404EDA36B4D8A8007CD9ED6986267"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notification required by clause (i) with respect to a civil action shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE75507607DBA47AE93195FD26AD73A57"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required by clause (i) before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF5F5B09D37D4DC99C8D1530C14B81AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intervention</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving the notice required by subparagraph (A), the Commission shall have the right—</text> 
<clause id="HB3AB106F276845A4ACABC524CCB53B8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to intervene in the action; and</text></clause> <clause id="H931790DF86214AE198095688BF74422A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon so intervening—</text> 
<subclause id="HB6367622D6EA4018A7347EF2A3F45166"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB98CAF578FF9489C8AF34F908F6D65E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></subclause></clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EFC282BA14F4C7D8397E3643FC2432A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigatory powers; savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to—</text> <subparagraph id="H0715B556C38F4E8C994E061830ECFBC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD46311A4D71345A88530E2788C02DF00"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit the attorney general of a State, or other authorized State officer, from proceeding in State or Federal court on the basis of an alleged violation of any civil or criminal statute of that State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9662C069E9BC4AC4B821737C6AB6AEB6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation on state action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission or the Attorney General of the United States has instituted a civil action for violation of this Act (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>Federal action</quote>), no State attorney general, official, or agency may bring an action under this subsection during the pendency of the Federal action against any defendant named in the complaint in the Federal action for any violation of such subsection alleged in such complaint.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9D533C99F21145DA966B227812D040B6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Award of costs and fees</header><text>If a State prevails in any civil action under paragraph (1), the State may recover reasonable costs and attorney fees.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF01CAECAE81B47C38FD9B55A1C2F8100" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6B035C42D86D4B81AA418A4F8C6F2EFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10276D9FAC46427A8A5D32ADEF37DA91"><enum>(2)</enum><header>First purchaser; manufacturer; motor vehicle; motor vehicle equipment</header><text>The terms <term>first purchaser</term>, <term>manufacturer</term>, <term>motor vehicle</term>, and <term>motor vehicle equipment</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 30102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEA483076CFC49F19E053B0B08F109CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Motor vehicle model</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle model</term> means a class of motor vehicles—</text> <subparagraph id="HF2804713B15C49D597CD1E03E427C428"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of the same type and make; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA36484A15A2544CDBE10846C9B09DE00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that share a high degree of commonality in design and construction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C3EB88009B24FC690299B3A5B5E42EE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Motor vehicle trim</header><text>The term <term>motor vehicle trim</term> means a class of motor vehicles—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7C20A9F9E709409CB8B7EC0F4810CE94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of the same type, make, and motor vehicle model, but not identical to the motor vehicle model; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4645FE024D084CBEA31D1B6F5E156E6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that share a high degree of commonality in design and construction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98484109DF0D410FA69DCD008F8816B4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-safety feature</header><text>The term <term>non-safety feature</term> means optional motor vehicle equipment that is not standard model equipment or an optional safety feature.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07EBA93BFB0340C9B46090C5A8FDD162"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Optional safety feature</header><text>The term <term>optional safety feature</term> means motor vehicle equipment that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HED25471B0BC84105870558E3F9E7FD8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not standard model equipment; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5151E346D394B0F819B53C4E176B240"><enum>(B)</enum><text>either—</text> 
<clause id="H349674A8F8EE471FB61BFDA9A8959995"><enum>(i)</enum><text>performs the lateral or longitudinal (but not both simultaneously) vehicle motion control subtasks of the dynamic driving task with the expectation that the driver monitors the system to execute a response to an object or event when necessary;</text></clause> <clause id="H2230A2E0C6A24A7990FB5B0D6DD1237A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>alerts the driver—</text> 
<subclause id="H8D6ED8CCEC274A11BC4DDE0C0F276C3A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if there is an unreasonable risk of a collision;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC8C99FBDE6F342BEB69971A7A7F9E08D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to maintain the lane of travel; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5AEF118CF24046539E79092F8E818E98"><enum>(III)</enum><text>if the driver is operating the motor vehicle in a way that indicates the driver may be distracted, disengaged, fatigued, intoxicated, or otherwise impaired;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H8B8010F2EE414550B19A3BB7537BCCFF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improves illumination of the roadway;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H53937AE808FC406CAC2110C495DD9136"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>enhances the view of the driver of the roadway;</text></clause> <clause id="HE4265DE086F64BC69A6D66C7B05EAC2B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>alerts emergency services after a crash of the motor vehicle is detected; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE61FEE785CC2435B822E30DFBC661524"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>performs such other safety functions as the Commission, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3D636FA44AF46B6AFEBBB12101991B6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Standard model equipment</header><text>The term <term>standard model equipment</term> means motor vehicle equipment installed in each motor vehicle within a motor vehicle model, regardless of the motor vehicle trim.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8249A45CE0114D9FA3150DF1A00E93B2"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Standard trim equipment</header><text>The term <term>standard trim equipment</term> means motor vehicle equipment installed in each motor vehicle of a motor vehicle trim.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

