<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0ED7676D067C48CD88E199F10C711750" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9232 IH: Critical Infrastructure Airspace Defense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9232</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000139">Mr. Van Epps</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To grant authority to use counter-unmanned aircraft system technologies to private owners of critical infrastructure facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H09EC56ABE3C040EC9AA4B8B18ED448BB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5B81EF2327D04A22AE70E8169EE16E0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Critical Infrastructure Airspace Defense Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H03CAC69BDFE7451FBA6DCA5CEAE46540"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HFF06EA41B87A43DBB7B2C021786CE688"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The North American electric grid and other critical infrastructure sectors face growing threats from unmanned aircraft systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EB61B2975244C2FAEE6A00A44E7E992"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Counter-unmanned aircraft systems activities are authorized for Federal agencies and for trained State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement, but private owners and operators of critical infrastructure lack clear statutory authority to independently detect, track, and mitigate in-flight unmanned aircraft systems threats.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2B033CBF4E348629764574EE95D6879"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prompt action is required to close this gap and protect the reliability of the bulk power system and other critical infrastructure.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HE9389551F5B942BE9EBF68F91BDAC08D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Drone countermeasures for critical infrastructure owners and operators</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H5AA6D18A3F8B4176936AFA893E6092EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25D2AF168FB14C1C9DFD0D26A4A91238"> <paragraph id="H73FAD6EFC887412F89584E72F593352E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority of critical infrastructure owners and operators</header><text>Notwithstanding section 46502 of title 49, United States Code, or sections 32, 1030, 1367, and chapters 119 and 206 of title 18, United States Code, and after completing the training and certification detailed in subsection (d)(3), any owner or operator of a covered critical infrastructure facility (or designated security personnel or contractors of such owner or operator) may, subject to subsection (d)(3), take, and authorize personnel to take, such actions as are described in subsection (b)(1) that are necessary to mitigate a credible threat that an unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft poses to the safety or security of a covered critical infrastructure facility.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H102EC5A11F674140939AF2EF2419F0A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5438A01E5E024426BADBDA5ACAC6C6EF"> <paragraph id="H46161802E9EB405FA291C3327D595884"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text>Any unmanned aircraft system or unmanned aircraft seized pursuant to subsection (a)(3) shall be subject to forfeiture under the laws of the jurisdiction in which the seizure occurred, consistent with procedures established by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H32690DF398344259BA3F9976BDE4FFB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05FAFE4631A44A7B9C2BD498FC082DA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(D), by striking <quote>counter-UAS</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>counter-unmanned aircraft system</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3F18614B3E384102AFB762306182E82D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACCF7C2ADF2248EDBBE5DC260AF1034C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86A9F97D4F654C90915BEEEAC8A61E0F">
<paragraph id="H3427C9A359074060AD482331A39BAAB3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure training and certification</header>
<subparagraph id="H7F819B616D984B5FB8F69A3D333306AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Only personnel who have been trained and certified by the Secretary (in coordination with the Secretary of Energy and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration) may exercise the authorities granted under subsection (a)(3).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1044A340EF10478F97E5D1077E22C964"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Critical Infrastructure Airspace Defense Act</short-title>, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Transportation, shall establish a national certification program, which may utilize or expand the national schoolhouse established under paragraph (2), that includes—</text>
<clause id="HD212C45CA9A443709C65F9BB17123A9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>standards for legal, operational, and technical proficiency;</text></clause> <clause id="H4FD84C678A5C4755B21C9BC4087A981B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use of only counter-unmanned aircraft system technologies included on the joint authorized list described in paragraph (2)(A)(iii); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H79368D5363234CC9B26C092900351ED8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mandatory coordination protocols with the Federal Aviation Administration to protect the national airspace system.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H43C6333143664A76869FDCBC2345AA9C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Critical Infrastructure Airspace Defense Act</short-title>, and biannually thereafter, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Transportation, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an unclassified report with a classified annex on activities carried out by critical infrastructure owners and operators exercising the authority granted by subsection (a)(3) and subject to the training and certification requirements described in this paragraph, including—</text>
<clause id="H841C241279ED4A1E9F1AFA4ED1E54830" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the training and certification procedures developed and implemented pursuant to this paragraph; and</text></clause> <clause id="H376E3FE413A04B19BBBCA237A3664984" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of personnel that applied for and were certified to exercise the authorities granted by subsection (a)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9F1F8A55EFC546CA9049EE2DE8F02CD5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>each Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>the Secretary, the Secretary of Transportation</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B2D2A776EB04E01903C5C3F221E5BE1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(3), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (a)</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2B453DF27974BE3B3FD0F3DD759B583"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by striking <quote>subsection (k)(3)(C)(iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (l)(3)(C)(iii)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B9CFDB7091749B19F1F867D25515139"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (j), by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51132A952B104A448E7360255A65373A">
<paragraph id="H35AC830AA5E8440C8DFEF2F1FAFAB9F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure authority</header><text>The authority relating to critical infrastructure facilities established under subsection (a)(3) shall terminate on September 30, 2031.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F43A52060DB40F3A8E323BB8F3ED48F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subsection (k), by striking <quote>subsection (k)(3)(C)(iii)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (l)(3)(C)(iii)</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD20230B07194BD391AF38534F04B1A6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in subsection (l)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA25CA755654C4D4D87667DF44F887305"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (10);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9C229FE936D45C28BEE540E2E389167"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3), (4), (5), (6), (7), (8), and (9) as paragraphs (4), (6), (7), (8), (10), (9), and (5), respectively, and moving the paragraphs so as to appear in numerical order;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61700873EB184E77A260D7C2C032D5F5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A8AC07B06CE43FE9D98343ED268CF26">
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H55F59E5D05B740B79374BEE555D010AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>covered critical infrastructure facility</term> means a critical infrastructure facility designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, as a high-risk site, including, at a minimum, nuclear generating stations, key substations, transformer stations, and control centers of the bulk power system.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCC2B4FA5619342C495633A8EE2206C88"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>meaning</quote> and inserting <quote>meanings</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF0C352B4A414EBA81411B7FC99CE89C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (8), as so redesignated, by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0AC8CD1734944D77A822B5655C738091"> <subparagraph id="H8536F666CE73421D89FBAF8FA05AB7EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(3), the term <term>personnel</term> means officers, employees, or contractors of the owner or operator of a covered critical infrastructure facility who are assigned duties that include the security or protection of the facility.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H171E2A7198944EF586061EAC30E9AE49"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), as so redesignated, by striking the comma after <quote>44801</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H0569D69B26F045AEA601BF88E7BCC2FE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Critical infrastructure counter-unmanned aircraft system grant program</header> <subsection id="H3ED947D0A42243EDA4FDD4C28C2965E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, shall establish a counter-unmanned aircraft system grant program for critical infrastructure owners and operators to purchase, install, and operate approved counter-unmanned aircraft systems.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA324875F190C4095B22E5EADA4B9F21F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Grants may be awarded to owners and operators of covered critical infrastructure facilities, as defined in subsection (l)(3) of section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n</external-xref>), as added by this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H55EA64969C854566BBC0850FFBE6E153"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $250,000,000 for fiscal years 2027 through 2031 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HCAE05E1ECE6C4837815D5B52EDB032FB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Liability protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any action taken in accordance with the authorities granted under subsection (a)(3) of section 210G of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/124n">6 U.S.C. 124n</external-xref>), as added by this Act, shall be deemed to be a Federal action for purposes of liability protection, and no owner, operator, or authorized personnel, as defined in subsection (l) of such section 210G, as added by this Act, shall be liable for any civil or criminal claim arising from such authorized action, except in cases of gross negligence or willful misconduct.</text></section> <section id="HECC3D4CE33814038854A978BCC07C4F3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking and implementation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Energy, the Attorney General, and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, shall issue regulations and guidance to implement this Act, including procedures for real-time coordination with the national airspace system.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

