<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EDW25402-K3G-VN-WV2"><form><distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3972</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To modify a provision relating to adjustments of certain State apportionments for Federal highway programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Highway Formula Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idFF20ABCD411B41F5AA4A2D4A7FF4BE90"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adjustments to certain State apportionment amounts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 104 of title 23, United States Code, is amended by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5748E7C5289244AEB6AFF75C97EE00F8"><subsection id="id4F94025FF89F4521B8946438F1EFBEB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Calculation of amounts</header><paragraph id="id38B4EA492FA54A63A44924F31927301F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State share</header><text>For fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter, the amount for each State of combined apportionments for the national highway performance program under section 119, the surface transportation block grant program under section 133, the highway safety improvement program under section 148, the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program under section 149, the national highway freight program under section 167, the carbon reduction program under section 175, to carry out subsection (c) of the PROTECT program under section 176, and to carry out section 134 shall be determined as follows:</text><subparagraph id="idB61519897B34479DB3FAD0D056AEC607"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial amount</header><text>The initial amount for each State shall be determined by multiplying the total amount available for apportionment by the share for each State, which shall be equal to the proportion that—</text>
                            <clause id="idAF577FCF82DF4246A03E86CCB3E6E622">
                                <enum>(i)</enum>
                                <text>the amount of apportionments that the State received for
                                    fiscal year 2012; bears to</text>
                            </clause><clause id="id023DB19D9B9D498B934F6C53E311105D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of those apportionments received by all States for that fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9C6E7A59929D4781974E896985BA640B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adjustments to amounts</header><clause id="id3557C3B5F2AD4D2EB2E83BDB2D66CB53"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The initial amounts resulting from the calculation under subparagraph (A) shall be adjusted to ensure that, for each State, the amount of combined apportionments for the programs shall not be less than an amount equal to—</text><subclause id="idCF29BB0CFDEF4C32BBCC6D91EFAF592F">
                                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                                    <text>95 percent of the applicable percentage; multiplied
                                        by</text>
                                </subclause><subclause id="idBF433AF801EE4DEE9DEA2F2526A7CF4E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total amount of funds available for apportionment.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id57504B7F91DB4997B2AF1B5FBB20720F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the applicable percentage shall be an amount, expressed as a percentage, equal to the quotient of—</text><subclause id="id0F8473876AC5463D9FA71BE95B95D842">
                                    <enum>(I)</enum>
                                    <text>the estimated tax payments attributable to highway users
                                        in the State that were paid into the Highway Trust Fund
                                        (other than the Mass Transit Account) for the most recent
                                        fiscal year for which data are available; divided by</text>
                                </subclause><subclause id="id59D64A68C05848DD993AA0B84F6EAEA3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the estimated total tax payments attributable to users in all States that were paid into the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) for that fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDD3A553E565143949A50473B70FB9A8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State apportionment</header><text>On October 1 of each fiscal year described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall apportion the sum authorized to be appropriated for expenditure on the national highway performance program under section 119, the surface transportation block grant program under section 133, the highway safety improvement program under section 148, the congestion mitigation and air quality improvement program under section 149, the national highway freight program under section 167, the carbon reduction program under section 175, to carry out subsection (c) of the PROTECT program under section 176, and to carry out section 134 in accordance with paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>
