<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H254F772B4E60447BB1C86CE9C4A39352" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7052 IH: Conflict Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7052</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Center for Conflict Analysis, Planning, and Prevention in the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC8821380E2AE40EA905D3E2AA42437E8" style="OLC"><section id="HCE4516E35D0A480BBB8CF0FAD3B2EB90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Conflict Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC8BA6008419149FCAD74F7364F4AAE32"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HEE5F373304CF490C88E559FF0AE5D609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>better understanding and responding to conflict and supporting peace processes and complex political negotiations will further United States national security and foreign policy interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA279C24E243B48F283FEBCA5158EABD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of State should possess an institutional hub to help regional bureaus and embassies efficiently and effectively address violent conflict, peace processes, and complex political negotiations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F7DD7835EF143B095BA61D24EBE591B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such an institutional hub should be staffed by subject matter experts that can equip United States diplomats in conflict analysis and peace negotiations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H513569D5660E4F8D8D8D0C2C7AFAB420"><enum>3.</enum><header>Center for conflict analysis, planning, and prevention at the Department of State</header><subsection id="HED50C1605DB14A6280453D498572194C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There shall be in the Department of State a Director for Conflict Analysis, Planning, and Prevention, who shall be responsible to the Secretary of State, acting through the Under Secretary for Political Affairs, for matters relating to conflict prevention, mitigation, and negotiations to develop policy options and provide expertise for the Under Secretary of Political Affairs and for the Assistant Secretaries of each regional bureau.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D4E483418EE44208F7A38138F3A8A71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>In addition to the responsibilities described under subsection (a), the Director and the Center established under subsection (c) may carry out the following, as appropriate:</text><paragraph id="H5EC559493BFB4E6790DFE77FA8AFC5EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Developing advanced analytic methodologies, data, and tools to understand global conflict dynamics, produce conflict trend assessments, and inform the Department’s efforts to prevent and mitigate conflict and crises of top priority to the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B91304BD774E7FAABEA3D4682F66D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Forecasting potential hotspots of violent conflict in foreign countries to best identify risks to United States national security interests or opportunities for advancing United States foreign policy priorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C25B6F8B33E4C3CA7E1785881F69525"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Conducting in-depth analyses of conflict dynamics in foreign countries to—</text><subparagraph id="H3FE321D61158408682580A9EE0F143FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise regional bureaus on program goals and approaches to burden-sharing with foreign partners; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4688CF1AD604F1DA9F6CE501D6FE193"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide quantifiable metrics to inform effective use of the Department’s resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5CDA94CDF5A4C1DABF3BF394C34C964"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Supporting peace processes by providing expertise to the Under Secretary of Political Affairs, regional bureaus, and chiefs of mission, to enable and inform peace negotiation and mediation strategies, implementation, and monitoring.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9D5FB306FEF4CD0A88C3FF0400E7ED5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>At the direction of the Under Secretary, coordinating with regional and relevant functional bureaus on the implementation of the Global Fragility Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9801">22 U.S.C. 9801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H527680EC6D054384A394BC849FA79030"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Providing strategic gaming, <quote>red team</quote> (contrarian-structured analytic techniques to challenge assumptions and test vulnerabilities), and table-top exercises, to rigorously test foreign policy options and strategies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90339BFCB70541F4ABBF570947F4F77E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Supporting the development of training for Foreign Service officers on conflict prevention and mediation skills, including the trainings required under the Elie Wiesel Genocide and Atrocities Prevention Act of 2018.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H768FD05A3370465A96954A313DC6BEB5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Such other functions as the Under Secretary for Political Affairs may designate from time to time.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14F56E4814E74E2E88125E7D6A9FFD19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be in the Department a Center for Conflict Analysis, Planning, and Prevention (in this section referred to as the <quote>Center</quote>), led by the Director appointed pursuant to the authorization under subsection (a), which shall perform functions related to data analysis and strategic planning on emerging or ongoing foreign conflicts to develop policy options and provide expertise for the Under Secretary of Political Affairs and for the Assistant Secretaries of each regional bureau.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1250BC9D89C46AEB59ADF4CB2315CD9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Dissemination of analytic products</header><text>The Under Secretary shall ensure that the Center’s analytic products are disseminated to relevant stakeholders within the Department, as well as other elements of the United States Government, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE7A2D3BF70274CDBAD9BE80269E1D483"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Center shall be comprised of not more than 20 full-time Department employees, including a contingent capable of temporary deployments to support embassies—</text><paragraph id="HDFE96793CB4E4C1A997A41C7957034C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in conflict-affected regions; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCECBBAD00A6E42719C4F628FBF62DA27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in regions that the Under Secretary for Political Affairs determines to be at risk of conflict or civil strife.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

