<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26434-CJF-N9-46S"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 725 ATS: Congratulating the University of Oklahoma women's gymnastics team for winning the 2026 National Collegiate Athletic Association Championship, the eighth national title in program history.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 725</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S440">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the University of Oklahoma women's gymnastics team for winning the 2026 National Collegiate Athletic Association Championship, the eighth national title in program history.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the 2026 University of Oklahoma women's gymnastics team (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>Sooners</quote>), under the direction of head coach K.J. Kindler, won the program’s eighth National Collegiate Athletic Association (referred to in this preamble as the <quote>NCAA</quote>) championship title with a final score of 198.1625, defeating Louisiana State University, the University of Florida, and the University of Minnesota.</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Sooners scored a 49.600 on vault, a 49.4875 on bars, a 49.4375 on beam, and a 49.6375 on floor;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Sooners have competed for the NCAA championship in the team finals 12 out of the last 13 years;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Sooners rank third in the number of team national titles in NCAA women’s gymnastics history;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Sooners posted a 35–1–1 record, secured the Southeastern Conference regular season title for the second year in a row, and won an NCAA Regional Championship for the 16th straight year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 8 Sooner student athletes combined for 15 All-America honors; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Faith Torrez won the individual all-around national championship and Keira Wells won the vault national championship, giving the Sooners 24 all-time individual national titles: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idd95834ffde9c45c1a51d436392a965f2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the 2026 University of Oklahoma women's gymnastics team for their hard work and dedication to the sport and for the excitement they bring to the University of Oklahoma, the State of Oklahoma, and to Sooners everywhere; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id486a8927a2ce4663a4a52383d7975869"><enum>(2)</enum><text>congratulates the 2026 University of Oklahoma women's gymnastics team on a wonderful season.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

