<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDDDD6E893A2A4D838B549EEE253B1B04" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7753 IH: First Look for First-time Homebuyers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7753</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen and standardize <quote>first look</quote> protections for covered properties to ensure first-time homebuyers have priority access to foreclosed homes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H537E0D8C65E34553B912C5DB7F31E5B1" style="OLC"><section id="HB717D75F168E4F8D95A0377451E3DBA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Look for First-time Homebuyers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H932F8FD1CAFE47968E06D1D0D8A820BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>First look protections for first-time homebuyers</header><subsection id="H3C76229E14C04FA2897147298306AA08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H39DA752E3C0B4B08A9B8D730D8673981"><enum>(1)</enum><header>15-day first look period</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), each covered entity shall ensure, when selling an covered property, that the covered property is only available for purchase by first-time homebuyers during the 15-day period beginning on the date that the covered property is listed for sale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H537192E84F504FC293AFE9E839BCBD81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension of period</header><text>A covered entity may extend the period described in paragraph (1) if such extension would increase the chance of a first-time homebuyer purchasing a covered property.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F46B813498147DAA4744D64961DA102" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pricing of covered properties</header><paragraph id="HDB8B97FA8C244D02B4BD38EF2237C4D9" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 15-day period beginning on the date that the covered property is listed for sale during which an covered property is only available for purchase by first-time homebuyers the covered property shall be offered by the covered entity at a price that is the fair market value of the property as determined by an independent third-party appraisal or broker price opinion not more than 60 days before the date on which the property was listed for sale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67866F9F46BC4224B3610076CB59FE6A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the covered entity selling the covered property determines that the fair market value of the property can not be determined by an independent third-party appraisal or broker price opinion not more than 60 days before the date on which the property was listed for sale the covered entity may offer the covered property at a price based on a standardized valuation model used by the covered entity if the covered entity publically discloses the methodology used by such standardized valuation model.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H370151664FAC4DD09389D4A1ED7ECBCE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Listing on public website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 15-day period beginning on the date that the covered property is listed for sale during which an covered property is only available for purchase by first-time homebuyers the covered property shall be listed on a publically accessible website by the covered entity in a manner that identifies the covered property as only available for purchase by first-time homebuyers and indicates how many days remain in the 15-day period during which the covered property is only available for purchase by first-time homebuyers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H77228F25D762449A867B679373AAF799" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on bundling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity may not bundle covered properties during the 15-day period beginning on the date that the covered property is listed for sale by the eligible entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFFD51F3FF58542BBB3DB466A14CA5641"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date described in subsection (h), and every 6 months thereafter, each covered entity shall submit to the Congress a report that describes—</text><paragraph id="HD37D6C09C2BC4EADBAAE6462C1D05288"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of offers made by first-time homebuyers for covered properties during the 15-day window;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB81CDF640884AA79241845D48246EEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of covered properties sold to first-time home buyers during the 15-day window;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DEA613EC08246378DFDC710EE0F71B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the pricing methodology used; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C6B8C2AC0764B7385D0ED13F00B6BBC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the ratio of the sale price to the fair market value as determined by an independent third party appraisal, broker price opinion, or standardized valuation model.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88CE2E25EED149ACA9C976F67860D726" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="HD57EDC960E06422D9D18641C887FFF98" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Inspectors General of each covered entity shall, each year, review all sales of covered properties by the covered entity in the prior year and determine whether any provisions of this section were violated during such sale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H645BD14DAB2A4A2FA1BB6C39D23F9C85" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspectors General of each covered entity shall submit a report to the Congress each year that includes the results of the review conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H938A8794D9F44E6193D8C72EBD74E7C6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspectors General of each covered entity shall publish the report submitted under paragraph (2) on a publically accessible website of the covered entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA475474D38704178A20D3AFF400E0A19" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered entity shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, issue such rules as are necessary to carry out this section and such rules shall include a process to verify the eligibility of first-time homebuyers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4186FE72EF7B46A99D23B54F0CDBB82A" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect 30 days after the date of the final rulemaking described in subsection (g).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2420731347514A0E92D5DF00FDA46ECF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H65E0B3A4E62C47939225FD21DC57FCB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered property</header><subparagraph id="HA1ECB89ED68A4492839635EFDBDCCDC5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>covered property</term> means any single-family residential property made up of 1 to 4 units that is owned or foreclosed upon by a covered entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25A8C20D89DF45B5B019FC4EA2E75E28"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good Neighbor Next Door Program</header><text>For the purposes of this Act, a covered property shall not include any property under the program known as the <quote>Good Neighbor Next Door Program</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FC12422BC644ECD955B0AE9D421F1C1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC0E447D8AB1A4DAFA9C1A729DEF3C35D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Housing Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4D7D15DC7E94CA9AB385ACB2D32C691" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Federal Housing Finance Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92EA19164F61422EA13B3165AF5B9CD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal National Mortgage Association;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55D3D93A06A34B789A9026ED5758EECD"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A7FCC60B5334C4F8FC95D05E9FAC308"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E69B77171B3454A8ED47CE5A3D943FA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>First-time homebuyer</header><text>The term <quote>first-time homebuyer</quote> means any individual if such individual, or such individual’s spouse, has not had a present ownership interest in a principal residence at any time prior to the date of sale to which this Act applies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

