<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0524A8AB0EBA4193B283768F9C379B32" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5970 IH: Save Our Ships Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5970</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to support the conservation and preservation of historic military ships and submarines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEF8FF62AF1E243DE8B127C3F4A7E5DDA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4104026936C347DA847C7609E4464A6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save Our Ships Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9FD24D77E77A49E998256FDDAEF7D69B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Historic Naval Ship Preservation Grant Program</header> <subsection id="HC7A950F57E5E40DDAC75FD9CC85D36CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Department of the Interior the Historic Naval Ship Preservation Grant Program to support the physical preservation of historic military vessels, ensuring the continued availability of these vessels to the American public to educate on the past and inspire the future of United States military maritime endeavors.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5DE7ACAF59947CBA46D0A10345D53B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Program shall be administered by the Secretary, in consultation with the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Defense.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H37274FADB6EA485D926FCA56EBF83244"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant uses</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities for the following activities:</text> 
<paragraph id="H51760E73D9384D09A5D1E8419DCAEEF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Conserving and preserving historic military vessels at covered sites, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HD593E69F7CA74CF0A213D827272E2ECD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>physical upkeep and repair of the vessels; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H843C9FDC93254EE3AB1D4A3E3B2B4D3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mitigating environmental hazards or damage to the vessels. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H674C5D35DEB44655BB68DEA2FF6DBAE4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implementing education and workforce development programs related to military maritime careers, including shipbuilding and submarine construction. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB147CEAA5AFF403A8BC37747F8ABF659"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header> 
<paragraph id="HE2E99DFA3CB9475C92D625B374F18C16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may award grants to a unit of State or local government or a private nonprofit organization that administers a covered site.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5633B903121F4F3896E626E7BCA8A038"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an organization that administers a covered site shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H21AF03CADC874B8285EC1119A5FAB200"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the Program $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HA22C1D6F3FC14E1F8C91967B06AFB2AE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H47D0995823D8464EA40E7F811E3FE6AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered site</header><text>The term <term>covered site</term> means a museum, memorial, monument, educational center, or other venue that provides public access to, or publicly displays, a historic military vessel.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8D1910FE13340B4AF9D8965091D1E3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historic military vessel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>historic military vessel</term> means a vessel that has been decommissioned or otherwise removed from service and—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F3D8B5EFB2145B9925A5326C73766F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was owned and operated by the Department of Defense or the Coast Guard, other than a time- or voyage-chartered vessel; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD934778B66E40DFAF2053005A82E9E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was owned and operated by the Department of Transportation and designated by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating as a vessel equivalent to a vessel described in subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3170CD9E5DBE4B7CBEFD173ABC7DC97B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>was built for, or pursuant to a contract with, the United States Maritime Commission or other legacy branch of the Department of Transportation and at some point in the vessel’s service was equipped with armaments and embarked Navy Armed Guard personnel to operate the armaments. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D396B15B63D4EC7A46E5428FA75A8D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Historic Naval Ship Preservation Grant Program established by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF928418EA86F4921BB0C21B78C56A36A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

