<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0FB2903B405B4DBC808A5AE148649613" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5820 IH: Mono Lake Kootzaduka’a Tribe Recognition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251024">October 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000401">Mr. Kiley of California</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To extend Federal recognition to the Mono Lake Kootzaduka’a Tribe, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDFF5565707E5426B9E1C1AA026A223F3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H474CD01BBB4542D7B2F679E4FC6C533B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mono Lake Kootzaduka’a Tribe Recognition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HDAD4CACBBD6B47BBBAFB8B736FA4312E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9DE05F67D20D4BF1B782E63928B7B2B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Member</header><text>The term <quote>member</quote> means an individual who is enrolled in the Tribe pursuant to the constitution of the Tribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1CC3F0B93BA4550A6B540C9CE362089"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BDE1249C27C451AB915C53243D47906"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Tribe</quote> means the Mono Lake Kootzaduka’a Tribe.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H81DB56F6BF6E4991AB6FF0258DF4B0B5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal recognition</header> 
<subsection id="H8EB5CB88B82B4139ABEE2335A2706F16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Federal recognition is extended to the Tribe.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0C2481B9E37C4DA49AC90B0314F15492"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Effect of Federal laws</header> <text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, all Federal laws (including regulations) of general application to Indians and Indian tribes, including the Act of June 18, 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5101">25 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the Indian Reorganization Act), shall apply to the Tribe and members.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H9982857312C04550AB58DFB546B67058"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal services and benefits</header> 
<subsection id="H3130C51CB5644BBDA5207DB664AC72D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Tribe and each member of the Tribe shall be eligible for all services and benefits provided by the United States to Indians and federally recognized Indian Tribes, without regard to—</text> <paragraph id="H4C685AF6D00044CA9CBA39D1EFF19BC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the existence of a reservation for the Tribe; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7757E76545404AD58BB6877F4CFD33D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the location of the residence of any member on or near an Indian reservation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H73947146BE5E4C23BECE1AD5D26E980C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Service area</header><text>For purposes of the delivery of services and benefits to members, the service area of the Tribe shall be considered to be the counties of Mono and Inyo, in the State of California.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB6BF548CF88A40B2A2FE2160428CA287"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reaffirmation of rights</header> 
<subsection id="H8A91848502594014A0B2B84225BDC05C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act diminishes any right or privilege of the Tribe or any member that existed before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF869C5A77123465AB4E9059D7A6FDA40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Claims of tribe</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, nothing in this Act alters or affects any legal or equitable claim of the Tribe to enforce any right or privilege reserved by, or granted to, the Tribe that was wrongfully denied to, or taken from, the Tribe before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7305A61E9214745B0B338E26F7BAA4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hunting and fishing rights</header><text>The Tribe shall be granted hunting and fishing rights on all Federal lands within its aboriginal land area. Each Federal agency who administers lands within the Tribe’s aboriginal land area shall work with the Tribe so as to accommodate the exercise of its hunting and fishing rights within the agencies existing land use plans, Federal law and governing regulations.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFCA7733C1B404ADEBEB5CEE3630713BC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Membership roll</header> <subsection id="HC8FCB5BD8C96458EB2E5343064D0F796"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of receiving recognition, services, and benefits pursuant to this Act, the Tribe shall submit to the Secretary, by not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, a membership roll consisting of the name of each individual enrolled as a member of the Tribe.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7CA982BE0E804FB988B29D2C3D421CAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination of membership</header><text>The qualifications for inclusion on the membership roll of the Tribe shall be determined in accordance with section (a) of Article III of the constitution of the Tribe, dated June 23, 2003.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD15D4AE65BA54895A6EC58ECF5D21E07"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maintenance of roll</header><text>The Tribe shall maintain the membership roll.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA30B75D855A24B07B142B6207F3CC5AA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Trust land</header> 
<subsection id="H4BE7A13590384FA687DF897884C91DE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of land</header><text>The Secretary shall identify land administered by the Bureau of Land Management that is located in that portion of Mono County that is within the Tribe’s ancestral homelands, sufficient to support the location of Tribal Government administration and services, economic development, and housing.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9748BABFD1DB49C5A897D3DF74DAB461"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Land into trust</header> <text>After the Secretary identifies said land to meet the purposes so described, the Tribe shall request and the Secretary shall accept such lands into trust for the benefit of the Tribe. Nothing in this section shall prevent the Secretary or the Tribe from acquiring land, and the Secretary taking land into trust for the benefit of the Tribe, pursuant to section 5 of the Act of June 18, 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5108">25 U.S.C. 5108</external-xref>; commonly known as the Indian Reorganization Act). For purposes of acquisitions under such Act, the Tribe shall be deemed to have been under Federal jurisdiction in 1934.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

