<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDEC1E04608EF457DA0FA6AADB63141A4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8288 IH: Strengthening Export Controls Compliance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8288</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to provide assistance for compliance with that Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3ADC85DEC12642BAAE0195D84F1CCEEF" style="OLC"><section id="HDCA1414841D7432E93225711EF073E33" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Export Controls Compliance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H429F6AFDD6194510A11B6DCF0C92F8B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H87831041BF9E4154B80EAAB8775E2628"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Export Control Reform Act of 2018 calls on the Secretary of Commerce <quote>to establish a system to provide United States persons with assistance in complying with</quote> United States export controls as well as <quote>keep the public appropriately apprised of changes in policy, regulations, and procedures</quote> established under that Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H881E22828A804377A963116DA642E4EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Export Control Reform Act of 2018 also calls on the Secretary of Commerce to report annually to Congress on <quote>efforts to provide exporters with compliance assistance, including specific actions to assist small- and medium-sized businesses</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3CBB7649AF4471980FFC664A64283A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Bureau of Industry and Security also generally holds an annual update conference on export controls to increase the public’s and industry’s understanding of United States export controls policies, as well as provide compliance guidance and regulatory updates.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7DD9EF8FD3B5421C88C8C37A19403F33"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HBF828569302B4CA9A6AAA6F74693B6F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it is critical for the national security and technological leadership of the United States that the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce consistently inform and educate United States businesses on evolving export control regulations and their implementation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E9A6457F44A4E19B5D9102E450DB26E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seminars and trainings offered by the Bureau of Industry and Security can serve as a valuable resource for United States businesses, especially small- and medium-sized enterprises, that do not have large compliance departments. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H53DD8C3C87104C5290562C722BF9914D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compliance assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1757 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4816">50 U.S.C. 4816</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H00F96B5F724046799A4A439DEF97C122" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H78EBC73A75BE4585A30E74B2A26FC53D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance for U.S. industry</header><paragraph id="H25B310D008EA4B05B7819EBA80E4D5B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Industry Outreach Plan</header><text>Every two years, the President shall develop and submit to Congress a plan to assist United States persons, especially small- and medium-sized United States businesses, in export licensing and other processes under this part. The plan should include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H994FD3C074D84040BA03AA053C8EEB3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Arrangements for the Department of Commerce to provide counseling to United States persons on filing applications and related submissions, including identifying items controlled under this part.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2F276E2DA504D32882ADA43206F5721"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Proposals for virtual and in-person trainings, seminars, and conferences to educate United States businesses on export controls, Bureau of Industry and Security licensing procedures, and related obligations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0EAF47181664781B6F22E7D428CA749"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other activities to facilitate compliance by United States businesses, including review of company compliance plans, follow-up on license conditions, and company specific consultations on specific issues.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA84D13337FD7420186FF70FB2309C542"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual conference</header><text>The Secretary shall host an annual conference, to be known as the <quote>Update Conference on Export Controls and Policy</quote>, to provide compliance assistance and policy updates to industry and other stakeholders. The conference should be listed on the Bureau of Industry and Security’s website and open to anyone from the general public. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00D573F148B74AAD971FA188F7B05BF8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance assistance for new rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to the promulgation of major new rules to carry out this part, the Bureau of Industry and Security shall carry out dedicated public and industry outreach to share details with respect to the intent and implementation of the rule, with the goal of strengthening compliance.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H28C9016CB7074241997D5424DD5AD19E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Amendments to the annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1765(a) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4824">50 U.S.C. 4824(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H37DA80FD5A7E49F1B5D7A9FCEA60951F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a review of</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC50BE49DF3A4E599D7C8124A4AE528E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), insert <quote>a detailed list of</quote> before <quote>efforts</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27D89F958E10462E92F9F44572FBB16D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), strike <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H102059625D7A46938E542B220FE561B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H488F9917C8A647FA8FB888C0BBA411B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBEEEC31713484F958BD74306E08E77CE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HC8DB2218475E4A7297BCECB6FAAF79C4"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the number of Advisory Opinion and Commodity Classification requests, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF8A61DD8A84F4C8C9F7AE02AD08E9989"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of requests submitted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE93ED8B4D314DA2AFEF1DA6C201215D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of Advisory Opinion or Commodity Classifications issued as a result of the requests submitted under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H934A27B51814475C9DEB561A858B7EB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the average processing times for each category of request; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A0258C71520416EA4FA539E8D4C5CC2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of redacted Advisory Opinions of general applicability posted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

