<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC26344-KXH-DV-N61"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4223 IS: First Island Chain Deterrence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4223</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Comptroller General of the United States to submit a report on the manner in which delays in arms deliveries to Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines affect the ability of the Department of Defense to build and sustain a strong denial defense in the First Island Chain.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Island Chain Deterrence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5d155cb53b9448aa76bc1ab08ded545"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idf46e383fb3d5471fbde42953c8247137"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a0aa6eeace24a9a80a6d5a66f14d492"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id221a461719ff4b5b8ea77f269f08b323"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1e574649d54f4617b0a4215dce93db2c"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">First Island Chain</header><text>The term <term>First Island Chain</term> means the chain of archipelagos extending from the Kuril Islands and Japan, through the Ryukyu Islands, Taiwan, and the Philippines, to Borneo, which form the first line of islands off the East Asian continental mainland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddeca8072ac6848f4979af1449ffce01a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Major defense equipment sales</header><text>The term <term>major defense equipment sales</term> means all foreign military sales that meet Defense Security Cooperation Agency thresholds for congressional notification under section 36 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2776">22 U.S.C. 2776</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f1d8edd984744d88247258a6e0d5937"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Strong denial defense</header><text>The term <term>strong denial defense</term> means the prevention of an adversary from taking aggressive action by demonstrating that success in such an action would be prohibitively difficult.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c2ba0da0f1347d19a9e46409ec14c01"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on delays in arms deliveries to Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb8115e5d47bc40bfa3af2f5cb8e0699d"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the manner in which delays in United States weapons sales to Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines through the foreign military sales process affect the ability of the Department of Defense to build, posture, and sustain a strong denial defense in the First Island Chain.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb6e8d0d1c30b4bafb9090a1fcf9cd6c7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="idca22de931d8b4a6e81b74dd7c5158eb7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the benefits to United States national security of United States arms deliveries to Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines, and the importance of interoperability in the event of a contingency across the Taiwan Strait.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3634b6b4df234815938ee3947207dc0a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idecadb031ec404e4c8bcfd8de01c8fd5f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current status of major defense equipment sales to Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines that have been approved but have not been completed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2218563b5b934a3bb7be8ef762a5c09d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relevant metrics for identifying delays in the timelines for delivery on such major defense equipment sales, including such delays attributable to—</text><clause id="ida366d92492514390ace04a852b11bc5e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Department of Defense review, procurement, and administration processes for the foreign military sales mechanism;</text></clause><clause id="idb21133432d3941d6ad9b4146919ed595"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>production constraints on the United States defense industrial base with respect to materiel currently under contract with Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines; or</text></clause><clause id="id05556f8c88454d13b010ef923023823b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Department of Defense prioritization of arms deliveries to allies and partners in the midst of conflict, such as allies in the Middle East region.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4df10b559ad64209a6d8d70b5f1e680a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of possible impacts of such delays on the ability of the Department of Defense to build, posture, and sustain a strong denial defense in the First Island Chain, including by enabling interoperability with Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd8544bc9ede4492183f92d7cfde8efae"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An evaluation, as applicable, of the impact any other relevant authority for arms sales or transfers to Japan, Taiwan, and the Philippines may have on the ability of the Department of Defense to build, posture, and sustain a strong denial defense in the First Island Chain.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida05dd3af3e3f485aadda66fb5e0e4086"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a)—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8e03c8e99e24a038e58f46357bc049f"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the maximum extent practicable, shall be submitted in unclassified form without any designation relating to dissemination control; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id470766edc14d45d6850887ca2782ed5b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf1b247caa8904f79a02ab36346e4394c"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support from Department of Defense</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall provide the Comptroller General with timely access to any appropriate information, data, and analyses requested by the Comptroller General under section 716 of title 31, United States Code, that is necessary to develop, in a timely, thorough, and independent manner, the report required by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

