<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H623F78F0C30D4259AFCF003B6381B0F8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7764 IH: National Threat Evaluation and Reporting Program Reassignment and Funding Reform Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7764</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000139">Mr. Van Epps</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the transfer to the Office for State and Local Law Enforcement of the Department of Homeland Security of the National Threat Evaluation and Reporting Program of the Department, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H484746A5D8814C798CF2361B346E962A" style="OLC"><section id="HFEB4243A936F4E5D9CD593B4E48F4444" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Threat Evaluation and Reporting Program Reassignment and Funding Reform Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC55241B4EA884E959B75EA65C754E31A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><subsection id="HE49D74A654B446439A2B7AC1EC677F96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H13F20114C9914471827BBBFDB9B4D561" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Threat Evaluation and Reporting (NTER) Program of the Department of Homeland Security plays a critical role in equipping State, local, Tribal, and territorial (SLTT) partners to identify, assess, and report threats of targeted violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5C0B15CBFC4EC68304E2B6F5D4ABB9"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>The NTER Program primarily serves non-Federal stakeholders and is operationally distinct from national intelligence priorities.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HDA11B4EEDB9D4DD3AF5689F3C2EEE67A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Office of State and Local Law Enforcement (OSLLE) is the primary DHS component responsible for coordination with SLTT law enforcement and is best positioned to manage the NTER Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H368786DE59494012998CA8A6BFE14E7D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Funding of the NTER Program through National Intelligence Program (NIP) appropriations is inconsistent with the program’s mission and scope.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD284F28856DC44D08F82FEC26B41A773"><enum>3.</enum><header>Transfer of NTER program</header><subsection id="H90D75109C75E4A3EB073DFB485C8C1FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer</header><paragraph id="H0518B1E17AD546A399AAE82400E61EC0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall transfer the National Threat Evaluation and Reporting Program to OSLLE from I&amp;A.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E9DC8E69D074F9789FD10BBEC52C4EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuity of operations</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure the continuity of mission and operations of the NTER Program during the pendency of the transfer under paragraph (1), and maintain engagement with SLTT partners throughout such pendency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC88AE7417E9487F8239B0DDF231E93F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personnel and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall transfer to OSLLE such personnel, assets, equipment, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, or other funds employed, held, used, available, or to be made available in connection with the NTER Program as necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA4A7CF4EFE841E5898E0AEDDE036529" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The transfer under this subsection shall not result in the reduction of capabilities or services provided to SLTT partners by the NTER Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0510DB50189444A488DC71C45371DCAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of National Intelligence Program funds</header><paragraph id="HAEDE3E3341BA4143A77A27D2CFDC7BDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds appropriated or otherwise made available under the National Intelligence Program may be obligated or expended for the NTER Program on or after the effective date of the transfer of the NTER Program in accordance with subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0323DA3DEDC46A2A002635115BB246A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative funding mechanisms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall identify and allocate appropriate non-NIP Program funding sources to support the continued operation and expansion of the NTER Program under OSLLE. Such funding sources may include appropriations made available to the Department of Homeland Security for State and local programs, preparedness grants, or other relevant nonintelligence funding streams.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6E08438F031427F880D2CE0E9F956FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 180 days thereafter for two years, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the following:</text><paragraph id="HC51109720534479EBFA88CCCDCC0EB6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The progress of the NTER Program transfer under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52E8A440D2784E09A9E672597A7B860A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The impact on NTER Program operations and SLTT stakeholder engagement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H731F2673DE794F9B9FEAFC8965AD19E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Funding adjustments made pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10F9262D6789447B8116DDF5924DDD1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any challenges encountered in such transfer and recommendations to address such challenges.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H659F3A02F80B4581B2B1EFC5BB807467"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H724AF8D71EB848A1B450CF114809A83D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>I&amp;A</header><text>The term <quote>I&amp;A</quote> means the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0665CCC3E6374B2684E2827235DA3B93"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Intelligence Program; NIP</header><text>The terms <quote>National Intelligence Program</quote> and <quote>NIP</quote> have the meaning given the term <quote>National Intelligence Program</quote> in section 3(6) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5017D179CE043FBAB46DF7656E3681D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Threat Evaluation and Reporting Program; NTER Program</header><text>The terms <quote>National Threat Evaluation and Reporting Program</quote> and <quote>NTER Program</quote> mean the initiative of the Department of Homeland Security designed to build threat assessment and management capabilities at the State, local, Tribal, and territorial governmental level to prevent targeted violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22D55886BCCE4B41AAE39DF32C07E46B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>OSLLE</header><text>The term <quote>OSLLE</quote> means the Office for State and Local Law Enforcement of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

