<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25L87-3N5-JF-FDL"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3451 IS: Houthi Human Rights Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3451</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the imposition of sanctions with respect to the Houthis, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC"><section id="HC9E769952F6F41F2B8D1F3ECA7E69600" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Houthi Human Rights Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0892CFA01E5246B285FA9EDFD0D2F22C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H06057384905047F183260E326BE6DBEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Houthi efforts to indoctrinate Yemenis into a violent, anti-Semitic, and extremist worldview are a threat to a Yemeni-led peace process and to regional stability; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8A6700FC7224E72808DECE6F993F7B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is counter to United States policy to provide support to the Houthis in Yemen, including by supporting any efforts by the Houthis to indoctrinate, coerce, or force Yemenis to conform to their violent, anti-Semitic, and extremist worldview.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC740DFDAF6BE4DBF8A0F8E12FAC61EF0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on Houthi indoctrination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text><paragraph id="H3EBA0797CC7C4E63B064ABF8A488C98D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Houthi efforts to indoctrinate Yemenis into a violent, anti-Semitic, or extremist worldview; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C08C5C3A043415FA83CCFB95D9BC5C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the long-term threat this indoctrination campaign poses to regional stability.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H23E3776EC3284FAFBF41FF9D975A55DE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on obstacles to provision of humanitarian aid in areas of Yemen under de facto Houthi control</header><subsection id="HA13FDB18288A4473ACAF54B09201475E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on obstacles to the provision of humanitarian aid by international organizations and nongovernmental organizations in areas of Yemen under de facto Houthi control.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE2A988285994332AB225493D2651258"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HEB4447AA3AF04140A8C298A87958ED96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An identification of challenges to distribution of humanitarian aid created by Houthi-enforced rules, regulations, and bureaucracy with respect to access, and freedom of movement, and the overall impact on such rules, regulations, and bureaucracy have on the international community’s ability to distribute such aid in a manner consistent with basic humanitarian principles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19CED26C2599452EA6345E668CD6C3D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of attempted Houthi interference in the delivery of humanitarian aid, including the manipulation or undue influence of beneficiary lists or related data for political or military purposes, and the implications of any interference on civilian needs and aid distribution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H339F68ACA0EC48B8A41852A318809964"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An evaluation of the Houthis’ use of violence and intimidation against humanitarian workers and diplomats, including current and former United States Embassy locally employed staff.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E928B76487845088864FBD23B8AA960"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An overview of the steps the United States and its partners are taking to ensure humanitarian assistance is delivered unhindered and consistent with basic humanitarian principles, including how United States-supported organizations respond to attempted Houthi diversion or interference.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CE1800671C44294B01251394D5E8A9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall address the period beginning on January 1, 2020, and ending on the date that is 90 days after date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCD8FF7E2BF5C4BFB982552FF697012AC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on human rights abuses committed by the Houthis</header><subsection id="HF87A614C92DC477697C43E9F0E3D94AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on human rights abuses committed by the Houthis, including gender-based discrimination and violence, including—</text><paragraph id="H810B0548891C47A8A2A8994891927FD6"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Mahram regulations;</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC167FABA7A5E4ED9A11DD0EFADE974D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the recruitment and use of child soldiers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1365CEB70BE4BE68DCC1F4B37B49D03"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enforced disappearance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7348A8424FEB40B487ED5C81B2E93AC5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prolonged and arbitrary detention;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C98DB21A3384517B719ECC00DC3D015"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conduct that amounts to torture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D2B2E612D1E474E8A6E2FB44152FA19"><enum>(6)</enum><text>unlawful killing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD014D520DFCB480099F5303FC3DAD8BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall address the period beginning on March 1, 2015, and ending on the date that is 90 days after date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H98EA8CE28F3B4CAF9CF3AA7314367DFD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sanctions authorized under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights and Accountability Act</header><subsection id="HA76CD3D387EE4BA3B59EC0624EFA916E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination on whether foreign persons described in subsection (b) meet the criteria for sanctions authorized under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights and Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) or are responsible for acts that constitute gross violations of internationally recognized human rights (as defined in section 502B(d)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)(1)</external-xref>)).</text></subsection><subsection id="H392B9D64E2D94BC89E217813CC959D38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>A foreign person described in this subsection is a foreign person that—</text><paragraph id="HCDBE6A1AA03C4F92BE60311B4DDB2C1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a member of the Houthis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3F0D950C23442BA976AB7CBC3488FD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>knowingly—</text><subparagraph id="H1FD5B9B3347C4B4BA7D75745FCC5F0A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>imposes unlawful restrictions on the delivery of humanitarian assistance in Yemen; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87FB36F3DA2C4F688D8A651B0817CED3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engages in the human rights abuses described in section 5(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF48163E1BB4B4372B444DB5D0EE0FAA2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sanctions authorized under the Robert Levinson Hostage Taking and Accountability Act</header><subsection id="HFA6392B3E40C41AE827D003C3AE44F6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a determination on whether foreign persons described in subsection (b) meet the criteria for sanctions authorized under the Robert Levinson Hostage Recovery and Hostage-Taking Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741">22 U.S.C. 1741 et seq.</external-xref>), and Executive Order 14078 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/1741">22 U.S.C. 1741</external-xref> note prec.; relating to bolstering efforts to bring hostages and wrongfully detained United States nationals home).</text></subsection><subsection id="HACE2EF6717C74FDF94A7A54E7B52A603"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>A foreign person described in this subsection is a foreign person that—</text><paragraph id="H2B76EA89FF7545489713B91DA87DEE69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a member of the Houthis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57A76856840C4385A45F89767C822266"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF7F59FEFAB3D405E98A886613A8D59E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is responsible for or is complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the hostage taking of a United States national abroad or the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national abroad; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB70E887A60A4D80A833078221F52BC6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>knowingly provides financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, an activity described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H83C2E3EE1AA24CB193AD0AA5B5B5FA01"><enum>8.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section><section id="H7B1B0313F58D4C688EC71107171AF143"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H732A9E1EBA314F71A4802F17AB9FFEFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF84B90D41CFA4A5D8F2AE087CACA4B6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ef1188e815d4fab9c45f6a7f798e405"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC4EE9B5D07247A892D808842B8FB9D7"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad00274dd6cb441e9831babf8f4f9da7">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD2610B7F57D4623A368FAB315C59361"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59C91452EEDE462B9399005EB8ACFC58" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Houthis</term> refers to persons officially known as <quote>Ansarallah</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF6248C79DC94D45BC7774DAB826422E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>person</term> means and individual or entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC8EC82D9236489B9E7E39D3EA5AF65D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HDC2C8E10043543289DA30DB56EAFB9D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a national of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92273B6998BB48C59DE9402EC742849C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alien who is lawfully present in the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H429C7977BF1E408AB47911C9E831CB1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

