<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H233E247837C644F0BD932418863F8C83" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1126 IH: Recognizing the role of Mae Krier and her contributions as she celebrates her 100th birthday.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1126</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the role of Mae Krier and her contributions as she celebrates her 100th birthday.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on March 21, 1926, Mae Krier was born in Dawson, North Dakota;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mae Krier answered the call to work on the wings of B–29 and B–17 aircraft at Boeing in Seattle during World War II, becoming an original <quote>Rosie the Riveter</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mae worked for Boeing for the entirety of the war, helping build over 6,000 aircraft;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, after the war, Mae moved to southeastern Pennsylvania with her family;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mae represents an example of the incredible women who stepped forward as Rosie the Riveters during World War II, representing a cultural shift that opened the doors for future generations of women;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, between 1940 and 1945, women entered the workforce in unprecedented numbers, with the percentage of women in the workforce jumping from 27 percent to nearly 37 percent;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Mae has been a fierce advocate for preserving and teaching the history of the Rosies, and their contributions on the homefront, which helped lead to the defeat of tyranny and the preservation of democracy;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mae’s efforts as a Rosie have been recognized with the Congressional Gold Medal, the highest civilian honor awarded by Congress;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the service, courage, and unyielding spirit of the Rosies serve as an example of American perseverance and resilience;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Mae is beloved by her children, her grandchildren, her great-grandchildren, and the entire community; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas honoring Mae Krier, in her efforts as a Rosie and in advocating for the memory of the Rosies, strengthens the Nation’s sense of patriotism and serves as an inspiration to young women across the country: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HF9156B05D4BC42FBBEA64B0CDD44BE35"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA8745C3B0E0F42B8AD3FBB9CF3175340"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives recognizes and thanks Mae Krier on her 100th birthday for her contributions to the Nation as a Rosie the Riveter and trailblazer.</text></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

