<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC8E434D0B2E94AE283C60EF0F9137F45" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9173 IH: Charitable Deductions for Digital Asset Donations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9173</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to except digital assets from the appraisal requirement applicable to certain charitable contributions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H59EE8928066D4B19A38AF69816966908" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H200645A29C6C449B82F042D9DF1FF7B3" section-type="section-one" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; etc</header> 
<subsection id="H13C5966E2F55412585F751F64A920AF6">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Charitable Deductions for Digital Asset Donations Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HE21EA4ED97BD4474AAD03B52BC1FE45B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD6EF5A4C9BE545B88814C4AEE843E277"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H200645A29C6C449B82F042D9DF1FF7B3" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; etc.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H10E6B92121AE44708E72645F42845059" level="section">Sec. 2. Charitable contributions of widely traded digital assets.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H9D44E534C7194505BD36CC7EAC271E5A" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8FCBDF114AAE4DD698FD8C0FE472FFC7" level="section">Sec. 4. Rules of construction.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H10E6B92121AE44708E72645F42845059" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Charitable contributions of widely traded digital assets</header> 
<subsection id="HC74A7CE254E343449923B3372C37F251"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exception from appraisal requirement</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/170">Section 170(f)(11)(A)(ii)(I)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>widely traded digital assets (except as the Secretary determines appropriate to prevent abuse of this section),</quote> after <quote>publicly traded securities (as defined in section 6050L(a)(2)(B)),</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H574C62ADDF4643F99A7318421371A16C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9D44E534C7194505BD36CC7EAC271E5A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">Section 7701</external-xref> is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H826407182B314597BC510134E84253AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (p) as subsection (q), and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40E5C7C54EC6435097FBE0029763DE25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (o) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8B1592F90BB149E1AE93EF09D1FFA4A1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H5F79C9A13F654FF29EAE5CBF7D731723"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Definitions related to digital assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7112C76682244D2AFF2F9D3023F9BED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>digital asset</term> means, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger or any similar technology as specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8D76BF332A34429A3C31CFAA24C0EC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Traded digital asset</header><text>The term <term>traded digital asset</term> means, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, any digital asset if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3EF5989413EA4D968548D3FFF0A12475"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such asset is fungible,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9626DBD62464D9DBBFE2A62796AA3BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>quotations of such asset are readily available on an exchange (or, in the case of an exchange that does not provide quotations, such quotations are readily ascertainable), and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB82E49361041419AB9D639EF6CF250E2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such asset is either—</text> <clause id="H69805E9FF8294F6CBD1CDFE6E6935900"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not a tokenized digital asset, or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0857805DF3584540A16E61DB353DE1A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a wrapped digital asset with respect to which the reference digital asset is a traded digital asset.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE89C57EA51D64BE8883EE9083439AD2B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Widely traded digital asset</header> <subparagraph id="HF7CA74C0096B4A209B2F4F6EB0695C36"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>widely traded digital asset</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year and except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, any traded digital asset if—</text> 
<clause id="HF7DA6F3762A643B0840DDC1BE59BDCC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>quotations for such asset were readily available on an exchange for the entire calendar year which ends in or with the taxable year preceding such taxable year,</text></clause> <clause id="H7B6CCE5A06B0422EBECB1177EEAEEBE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the market capitalization of such asset exceeded $500,000,000 at substantially all times during such calendar year, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H680D25E0C5214EAD878A0AFFE39A7248"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not more than 10 percent of the units of such asset were owned, directly or indirectly, by the taxpayer or any person described with respect to the taxpayer under section 267(b) (applied without regard to section 267(c)(3)) or section 707(b)(1) at any time during such taxable year or such preceding taxable year.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2093248499964F1FA5644E96347CA497"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for wrapped digital assets</header><text>In the case of any wrapped digital asset, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, such asset shall be treated as a widely traded digital asset if, and only if, the reference digital asset with respect to such wrapped digital asset is a widely traded digital asset.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72370CCE0E57476FAD4EA925C3183025" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority to ensure reliable price discovery</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B), the term <term>prevent abuse</term> includes the exclusion of assets that lack reliable price discovery or that the Secretary determines are at risk of price manipulation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H094059ECE4644BF598041C088310CB84"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Authority to adjust requirements</header><text>The Secretary may, by regulation, provide requirements that apply in lieu of one or more of the requirements of clauses (i) through (iii) of subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that due to changes in market conditions (including by reason of the enactment of Federal digital asset market structure legislation) that such alternative requirements would more effectively or efficiently identify traded digital assets for which there is consistent and reliable price discovery.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H411F98910B544C208258D5A1EAD6D7A0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any calendar year after 2027, the $500,000,000 amount in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text> <clause id="H38A5F4E944AC4B4591A34A8E0EAB83A4"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text>
                                </clause> 
<clause id="HD0AF51F760A04B77B34A80F03B581A13"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for such calendar year, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2026</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any increase determined under the preceding sentence which is not a multiple of $100,000 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEED0E0E41904BB8A49C01CE24FBFB9A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tokenized digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tokenized digital asset</term> means any digital asset (other than any qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin) if more than an insignificant portion of the value of such digital asset is related to anything other than the operation of the cryptographically secured distributed ledger on which such digital asset is recorded.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H055AAE8E32F04422A108361416A2B9B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Wrapped digital asset</header><text>The term <term>wrapped digital asset</term> means, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary to prevent abuse, any digital asset if such asset—</text> <subparagraph id="H3078A16A7BB0481699DCA7D424277DB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is redeemable on demand, on a one-for-one basis, for another digital asset, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD09BE1902F4440539C371AF2472F0488"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger other than the cryptographically secured distributed ledger on which the digital asset referred to in subparagraph (A) is recorded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE7873564C9D4559B0A1E99C755D6EA0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reference digital asset</header> <subparagraph id="HDB6BEE88E0064A949E7AEB2B2FC5B7BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>reference digital asset</term> means, with respect to any wrapped digital asset, the digital asset referred to in paragraph (5)(A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4D4624C333CC4F32A7A00DE210E3D039"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for rewrappings</header><text>If, but for this subparagraph, the reference digital asset with respect to any wrapped digital asset would be a wrapped digital asset (hereafter referred to in this paragraph as the lower-tier wrapped digital asset)—</text> <clause id="HBB7939B2CAF948A8AD4E9F0F0DB2753E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subparagraph (A) shall be applied with respect to such lower-tier wrapped digital asset, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA74D37FED69A4C2D9FB2301DEB383E17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reference digital asset with respect to such lower-tier wrapped digital asset shall be treated as the reference digital asset of such wrapped digital asset.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H70DBE16E00694CD9851F8AC1D9BF372E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Multiple wrappings</header><text>If, after the application of subparagraph (B), the reference digital asset with respect to the lower-tier wrapped digital asset is a wrapped digital asset, such subparagraph shall be reapplied by treating such lower-tier wrapped digital asset as the wrapped digital asset.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H304E4A30C8904F878DC9007F8F1FE734"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Stablecoin</header> 
<subparagraph id="HBB9E9DE91F464809A7ED871F551535E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified U.S. dollar stablecoin</term> means any U.S. dollar stablecoin which is issued by—</text> <clause id="H5C85264B3FB144DFBC67E655D557ED48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a permitted payment stablecoin issuer (as defined in section 2(23) of the GENIUS Act, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph), or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8686CB5D9FF647F88CE79AFE5F2AAD8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a foreign payment stablecoin issuer (as defined in section 2(12) of the GENIUS Act, as so in effect) which is permitted under such Act (as so in effect) to offer, sell, or otherwise make available such U.S. dollar stablecoin in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39B5F9210BB34BB4A2B914CC5316F916"><enum>(B)</enum><header>U.S. dollar stablecoin</header><text>The term <term>U.S. dollar stablecoin</term> means a payment stablecoin as defined in section 2(22) of the GENIUS Act (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph) applied by substituting <quote>dollars</quote> for <quote>monetary value</quote> each place it appears in such section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H940BF216FEA74750860D7A83617BEF67"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication of list</header><text>The Secretary shall, to the extent feasible, regularly publish a list of qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6B2C0E2AB0842089C730B8C1047591A"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limited authority to treat stablecoins as money</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to (except as otherwise expressly provided in this title)—</text> 
<clause id="H7CAE6237D4C04BEB9722FA475FFB8C40"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treat qualified U.S. dollar stablecoins as dollars, and</text></clause> <clause id="H48222C7F566B4879B1914A0912531576"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>treat other stablecoins as currency if such treatment would increase Federal revenues.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8FCBDF114AAE4DD698FD8C0FE472FFC7" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> 
<subsection id="H7DBABCA43C844FDFA5321477144C61F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No inference with respect to application of other provisions of law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided by this Act (or an amendment made by this Act) with respect to the application of one or more provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, nothing in this Act (or any amendment made by this Act) shall be construed to create an inference that a digital asset does or does not constitute a security, a commodity, debt, equity, stock, a partnership interest, or an interest in a trust, for purposes of any provision of law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD6D6986C1CBD4D76958434DC26AC9999"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No inference with respect to prior periods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No provision of this Act (or any amendment made by this Act) shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the proper application of any provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to any period before the period to which such provision or amendment applies.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

