<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H851A7B6DAB7749468F03907105F94298" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6769 IH: Restoring Trust in Public Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6769</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Attorney General to make grants available to support State, Tribal, and local firearm destruction activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3095524200F9484EBDC4FFA82A765061" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H80D1CE76138D40AC9D1940192DC0C275" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restoring Trust in Public Safety Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8732069AC6214E0BB629C68586592B2F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header> <subsection id="HE7F4ACFE8C2945D4A24767C459F0D3E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may make grants to an eligible entity for activities related to firearm destruction. For purposes of this section, the term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means a State, Tribal government, or unit of local government, or any law enforcement agency thereof.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HD2B06EE7F87E46F486F2346DA98D4E89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>Not later than 180 days after such amounts are appropriated, the Attorney General shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities whose applications are approved under subsection (c) to assist such applicants in firearm destruction.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9467A84597B04A9FB157CBD2BFBB05E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H48385F50A82F44709634BEA2665FA688"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of how the applicant will use the grant to carry out firearm destruction;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4B7A5192C024DC19461E2323FACC0B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of community partners and organizations contracted by or working with the eligible entity and their roles in supporting a State or Tribal government or a unit of local government’s programs and initiatives related to the acquisition, disposal, or destruction of a firearm or firearm parts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE564796F04A84B5380758FF1946B0D56"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certification that funds awarded to the applicant will be used to destroy firearms fully, including all parts and components; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A8269EA0DAA49E78020ADC4F9AC30BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>certification that the applicant will make and maintain records on the firearms and firearm parts that are destroyed.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H6F082F24B21E4699A180C56FDA4F275F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States, Tribal governments, and units of local government that are grantees shall award subgrants to units of local government or law enforcement agencies thereof. A unit of local government or law enforcement agency thereof seeking a subgrant that does not receive a grant under this Act may submit an application to the chief executive of the grantee that is substantially similar to the application prescribed by the Attorney General.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD108512C8A7F4D588D5DB7306F4A13A5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant duration</header><text>The duration of a grant awarded to an eligible entity under this section shall be two years.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HAE2F9041BF3340C191881E521967073A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Proof of firearm destruction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall require that a grantee or subgrantee develop and maintain a written policy on the destruction of firearms and other weapons including, without limitation, policies for identifying firearms and other weapons that are determined to be destroyed, keeping records of those firearms and other weapons and provide documented proof of firearm destruction. The Attorney General shall by rule establish acceptable forms of documented proof of destruction.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC27B76A51718431EA0793FFF5BC68BBB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grantee may use the grant for firearm destruction and related activities, including the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H1106819FA997465DAAA60BA23273B661"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purchase or maintenance of equipment used for firearm destruction, including tools used to smelt, crush, cut, or shred a firearm and components of a firearm.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9196C2A335C4AEB8435309890057FCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contracts with businesses that offer firearm destruction services, provided that they fully destroy the firearm, including all parts, components, and accessories of such firearms.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCE92A0E40C804F31AD3B27F4AC072856"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The training of staff in firearm destruction.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8FAD980F822432081674681C5408F03"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>An eligible entity shall use not more than 10 percent of such funds for the administrative costs of carrying out the grant program under this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEABE89850779410DAD4502EA0785D2A8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Small urban and rural preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants, under this Act, the Attorney General shall set aside one-third of the total appropriated funding for grants to applicants representing a Metropolitan Statistical Area (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget) or rural area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB1B22469BD746A5996548A63D6263CC"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031 to carry out this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1F21B5B834624A769BC7997CF062FCBF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H260A181E428D4EB7A6C2C1288C439354"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, or any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H93F595F0FC86484F8645AC7E2DCDB8A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Tribal government</quote> means the recognized governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H169D874DFB644068A5732A4997F76E90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Firearm destruction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>firearm destruction</quote> means to destroy a firearm or other weapon in its entirety by smelting, shredding, crushing, or cutting and shall include all parts including, without limitation, the frame or receiver, barrel, bolt, and grip of a firearm, as applicable, and any attachments including, but not limited to, a sight, scope, silencer, or suppressor, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

