<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA8534122DFBC46C4A93C1F2CE406E831" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6109 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish certain requirements with respect to rates of reversed prior authorization coverage determinations under Medicare Advantage plans.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6109</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish certain requirements with respect to rates of reversed prior authorization coverage determinations under Medicare Advantage plans.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAA5D467C35C44F61AEE9C0EFAF6A7D7C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2088577DA21340C78B15DC293EC385D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Establishing requirements with respect to rates of reversed prior authorization coverage determinations under Medicare Advantage plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1857 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0B536E043E7B4160A3A655065C6418BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD921312FC27A40C882CEE8894F120FA1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H91F2ACF967F64C57BC49309C9D76C638"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requirement on rates of reversed prior authorization coverage determinations</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8F1E76EBF9FC41AFBBB1D0F1C98108B0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a Medicare Advantage plan that imposes any prior authorization requirement with respect to items or services furnished during a plan year beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, if the Secretary determines that such plan exceeds the allowable rate of reversed prior authorization coverage determinations under <internal-xref idref="HFE789B04B2F74E339DDB5275E75CE62B" legis-path="(6)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> with respect to such plan year, the Secretary shall terminate the contract with respect to the offering of such plan under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE789B04B2F74E339DDB5275E75CE62B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allowable rate of reversed prior authorization coverage determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of <internal-xref idref="H8F1E76EBF9FC41AFBBB1D0F1C98108B0" legis-path="(6)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, a Medicare Advantage plan exceeds the allowable rate of reversed prior authorization coverage determinations under this subparagraph with respect to a plan year if—</text> 
<clause id="H32DE536EBB574975A678FB571C183733"><enum>(i)</enum><text>greater than 25 percent of prior authorization coverage determinations made during such plan year initially deny coverage and are later—</text> <subclause id="H29C4422BE48A43D1B2AD9AB874EBA2FF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reconsidered and reversed pursuant to section 1852(g)(2); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HACF43911198445B5B68D8DD68B9EB066"><enum>(II)</enum><text>appealed and reversed pursuant to section 1852(g)(5); or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H0D08D54158934AC58DDCAE601BD2098F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that—</text> 
<subclause id="H63328EE0B9C449849B2DC9068328CD6D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>significantly fewer prior authorization coverage determinations made during such plan year that are reconsidered pursuant to section 1852(g)(2) are reversed, as compared to the number of such determinations made during the previous plan year that are so reconsidered and reversed; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA048C6CA18C142998507F3402086C49E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reduction in the number of reconsidered and reversed prior authorization coverage determinations described in <internal-xref idref="H63328EE0B9C449849B2DC9068328CD6D" legis-path="(6)(B)(ii)(I)">subclause (I)</internal-xref> occurred because the Medicare Advantage organization that offers such plan failed to appropriately reconsider prior authorization coverage determinations made during such plan year pursuant to section 1852(g)(2).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC5CB7663BA8F412A898EC8F05FDF596D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Prior authorization coverage determination defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <quote>prior authorization coverage determination</quote> means, with respect to a Medicare Advantage plan, a coverage determination made under section 1852(g) regarding whether an individual enrolled in such plan is entitled to receive an item or service under the prior authorization requirement imposed under such plan with respect to such item or service.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C52FE70B8BB4DBDA541FF2EB6C994EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1)(A), by inserting <quote>except in the case of a termination of a contract due to failure to meet the requirement under subsection (e)(6),</quote> before <quote>the Secretary</quote>. </text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

