<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4DC8E5685C4E48DABBEE29402CE40B07" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>118 HR 6878 IH: El Salvador Accountability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6878</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to the regime of President Nayib Bukele in El Salvador, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA2AB4EE5BE7845449355112504ACB743" style="OLC"><section id="H57CFF3D4FB7F4D54BDA8E5F8BB7A05B0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>El Salvador Accountability Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H885CE1D890104A83AE00E9FD64C982D5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7AD7EF4175244485B3C0892392A1F12F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC1F0A34A9734A0CA9EE5220739CB432"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF618E66734A34F26B1035BCAE10DF856"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F6CCA88FE734B56A81D4100FDABC6C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C9F5D5091C4434E81CD50E629B46209"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</header><text>The term <term>gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</term> has the meaning given that term in section 502B(d) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7D4F2D0586342C09CB035CAB62BE733"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person had actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD678CC2FE7C64E3B84DE21AD30B6D3CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Salvadoran entity</header><text>The term <term>Salvadoran entity</term> means an entity organized under the laws of, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1C4EB2442C24F388BBB8BA1C522D87E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H63D686BBC1B749F3BE1364DB6089DE25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H202D65DD3D2B43648CE58A83FABDE860"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77A6A9ACEF8A4DAE83A7BA16D456D1D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C95EF5247774C3B8B96F901C2B2D6BC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Bukele government in El Salvador</header><subsection id="H740ADED858A84ACC80B4FAEA91EAEA89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to the following:</text><paragraph id="HC48062BA7C0348F48F264ABFCC4E0E34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The President of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EDA63D48FB448218EFDFBA8B902656D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Vice President of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A02F36D628A439C980A376E2F675715"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Minister of Foreign Relations of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBB6D5F9C62D4B14AB7DB6197050DE45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Minister of Defense of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BFDAB5C48FB49289D7DBD2422B2B0E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Minister of Economy of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H403A6985CE614ACDB1DB0CF3B99156B4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Minister of Finance of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2977774DCF4FF7A413248B673B4536"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Minister of Government of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE85E776E3AD4CF2BB9DD3FC374D2713"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Minister of Justice and Public Security of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E0E1F9B4C5649F397E79993FB3E28BF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Vice Minister of Justice and Public Security of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEB9BBFC558D40B4B8AB33469C1577F5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Minister of Tourism of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H266FDC8EA0704EB684F802775CB68AD9"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Attorney General of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4447278CBDB44AC0ABD48E13F2F752B1"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The President of the Central Reserve Bank of El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2947BF1F73E438A8970997DAEACA557"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Any foreign person in El Salvador, working on behalf of the Government of El Salvador, or who is a leader, official, or member of any Salvadoran entity, including a political party or government dependency, or a member of such a party or dependency, that, based on credible information—</text><subparagraph id="H0FACFCD37FCF4C3881E3E700788C8C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has engaged in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights, or violated international law or international human rights standards, including in connection with the ongoing <quote>state of exception</quote> in El Salvador;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2347F7DD49E94E37B2D1368D842499F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has engaged in the scheme, including by accepting United States taxpayer dollars, to deprive individuals residing in the United States of their rights under the Constitution of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D5960B09AC944B68616F6BEC0AB33F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, any person that has engaged in activities described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95A66AE7C8B4404FAD52C8F1C2705D86"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanction to be imposed under subsections (a) with respect to a person are the following:</text><paragraph id="H8F034A2C5DD64063914F4B201AD529E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person described in subsection (a), if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H299E2B04AE6F417B8B7390F084901F84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens inadmissible for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H522BFF9DB7844B78927F68B02E1D2E60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an alien described in subsection (a), the alien is—</text><clause id="H0CA19D5C6EDB45BEB8F54AB258F63893"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H5E6E39C5C38B41ED928CAF4415C646EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H8B7BDE1BE11F4761836A9C0FEFCEAE3E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20590C0C99BB48FC9D75FBF6312E5EBA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="H0441ABF4ED4C4A5E95255B489CD4D7E8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subsection (a) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation was issued.</text></clause><clause id="H528D76562F4C43C998705D979629C592"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="H603BE70646134FE29C9F0F6392A59087"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9F78D0A19B9A4F68ABF33D83822FC4C4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36A62F57CE0F4B668C9C94B3EF6E9701"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Loans from United States financial institutions</header><text>The President shall prohibit United States financial institutions from making loans or extending credit to a person described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C231169F4C345D19A2CECE9C2F46EF3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign exchange</header><text>The President shall prohibit any transactions in foreign exchange that are subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and in which a person described in subsection (a) has any interest.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9EB873E30E2649BDB9FD10FA1F7B7F45"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports required</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF75F2497CD694C0ABC67E6B77DABDAF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on imposition of sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after any imposition of sanctions under this section, the President shall provide written notification to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the imposition of such sanctions that includes a description of—</text><subparagraph id="HAE5B33B0BBB54B26BB8836062A3066A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the person or persons subject to the imposition of such sanctions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE46F9C5298C04B5BB11F0331DA2404DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the activities that led to the imposition of sanctions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H106E427E336B4540AA8E4C590C4BE5C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HF863746C3C3F46EB8F089FF8A76F549A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the persons with respect to which sanctions have been imposed under this section during the year preceding submission of the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CA46BB573994956883043CD876D196D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the activities that led to the imposition of such sanctions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEFA2F224B1F4D61A2745EA147FAD392"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of any assistance provided by the United States to El Salvador during the year preceding submission of the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4313E23D809495989114687518B93F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the full text of any written agreements, including grant agreements, made between the United States and the Government of El Salvador during that year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F6559BFD7CE49C1BC9BD4BFAC772966"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a list of any officials of the Government of El Salvador who are, as of the date of the report, subject to sanctions under other sanctions authorities, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H44A3EC7AB2B1431DAA2FBE705F03740A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H83C24361959F43AE85CEFF4053C84E5C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 7031(c)(1)(A) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/47">Public Law 118–47</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3519F8D93EDD442B84641A3F70ECDE17"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a determination of whether any of the individuals on the list required by subparagraph (E)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H84559AB620764C4BA1DF34F48CD1ABA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has received, or is part of a government institution that has received, United States foreign assistance described in subparagraph (C); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD62FCF834E284BC286245D156ED6D43A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is implementing a bilateral agreement described in subparagraph (D);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34D031E538ED466793A4ADF15F3DA95B" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a determination of whether any nationals of El Salvador subject to sanctions under other sanctions authorities, or government institutions led by such nationals or of which such nationals are members, have received United States foreign assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DCA7BFAD3874CC98380F4C444661BEC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the full text of any written agreement between the United States and El Salvador pursuant to section 620M(c)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378d">22 U.S.C. 2378d(c)(1)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55739A0ABB3443FDAFF6B66640517BFB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a list of any units of the security forces of El Salvador prohibited from receiving United States foreign assistance under section 620M of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378d">22 U.S.C. 2378d</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4B6F07995F540A0B40E5489ABE90F95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="HF7D1718BB8B6428EAD981F13002836BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international agreements</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (b)(2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien to the United States if such admission is necessary to comply with the obligations of the United States under the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success on June 26, 1947, and entered into force on November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna on April 24, 1963, and entered into force on March 19, 1967, or other international obligations of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H210EB8EFDDEC49E6B6F365631B98DFA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Humanitarian exception</header><text>The President may not impose sanctions under this section with respect to any person for conducting or facilitating a transaction for the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices or for the provision of basic human needs or humanitarian assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3CF1F109E3D4BE5A92DAC3CD2AD7DAF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="HACD61E26823647FC9D0EF0583421A86C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85805734BBE84A0C96AC6EFA311C5879"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04C0FAE35E1641B8AAA2E8754FA42324"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48A34F0167D14EE7AAE83D7EF8A92829"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), sanctions imposed under this section shall terminate if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the Government of El Salvador—</text><subparagraph id="H7D7B916DE2844B919786F5ED60DC3DA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is no longer engaged in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights and is complying with international law and international human rights standards, including in connection with the ongoing <quote>state of exception</quote> in El Salvador; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C9BEA62A8734A8591B7BAADA6C32BA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is no longer engaged in the scheme, including by accepting United States taxpayer dollars, to deprive individuals residing in the United States of their rights under the Constitution of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9DA4E9FDD2447FAAC4A8377F8B041D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The President may not submit the certification described in paragraph (1) before the date that is 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E4518BDEA9845239CE7276398A3EA07"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions snapback</header><text>Any sanctions terminated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be reimposed with immediate effect if the President determines that the Government of El Salvador resumes engaging in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights or the scheme described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B2D8591F0D7491DBA40AFF8C7DCCD3F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The head of any Federal agency responsible for the implementation of this section may prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section (which may include regulatory exceptions), including under section 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1704">50 U.S.C. 1704</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2D295327767149A2A16C6FC4B5EE9095"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the President pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H13EC67CC20E0475AA70BA88A11495C7C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Assistance to Government of El Salvador provided through international financial institutions</header><subsection id="HF3867E06DF9E47C7A9B094C9BEBA9349"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the international financial institutions to use the voice and vote of the United States in those institutions—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C14E3296FFF489CB2249EBE09334AA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to oppose any loan or extension of financial or technical assistance to the Government of El Salvador; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H628353F5EE004DC895D5D20628784907"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to suspend any such loan or assistance provided before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F73859CD94E40F89F29BFB198E5600A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception for humanitarian purposes</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to loans or financial or technical assistance provided for humanitarian purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0C5B43C3B52F434E9E9F7D4E9E9F96D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Subsection (a) shall terminate on the date on which the President submits a certification under section 3(f)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FF57CEB2A4143448BE77D0DF9E77C33"><enum>(d)</enum><header>International financial institution defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>international financial institution</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1701(c) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HCB15C1AC6ED8485CBEF37DE84E888DD9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on cryptocurrency as a vector for Bukele regime corruption</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H174733691E9A41C3B883FAF5355CBEA6"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the actions of officials of the Government of El Salvador, including President Nayib Bukele, to use cryptocurrency as a mechanism for gross corruption, graft, and sanctions evasion.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC83E3470826341988C61A3349EDF3AEB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HF2213A186E4844368F53467444BDAD7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an estimate of the amount of funds used by the Government of El Salvador to buy Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1731C0578ED0490A8DA1DE7BBB06664E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of exchanges through which the Government of El Salvador bought Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC399A69841F4452DA8EB5BC721C8F1A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the addresses of the locations where the Government of El Salvador deposited Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66964EF9A9094DD8B9F63CD48A8AEE38"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of individuals who have access to Bitcoin and other cryptocurrencies bought by the Government of El Salvador;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B9E50EAFB654C2F8993053EDF6D77A0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assessment of existing gaps in the use of Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies by the Government of El Salvador being exploited for corruption; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF03761F84594C5784AEB66036F9EC61"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an assessment of whether Bitcoin or other cryptocurrencies have been used in El Salvador as a vector to evade financial sanctions imposed on other countries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H427E926CFA2F4514A98B1B0968BE7502"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form; availability</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5B652652A424BB5805D9D998FF85C70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0240AEE5244B7B8838EF285EEB930A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability to public</header><text>The unclassified portion of the report required by subsection (a) shall be made available to the public on a publicly accessible internet website of the Department of State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7A1564C7DD9E4F5E9EAD9608CE5E07CB"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibition on making funds available to Government of El Salvador</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available by Congress may be made available to the Government of El Salvador until the President submits a certification under section 3(f)(1).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

