<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8C71D4701BED4B2BA470E9291ECC3C5A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9504 IH: Tax Exempt Hospital Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9504</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish additional reporting requirements for hospital organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1AD9AA3C4D944927857C8DA46C0DA0CA" style="OLC"><section id="H181C3BAE8E8446EE9AC354091349771F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tax Exempt Hospital Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6EA5BF1247B34C9CA3BF28C3B2BE63E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information reporting by hospital organizations</header><subsection id="H0AC111DFD9DE4C4BB2304FFECFA2BE2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart A of part III of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 6033 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB7C4AE5BEE0847F3BED9BA64500995F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H8FD2F32D7D3541B49D20A0632688B363"><enum>6033A.</enum><header>Reporting by tax exempt hospital organizations</header><subsection id="HC553FBD3831D44C0AA54EC68079A950A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting by tax exempt hospital organizations</header><paragraph id="HB4389DCD73E24033B5C5AFEED7EFEC83"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every tax exempt hospital organization shall include on the return filed under section 6033(a) for the taxable year—</text><subparagraph id="HA435778A22B2470394ED4B4328EAE10D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how the organization is addressing the needs identified in the most recent community health needs assessment conducted under section 501(r)(3) and a description of any such needs that are not being addressed together with the reasons why such needs are not being addressed,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9BA5300C20D4AC8BCE7D86B947252C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the audited financial statements of such organization (or, in the case of an organization the financial statements of which are included in a consolidated financial statement with other organizations, such consolidated financial statement),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC57FBE8D788C466CB3A21794F8C2F762"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services certification number of the organization (or such other identifying information as the Secretary may require),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EDC1AE45B92464380DB9F1742536485"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the value, at cost, of the financial assistance provided during such taxable year pursuant to the organization’s financial assistance policy (as described in section 501(r)(4)), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6344D3DB38F4926824506A8CF58E3BA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the numbers of completed financial assistance applications received, granted, and denied during the taxable year pursuant to the organization’s financial assistance policy (as described in section 501(r)(4)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5250877207A14592BABAC9050D8A4BA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Separate reporting with respect to each facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of any large tax exempt hospital organization or any high revenue tax exempt hospital organization, the information described in subparagraphs (A), (C), (D), and (E) of paragraph (1) shall be provided with respect to the organization and separately stated with respect to each hospital facility operated by such organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4453858A0DE416496847F9E7ABAE2D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional reporting by large tax exempt hospital organizations</header><paragraph id="H6058FCC2FED041598F53F037FEA2D9C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every large tax exempt hospital organization shall include on the return filed under section 6033(a) for the taxable year—</text><subparagraph id="H0D79B47CE50C49698930EC717EA0406C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 3 highest priority health needs identified in the most recent community health needs assessment conducted under section 501(r)(3), the amount of spending during the taxable year on programs designed to address each such need, and a description of actions taken during the taxable year to meet each such need and the impact of such actions on community health, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H293D35CE8BC742109A24A1B99179C5B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of spending by the organization during the taxable year on—</text><clause id="H5849072EEC3848658F01D818F149F05E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>quality improvement,</text></clause><clause id="HE906599C7E8E46A79E2655AADA5CF1C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>nonclinical programming, and</text></clause><clause id="H0EECBC35298C4D8EA4FF56DF9C32CCD7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other community benefits as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA7BA48D472B4A64AD5B87269C025C2F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quality improvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>quality improvement</term> means any program, initiative, or department, with the primary purpose of improving health outcomes for patients of the organization, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HAD1CDDFC98874474B8D5FA93F7D67AE4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>education,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE738FE2653949B0BDCAF29871F5135C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3698DB4148AF4EF0946CB85F2E08D8B5" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>compliance with quality improvement programs (such as quality improvement programs under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H566EED649F7E49E5BC00B621864D163A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>technical assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB332297C0DE7406E8F4327173BE01B0D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonclinical programming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>nonclinical programming</term> means any program, initiative, or department, with a purpose other than the purpose of improving health outcomes for patients of the organization and which is related to—</text><subparagraph id="H88106CCBE1D2421C9565381708FB249E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administrative support and management,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H731643B6A96F4B62AD640869A3F777D8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information technology, hospital administration, human resources, medical billing and coding, public affairs and communications, government affairs and lobbying, regulatory compliance, or financial planning and budgeting,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC2FC32B7F3344AFB081BC7DF25F9B1D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operations and facilities management,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A5C7C6F899248A191EEACE7BE086AB9" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>programming related to patient experience, patient education, family support, or financial counseling, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00A0081584A466E83A865B82EADE749" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>discharge planning and appointment scheduling.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD38D23026514D9E92FC8D4AFD3BA4BA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Separate reporting with respect to each facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the information described in paragraph (1) shall be provided with respect to the organization and separately stated with respect to each hospital facility operated by such organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49B59B31AAE94F9FA1E575497165BB5F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional reporting by high revenue tax exempt hospital organizations</header><paragraph id="H28A225EC378F460D9F560D64CFE187DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every high revenue tax exempt hospital organization shall include on the return filed under section 6033(a) for the taxable year—</text><subparagraph id="H49B7EB3954D14828809CA4AA40D3A753"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the specified advertising information,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61DE9B3ACEDE455EA3941E61275A3403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the specified health service line information, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA02E0A41226547EA99A05814FF3EE89A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an organization which is a covered entity described in section 340B(a)(4) of the Public Health Service Act, the specified Federal 340B drug discount program information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF55201174874005AEBEC1BE9D2793A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified advertising information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>specified advertising information</term> means— </text><subparagraph id="H0C4E9564310C4B4696E66B7813318CAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the allowable advertising costs as reported to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services for purposes of cost reimbursement, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD83B860E9ED04E85844503199F1AD8E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the unallowable advertising costs (as so reported).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB74AD159750F4FDCB857EA530B430680" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specified health service line information</header><subparagraph id="HDE6830C5D9464B0EA37E77BAFC4DC5F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>specified health service line information</term> means—</text><clause id="HFDF5217183A049BE971AE2020C3582BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of each health service line of the organization,</text></clause><clause id="HCAC11ED8797145BA914164BEB117E0A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of gross receipts generated by each such health service line, and</text></clause><clause id="H5EDF02217E3A49D2890CA61D9E23A29E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the costs of each such health service line (and in the case of costs that are shared by 1 or more health service lines, an explanation of how such costs are allocated).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H999782EAD7F1420486E9ED7FB53CAD32" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Health service line</header><clause id="H93735048CF90447C8269CED99F15BC15" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>health service line</term> means a discrete clinical program, department, or care category operated by the organization that—</text><subclause id="H59F677DA9DC544C7B2C035661426AE2D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serves a defined patient population grouped by disease category, organ system, care setting, or clinical specialty,</text></subclause><subclause id="HA4A70F532B0F41A4901EBECEAC2AAE46" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">delivers a distinct set of medical or health services through dedicated or allocated staff, facilities, or equipment, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0A9BD76D356249E0BC58EC681F4EC93E" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is separately tracked or identifiable in the organization’s internal cost accounting, service line management, or operational reporting systems.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">For purposes of this paragraph, any cost center separately identified on the organization’s most recently filed cost report under section 1815 of the Social Security Act shall be presumptively treated as a health service line. If the organization asserts that such a cost center does not constitute a health service line, the organization shall bear the burden of demonstrating that such cost center does not satisfy the requirements of subclauses (I) and (II).</continuation-text></clause><clause id="H2AC8D37A301047F29135AB754BD3EA56" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Standardized health service line taxonomy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph—</text><subclause id="HC2CD71A44AB44D2894D1975471040244"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary, shall publish and maintain a standardized health service line taxonomy to which high revenue tax exempt hospital organizations shall map their internally defined health service lines on their returns under section 6033.</text></subclause><subclause id="H639A8E6D99CA44D7A8865555450E4A5B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary, shall update the taxonomy described in subclause (I) no less frequently than every 5 years to reflect changes in clinical care delivery, hospital organization, and cost accounting practices.</text></subclause><subclause id="H20F40675E94141A493B64ED631929B94"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Compliance obligation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A high revenue tax exempt hospital organization’s compliance with the reporting requirements of this subsection with respect to a health service line enumerated in the taxonomy published, maintained, and updated under this clause shall not be conditioned on whether the organization separately tracks such service line under clause (i)(III). A high revenue tax exempt hospital organization that does not separately track such an enumerated health service line shall disclose that fact and provide an explanation on their return under section 6033. The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary, may, by regulation, designate categories of clinical activity that shall be treated as a single health service line for reporting purposes notwithstanding any difference in how a high revenue tax exempt hospital organization tracks such activity in its internal systems.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE860EF8D83B4A79B7BA2705456FC5AE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Specified Federal 340B drug discount program information</header><subparagraph id="HDC8D0DA2FFC34BD58193F3523D94D48D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>specified Federal 340B drug discount program information</term> means—</text><clause id="HF81B56B22519496A867AE8D7169590BF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of individuals, by their type of insurance coverage, who were dispensed or administered covered outpatient drugs during the taxable year that were subject to an agreement under section 340B of the Public Health Service Act,</text></clause><clause id="H954F0A2425E3464F8D948F992A78204C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregate net 340B payment amount with respect to such drugs subject to such an agreement dispensed or administered by the organization during such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="HDA84B029AFB44F13AA0152C342F10784" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the aggregate costs incurred by the organization during such taxable year that were necessary for such organization to participate in the program under such section and to comply with such program’s requirements (including program-related compliance, legal, educational, and administrative costs, and compensation paid to independent contractors to carry out program-related functions).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAADD0EF7CDC4AAFABD49E1A799A5CCA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered outpatient drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>covered outpatient drug</term> has the meaning given such term in section 340B(b) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D94ADF906984610943C75C4857C740C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Aggregate net 340B payment amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>aggregate net 340B payment amount</term> means, with respect to a covered outpatient drug purchased by an organization under an agreement under section 340B of the Public Health Service Act and dispensed or administered to an individual by such organization, the excess (if any) of—</text><clause id="H8C3743F9B1A4418EBE819BD20BB3FE33" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of payments received from any payor by the organization for such drug, over</text></clause><clause id="H573CB88BACD4448D8CFDB28107744595" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ceiling price (as described in subsection (a)(1) of such section) for such drug (or, if less, the price at which such organization acquired such drug).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38D00ED206F9409C87CAC8C7C8FA2A46" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Separate reporting with respect to each facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, the information described in paragraph (1) shall be provided with respect to the organization and separately stated with respect to each hospital facility operated by such organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8DF9207D93045198D2FF5DB58187D5B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Agency coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with—</text><subparagraph id="HB1FD5DEE804D461A8C9E01E2A590120A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to carry out the purposes of paragraphs (2) and (3), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7F7157FBFDC4D23BC1DB94B92715AE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration to carry out the purposes of paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0C4209929CB4486B44A6E4801703BA7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H0D8C3476E0CF46D4A9575AF090217859"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tax exempt hospital organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tax exempt hospital organization</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, any organization—</text><subparagraph id="HB1A5F95D67344380AD034E7981C35D92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to which the requirements of section 501(r) apply for such taxable year, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H363DE47AA66B4D1B8F4204FBDB21C2BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is required to file a return under section 6033(a) for such taxable year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9A2F464E31B4F95A6F48683A91225CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Large tax exempt hospital organization</header><text>The term <term>large tax exempt hospital organization</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, any organization which—</text><subparagraph id="H9BC4B1C4D1C54BBF93192C45547D58F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a tax exempt hospital organization for such taxable year,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4E6C272B52A480E8A05DD36F4FA2FC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not a critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of the Social Security Act) for such taxable year,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD52D584E1B94A69910D5D57E9AAC76F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not a rural emergency hospital (as defined in section 1861(kkk)(2) of the Social Security Act) for such taxable year, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8385C02CE1634F5CADD450A69659EE00"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has more than 100 staffed inpatient beds (as reported in any cost report under section 1815 of the Social Security Act with respect to any portion of such taxable year or any portion of any of the 3 preceding taxable years).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC6D5B1961B34323B2735054339097AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>High revenue tax exempt hospital organization</header><subparagraph id="H1136639201BE464C8222CB0434D9C6BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>high revenue tax exempt hospital organization</term> means, with respect to any taxable year, any organization which—</text><clause id="HF6995125245F4D589C4FAA91FCECC61D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a tax exempt hospital organization for such taxable year,</text></clause><clause id="HA3C7BA1F003B4C688F12B7AA0ED578B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not a critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of the Social Security Act) for such taxable year,</text></clause><clause id="H4C55B18D9C7F43129A609593128410FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is not a rural emergency hospital (as defined in section 1861(kkk)(2) of the Social Security Act) for such taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="H8AED34E4F1C7496FA7ACD9221A7777DC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has net patient revenue (determined in such manner as the Secretary may provide) for such taxable year of more than $100,000,000.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD0232EE0967494AB3348B8C4DCED27C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><clause id="HE785C24396FE45FC8D97A052C89BF82B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any taxable year beginning in a calendar year after 2028, the $100,000,000 amount in subparagraph (A)(iv) shall be increased by an amount equal to—</text><subclause id="H2AC05E4D776540828DCB3F647714DECE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such dollar amount, multiplied by</text></subclause><subclause id="H6D5F730F971848DBBAAC333EF4C737D9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the cost-of-living adjustment determined under section 1(f)(3) for the calendar year in which the taxable year begins, determined by substituting <quote>calendar year 2027</quote> for <quote>calendar year 2016</quote> in subparagraph (A)(ii) thereof. </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2219FF2F29244A42AD6FAB946094F036"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>Any increase determined under clause (i) shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H774A41F3DA7349A1A1E922905ABF0035"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment as part of annual return</header><text>For purposes of this title, the information required to furnished under this section shall be treated as information required to be furnished under section 6033.</text></subsection><subsection id="H602A962BD6FD4182B07396482C52EBD4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including regulations or other guidance providing a methodology for allocating costs between the categories described in subsections (a)(1)(A), (a)(1)(D), (b)(1)(A), (b)(1)(B)(i), (b)(1)(B)(ii), and (b)(1)(B)(iii).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFEC1B83587AB409F82AF0A451DCF7BBA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H8156058ED03F491C8CE4CBC3E6011E0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6033(b) of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H4111BB7F519E4C109290D7C460508DE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (14),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H638D5DE6605A4B95B3C320D11705A7FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (15), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2350EDC0D7B149EBB7BF15C76F32112A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (16) as paragraph (15).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE2CB30D25334A418C91A71AD956AA7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart A of part III of subchapter A of chapter 61 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 6033 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3A1456F944C2406EA28D7619738BC2ED" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HB7C4AE5BEE0847F3BED9BA64500995F3" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H8FD2F32D7D3541B49D20A0632688B363" level="section">Sec. 6033A. Reporting by tax exempt hospital organizations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D573EFE95344E9F99319BDF3D60F5ED" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph id="H28BF36BFE44447D2BAEAB0BC4A0C1675"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date that is 1 year after the date of the publication of the first standardized health service line taxonomy under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6033A">section 6033A(c)(3)(B)(ii)(I)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BB1D675C9734469982804D5868D5D19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In the case of any tax exempt hospital organization which is neither a large tax exempt hospital organization nor a high revenue tax exempt hospital organization, subparagraphs (D) and (E) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6033A">section 6033A(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section) shall (notwithstanding paragraph (1)) apply to taxable years beginning after the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. Terms used in this paragraph which are also used in section 6033A of such Code (as so added) shall have the same meaning as when used in such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3000B62B5E8D403595EFB9EA535D5706"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No inference</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the proper application of section 340B of the Public Health Service Act, of section 501(c)(3) or 501(r) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, or of any operational test or the private benefit doctrine.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9CF2DB46C81A4898A136EE4F7431D5C2" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">During the 1-year period beginning 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall initiate a study and subsequently report to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate on the following:</text><paragraph id="H2612F9520F0E44069D1B545C753015AB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate of the additional labor and resource costs of the Department of the Treasury to administer, and of the additional costs of tax exempt hospital organizations (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6033A">section 6033A(d)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this Act) to comply with, the reporting requirements added by the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFB48B15E6F9431B96C85E31755FFB42" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to the 25 tax exempt hospital organizations (as so defined) which have the highest amount of gross revenue, the estimated amount of tax which would be imposed under chapter 1 of such Code with respect to each such organization if such organization were not exempt from such tax.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

