<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Engrossed-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26017-7H1-3W-4C6" stage-count="1" public-print="no"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SCON 25 ES: Recognizing the 15th anniversary of the January 8, 2011, Tucson, Arizona, shooting and honoring the survivors and victims, including former Congresswoman Gabby Giffords, a gun violence survivor and one of the most influential voices of courage in the United States in the fight to end gun violence.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form display="yes">
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">S. CON. RES. 25</legis-num><current-chamber display="no">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><legis-type display="yes">CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="no">Recognizing the 15th anniversary of the January 8, 2011, Tucson, Arizona, shooting and honoring the survivors and victims, including former Congresswoman Gabby Giffords, a gun violence survivor and one of the most influential voices of courage in the United States in the fight to end gun violence.</official-title></form><preamble commented="no"><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas, on January 8, 2011, a tragic act of gun violence occurred in Tucson, Arizona, during a <quote>Congress on Your Corner</quote> event hosted by Congresswoman Gabby Giffords, resulting in the deaths of 6 individuals and the injury of 13 others, including Congresswoman Giffords;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas among those killed were Chief Judge for the U.S. District Court for the District of Arizona John Roll, Gabriel <quote>Gabe</quote> Zimmerman (a congressional staff member to Congresswoman Gabby Giffords and the first known congressional staffer killed while serving), Dorothy <quote>Dot</quote> Morris, Phyllis Schneck, Dorwan Stoddard, and 9-year-old Christina-Taylor Green;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Ron Barber, who was serving as District Director to Congresswoman Gabby Giffords at the time of the attack and later became a Member of the House of Representatives, was critically injured while performing his public duties, and has since demonstrated extraordinary resilience and continued commitment to public service;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Pamela Simon, a congressional staff member dedicated to supporting the work of Congresswoman Gabby Giffords and the constituents of the 8th district of Arizona, was also injured in the attack and continues to exemplify perseverance as a survivor and advocate;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the attack shocked the United States, underscoring the dangers of political violence and the importance of civility, empathy, and respect in American democracy;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the people of Tucson and the State of Arizona came together with resilience, compassion, and unity after the attack, inspiring the nation with their strength in the face of tragedy;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas former Congresswoman Gabby Giffords has, in the years since the attack, become a champion of courage and perseverance, dedicating her recovery and her voice to preventing gun violence and promoting civility in public life; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas countless people of the United States, community organizations, law enforcement officers, and first responders have worked in the years since the attack to honor the victims through acts of service, advocacy, and civic engagement: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" display-resolving-clause="yes-display-resolving-clause"><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Congress—</text><paragraph id="idf93e9530845b446ea7604bbb23de3836" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the memory of the 6 individuals whose lives were lost on January 8, 2011, and expresses continued support for all survivors and families affected by the tragedy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idecab77d2cbcc42c0a7a6ae8c62f2b40d" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes the courage and leadership of former Congresswoman Gabby Giffords and her ongoing work to promote civility, bipartisanship, and solutions to prevent gun violence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id980e79e75da14726b711882610c283dd" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commends the people of Tucson and first responders for their strength, compassion, and heroism in responding to the attack; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9867e2c525ee488b9e59cdaf2c614078" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirms its dedication to promoting a respectful dialogue, condemning political violence and hate, and maintaining the core principles of peaceful self-governance.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260205" chamber="Senate">Passed the Senate February 5, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no"></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement display="yes"></endorsement></resolution> 

