<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCE885BA1133D4595A6179FFDB4AB2274" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7997 IH: Research and Oversight of AI in Courts Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7997</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a task force to address legal and ethical issues related to the use of AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H816D77F1B149426B83196B88415E8EF1" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H067A699ADE2E4B8E8B66509C47C4371D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Research and Oversight of AI in Courts Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7361E6A96F4644BE97417F737A30D4E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>AI research and oversight in courts task force</header> <subsection id="H1BB0217A344C461A9251CBDC9D2D8C9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to provide Congress with—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6CE22663778445A954AA00A350FDEBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of any issues or benefits related to the use of AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8861442E3E8B445D9C1824261C1DC624"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of the use of AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H966C6EE9B9D04D819240A9FFCA12AF9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations based on the analysis and review conducted under paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF2ECAB8670814D21BCCDC618350E9D25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of task force</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General of the United States, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Justice, shall establish a task force (to be known as the <quote>AI Research and Oversight in Courts Task Force</quote>) to assess the feasibility, accuracy, privacy, and civil liberty implications of using AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3117EA898E1B40AF859AD5420A6A2704"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Task force duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the task force established under subsection (b) shall be to—</text> <paragraph id="HDBD3FA57300F4CA2A634D4FF5CF61B46"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess policy findings, regulatory findings, and legal findings with respect to the use of AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF352228E60BE4F458E286CDAFE684ABD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make recommendations to Congress, the executive branch, and the judicial branch for any judicial, legislative, or regulatory reforms to ensure the use of AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system does not infringe upon any rights under the Constitution of the United States, including the litigant’s right to an accurate official court record.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB2031E2D9D5B4588A717E81947D638BC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Task force appointees</header> <paragraph id="HB4FCCADC05A9416A90776B717E1631B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The task force established under subsection (b) shall be composed of 15 members, to be appointed by the Director of the National Institute of Justice, as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEF2FB5E440C047EDA75E2BF41F366877"><enum>(A)</enum><text>4 members employed by the Federal Government in at least one of the following capacities:</text> <clause id="H9FCEA0DACDAE444CB7945EFA121CD1B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As an employee of the National Institute of Justice.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6EB3C88A06E14B539C5A9F792E0CE0FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As an employee of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts.</text></clause> <clause id="H748C7B0CE93B423B9F7FCB3A987FC07C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>As a clerk of court.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6482705CCCB544FA9645C4990585DEE1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>As a Federal judge.</text></clause> <clause id="H46B5CAFFA2A74F2CB7BCEB53F539FBC5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>As a Federal prosecutor.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF38B34B358B84061A169860C6A7D759D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">11 members not employed by the Federal Government, which shall include the following individuals:</text> <clause id="HE227744084B54A97AA681FBF14B6C1EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is a member of a professional association that specializes in the official record making process of the United States judicial system and in the technology used for such record keeping.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H59CACB78379C4D2CBA73E24357642F0D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An individual who is a specialist in civil liberty law.</text></clause> <clause id="HDC0A35B5353944068FA1480E0BFE11DF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An active State court judge or a retired Federal court judge with experience reversing a ruling because of a written or audible deficiency in the official court record.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE088414ECB548AA8F4951052CDAB6E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member appointed under paragraph (1)(B) to the task force established under subsection (b), may not be employed by, contracted with, receive compensation from, or otherwise represent any entity that develops, markets, sells, or provides artificial intelligence technologies or related services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H433D23AEB79C4DB397FB08EF5C1A1E68"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required expertise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members appointed to the task force established under subsection (b) under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall have expertise in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H65174C9E6A8D407CA4E62E5F538EE3BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the official record making process in the United States judicial system; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7BB33E09D4E94ED8B1A06BC4F3260E1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the technology used by the United States judicial system to create and modify a court record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B42E6C9010145AFBC5E6202761823FA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Co-chairs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Justice shall designate as co-chairs of the task force established under subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9F56821A756F4E66BECDA388BCA91E0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 member appointed to the task force under paragraph (1)(A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5733C369F6AF48F9B84DDC9B1AEEBF04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 member appointed to the task force under paragraph (1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD10789B8E00D4ED3B02556D68A14E906"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>In the case of a vacancy on the task force established under subsection (b), the co-chairs appointed under paragraph (4) shall appoint a new member not later than 15 days after the vacancy occurs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDAE7D27B41904945AFC7A504B32C2B26"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Compensation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H0460EAB73C7F423BBE8AE1805CA6DE56" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the task force established under subsection (b) appointed under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for services as an employee of the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CB0FE4D19FA4AF58FDA29D359CFE605"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member appointed to the task force established under subsection (b) under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection shall serve without compensation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0B8CC8A838E4FC5BF81E89FD84A655E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member appointed to the task force established under subsection (b) under paragraph (1) of this subsection shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business while carrying out the duties described under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1A59413AFC304E609AADFB3D8F9F1287"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the task force is established under subsection (b), the task force shall submit to the Attorney General, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a final report on the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEB68B64313E84049ACB4D73E84E14D4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether a court record created or modified by AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology affects the quality or accuracy of a transcription of a legal proceeding.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0011EDE7FEF64AB09B5D2CAFC8DFDE32"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology alters any comments made in a courtroom by an individual with a speech impediment, unique speech pattern, accent, or dialect.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0CEA75B9C6841ECAA1649C898CCADA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether using AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology to perform tasks in the United States judicial system will increase or decrease costs for litigants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H369712D4C4A148B3A228DA13DC1AE5B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of any cybersecurity risks associated with using AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology to perform tasks in the United States judicial system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB3FC7F6CA7B4096B173938B892EE739"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of any other risks associated with using AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology to analyze or process a court record and perform tasks in the United States judicial system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E5EEB435232440991079A4AC0A39458"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of any effects on the data integrity, authenticity, or preservation of the evidentiary value of a court record when using AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology to manage, process, and store such court record.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BFD8D80AF51404080D3ADA49135F916"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether implementing AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology to conduct managerial and administrative tasks in the United States judicial system will increase or decrease court expenditures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H09A6E620F9D44271BFD31166680C962F"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether a court record created or modified by AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology should display a watermark, header, footer, or banner to indicate that such court record was created or modified by such technology.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8A4BCFA63504BCD873446D69D8E96F8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether a watermark, header, footer, or banner described under paragraph (8) should be displayed permanently on a court record.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECB36338E08F4CACB45591F3F6B2F2AA"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether metadata should be included in a court record created or modified by AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAEEE3CACA3354C26B726D19A6719CF81"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology tool was used to create or modify such record;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97790E2909A646E59B6F3576235BA48E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which version of the AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology was used to create or modify such record; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FEE69BE83D840FC9156E1F4D208DDBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any changes made by such technology to such record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4178A6038562481891D3DABF180D026B"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the United States judicial system should provide guidance on the selection process of vendors providing AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology to ensure the safety and privacy of parties and individuals involved in the United States judicial system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD84E141C99104344955FBA0488F18404"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the use of AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system compromises the accuracy or integrity of a court record.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EAA1DA8C2884AA28A77BC5CD4AC7EDE"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the use of AI speech-to-text technology or automatic speech recognition technology in the United States judicial system causes any disruptions during a judicial proceeding.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9093F70932EA44AAB7B86FD878DCF7D3"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of any potential future developments and advancements of AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology within 10 years of the date of enactment of this Act, and how the United States judicial system should adjust its policies to keep pace with the quickly evolving technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6629DC3FC1D45EE9A2D01E6A3BD010D"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any recommendations for policies to be implemented in the United States judicial system with respect to AI speech-to-text technology and automatic speech recognition technology.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F626A5C95814BD19F10C4055CFD6A75"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Status report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 4 months thereafter until the task force established under subsection (b) submits the final report under subsection (e), the task force shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on—</text> <paragraph id="H3A3BED479DC249F6AE07307FCB7B7078"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of the final report; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE50B0AAF2CC9445A9CED7ADB1B503CED"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the final report will be submitted to such committees by the deadline established under subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD721118554384001A402146E49CEC3F5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The task force established under subsection (b) shall terminate, and this Act shall cease to be effective, upon the date of submission of the final report under subsection (e).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2DAAB20DC12F480BB54AB3191291002A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H6DF08C190DED4E7491700BC5F6AF0BCC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>AI speech-to-text technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>AI speech-to-text technology</term> means a machine-based system that uses artificial intelligence, including machine learning and natural language processing, to automatically perceive, analyze, and convert human speech into written text or machine-readable data, enabling real-time transcription, accessibility, and interaction with digital systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H716A1B3FFC524F688F7C32FE33837F1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Automatic speech recognition technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>automatic speech recognition technology</term> means a technology that processes human speech and converts it into a written or machine-readable format without using artificial intelligence to facilitate communication and accessibility.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34AA0FDCE0A14671AFD6A18A06F86192"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States judicial system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States judicial system</term> means all State and Federal courts in the United States and the territories of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

