<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H45347F0E951A481DBEDE5F229780FC9B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8067 IH: Candis King Hope for Sickle Cell Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8067</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a program under which the Secretary will collect data with respect to sickle cell disease in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA83187F0D48E46AF9A3083B758F994D7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H200C3519C69244EA8BB073EB94DFF770" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Candis King Hope for Sickle Cell Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H960A5A4717CD4230B4E28CF3E4D637EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sickle Cell Data Collection program</header> 
<subsection id="HBDF78EB3C1874362BE62FB9E0646B1FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall carry out a program under which the Secretary will collect data on the incidence and prevalence of sickle cell disease in the United States, to be known as the Sickle Cell Data Collection program, through awarding grants to States for the following purposes:</text> <paragraph id="H9B4B317D53CC4C15AB05673DA44AD6F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To collect and maintain data on sickle cell disease to gain a better understanding of the incidence and prevalence of sickle cell disease in the United States, the demographics of individuals in the United States living with sickle cell disease, and the healthcare utilization patterns of individuals in the United States living with sickle cell disease.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD91F955FAE064BD8B3D281C6E40A4358"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To collaborate with other entities who received grants under the Sickle Cell Data Collection program of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for purposes of increasing the standardization of methods for sickle cell disease surveillance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0DCF6A44297D461180955EB628A3C9F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the program referred to in subsection (a), $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H994F43ABE72C4F43A7C6781771FE24E6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Division of Blood Disorders and Public Health Genomics</header> 
<subsection id="HE8F9233B8DFF42DC871F824862933D77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall reinstate any covered employee of the Division of Blood Disorders and Public Health Genomics of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6A13697A641044FB98B3BED1AF57FBF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered employee defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered employee</term> means an employee of the Division of Blood Disorders and Public Health Genomics of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention who was removed on or after January 1, 2025, under any agency action (including any reduction in force conducted pursuant to subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code or any agency reorganization) that provides for the removal of 3 percent or more of the total number of employees at such Division within a 60-day period.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

