<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7039727DF66E4176B766A0F088ACC23E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7679 IH: Child Automobile Restraint Safety Education and Training Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7679</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000602">Ms. Gillen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 23, United States Code, to include public information and education activities as authorized programming under highway safety programs and to require the Secretary of Transportation to carry out an education campaign on the dangers associated with noncompliant or counterfeit child restraint systems, including car seats and booster seats, and methods for identifying and avoiding such systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB7F9213F52746298439379247764A4A" style="OLC">
<section id="HD8B680AABBDE433B8A983D9ECDE0BE4B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child Automobile Restraint Safety Education and Training Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CAR SEAT Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> 
<section id="H66256181FC46466DB9EC2B10055522D8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Education campaign</header> 
<subsection id="HA6629BA079704291B0E42A2BF5DDA8F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall carry out an education campaign on the dangers associated with noncompliant or counterfeit child restraint systems, including car seats and booster seats, that do not meet Federal safety standards under sections 571.213 and 571.213b of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, and methods for identifying and avoiding such systems.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2B6A4A7F52E246B09011D803047C98E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $1,500,000, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2CE028A1A17344739B192008054FE9AB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Highway safety programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402(a)(2)(A)(iii) of title 23, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, and to carry out public information and education activities related to the dangers associated with noncompliant or counterfeit child restraint systems, including car seats and booster seats, that do not meet Federal safety standards under sections 571.213 and 571.213b of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, and methods for identifying such products</quote> after <quote>underserved populations</quote>. </text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

