<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-ROM25614-CGR-RC-24T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 639 IS: Establishing an annual Senate academic civics competition for secondary school students.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 639</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260311">March 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Establishing an annual Senate academic civics competition for secondary school students.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="id56292591497f47f3af16030792a2fa6a" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Senate finds the following:</text><paragraph id="idccd1e1a1c99c450f8d5f0b100269765b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to the 2022 National Assessment of Educational Progress civics and United States history assessments, the average civics score for students in grade 8 was 2 points lower compared to the average civics score in 2018, the first time the civics score dropped since the assessment was first administered in 1998.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddddd4eaccbe84bfe818b5efa105c261c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the 2023 Annenberg Civics Knowledge Survey, a nationally represented survey, 1 in 6 adults in the United States could not name any of the 3 branches of government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b9b376dda5b421282fbdd4471adb952"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The decline in civics education contributes to civic disengagement, evident in lower voter turnout among young people and reduced participation in community life.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd93392b20ba04dee99d15fe333b8ae9b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The spread of misinformation and disinformation has further highlighted the urgent need for students to gain civic reasoning and media literacy skills.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idccc5fa6e98834f83a606099bbe777384"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The success of the Congressional Art Competition and the Congressional App Challenge demonstrates that Congress can play a unique role in elevating student talent and achievement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d600c839c1947dfb7485fe47454f521" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text>With the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States approaching next year, the Senate has an opportunity to renew America’s commitment to civic education and democratic participation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id17dff3ede2bf4d829eb0f2a396dfc271"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual Senate civics competition</header><subsection id="idce539c0912d640089f2e00b6b329055f"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb71b531f805c45dea425175bbd50e2e7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Committee</term> means the Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id372b5b81841540a2b2278c69e515d541"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>secondary school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id75ae5fb0ae9e465cba37d19faef10efd"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Competition established</header><text>The Committee shall establish and carry out an annual academic competition in the field of civics for secondary school students.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9b08fb4b8dca4538acffffc7b6c5f50f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text>The Committee may—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id988bf3eaa45c4046acb8f9ed2fac63f0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partner with relevant public or nonprofit organizations, such as iCivics or the National Constitution Center, to assist with the design of judging rubrics and to offer support with the competition described in subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb42f35be6a894f1ba2fac70c59a8fe53"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accept donations from private entities to offset costs associated with the competition described in subsection (b). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida977eeee471f40709aa51b57d6dedf59"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Committee shall promulgate regulations necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

