<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF088EAC87EC743BD9C778014DC6221BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8748 IH: Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000480">Mr. Fong</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to carry out certain activities related to surface transportation research, development, and deployment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC7DE02270D60416AB261F1A4131B78DE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9AD5BCBB13C741DB82D039B3D1F49A45" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Surface Transportation Research and Development Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H27ABEA2A83AC464B8E83B0DCD97E2661"><enum>2.</enum><header>Technology and innovation programs related to highway and intermodal transportation systems</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 503 of title 23, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4B8DFEDAAD9A4012A3046A750B17D37F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(D), by striking <quote>fiscal years 2022 through 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal years 2027 through 2031</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABBF1AA66E0A4442880E116C4C6733D2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(I)(i), by striking <quote>fiscal years 2022 through 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal years 2027 through 2031</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3415A5886614E51826C9527ABEEEF4F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(C), by striking <quote>fiscal years 2022 through 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal years 2027 through 2031</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H42979294165440E59B34D60F93573DCF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Update to transportation statistics programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6302 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HAD901C4F127544BC9EFE6F9ED97D0F8E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3) by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="H9CE56B37AF1E4A2A87B34AE07C0226DD" style="USC"> <subparagraph id="H64D3FE8DFF4B4C52813DD9DD465E055D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall be located within the organizational structure of the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Research and Technology.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45EB70489D684F358B5AEC49CA3AFCFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>a significant role in</quote> and inserting <quote>exclusive authority over</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACB9A52F95D0478DAD67EB235DA9E83C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H2FA31DA6D6774290A53D2E01BE3F32FC" style="USC"> 
<subsection id="H14A8F9999EC9480F9D29DFA1ECC96EE2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination of statistical activities</header> 
<paragraph id="HF4DBDFDD0BC343318BD3773AA5720710"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H592B95AD75CD40EE9EC0A520A9DC7163" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any activity of the Department related to the collection, analysis, and use of data for a statistical purpose is conducted in a manner that protects the trust of information providers and maintains the confidentiality, objectivity, and integrity of such data, in accordance with subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD45FFB3FC8824D039449BD9A6B37550E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Department and each operating administration thereof is following, as appropriate, best practices, technical standards, and requirements in accordance with subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of title 5, subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, and any other appropriate Federal policy in the collection, analysis, and use of any transportation-related data intended for a statistical purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB167338292C436BBC2FD8558E1ABBCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statistical purpose defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>statistical purpose</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3561 of title 44.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB15DE471E30C4ED1A44C3A9A9BB9131A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transportation Statistics Coordination Council</header> 
<subsection id="H5C52FB7BB734411DB39399F70F94F51F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after section 6302 the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H1C08A9299D474942AAAA3FC754243848" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H6A25A4F5C3514977A0053CA28DCDE841"><enum>6302A.</enum><header>Transportation Statistics Coordination Council.</header> <subsection id="H83A58D6FB51C417CA3D61F25F561E2DF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish the <quote>Transportation Statistics Coordination Council</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Council</quote>) to coordinate statistical activities and evaluations across the Department.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5209CD8E2FE402D92AD8342654576E8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall be composed of a representative from each operating administration of the Department that conducts a program related to any statistical activities and evaluations documented by the Department. The Secretary may designate additional members to the Council as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5ED21459E09445A6BB18AD09629F9AA1" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Director shall serve as the Chairperson of the Council.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD5A29BCA2C7944CB9F384848AD2CEA0A" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Council shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEA1F0A53D4FF43FB92EFCD354AD6FA5F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assist the Director in carrying out the duties required under subsection (b)(3) of section 6302. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA777FE8EC4644F7A9C28E699166C5D06" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Review the comprehensive data inventory of the Department developed and maintained pursuant to section 3511 of title 44, to identify any data assets of the Department that are duplicative or fragmented across the Department;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05C24FF0E0CE4FEAA39662700A9318A0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identify any opportunity to reduce burden, including with respect to a State, local, or Tribal government or a private sector entity, by consolidating into a centralized repository managed by the Director similar collection of information from different operating administrations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H143D9387FDB441A9B96B1A5FBD9182E6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Advise the Director with respect to the development and implementation of Department-wide data guidelines, standards, metadata schemas, and common taxonomies related to any statistical activities and evaluations conducted by the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H65D7F90577C74918AD5D85388C698364" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that includes information related to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAE1452F5AB2F4FBAAC597DC92D6A2568" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A comprehensive inventory of any statistical activities and evaluations conducted by the Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AD3DADDF4324CF1876AE193EBDEF1D7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for the elimination of any statistical activities and evaluations conducted outside the Bureau that duplicate the duties required under subsection (b)(3) of section 6302, including information relating to the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H82A73A77FE964F46B162BAF26F81A15A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any plan for an order or agreement under section 1535 of title 31.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D928A9489CC4E6F8D9FB2680392A5FC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis related to whether all statistical activities and evaluations of the Department should be centralized within the Bureau.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE568E38C349443B7A9A95650268A7C7F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A governance strategy and any recommendations to ensure the Department and any operating administration of the Department is following the Department-wide data guidelines, standards, metadata schemas, and common taxonomies referred to in subsection (d)(4).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCDE0C5FA1424547B12BEE514C7FA440" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of any administrative, technical, or legal barrier to the governance strategy and recommendations described in paragraph (3), including any findings or milestones for implementation by the Department the Council determines necessary to achieve a unified, secure, and efficient departmental statistical infrastructure in accordance with such subparagraph.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD481A5B94CF142AAB324D179AD3CD675" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0E27754784DB4F36BABFCD2E459007C5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Burden; collection of information</header><text>The terms <quote>burden</quote> and <quote>collection of information</quote> have the meaning given such terms in section 3502 of title 44. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85B6F83A11D84E4BA91010E5AA37875B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The term <term>evaluation</term> has the meaning given such term in section 311 of title 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A5027D582DB425990D0EF2432E5B334" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Statistical activities</header><text>The term <term>statistical activities</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3561 of title 44.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FA02085C9B746D1B4F2D9830B8E4B85"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/63">chapter 63</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/6302">section 6302</external-xref> the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H8FD15177172A4A0085E44FA2FA449FFB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">6302A. Transportation Statistics Coordination Council.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HC0CD5913776B480C8C8C58C108900DFF" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Amendments to the university transportation centers program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5505 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC7D39BC3C9442F79E3288554FAD0F1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) of subsection (c)(4), by striking <quote>not more than</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EA6A99490C9407AA243D3E077A0B78A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3) of subsection (d), by striking <quote>fiscal years 2022 through 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal years 2027 through 2031</quote>. </text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5350B16076FF445EACDAC3729D578863"><enum>6.</enum><header>Open research initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5506 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H68C8EDC17A644EA0B87367F45F2F7D4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Not less frequently than biennially, in accordance</quote> and inserting <quote>In accordance</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1B9DB5345124514A43E015E52033276"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (i), by striking <quote>2022 through 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>2027 through 2031</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62C634BC82274421B8E2266623D8C94B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (i) as subsection (j); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H916B773B727C4ECFAC76B0AC1CF8D7EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (h) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H7FA95DBAB3644F3B832901EB5CC473B2" style="USC"> <subsection id="H8FF8862B01E44AB29223E95ED588B74D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header> <paragraph id="HD61A06EAB7C34A72984E06D82EF7D3EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop an implementation plan to transition the advanced transportation research pilot program described in subsection (b) to a sustained open research initiative.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H379C310A67BC4ACEB411B6DE64A89F38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report that includes information relating to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H70144A9CDE6D48AABBA83E20F4E5AF2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The implementation plan under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00D66EBD777E447EAD48A051C9394838"><enum>(B)</enum><text>How the Secretary is carrying out such implementation plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H27F4B6DC6AD24665B69900B9302E98B9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Study on and recommendations relating to the safety effects of emerging headlamp technologies</header> <subsection id="H34BC1BFF994D4982B2CDD407FA09D1C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, Secretary of Transportation (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Assistant Secretary of Transportation for Research and Technology, and in consultation with the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, shall seek to enter into an agreement with an appropriate entity with relevant expertise, as determined by the Secretary, to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5817702F23A446CCBB584D1D6930A672"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on the effects of high-intensity light-emitting diode (LED), matrix LED, and other emerging headlamp technologies with respect to driver visibility, glare exposure, and roadway safety; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4046639018743BF997FD2965E168971"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations relating thereto.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCD91B7C25DFE435CAE0F2A4F7BEDFF6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header> 
<paragraph id="H02228D5576EF44FA936C2E7A6DB48321"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The study under subsection (a) may include any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H83770B8EC1904404AB6B0BB83205EA6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="HAA4445FFAB87422EB9F27A7855991C0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Luminous intensity, total luminous flux, and beam-pattern characteristics of headlamp technologies utilized in road vehicles.</text></clause> <clause id="HC5A27117888E403CA4693C697FCC646D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The role of vehicle mounting height and headlamp aim in real-world glare exposure, including the geometric interaction between headlamps and occupants of preceding or oncoming vehicles, across a range of vehicles and vehicle mounting heights.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7C895B32799542439F1F9CF06579C027" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The physiological and cognitive effects of high-intensity headlamp exposure on the following:</text> <subclause id="HFEC60E2CA9B948928DA032BB4F0CAC18" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Drivers, with particular attention to older drivers, as defined by the appropriate entity referred to in such subsection, and drivers with cataracts or other visual impairments.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE45ADA14AAA640E5B7E7633CCCFF3546" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The ability of drivers to visually identify and avoid vulnerable road users, including pedestrians, bicyclists, and motorcyclists.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD330C4F494194D8985DE0F1785307949"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the adequacy of existing headlamp photometric test procedures to address the luminance, spectral, and glare characteristics of high-intensity LED, matrix LED, and other emerging headlamp technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D5B53C2F2AB437EBA0B77F84F54DA5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The recommendations under subsection (a) may include a recommendation regarding how to mitigate a negative finding of the study under such subsection with respect to the effect of high-intensity LED, matrix LED, or another emerging headlamp technology on driver visibility, glare exposure, or roadway safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD8197155FBFF4B48BB05058AEB87BB78"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after entering into an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and make publicly available on a website of the Department of Transportation, a report that includes information relating to the findings of the study conducted pursuant to such subsection and the recommendations relating thereto.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD4F6D8A8E894474BB98D058B2104FCA1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Strategy on reclaimed asphalt pavement</header> 
<subsection id="HBE25121A6FE941BCA0CC92EC8264465C" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a strategy to encourage the standardization and utilization of reclaimed asphalt pavement on roadways nationwide and ensure asphalt mixture quality does not decrease as a result of such utilization.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H649C94197A7C44099604BDA6EFC87E7C" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategy under subsection (a) shall include information relating to the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5A3C84525E554DC5AE476D0552D26D01" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A review and inventory of the activities of the Secretary with respect to reclaimed asphalt pavement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5143C9BADC0145A5AF80FFBA7C5D4904" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An analysis of cost savings related to increasing the allowable use of reclaimed asphalt pavement on roadways nationwide.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H040F2AB6369049F8B71AF5408C702A31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of any such activities related to supporting the development of technical standards, best practices, methodologies, and frameworks for testing and use of reclaimed asphalt pavement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3ADCA1469BF41FF8568395E9ED6136D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations to promote through programs of the Department of Transportation the utilization of reclaimed asphalt pavement.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFBB35A52FC464384B8404BD7DA8FE553"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In submitting the strategy under subsection (a), the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration, shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9427E356C4C748809270C4D1A49C24F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Seek to consult with representatives from the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0CDDAE6427B5475EB62EA7535EAE1833"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8390D5BEF24A4675892F53760C89E8B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State departments of transportation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAAA0C52401B146B9A7D1D02AB643133F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Units of local government.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA978F6B2139F45899E4E05628CC56E9A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Metropolitan planning organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9B845BBAFAF402C9A8BE93D11BCBFBD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Regional transportation planning organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4F8BDAC8C9240B3A9D5D309D051FE3E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Nonprofit research organizations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72BFCB05D49F4D8EAD5BC24355C49BED" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Private sector entities that produce asphalt materials.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E94844AD9D340C9862D0A0569DC0CA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Consult with the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEB7F6E7A5BEC4FD3A5983D9891C47D6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC26980D42BFD4979A51AA1B632A3D52C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any other relevant entity as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HACCF5610F49E495580898360E48099E3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H3CD53EBDEEE244AF97D63FA2DF25FC55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H310A5699EE884CDAB0209961EE2CCE4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Metropolitan planning organization</header><text>The term <quote>metropolitan planning organization</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5303 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9632ABF05D874EAEBDF4DD8698D8B78F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonprofit research organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>nonprofit research organization</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>nonprofit institution</quote> in section 4 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3703">15 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14D89AEED88647DD8252304703AF5502"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reclaimed asphalt pavement</header><text>The term <quote>reclaimed asphalt pavement</quote> means material that is removed in the resurfacing, rehabilitation, or reconstruction of asphalt pavement and processed for utilization in the production of new asphalt pavement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21362B24C277408DAAEB31BDCD1464B6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Regional transportation planning organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>regional transportation planning organization</quote> means an organization designated under subsection (l) of section 5304 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5AE130AB52234AAFA9FF14A409B8D5E9"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rail research programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 24910 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H977C942216774B11ADBEA69D3F069C13"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H72D6A1788F0F4D12AB262CF76D07B797"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H404C436F37024AEC85345D0C5DF86299"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE676658ED85541CFA8B9DE9A95FA0E4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HDEB32BC43748411F8C61DB6DCFD892D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H9244DCE1F2F24380A29E2458BA0E6200"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address safety challenges with modern and future infrastructure and technology related to commuter rail, passenger rail, freight rail, and other rail networks.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA57C577291E544FCA0D9C85525D1FAA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <subparagraph id="H03926DAD6DD8407E8B409055E9DF501F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (13), by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E4A5C3D11AB461E98EBFCEC6D4BADC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (14) as paragraph (15); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEA20B9842DAC40079ED18167E5A28F04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (13) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H12E761CCD9A34720A51A18D1B08422C4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HA18E4BCDD45B4723A0A4F30C7319F067"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to review safety standards related to the transportation of hazardous materials on freight rail; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36296AFC4295428DB8C6BD994F0A52A5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3) of subsection (c), by striking <quote>2019</quote> and inserting <quote>2031</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB0608226239407DA9C1356E3D48C025"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking <quote>2010 through 2013</quote> and inserting <quote>2027 through 2031</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

