<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26032-4JX-YM-YDH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 585 ATS: Honoring the life, achievements, and legacy of Ben Nighthorse Campbell.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 585</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S293">Mr. Graham</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S345">Mr. Johnson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S174">Mr. McConnell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life, achievements, and legacy of Ben Nighthorse Campbell.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell was born on April 13, 1933, in Auburn, California;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell joined the United States Air Force in 1951 and was stationed in Korea during the Korean War, serving as an air policeman;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell left the United States Air Force in 1953 with the rank of Airman Second Class and was awarded the Korean Service Medal and the Air Medal;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell went on to graduate from university and excel in judo, winning 3 national titles in the United States, competing in the 1963 Pan-American Games, and representing the United States on a global stage during the 1964 Summer Olympics, where he was the first Native American to ever compete on the United States Olympic judo team;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell and his wife, Linda, moved to her home State of Colorado and went on to buy a ranch near Ignacio on the Southern Ute Indian Reservation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell learned how to fashion jewelry from his father, going on to create internationally award-winning jewelry and founding Nighthorse Jewelry, a successful family business that spans 3 generations of craftsmanship;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell was elected to the Colorado State Legislature, where he served for 4 years and was voted one of the 10 best legislators by his colleagues;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell was then elected to the House of Representatives in 1986, becoming one of the few enrolled members of a federally recognized Tribe to serve in the United States Congress;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during his tenure in the House of Representatives, Ben Nighthorse Campbell authored landmark legislation to establish the National Museum of the American Indian, honoring the legacy of American indigenous communities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell also authored legislation elevating Black Canyon of the Gunnison to a national park, creating the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site, and passed the Animas-La Plata water projects for the Southern Ute Indian and Ute Mountain Ute Tribes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell was then elected to the Senate in 1993, serving as the chair of the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate between 1997 and 2005;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, during the 105th Congress, Ben Nighthorse Campbell passed more legislation than any other Member of the Senate;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell was the first and only American Indian to chair the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate and was a member of the Council of 44 Chiefs of the Northern Cheyenne Tribe; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ben Nighthorse Campbell was a trailblazer who championed bipartisan action and dedicated his entire life in service of his community, the people of Colorado, and the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id02552e1f71a548fdafbd1926b7542934"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has heard with profound sorrow and deep regret the announcement of the death of Ben Nighthorse Campbell, former Senator from Colorado;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5f902de35600478ab48d3a13409cd2f1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the life, achievements, and legacy of Ben Nighthorse Campbell for—</text><subparagraph id="id6f38c7b22dae4d4f869b662d1f50ffb8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>his service to his country in the United States Air Force; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idedc6ac7f6aff40c098dfc1981053d344"><enum>(B)</enum><text>his exceptional tenure as a Member of both the Senate and the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id17ccb755289f4d0c9d40b3069ecd6b5a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests the Secretary of the Senate to—</text><subparagraph id="id70c88809fef14a708c058b8beb4f93cf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>communicate this resolution to the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id221d94f419aa4649a94a0520f740b3f3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the family of Ben Nighthorse Campbell; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id663b53e5cacd4e70854e848283fea48c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>stands in recess as a further mark of respect to the memory of the late Ben Nighthorse Campbell when the Senate recesses today.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

