<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MCC26754-YR5-YR-243"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4547 IS: America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4547</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to strengthen requirements for naturalization, to require instruction on the oath of allegiance and the principles of the Constitution, to establish consequences for fraud and concealment in the naturalization process, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5dd07002062942bdabeb47e17cad6e2c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4c1761d0c2440429e996673a58d9cc8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf4edcce80a54466888c91c123b4be1ec">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide02b1edc571a449bbe1f95dc2d4b2994">Sec. 3. Purposes.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idbac6c56a482047ca9d7e95bfd65e60c0">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id655eb92eb8bd412c9b9086e16d53289d">Sec. 5. Strengthening civics and English requirements for naturalization.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id32689ba6099042c5961268d6f7bbb36e">Sec. 6. Attachment to the principles of the Constitution and allegiance to the United States.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id788ec0c2d0a444b0af9402a5f4cbba35">Sec. 7. Instruction on the oath of allegiance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id47ec4174e9734ce3a7a183d72faaca50">Sec. 8. Consequences for fraud, concealment, false statements, and abuse of the naturalization process.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id919c912e3a634fd5a8d116bee8cbeb32">Sec. 9. Preservation of denaturalization authorities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idf54dca3fe8ae480990fce40fb69075de">Sec. 10. Criminal penalties for naturalization fraud and false statements.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id31ecdc27d7b442bc9edf97f9fe9300bc">Sec. 11. America 250 Citizenship Initiative.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id5fc8495669414eaeb04a534fd994f7cf">Sec. 12. Annual report to Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide1e743d18f4b43bda28f32b289b0a6d7">Sec. 13. Regulations.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id669361d69b5b4368bfa36dd3473dec4d">Sec. 14. Rule of construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="iddd5da27942bd4bbaafe519ed5ee49dd4">Sec. 15. Severability.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idaf55eaad22514b5f816c51ccbee1ebb2">Sec. 16. Effective date.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="idf4edcce80a54466888c91c123b4be1ec"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id835304d533694e7a8eac742ba45e817c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>American citizenship is not merely an administrative status, immigration benefit, welfare ticket, or entitlement to public resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id13ce9d2e994c45d3883055fd578d1da8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>American citizenship is membership in the American political community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id919dcc8ca8974a77bb673cac2a4ac77a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>American citizenship carries rights, privileges, duties, and obligations, including allegiance to the United States, fidelity to the Constitution of the United States, obedience to the laws of the United States, and attachment to the principles of republican self-government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e4073b46f3e493091392c09b0bf9274"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States is a sovereign Nation with the inherent authority to determine who may join the Nation as a citizen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id059e846f2f69433eb0c67005097e912f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Naturalization is the formal act by which an alien is admitted into the American people and assumes the obligations of American citizenship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ed5ad90a141482bb0cd45412fc5f598"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Naturalization is not a ministerial transaction. It is a solemn act of allegiance to the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34aef3e132e54d6c8de2ae97734ef9fc"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An applicant for naturalization must demonstrate more than physical presence, technical eligibility, or completion of paperwork.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id82e16d4655eb4ec0a002a88453592a78"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An applicant for naturalization must demonstrate good moral character, attachment to the principles of the Constitution of the United States, and favorable disposition toward the good order and happiness of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a2a7c3ab45f4486b6383a14f0c7c555"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The oath of allegiance is not ceremonial language alone. It is the formal promise by which a new citizen renounces prior political allegiance, pledges true faith and allegiance to the United States, and accepts the duties of American citizenship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0aefab17504c4ae69bf317c8a105a659"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A person who seeks naturalization should understand the English language, the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution of the United States, the Bill of Rights, the rule of law, separation of powers, Federalism, equal citizenship, religious liberty, freedom of speech, and the duties of citizenship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2715270626de431697baacec96a33dac"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A person who knowingly engages in, incites, prepares, plans, assists, or provides material support for terrorism, violent revolution, political violence, the overthrow of constitutional government, transnational criminal organizations, cartels, or criminal gangs is not attached to the principles of the Constitution of the United States and is not well disposed to the good order and happiness of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde9b970415b04e07928df4f263b93e4b"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A person who knowingly acts as an agent, representative, or instrumentality of a foreign power, or knowingly acts under the direction or control of a foreign power, in a manner materially inconsistent with allegiance to the United States, is not attached to the principles of the Constitution of the United States and is not well disposed to the good order and happiness of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94d498dd2f564a7597999222417c27c4"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Fraud, concealment, false statements, false identity, fraudulent documents, unlawful voting, obstruction of background checks, and concealment of criminal, terrorist, gang, cartel, or foreign-power affiliations corrupt the naturalization process and attack the integrity of American citizenship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60fe2a08b62a4ea492a95a5b9fec08fa"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Congress has a duty to ensure that naturalization remains a meaningful act of allegiance, assimilation, and membership in the American Nation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ide02b1edc571a449bbe1f95dc2d4b2994"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="id8dcebe2890214960af1f923df392b1c1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to restore naturalization as a serious act of joining the American people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b69de5870794fa591d2d6e988328ada"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to reaffirm that American citizenship is a bond of allegiance, constitutional attachment, civic duty, and membership in the Nation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaba1d4e2f50a4b0291be69d5cd8aaae2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to strengthen the civics, English, and constitutional-attachment requirements for naturalization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddddf58e312c44bb696be43bfbce259dc"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to ensure that applicants for naturalization understand the oath of allegiance before becoming citizens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idad62533a4c5c4e1b927c23190d1f0680"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to prevent persons who engage in, incite, prepare, plan, assist, or provide material support for terrorism, violent revolution, political violence, criminal gangs, cartels, or the overthrow of constitutional government from obtaining citizenship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ed6f5addec94d34bda36e1d84f0a643"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to prevent persons knowingly acting as agents, representatives, or instrumentalities of a foreign power, or knowingly acting under the direction or control of a foreign power, in a manner materially inconsistent with allegiance to the United States, from obtaining citizenship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee45d8d56d9745a1b387bdb0fa0052d8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to impose meaningful consequences on persons who defraud, corrupt, obstruct, or abuse the naturalization process; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c374651cc5748c68ae67f9fb63b7e85"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to ensure that the 250th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence is marked by a renewed national commitment to American citizenship, constitutional liberty, and civic obligation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idbac6c56a482047ca9d7e95bfd65e60c0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id5a79cec764b34ee2a3f2d951ec479dec"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alien</header><text>The term <term>alien</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d381865142241eca76d203a3dc7d169"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>The term <term>applicant</term> means an alien who applies for naturalization under title III of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1401">8 U.S.C. 1401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d6f9c414299429ab943cdea1eaaf205"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign power</header><text>The term <term>foreign power</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="ida24c5ec48fd04ca7a4dc72d91c5e1212"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a foreign government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8249754ff66443b8b25118c6fdff45f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a faction of a foreign nation or foreign government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ad46ced038748629e44d1b4a11038ac"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity that is directed or controlled by a foreign government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3b85c61d750841258f286911a6378183"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a foreign military, paramilitary, intelligence, security, or law-enforcement service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0be3c4078b414d95a3c30b7136c66e5a"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a foreign terrorist organization designated under section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f8e2a6d1bbc4538b148f697cd2416b9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a transnational criminal organization, cartel, or criminal gang that is based primarily outside the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idad06a760ff0d417d94b1c9140609844f"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any person or entity knowingly acting as an agent, representative, instrumentality, or proxy of an entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id80387f923bfa4735a19e32304fe4e0f1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Material fact</header><text>The term <term>material fact</term> means any fact that has a natural tendency to influence, or is capable of influencing, a decision of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, or any other officer or employee of the United States concerning eligibility for naturalization, good moral character, attachment to the principles of the Constitution, admissibility, removability, identity, criminal history, national-security risk, immigration history, or eligibility for any immigration benefit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id17270dbefb4346eda36055e543a65cc4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Naturalization process</header><text>The term <term>naturalization process</term> means any application, interview, examination, investigation, oath ceremony, background check, biometric collection, submission of evidence, administrative proceeding, judicial proceeding, or other act or proceeding related to naturalization under title III of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf727925055a143979571f5501974476e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaa31c59f8c754202bc73108762c5389e"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Material support</header><text>The term <term>material support</term> means material support or resources, as defined in section 2339A(b) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf2ad55646b1b416685e5e5a69606d32a"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Terrorist activity</header><text>The term <term>terrorist activity</term> has the meaning given such term in section 212(a)(3)(B)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(iii)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id55a28c67bdc84823aca16d9d5be89ae5"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Terrorist organization</header><text>The term <term>terrorist organization</term> means an organization described in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of section 212(a)(3)(B)(vi) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)(B)(vi)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id655eb92eb8bd412c9b9086e16d53289d"><enum>5.</enum><header>Strengthening civics and English requirements for naturalization</header><subsection id="idbe2cb51f469f44ad9f87905801af45f2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 312 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1423">8 U.S.C. 1423</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd165b500ab7b4c58b2c81957dfa35844"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="iddfc06e957db04950800b0af3ed4e5d95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>an understanding of the English language</quote> and inserting <quote>a sufficient understanding of the English language to read, write, speak, and understand ordinary English, including the English language used in the oath of allegiance described in section 337</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9642b38762314bce98c3098a6f815538"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>a knowledge and understanding of the fundamentals of the history, and of the principles and form of government, of the United States</quote> and inserting <quote>a substantial knowledge and understanding of the history, principles, form of government, constitutional structure, and civic obligations of the United States</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide34ec7ba2de741688115dae31d9486bc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida633edb7b8654f4e8483a5ed583bf0d5"><paragraph id="id494f4c7fe21446ef86bdbabab21fa501"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The examination required under paragraph (2) shall include questions testing the applicant’s knowledge and understanding of—</text><subparagraph id="idabbe28fdc7384c4899948925fbcc2629"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Declaration of Independence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c535f8ba88f4ab3869eef3caff81fbf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Constitution of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65da1721fed740e982ed6ccbc4397a60"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Bill of Rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce0eb1d2090d4a7f978bd1e66033d5ce"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the separation of powers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfde6a66c31c040a7a35f9f82de9d6ec4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Federalism;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7592c46574d4bc6a1097a8296e2c7e3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the rule of law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26597a90c8cf4db087f112991763c761"><enum>(G)</enum><text>equal citizenship under law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2c8d75c4d1224815ba63df6a795e38bc"><enum>(H)</enum><text>religious liberty;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb49ab0eb484a4890ab08b742a8b95f28"><enum>(I)</enum><text>freedom of speech;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc68100a69b3240c0b140a3cbf98e0af6"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the history of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0699ad89b34c4b7d8565b1fd6592000d"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the duties and obligations of citizenship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf561330f163741b4862b1a9c398c7e01"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the meaning of the oath of allegiance described in section 337; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb6e0804dbbdf4732bc64ac0016720479"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the requirement that a citizen bear true faith and allegiance to the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc44c87c33d2b4f91b0d39ee0b02a9e8b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) or any other provision of Federal law, the examination required under paragraph (2) shall be administered in the English language.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfaa68ea555b045388597a1e25cef6385"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) or any other provision of Federal law, the Secretary shall ensure that an applicant may not satisfy the requirement under paragraph (2) unless the applicant correctly answers not less than 80 percent of the questions asked during the examination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc77068d090143dbba73558704e88932"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Except as otherwise provided in subsection (b) or any other provision of Federal law, the Secretary shall ensure that not less than 50 percent of the questions asked during the examination required under paragraph (2) concern the Constitution of the United States, the Declaration of Independence, the Bill of Rights, the structure of the Government of the United States, or the oath of allegiance described in section 337.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id460e4ed99bca4d89982d156b06b15a0f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf60cfb452022485fbc44dc34a29d7b97"><subsection id="id5acd3372e99e4e1c924f6f866846359e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review and publication of naturalization examination materials</header><paragraph id="id68086507fdaa4be7be944b6bb5d03f39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall revise the naturalization examination and study materials used to administer this section to comply with the requirements of such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id665f6038bfd54eeb96fcbda8b62b840d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary shall make publicly available the study materials described in paragraph (1), including a description of the subjects tested and the minimum passing standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideb0cabb394fb438dbac29ce9b3a43cca"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 4 years, the Secretary shall review and, as appropriate, revise the examination and study materials described in paragraph (1) to ensure that such examination and materials adequately test an applicant’s knowledge of the subjects described in subsection (a)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbb4905400a1b4d56970fafd0a63fbde3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on waivers</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report identifying—</text><paragraph id="idb2af0f82f98e4890a0ef889b25fe8dc7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of applicants granted a waiver or exception from any English-language requirement under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id507341981aa94568b6bd5b3573349d89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of applicants granted a waiver or exception from any civics or history requirement under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb00e4be6731f4f9b8a52b3d4f4144242"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the statutory basis for each category of waiver or exception;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc33aa02f3e2465689be3ad032d1fc5a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of applicants who failed the examination required under subsection (a)(2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd000950ba9aa42819dbd952eb7a36d7b"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of applicants who passed the examination required under subsection (a)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8c4dad80cb54c19a35a7142eb64bdb7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any recommendations for improving the integrity and rigor of the naturalization examination.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddf80a21873b041edb158509ae8360556"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any application for naturalization filed on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id32689ba6099042c5961268d6f7bbb36e"><enum>6.</enum><header>Attachment to the principles of the Constitution and allegiance to the United States</header><subsection id="id59ab67a17c4a41d5855d98037e41307b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 316 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1427">8 U.S.C. 1427</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id038b2463960b403e91c21a4bb07a046e"><subsection id="id8bf6025129ee47b4bcea01ab4db79752"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Attachment to the principles of the Constitution and allegiance to the United States</header><paragraph id="idbfeab10b4fcb4e229d06e58167eaad98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, an applicant shall not be regarded as attached to the principles of the Constitution of the United States or well disposed to the good order and happiness of the United States if the applicant knowingly—</text><subparagraph id="id15edaba316a4404bb46e6e628acf64b5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engages in, incites, prepares, plans, assists, or provides material support for terrorism or terrorist activity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide08a2e80bcab46529257a9a7660a3a44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advocates or teaches the duty, necessity, or propriety of the overthrow by force, violence, or other unlawful means of the Government of the United States or the constitutional order of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf33d5596e0ee4e60ac4e3bd15cacb512"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engages in, incites, prepares, plans, assists, or provides material support for assassination, sabotage, kidnapping, political violence, or other unlawful violence as a means of political coercion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b8d2f9182cf4d3aba22ee6859161de8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>participates in, assists, or provides material support to a transnational criminal organization, cartel, or criminal gang;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5c6dd33b2cb4e99928b5ab9adbc3f10"><enum>(E)</enum><text>knowingly acts as an agent, representative, or instrumentality of a foreign power, or knowingly acts under the direction or control of a foreign power, in a manner materially inconsistent with allegiance to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbde67bba5a2f43ccb695a4e2ea1149b5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>conceals any affiliation, association, agency relationship, representative capacity, or conduct described in subparagraphs (A) through (E);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbc7e54bf0c7498ba4c04f466d523c83"><enum>(G)</enum><text>makes any false statement or material misrepresentation concerning the applicant’s allegiance to the United States, attachment to the principles of the Constitution of the United States, willingness to take the oath of allegiance, or disposition toward the good order and happiness of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6499aae524064fcd9aea6777e5c7031a"><enum>(H)</enum><text>refuses to affirm, without mental reservation, the oath of allegiance described in section 337.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id057538da92fa4c7d88ce737dcb54b936"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign power</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>foreign power</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the <short-title>America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id734d419721754dfca1e595d7c7f67ba7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Material support</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>material support</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the <short-title>America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9348e807e4284f3cadd61be39b85fbbc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Terrorist activity</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>terrorist activity</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the <short-title>America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act</short-title>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id667e3261017545b9b13f595f3e8643e5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to authorize the denial of an application for naturalization based solely on—</text><subparagraph id="id0b781e1742ac497bbc8142bd0539be2a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>speech protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabedd9a88487486397117510e905a1e6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>religious belief;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46a5649a1ce046aebf2cc6b86f03074d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lawful association;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f16f6098c03436db1bf0446eb0de03e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>familial relationship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85cebc590e924213b608430982505345"><enum>(E)</enum><text>nationality;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a356a4fa7dc41c8ba5998b65ed3189c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ethnicity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14a9c7ae27fd436ea731e09f72af5b36"><enum>(G)</enum><text>dual nationality;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id591980bd1d0b411e9f7ca3e805f10343"><enum>(H)</enum><text>lawful contact with a foreign government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id374a8a3d4cee4e278cbf496f7fa557b4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>lawful contact with a foreign political party; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc6901c472dc64fb794851656eb0e0069"><enum>(J)</enum><text>lawful advocacy that does not involve force, violence, material support for unlawful activity, terrorism, fraud, concealment, or conduct inconsistent with allegiance to the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id92b7da7476ec4e4c98e1c45653f4f3ed"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to alter the burden of an applicant for naturalization to establish eligibility for naturalization under this chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id4b338931d51a425fbbf87af7f14bd2ec"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 316(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1427">8 U.S.C. 1427(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, including the requirements under subsection (h),</quote> after <quote>Constitution of the United States</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1e4fe9b0b5ea44e68393371e3e208fbf"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any application for naturalization pending on or filed on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id788ec0c2d0a444b0af9402a5f4cbba35"><enum>7.</enum><header>Instruction on the oath of allegiance</header><subsection id="idb3e4f9688d514b3d87641260eab253df"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 337 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1448">8 U.S.C. 1448</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id715f7f078e2e4072b54a5e49257f2df5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf73b6ea3467f4d6a8fa633af69d9cb06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7bc23c33a5914a87b52b973a4ffe2c5c"><subsection id="id941bbfbb4d044906b90d3dd2ee3eb095"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Instruction on the oath of allegiance</header><paragraph id="id0d389b8920cd4bc0b6b80564895e087c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before administering the oath of allegiance under subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that each applicant for naturalization receives instruction, in the English language, on the meaning of the oath of allegiance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd03bf4fef6174805a492e1803c1e02dd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The instruction required under paragraph (1) shall include instruction on—</text><subparagraph id="id6333fa223e9a40b1996246d75e886128"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allegiance to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf9617a7a916249ce945258105e1dda36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>renunciation of prior political allegiance to any foreign prince, potentate, state, or sovereignty;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21b8447e5341495db5951d35c36898fc"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the duty to support and defend the Constitution and laws of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id027b85f8cf124fccb4f537ad01385700"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the obligation to bear true faith and allegiance to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5a3e9458758409abf47dc426cbf88b1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the duty to obey the laws of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3efdd9215ccb4909a5b72dee2bc5a1b0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the rights, privileges, duties, and obligations of American citizenship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7be9664237f24b4580b4ec22ee49b410"><enum>(G)</enum><text>equal citizenship under law;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd421d7f5221f4fab9d09c231b49a48f8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the distinction between citizenship, lawful permanent residence, temporary presence, parole, and other immigration statuses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide17c022b8aef44518cbce9d8836271d4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the consequences of false statements, concealment of material facts, fraud, or refusal to take the oath without mental reservation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8abe56eaf4244af09c51e7ad5e756bee"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Before administering the oath of allegiance, the Secretary shall require the applicant to certify, in writing and under penalty of perjury, that the applicant—</text><subparagraph id="id3cdef14571714916903c141c4a5e6b64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>received the instruction required under this subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf53c46164ef940ebaa113bc62685ea57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>understands the oath of allegiance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d4934c2df08473b9cc93b724b30cc19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is willing to take the oath freely and without mental reservation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id19fc3b3f85cf439b93f58246338a34f9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>understands that a false statement or concealment of a material fact concerning the oath of allegiance may result in denial of naturalization, civil denaturalization, criminal prosecution, removal, or other consequences provided by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf25583ced0e045be97d2a173ae0c5085"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waivers, modifications, and accommodations</header><text>The requirements of this subsection shall not apply to a person for whom the taking of the oath is waived under subsection (a). In the case of a person who is permitted to take a modified oath under subsection (a), the instruction and certification required under this subsection shall be conformed to the oath that such person is required to take. The Secretary shall provide reasonable accommodations for any person with a disability, consistent with subsection (a) and section 312(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2f70c1a52cc5481e928931297be15db8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to alter, limit, or supersede any accommodation, modification, waiver, or exception expressly provided by this section, section 312(b), or any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7a48d5f728c447f09f4ffdfd8a580fc8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any oath of allegiance administered on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id47ec4174e9734ce3a7a183d72faaca50"><enum>8.</enum><header>Consequences for fraud, concealment, false statements, and abuse of the naturalization process</header><subsection id="id86eb681dab06473690bb682f71bfaf16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 2 of title III of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1421">8 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 318 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3573d20e583d4e3ebbb779f77f89b741"><section id="id351e85a89cea48dc9e1d673568543c8b"><enum>318A.</enum><header>Naturalization process integrity</header><subsection id="id0510aedfa2bb425cafb60814fa8ad422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory denial</header><text>The Secretary shall deny an application for naturalization if the Secretary determines that the applicant knowingly—</text><paragraph id="idec2fb435f17b40f3b1a2fba8fc121405"><enum>(1)</enum><text>made a false statement or material misrepresentation in the naturalization process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4dc7c290d7ca48fe8f914b94df88e0e3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>concealed a material fact in the naturalization process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb9e5266c625b49bd910a8164499b9d12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submitted, presented, procured, or relied upon any fraudulent, altered, forged, counterfeit, unlawfully obtained, or materially inaccurate document in the naturalization process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c5fd9c137fa4459ba6ee92779b94151"><enum>(4)</enum><text>used a false identity, alias, false date of birth, false place of birth, false nationality, false immigration history, or false Social Security account number in the naturalization process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3cc8ab2e2254401907a29f23d13c412"><enum>(5)</enum><text>falsely claimed eligibility for naturalization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id530ca9c01ccc47bb8d7a4eebeaecf7c3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>obstructed, impeded, delayed, or refused to cooperate with any background check, biometric check, criminal-history check, immigration-history check, national-security check, interview, investigation, or request for evidence required for naturalization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b8143d2e8cc4029856bd5a7380a481a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>concealed any criminal conduct, arrest, charge, conviction, sentence, prior removal, prior unlawful presence, unlawful voting, unlawful registration to vote, unlawful employment, immigration fraud, benefit fraud, tax fraud, gang affiliation, cartel affiliation, terrorist affiliation, association with a foreign terrorist organization, or conduct described in section 316(h), if disclosure of such information was required by statute, regulation, form, instruction, interview, request for evidence, or other lawful request in the naturalization process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd7c6aee7074464fbdda790659379a12"><enum>(8)</enum><text>procured testimony, sponsorship, documentation, translation, interpretation, representation, or evidence through fraud, coercion, bribery, threat, concealment, or material misrepresentation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd46c3857c0cd4bc283a0e8f40cebe7f3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>engaged in any other fraudulent or obstructive conduct that was material to the adjudication of the application for naturalization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2d75b9763a2b41b88dd84e86850d2083"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permanent bar for serious naturalization fraud or concealment</header><paragraph id="id5df8d1da360b45c0b60afd712362a730"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), an alien described in paragraph (2) shall be permanently ineligible for naturalization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23bc86eecff94c889cef3a36abe837d3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens described</header><text>An alien is described in this paragraph if the alien knowingly engaged in conduct described in subsection (a) and such conduct involved or concealed—</text><subparagraph id="id2db05866d0b5489cabd65a5402f25a5c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>terrorism;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida10d49df0ebe4ad0bedfe5fdab1a8ad1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>espionage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8901851cc5bc405fa05919b95a18e46a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sabotage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3fbfd0a1d08d4123a192d5af3115c059"><enum>(D)</enum><text>knowingly acting as an agent, representative, or instrumentality of a foreign power, or knowingly acting under the direction or control of a foreign power, in a manner materially inconsistent with allegiance to the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide908dc0790a04efa9f65bb30a9d3cc73"><enum>(E)</enum><text>participation in, assistance to, or material support for a transnational criminal organization, cartel, or criminal gang;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id620a8dcc8e8d4c7eb372705dd4df9870"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a crime of violence, as defined in section 16 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc49c6849bb34465db2e0a900ff0fa196"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an aggravated felony, as defined in section 101(a)(43);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd92a4d7875340e4b9de927a190e70b9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a sex offense, as defined in section 111 of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20911">34 U.S.C. 20911</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide160c9d0cf2a416cad8fa1808c9756a7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>child exploitation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6dea18a733594b7587075300936a2e34"><enum>(J)</enum><text>human trafficking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id587b27bb955044be84df77d2106a7e64"><enum>(K)</enum><text>unlawful voting or unlawful registration to vote;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93a3e6c45b9047a6bc8e679366eeb8aa"><enum>(L)</enum><text>use of a false identity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74d487e442234b1c84ef3564428edd77"><enum>(M)</enum><text>prior removal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idabd7529125c2481aa6e08726ad339468"><enum>(N)</enum><text>a false claim of United States citizenship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id585db671d2f8442da70a260d94dc4e48"><enum>(O)</enum><text>fraud against the United States, a State, a unit of local government, or an Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddaf785eb6f4043afbd3a879ada6af12b"><enum>(P)</enum><text>benefit fraud involving an amount equal to or greater than $10,000; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd69a786e35fb43779cf6f35fcc21a3f6"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>any offense involving bribery, obstruction of justice, perjury, subornation of perjury, witness tampering, or destruction of records in connection with the naturalization process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7028647f47144640bb1e0841422a85d7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for certain reasonable belief cases</header><text>Subsection (b)(2)(N) shall not apply if the alien establishes, by clear and convincing evidence, that each natural parent of the alien, or, in the case of an adopted alien, each adoptive parent of the alien, is or was a citizen of the United States, the alien permanently resided in the United States before attaining the age of 16 years, and the alien reasonably believed at the time of the false claim that the alien was a citizen of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb4b88d444de94678b04c84ff7b12454a"><enum>(d)</enum><header><enum-in-header>10</enum-in-header>-year bar for other material fraud or concealment</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), an alien who knowingly engages in conduct described in subsection (a) shall be ineligible for naturalization for a period of not less than 10 years beginning on the date on which the Secretary denies the application for naturalization or determines that the alien engaged in such conduct, whichever occurs later.</text></subsection><subsection id="id040bbda981524e7d81ae27f7fc95304d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect of withdrawal, correction, or claim of immateriality</header><paragraph id="id3d09e60cda414f019d685fd1e31ed4fd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No cure by withdrawal</header><text>Conduct described in subsection (a) is not cured merely because the applicant withdraws the application for naturalization after such conduct occurs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f1a6f409cd045b3b40139e302c4d659"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No cure by correction after detection</header><text>Conduct described in subsection (a) is not cured merely because the applicant corrects, supplements, or amends the record after the false statement, misrepresentation, concealment, fraud, or obstruction is detected by the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the Department of State, or any other Federal, State, local, Tribal, territorial, or foreign authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8cd7c6347a4b4ad9be7dd6482aa26e97"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No defense based solely on claim of ultimate eligibility</header><text>It shall not be a defense to a determination under this section that the applicant asserts that the false statement, misrepresentation, concealment, fraud, or obstruction was unnecessary to ultimate eligibility for naturalization, if the fact at issue was material.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide62742d3ad8d4b7188e6630b4cfca691"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Mandatory referral</header><paragraph id="id2f8734ab68ce4d14b185a72a02059311"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines that there is credible evidence that an applicant has engaged in conduct described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall refer the matter, as appropriate, to—</text><subparagraph id="idc92c04117c3c4a208de17c7621acf946"><enum>(A)</enum><text>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide5e0577279ff44d79981f6f33c4be65a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide950de80ba834f9185f26a7faba72bb6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd19d09f0a42d43d695589b198ed4f9be"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4f67bcaf0c14dd2b8f228e946b0a0eb"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id112d1493913748e58100e74a81e31da9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other appropriate Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id92c512299ab240e3b13211b5f4f47496"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of referral</header><text>A referral under paragraph (1) shall include any relevant application materials, interview records, sworn statements, documentary evidence, biometric information, fraud findings, criminal-history information, immigration-history information, and national-security information available to the Secretary, consistent with applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8af0c9ad20364549a32edf95b8812d6c"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Removal priority</header><text>An alien who is denied naturalization under this section shall be treated as a priority for removal if the alien is otherwise removable under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id072b3b51e95941c9b56895a5b5022033"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation on subsequent immigration benefits</header><paragraph id="id86233c50f4f9427ba7a757fc2882d4ef"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an alien who is denied naturalization under subsection (a) may not receive any discretionary immigration benefit under this Act during the period of ineligibility described in subsection (b) or (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddfa834263e4a4a33bb5601e69c4a26e0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text><subparagraph id="id971136fb47bb448084a3ddd62d5bceab"><enum>(A)</enum><text>withholding of removal;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd66fc6115a894c789873b3a3f5987ad7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protection under the Convention Against Torture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0a567ffd13474ed5bd248dbc94244625"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an application, petition, or request for relief or protection for which eligibility is required by Federal law to be available notwithstanding fraud or misrepresentation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id46840d6903e6442bbab287b6885ae2de"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a law-enforcement certification, protection, or benefit made available to victims, witnesses, or cooperators, if the Secretary or the Attorney General determines that such certification, protection, or benefit is in the national interest; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8e0e651505d443679c38b7eeed061570"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other protection that the United States is required to provide under Federal law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida58f92e2594d4e0cbcba1e078ea18acf"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Record of fraud determination</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain a record of any denial or determination under this section and shall ensure that such record is available to officers and employees of the Department of Homeland Security for purposes of adjudicating any subsequent immigration application, petition, request, or benefit.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8a9be5e4e88c4e9baa083d48252b0885"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary shall provide an alien denied naturalization under this section with written notice describing—</text><paragraph id="id24d5b53cdf3a42ac8b89a853a5ef1ddf"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the basis for the denial;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc093276d2dd04eed8c073ba68208f7ed"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any period of ineligibility imposed under subsection (b) or (d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbfca5f7ea6240a4b23e4b92106c25bd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any referral made under subsection (f), to the extent disclosure is not prohibited by law or contrary to law-enforcement or national-security interests; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3749ee657ac4f348f5c78f57cd7db51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any administrative or judicial review available under law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1f9a82a2811a498590b5b7f69873de8f"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit—</text><paragraph id="idd9e139a20b0f4444bcdf0604bdcbb886"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the authority of the United States to prosecute any offense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd676851c226541b795020e4eb2d30227"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the authority of the United States to initiate removal proceedings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6da2fedb091d43349cc7ba802311fcfe"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the authority of the United States to deny any immigration benefit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id585e16c305594855b9020f9bf2a9de6a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the authority of the United States to bring a civil denaturalization action under section 340;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9cbc202bb6146ed9060ae9b46461769"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any ground of inadmissibility or deportability under this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e9ee0114eb54a5197eb0494c76d8cbb"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other consequence provided by law for fraud, concealment, false statements, false documents, perjury, unlawful voting, false claims of citizenship, or obstruction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id82977c0f4f5a4f82a7a1930f684249e7"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <quote>foreign power</quote>, <quote>material fact</quote>, and <quote>naturalization process</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the America First Citizenship and Allegiance Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idd3634583dbe2462f95df86f8921f7e37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Immigration and Nationality Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 318 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id9bdca713-19de-4c7b-9617-23734598e872"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id351e85a89cea48dc9e1d673568543c8b">Sec. 318A. Naturalization process integrity.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id4515e418c88f4609b1885b07146a483f"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 318 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1429">8 U.S.C. 1429</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>deportability pursuant to a warrant of arrest issued under the provisions of this or any other Act</quote> the following: <quote>, or while a fraud determination, background-check investigation, national-security investigation, or referral described in section 318A(f) remains pending with respect to the applicant</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1bf6326065474566ad1280e662ed219e"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to—</text><paragraph id="ide467aad8bff748b4beefaf8a066e2500"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any application for naturalization filed on or after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3fe72b09afd64a9c8a188d2a1aba034d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any application for naturalization pending on the date of enactment of this Act, except that an applicant shall be provided a reasonable opportunity to supplement or correct the application in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf6b3d16926184fe390fc6481f32d31d3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any false statement, material misrepresentation, concealment, obstruction, fraudulent submission, or other conduct described in section 318A(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by subsection (a), that occurs on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id919c912e3a634fd5a8d116bee8cbeb32"><enum>9.</enum><header>Preservation of denaturalization authorities</header><subsection id="iddd6a6d07c83a4206a7fe5bf6a0ee5c94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, shall be construed to limit, impair, or otherwise affect the authority of the United States to institute proceedings under section 340 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1451">8 U.S.C. 1451</external-xref>), including proceedings based on concealment of a material fact, willful misrepresentation, illegal procurement of naturalization, lack of good moral character, lack of attachment to the principles of the Constitution of the United States, or lack of disposition to the good order and happiness of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id4278236fee7c47a6aa951ac027a56250"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of naturalization process violation</header><text>If an alien is naturalized notwithstanding conduct described in section 318A of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 8 of this Act, such conduct may constitute evidence that the order admitting such person to citizenship was illegally procured or procured by concealment of a material fact or by willful misrepresentation for purposes of section 340 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1451">8 U.S.C. 1451</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id8f99c19cd7f54b3794bbdd0d4589df84"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="id537545ca021b423c86edbb4e5781a213"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to require the United States to institute proceedings under section 340 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1451">8 U.S.C. 1451</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60bc89bcf82f46b385a39de8cf663622"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to limit any ground for denaturalization or revocation of naturalization under section 340 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1451">8 U.S.C. 1451</external-xref>) or any other provision of law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc8a86de45c541f8992a84057a763f81"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to create any defense to denaturalization or revocation of naturalization that is not otherwise available under law.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf54dca3fe8ae480990fce40fb69075de"><enum>10.</enum><header>Criminal penalties for naturalization fraud and false statements</header><subsection id="id7fcb32719eee4798935fe2c1f5482e00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Naturalization fraud</header><text>Section 1425 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id693a587c57d5449b8f689d17e9dc3f51"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>by striking the undesignated matter following subsection (b); and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id7eca419f7210474aa776584ddbf79625"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idabaeed7ad9134c8391e79e1e2fb89e51"><subsection id="ide57ba92067184016bb90458ff1c9a7c0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person who violates subsection (a) or (b) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned—</text><paragraph id="id24ee7ce7ff7a4bd58372064e9b181662"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 25 years, if the offense was committed to facilitate an act of international terrorism, as defined in section 2331;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idacfc0e41c2c64072a9950f2d14c4bcbf"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 20 years, if the offense was committed to facilitate a drug trafficking crime, as defined in section 929(a), or transnational criminal activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2060c4bc1a964a9ba45673cb929ba01f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not more than 10 years, in the case of the first or second such offense, if the offense was not committed to facilitate an act of international terrorism, a drug trafficking crime, or transnational criminal activity; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f2287e77c9d4c5b9f382a8acf237b37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>not more than 15 years, in the case of any other offense, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id624dd5e6d7da4cd19294a3e56ad1dc05"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text>Any document, thing of value, or proceeds obtained as a result of an offense under this section shall be subject to forfeiture to the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2ebc05530f9a4e3d894a29cb92eabe63"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Immigration consequences</header><text>A conviction under this section shall be deemed to involve moral turpitude, fraud, and obstruction of the naturalization process for purposes of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id488df7f327ab44feb23b5c19e0bbfe34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>False statements relating to naturalization, citizenship, or registry</header><text>Section 1015 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="idd503aa91de834daaba653ab6354a9a43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the undesignated matter following subsection (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id963df57286b346b390737815f50c3849"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a83856e171047d1b95c9e2e02bca718"><subsection id="id6d8e6e9333724e34a29a7caa0119ef99"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (h), a person who violates this section shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf409953d2b644f50b76b0447dd68f9a9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Enhanced penalty</header><text>If an offense under this section involves terrorism, espionage, sabotage, a transnational criminal organization, cartel activity, gang activity, a sex offense, child exploitation, human trafficking, unlawful voting, false identity, prior removal, or knowingly acting as an agent, representative, or instrumentality of a foreign power, or knowingly acting under the direction or control of a foreign power, in a manner materially inconsistent with allegiance to the United States, the defendant shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id09c5e9e6564f4c49b4233e7f4005fc97"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Document fraud</header><text>Section 274C(e)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324c">8 U.S.C. 1324c(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id29db7b7696a84e0db3538e305d11aa78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>not less than $250 and not more than $2,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than $2,500 and not more than $10,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0868298fb61f4a448c3d1fba53eb49d1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>not less than $2,000 and not more than $5,000</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than $10,000 and not more than $25,000</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc23580051d1c4e8682fbdc6effdaa4fb"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>transnational criminal activity</term> means criminal activity carried out by, at the direction of, or in material coordination with a transnational criminal organization, cartel, or criminal gang that is based primarily outside the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="id97aae21528e04275bb554f13421b578d"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section, or the amendments made by this section, may be construed to limit the authority of the United States to pursue denaturalization, removal, forfeiture, civil penalties, criminal penalties, or any other remedy available under law.</text></subsection></section><section id="id31ecdc27d7b442bc9edf97f9fe9300bc"><enum>11.</enum><header>America 250 Citizenship Initiative</header><subsection id="idef8758dfcfc244c7857b9212e5844c4c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an initiative, to be known as the <quote>America 250 Citizenship Initiative</quote>, to revise and strengthen naturalization materials, oath-of-allegiance materials, and civics resources in connection with the 250th anniversary of the Declaration of Independence.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida2580ef37dd14a83b49098f8e3416099"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The initiative established under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="id3d41950df1b546e496e060646ae5c800"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revised study materials for the naturalization examination required under section 312 of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id70155d611adf421eb9bf73e84287b43a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a citizenship guide explaining the Declaration of Independence, the Constitution of the United States, the Bill of Rights, separation of powers, Federalism, religious liberty, freedom of speech, equal citizenship, the rule of law, and the duties of citizenship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida7d50b73c6144d08aacbe352cb52904f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>model materials for oath-of-allegiance ceremonies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6329851b8e694b5991a43741753689ad"><enum>(4)</enum><text>materials explaining the distinction between citizenship, lawful permanent residence, temporary presence, parole, and other immigration statuses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb132368057aa47469757d16a27b5a3d0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>materials explaining that citizenship requires allegiance to the United States and attachment to the principles of the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf12af1b26924392980079e11895c083"><enum>(6)</enum><text>materials explaining the consequences of fraud, concealment, false statements, false documents, unlawful voting, false claims of citizenship, and abuse of the naturalization process; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ac0b0e0435d4525b878af0312538f62"><enum>(7)</enum><text>such other materials as the Secretary determines appropriate to promote understanding of American citizenship, constitutional liberty, civic obligation, and allegiance to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idff4c80e66df540558eadd391ade09526"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of materials</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the materials developed under this section are incorporated into—</text><paragraph id="ide09f13b1511b440c80055859d1d9b21a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>naturalization study materials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbff79ab1f635407aa57593260c5e866d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>applicant preparation materials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0d492a4ea9d44a5b77730fa0df35769"><enum>(3)</enum><text>oath-of-allegiance instruction required under section 337(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 7 of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7cef850d1f74dce9105d532b889e4a7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>public-facing materials concerning naturalization and citizenship.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id89a2b20f697c49e8a0d3b4a51a4d04f7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="id41ec5869a65f42a38170938069e977a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Archivist of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f15d3a178ec46ba8b0d448320dcf7f9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8e36a6767ef43f9b877dc313924322d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Director of the National Park Service;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb09fa932953d453aa4ea9247f89583ac"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Librarian of Congress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c7a5de04f894698a1bd6d6ea630d76d"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06ac1aa6af0e496080505f920d7957a3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other Federal officials as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb2b24e42e4f54b6ebae30bc14af632ee"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the Secretary to create any new grant program.</text></subsection></section><section id="id5fc8495669414eaeb04a534fd994f7cf"><enum>12.</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><subsection id="id9c6b6337309d4609942be53ecd99906d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report concerning implementation of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="idb8e2f98ee4dc41fba4ceb6fc2e83b8a4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="id5816f0cc29eb418185923b571f045ed1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of naturalization applications received;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60fefbe5ddbc40e6876222fda8995213"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of naturalization applications approved;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id658a09b33fe04ce7bf82241b08034773"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of naturalization applications denied;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id631ef0746d0d4b53bfc886a06b6607d4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of denials based on failure to satisfy English-language requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e9954e83aea49a78abe2cc833f139f5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of denials based on failure to satisfy civics or history requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id34e8716f78bb4450a44440eb033f3282"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the number of denials based on failure to demonstrate attachment to the principles of the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id872d1d90897140f5bceb9306f95fcde2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the number of denials based on failure to demonstrate favorable disposition toward the good order and happiness of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8dfb122df87941eba59545481db0d9ae"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the number of denials based on false statements, material misrepresentation, concealment of material facts, false identity, fraudulent documents, obstruction, or fraud;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id224569c0760c478c98f47b2b3fed96d1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the number of referrals made under section 318A(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as added by section 8;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ff89e1a021347f0a9fb6486edbae852"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the number of aliens denied naturalization who were placed in removal proceedings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3378eec2b6ff4548a113e58507675d69"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the number of applicants granted waivers or exceptions from English-language or civics requirements, disaggregated by statutory basis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3c117a80e59142439f8a4bad243773af"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the number of oath ceremonies conducted;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2cdc3e88a484a81ab5e8a762e6f198f"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the number of applicants who failed to certify understanding of the oath of allegiance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0428218fffc437fabb7b72d3f605eb6"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the status of the America 250 Citizenship Initiative; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fa66b28b79646ecaffa45c44360be19"><enum>(15)</enum><text>recommendations for legislation or administrative action to improve the integrity of the naturalization process.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6116b1f226b94366b4afe2d2d68e6717"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide1e743d18f4b43bda28f32b289b0a6d7"><enum>13.</enum><header>Regulations</header><subsection id="ida0f05b4e8bb64be9ad168869296e69ce"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General as appropriate, shall promulgate regulations to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act, including regulations concerning—</text><paragraph id="id08ad39034d844afc942a5d94117d2bd8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the naturalization examination required under section 312 of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11c238f37ec740e6a2c60bbbe2474e1a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>instruction on the oath of allegiance required under section 337(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43763f8c761f44d1830d18b3763a763e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>determinations of attachment to the principles of the Constitution of the United States under section 316(h) of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8331dfd69e2f4fe88c6d8d99bf04c48f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>fraud determinations under section 318A of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id065564bbefc545488526df2af3ab6bb5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>permanent and temporary bars to naturalization under section 318A of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id46b865691c6a48e8bccf9d49a8c67249"><enum>(6)</enum><text>referrals to Federal law-enforcement agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b6444f12cae45d8a63f07fb38f4e4f0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recordkeeping requirements;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide85a7a8896b740148185a43898589334"><enum>(8)</enum><text>notice to applicants; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f7be7e3fd44415b891b2a600a7d8d2f"><enum>(9)</enum><text>implementation of the America 250 Citizenship Initiative.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0faa3c8349144ea88778b2e49841d11e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No delay</header><text>The failure of the Secretary to promulgate regulations under subsection (a) shall not delay the effective date of this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="id669361d69b5b4368bfa36dd3473dec4d"><enum>14.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, may be construed—</text><paragraph id="id1ab6d720455e4e9b9e12ea37273f33ab"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to authorize the denial of naturalization based solely on speech protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb416efd78ea2401a98fab4ab8ead2221"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to authorize the denial of naturalization based solely on religious belief, lawful association, familial relationship, nationality, ethnicity, dual nationality, or lawful contact with a foreign government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48d0df1012a348289b507f753395ff96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to limit the authority of the United States to deny naturalization to any applicant who fails to establish eligibility for naturalization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id215441d55167406f967cc8269ac1152b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to limit the authority of the United States to bring denaturalization proceedings under section 340 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1451">8 U.S.C. 1451</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3129184782b14833b070ae227501b418"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to limit the authority of the United States to initiate removal proceedings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idca621fc9209a4143867e86571817979f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to limit any ground of inadmissibility or deportability under the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a8b4ddbf80a477a94872527a32b7793"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to limit the authority of the United States to investigate or prosecute fraud, false statements, false documents, false claims of citizenship, unlawful voting, obstruction, perjury, bribery, terrorism, espionage, sabotage, gang activity, cartel activity, or transnational criminal activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6a4903bc4293452b9438a512b1b891e8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to create any entitlement to naturalization, citizenship, or any immigration benefit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5aa14d20cc3d432f8a34320667f8a3b9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to alter the requirement that an applicant for naturalization bears the burden of establishing eligibility for naturalization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida2501b5e58ac4c25bc382b26a559739a"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to affect the citizenship or nationality status of any person who is a citizen or national of the United States on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id395c9d0785824a9885813bedc654fa06"><enum>(11)</enum><text>to alter the allocation of authority between the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Attorney General under the Immigration and Nationality Act, the Homeland Security Act of 2002, or any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="iddd5da27942bd4bbaafe519ed5ee49dd4"><enum>15.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional or otherwise invalid, the remainder of this Act, the amendments made by this Act, and the application of the provisions and amendments to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text></section><section id="idaf55eaad22514b5f816c51ccbee1ebb2"><enum>16.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

