<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBC5F78E6B7AF44A4BA60C59962955175" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1270 IH: Expressing support for the designation of July 15, 2026, as “Glioblastoma Awareness Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the designation of July 15, 2026, as <quote>Glioblastoma Awareness Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that more than 13,000 Americans will be diagnosed with glioblastoma in 2025;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas glioblastoma is—</text> 
<paragraph id="H31F0D543170F40AE89E205A67DD804B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the most common malignant (cancerous) brain tumor, accounting for approximately <fraction>1⁄2</fraction> of all primary malignant brain tumors; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79CCAFCFFF8F42BCAE4C462B578653FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the most aggressive, complex, difficult to treat, and deadly type of brain tumor;</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that more than 10,000 individuals in the United States will succumb to glioblastoma each year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the 5-year survival rate for glioblastoma patients is only 7.1 percent, and the median length of survival for glioblastoma patients is only 9 months;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas glioblastoma is described as a disease that affects the <quote>essence of self</quote>, as the treatment and removal of glioblastoma presents significant challenges due to the uniquely complex and fragile nature of the brain, the primary organ in the human body that controls not only cognitive ability, but also the actions of every organ and limb;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas patients and caregivers play a critical role in furthering research for glioblastoma;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, relative to other types of cancers, brain cancer patients pay the second highest out-of-pocket costs for medical services in both the initial and end-of-life phases of care;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, although research advances may fuel the development of new treatments for glioblastoma, challenging obstacles to accelerating progress toward new treatments for glioblastoma remain, and there are no screening or early detection methods;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2021, significant changes were made to the molecular characteristics of a glioblastoma diagnosis, necessitating critical biomarker testing for patients suspected of having a possible glioblastoma;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, although glioblastoma was first described in medical and scientific literature in the 1920s, and despite its devastating prognosis, only 5 drugs and 1 medical device have been approved by the Food and Drug Administration to specifically treat glioblastoma since the 1920s, and the mortality rates associated with glioblastoma have changed little during the past 30 years;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since the first Glioblastoma Awareness Day, the National Cancer Institute established the Glioblastoma Therapeutics Network (referred to in this preamble as <quote>GTN</quote>) in 2020 as part of a national infrastructure to enhance and support the discovery and development of glioblastoma therapies available for multi-institutional GTN teams to drive therapeutic agents through preclinical studies and early phase clinical trials, which are necessary to rapidly evaluate potential treatments to advance toward cures and improved quality of life;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there is a need for greater public awareness of glioblastoma, including awareness of both—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5D6FDA0B0C8347908C839CD372D6BE8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the urgent unmet medical needs of glioblastoma patients; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE5E7ECE30944C34851E3765CFCB3D72"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the opportunities for research of, and treatment advances for, glioblastoma; and</text></paragraph></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the House of Representatives supports designating July 15, 2026, as <quote>Glioblastoma Awareness Day</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H96F24218DA5F4B74A6FAC6BB67DCA0CB"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HFE7DB748CDD6419281135800B116F1C5"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H5FAE6C4B037B4ED8A14D4095DECE83F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the designation of <quote>Glioblastoma Awareness Day</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95F6E7AB064C4CDD8B34A1AC2B839BE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages increased public awareness of glioblastoma;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA4F89E1D15184FF188D3DEC670692DE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>honors the individuals who have died from the devastating disease of glioblastoma or are currently living with the disease;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9103627511084E71BBC7B3A5F10C97F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports efforts to develop better treatments for glioblastoma that will improve the long-term prognosis for, and the quality of life of, individuals diagnosed with the disease;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H852606CDAAD04C02AAF7DD02B612F22E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of molecular biomarker testing to the diagnosis and treatment of glioblastoma;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H234EB806F3A04EC1B2807124283EC26F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>expresses support for the individuals who are battling brain tumors, as well as the families, friends, and caregivers of those individuals;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52793FAD8506446FBBB4A0C4823773B5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>urges a collaborative approach to brain tumor research among governmental, private, and nonprofit organizations, which is a promising means of advancing the understanding and treatment of glioblastoma; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B486784EEBE4BC2A7F077D17BE92221"><enum>(8)</enum><text>encourages continued investments in glioblastoma research and treatments, including through the Glioblastoma Therapeutics Network and other existing brain tumor research resources.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

