<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD03C336085D0475BB04FD9164991EC6C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1433 IH: Honoring the life and military and public service of Colonel Lindsey O. Graham, United States Air Force Reserve (Retired), late Senator from South Carolina, and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Judge Advocate General’s School of the United States Air Force should be renamed in his honor.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1433</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life and military and public service of Colonel Lindsey O. Graham, United States Air Force Reserve (Retired), late Senator from South Carolina, and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the Judge Advocate General’s School of the United States Air Force should be renamed in his honor.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Olin Graham was born on July 9, 1955, in Central, South Carolina;</text></whereas> <whereas> <text>Whereas, in 1982, Lindsey Graham was commissioned as a judge advocate in the United States Air Force, serving on active duty as a defense attorney and, from 1984 to 1988, as the Air Force’s chief prosecutor for Europe at Rhein-Main Air Base, Germany;</text>
        </whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham continued his military legal career in the South Carolina Air National Guard from 1989 to 1995 and thereafter in the United States Air Force Reserve, including a recall to active duty as a judge advocate during the Persian Gulf War;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham deployed in support of overseas contingency operations, including service in Iraq in 2007 and in Afghanistan in 2009, providing legal counsel on detainee affairs, rule-of-law, and operational law matters;</text></whereas>
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, in 2014, Lindsey Graham was awarded the Bronze Star Medal for meritorious service as a senior legal advisor to the United States Air Force in Iraq and Afghanistan from August 2009 to July 2014;</text>
        </whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham retired from the United States Air Force Reserve in 2015 at the rank of colonel, culminating more than 33 years of military service to the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham was elected to the United States House of Representatives in 1994 and to the United States Senate in 2002, and represented the people of South Carolina in the Senate from January 3, 2003, until his death, including service as Chairman of the Committee on the Judiciary from 2019 to 2021 and as Chairman of the Committee on the Budget from 2025 until his death;</text></whereas>
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, throughout his military and public service, Lindsey Graham was a steadfast advocate for the members of the Judge Advocate General’s Corps and for the men and women of the United States Armed Forces, and he drew upon his experience as a judge advocate to inform decades of legislative work on military justice, national defense, and the rule of law;</text>
        </whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Lindsey Graham died on July 12, 2026, at the age of 71, while still serving the people of South Carolina in the United States Senate;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Judge Advocate General’s School of the United States Air Force, located at Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama, is charged with educating and training the officers of the Air Force Judge Advocate General’s Corps in whose ranks Lindsey Graham served with distinction; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas it is fitting and proper that the institution responsible for training the next generation of Air Force judge advocates bear the name of one of its most distinguished alumni and lifelong champions: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H172A5A470EB6410C8D32648F894EA21F"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H38A3154B5DA14C3A82A4525A3BDDAE3E"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H50B62C4C9B4E4658926B76C77ADC29CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the life, military service, and public service of Colonel Lindsey O. Graham, United States Air Force Reserve (Retired), and extends its deepest condolences to his family, friends, and staff;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB6975D4F0444D1290F1D5877374A6BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the Judge Advocate General’s School of the United States Air Force, Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama, should be renamed and designated as <quote>The Colonel Lindsey O. Graham Judge Advocate General’s School</quote> in recognition of his decades of service as a judge advocate and as a United States Senator on behalf of the Armed Forces;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED7860CA23334891A90EE66546066175"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the Secretary of the Air Force to take all administrative action necessary and appropriate to effect such redesignation, and expresses the intent of the House of Representatives to enact any legislation necessary to accomplish the renaming; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B7184810082493182B94C6DF4555E96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>directs the Clerk of the House of Representatives to transmit a copy of this resolution to the family of Colonel Lindsey O. Graham, to the Secretary of Defense, and to the Secretary of the Air Force.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

