<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22D03A4498B144B2BD5B157FF3B3645C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8100 IH: Safe Staffing Saves Lives Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8100</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XI, XVIII, and XIX of the Social Security Act with respect to minimum staffing levels in skilled nursing facilities and nursing facilities under the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDB47F0734C584EC68330BBCA10B91423" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBA46F7D446844189988210E7DB2CBE84" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Staffing Saves Lives Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC2A7EC0A9B554598B46C2FB66F5487D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Minimum staffing levels in nursing facilities and skilled nursing facilities</header> <subsection id="HECCC235263074A58962F3C59893B3DF3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishing minimum staffing levels for registered nurses in nursing facilities and skilled nursing facilities</header> <paragraph id="HD7F8571E2BE24871A1BA271AFB301C9C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medicare</header> <subparagraph id="H51A62FB3D2844C96A320C99C315DB52F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1819(b)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="HCD5F437F8AA048D0A6FBA332C3CD6F17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> <subclause id="HCBEB0D417867413ABD3F353B309D80BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">before 2029</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Required nursing care</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H20ADFD0B437C4DB8A96173295137F2EA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>Except as provided in clause (ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>With respect to skilled nursing facility services furnished before January 1, 2029, except as provided in clause (ii)</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H281382FBF6944002A48FF75C52C6261F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2DA7E4964B2D4DDBAFE326D1027590C9" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H7F3C55E9125D424D8230EB850617BD7F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Required nursing care beginning in 2029</header> 
<clause id="H2E2E512CCD7D4DDA9ACEF681A6DE69B3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <internal-xref idref="H0F7F27FB64544AB8BE2EA48EC800327A" legis-path="(D)(iii)">clause (iii)</internal-xref>, beginning January 1, 2029, a skilled nursing facility—</text> <subclause id="H60C45FB743EE49E2A494E9A0B373313E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>must provide 24-hour licensed nursing services which are sufficient to meet the nursing needs of its residents;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4474DB31F18D43B0B3D4E5581FF557CF" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>must provide for minimum nurse staffing levels with respect to each day;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H124BE3F6153041B0B6F457A932B2E800"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">must ensure that, in carrying out <internal-xref idref="H60C45FB743EE49E2A494E9A0B373313E" legis-path="(D)(i)(I)">subclauses (I)</internal-xref> and <internal-xref idref="H4474DB31F18D43B0B3D4E5581FF557CF" legis-path="(D)(i)(II)">(II)</internal-xref>, a total minimum of 4.1 hours of nursing care is provided per resident per day, with—</text> 
<item id="HA3D71F99B65E4A49A5CADB887F0BEB6E" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1.3 hours of care of such total minimum consisting of licensed nursing services, with 0.75 hours of such care provided by a registered professional nurse and 0.55 hours of such care provided by a licensed practical nurse; and</text></item> <item id="H89409C8329D848688B32819BDB02791E" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2.8 hours of care of such total minimum provided by a nurse aide (as defined in paragraph (5)(F)); and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE4AC15ACB3694E35B8D687E12C6AD102" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>must ensure that a registered professional nurse is onsite and available to furnish licensed nursing services 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="HE5BD83268ABC4EC5905204DA30EB7F6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Secretarial authority to establish higher minimum nurse staffing levels</header><text>The Secretary may establish and require skilled nursing facilities to provide for minimum nurse staffing levels that are higher than the levels required under this subparagraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0F7F27FB64544AB8BE2EA48EC800327A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Waiver</header> 
<subclause id="H824C22ED588E4C949F858C8DDA10C3D1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the succeeding provisions of this clause, the Secretary may waive the requirements under <internal-xref idref="H2E2E512CCD7D4DDA9ACEF681A6DE69B3" legis-path="(D)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> (and such additional requirements as may be established under <internal-xref idref="HE5BD83268ABC4EC5905204DA30EB7F6D" legis-path="(D)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref>) with respect to a skilled nursing facility for a period of not more than 180 days if—</text> <item id="H8431B48EF56D4F9D8267A8B9EF30FEA6" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the facility demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the facility cannot reasonably comply with such requirements;</text></item> 
<item id="H059DB709A2F5401FA93A1320DE242B54" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the facility provides to the Secretary such information as the Secretary determines necessary to support a determination under <internal-xref idref="H8431B48EF56D4F9D8267A8B9EF30FEA6" legis-path="(D)(iii)(I)(aa)">item (aa)</internal-xref>, which shall include information with respect to—</text> <subitem id="H80CEC64343BF4698A4901FA07B869B7F" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>workforce and wage data for the area in which the facility is located;</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H0A19376B9AEF4DC586C40C69F9F2F82A" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>additional employee benefits offered by the facility;</text></subitem> <subitem id="H33226CDA5FF544AF8B9AABA599F7A1BC" commented="no"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the annual rate of turnover with respect to nursing staff at the facility, disaggregated by category of staff; and</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="HB60CD0EA84FA4D45979CB428136CFEEA" commented="no"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>the facility’s demonstrated commitment to hiring nursing staff; and</text></subitem> </item> <item id="HE889630F16F24342B8A943FA7C53F5A3" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary provides notice of the waiver to the State long-term care ombudsman (established under section 307(a)(12) of the Older Americans Act of 1965) and the protection and advocacy system in the State for the mentally ill and the mentally retarded.</text> </item> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H1DE082B62FEE4CDBA526E25413B25388"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Ineligibility</header><text>The Secretary may not grant a waiver under this clause to a skilled nursing facility that—</text> <item id="H6B3E3EA8F5134E79A035A2AFC74C734F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been identified under the special focus facility program under subsection (f)(8) as having substantially failed to meet an applicable requirement of this Act; or</text></item> 
<item id="H4720C96A1AEE43548A92364DA1F57F8B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>during the 1-year period preceding a request for such a waiver, was found to have deficiencies that—</text> <subitem id="H9575A99BCB9048EDBA4A3886779BD5C8"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>resulted in harm to a resident; or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H54BD6D565CC24DAB8265A0404CD8AFD8"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>immediately jeopardized the health or safety of its residents.</text></subitem></item></subclause> <subclause id="H7D1987CA1D5944CDBC146321E76FE7CA" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>A skilled nursing facility may not receive more than 2 consecutive waivers under this clause.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H124405E8E4D04C6B89F86AC60EF9FEBF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding State authority to establish higher minimum nurse staffing levels</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph may be construed as preventing a State from establishing or requiring skilled nursing facilities in the State to provide for minimum nurse staffing levels that are higher than the levels required under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H574EB00FA99747FB8913A067D1F2AE84" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <clause id="H0A6CC4D69A05449D99940758D72114C2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Increased survey frequency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1819(g)(2)(A)(iii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(g)(2)(A)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subclause id="H23ED0C23A5724FAE83A7E15C33620B2F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>Each</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subclause (III), each</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H92781596DF7241969C66066DBBA1D890"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE9BEF8162D484B32894B5CA092740D8B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subclause id="H2E2B2E97BB714AD8A6D06A7EFB41B3F8"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Staffing level surveys</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, in the case of a skilled nursing facility that is found not to meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (including such a facility that has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), such facility shall be subject to a standard survey not later than 3 months after the date of the previous standard survey conducted under this subparagraph.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause> <clause id="H8F0F2FD41A524ECFA0C56F1C6DE375FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition on admission of new residents; audits</header><text>Section 1819(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subclause id="H909CDE23F80B4103AFEA5BAE135B79E6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>If a State finds, on the basis of a standard</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (7), if a State finds, on the basis of a standard</quote>;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H33EDFF1E9B6F469CABF46AB5AF2EF76D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>With respect to</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (7), with respect to</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD8C64B79402E47C383A44A295880E5B9" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEFEBCFBC8F4E47BB99E5B18224356F66" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H59EF9889819143B2A430492012E6C958" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Special rule with respect to minimum nurse staffing requirements</header> <subparagraph id="HEB2EDA8F3D944016BBD538B04F9A6FA3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, if a State finds, on the basis of a standard, extended, or partial extended survey under subsection (g)(2) or otherwise, that a skilled nursing facility does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (without regard to whether such facility has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), the State shall recommend to the Secretary that the Secretary take such actions as described in <internal-xref idref="H6DED88E9FC3F4220B6FBE6A062A36151" legis-path="(7)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DED88E9FC3F4220B6FBE6A062A36151" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Secretarial authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, with respect to any skilled nursing facility in a State, if the Secretary finds, or pursuant to a recommendation of the State under <internal-xref idref="HEB2EDA8F3D944016BBD538B04F9A6FA3" legis-path="(7)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> finds, that a skilled nursing facility does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (without regard to whether such facility has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), the Secretary shall deny any further payments under this title with respect to any individuals entitled to benefits under this title admitted to the facility for the period beginning on the effective date of the finding and ending on the later of—</text> <clause id="HA433941F438C4D80B29CA8E563AFCF57" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after such effective date; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H37A9FE8A011D4E2FA5084BA217FCE510" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary determines that the facility has come into compliance with such minimum staffing requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H672A995EE4E84D5CB994125BF3A61E11" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relationship to other enforcement mechanisms</header><text>The remedies provided under this paragraph are in addition to those otherwise available under this subsection and shall not be construed as limiting such other remedies. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H694CAA1612084FB69A6AAC3B3E0E4F60"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Ineligibility for SNF VBP Program</header><text>Section 1888(h)(1)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395yy">42 U.S.C. 1395yy(h)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subclause id="HF4AE4F248C464CABBC26C5948C20A4A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HFBB58489513540E0A89C69FA7C3C2A7C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>With respect</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE7B332BBCFDF4BC3AF30BD96220E37E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="H1EF84D1E4D9A4834B4B9489BDA141307"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause> 
<subclause id="H820091C30D12480FA944805E6362E95C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0129765615CA455380144AF1B41F15BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HCB754CC7FE43419E9AD8B4905DD3A2A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusion of facilities out of compliance with minimum staffing standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to payments for services furnished on or after January 1, 2029, this subsection shall not apply to a facility that does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (including such a facility that has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection). </text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H29521467B46547EBB1F21768B0D0CA51"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application to transfer and discharge rights</header><text>Section 1819(c)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the flush-left text the following new sentence: <quote>Beginning January 1, 2029, a skilled nursing facility may not transfer or discharge a resident solely for purposes of meeting the minimum staffing requirements under subsection (b)(4)(D).</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15C8DE3CC9D040C8B5C6604B84DDCC8F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Notice of noncompliance to residents and guardians</header> <clause id="HC9F6CC89C63B457D8AC4612A8F7AEE88"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1819(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H08D2A23D5B014BECB048D2BCB506135D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H00AF009E52B7495684B9BAA2014EBB9A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Notice in the case of noncompliance with minimum staffing standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, in the case of a skilled nursing facility that does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (including such a facility that has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), such facility shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H743DF5F720724A2C8F7E2D5596363E9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prominently display at the entrance to the facility a notice that such facility does not meet such standards (and has in effect such a waiver, if applicable); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52244638FD224EAB81899ABA32944835"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide each resident of the facility (or, where appropriate, the guardians or legal representatives of such residents) and members of their immediate families with a written copy of such notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H5EE8F7A9343A476E85EEF86836E14F46"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Nursing Home Compare website</header><text>Section 1819(i)(1)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i-3">42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(i)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(and, beginning January 1, 2029, information on whether the facility meets the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (or has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection)</quote> after <quote>staffing turnover and tenure</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47C6B5BAA541436494D1026D0CF84E51"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1819(f)(2)(B)(iii)(I)(a) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395i–3(f)(2)(B)(iii)(I)(a)) is amended by inserting <quote>or subsection (b)(4)(D)(iii)</quote> after <quote>subsection (b)(4)(C)(ii)(II)</quote>.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H297F0FE5EF2E4296BC46E78011B5B353"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medicaid</header> <subparagraph id="HDACB7D83B0B34D3BA5C248393E405CF6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1919(b)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<clause id="H133D1231C3A64065BDE0426E500046C0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(i)—</text> <subclause id="HDE9DE68F23B74517ACAA419858E16EBA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the clause heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">before 2029</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">General requirements</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H396BE53D91714C099A9A8ED19332C5C1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I), by inserting <quote>and before January 1, 2029,</quote> after <quote>With respect to nursing facility services provided on or after October 1, 1990,</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H919D7E73134649E88E716F58B3ECAD50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE5D28458CFF94F5DAE6A4E22144A0E77" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H08C762F7AFFA4C6CB8826BAD908E459D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>General requirements beginning in 2029</header> 
<clause id="HE24FC1E5E3F84A05B9F03C0CAC26ACAE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to <internal-xref idref="H73FDD3E9D6C744B1BEAE3BC8CFD919C9" legis-path="(D)(iii)">clause (iii)</internal-xref>, beginning January 1, 2029, a nursing facility—</text> <subclause id="H7B341BFA7AC9475D9E4BE1E469237E4E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>must provide 24-hour licensed nursing services which are sufficient to meet the nursing needs of its residents;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HEF2D226F0E4F480AB8049DF58626D6D1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>must provide for minimum nurse staffing levels with respect to each day;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6868B4B221C44B70BC7BC151F850F1C3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">must ensure that, in carrying out <internal-xref idref="H7B341BFA7AC9475D9E4BE1E469237E4E" legis-path="(D)(i)(I)">subclauses (I)</internal-xref> and <internal-xref idref="HEF2D226F0E4F480AB8049DF58626D6D1" legis-path="(D)(i)(II)">(II)</internal-xref>, a total minimum of 4.1 hours of nursing care is provided per resident per day, with—</text> 
<item id="HEEDF705863F6464F94582352691DA60D" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">1.3 hours of care of such total minimum consisting of licensed nursing services, with 0.75 hours of such care provided by a registered professional nurse and 0.55 hours of such care provided by a licensed practical nurse; and</text></item> <item id="H5B2AEFE50E534AC9861E3069DF07C5DF" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2.8 hours of care of such total minimum provided by a nurse aide (as defined in paragraph (5)(F)); and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H36B34C921A4449D498D17200DDFA0C26" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>must ensure that a registered professional nurse is onsite and available to furnish licensed nursing services 24 hours a day, 7 days a week.</text> </subclause></clause> <clause id="H3A2A68A260B34039BA5150E074B04934"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Secretarial authority to establish higher minimum nurse staffing levels</header><text>The Secretary may establish and require nursing facilities to provide for minimum nurse staffing levels that are higher than the levels required under this subparagraph.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H73FDD3E9D6C744B1BEAE3BC8CFD919C9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Waiver</header> 
<subclause id="H7954ADCB6E49453C87EEFC319EEAB246" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the succeeding provisions of this clause, a State may waive the requirements under <internal-xref idref="HE24FC1E5E3F84A05B9F03C0CAC26ACAE" legis-path="(D)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> (and such additional requirements as may be established under <internal-xref idref="H3A2A68A260B34039BA5150E074B04934" legis-path="(D)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref>) with respect to a nursing facility for a period of not more than 180 days if—</text> <item id="H6ACE61CE7BC640558F3C8ABEE136B5AE" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the facility demonstrates to the satisfaction of the State that the facility cannot reasonably comply with such requirements;</text></item> 
<item id="HAF9FCBE71A654E3B85F6523E27359B3A" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the facility provides to the State such information as the State determines necessary to support a determination under <internal-xref idref="H6ACE61CE7BC640558F3C8ABEE136B5AE" legis-path="(D)(iii)(I)(aa)">item (aa)</internal-xref>, which shall include information with respect to—</text> <subitem id="HDA00BDEC111142228DA59CAFDC2803C3" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>workforce and wage data for the area in which the facility is located;</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="HE0C9B80793A94CAB812599E0E3409E5A" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>additional employee benefits offered by the facility;</text></subitem> <subitem id="H4791BDBBD95D488A86604B7CA026462E" commented="no"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the annual rate of turnover with respect to nursing staff at the facility, disaggregated by category of staff; and</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H13169642B5CF469790147A8D63DC15B4" commented="no"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>the facility’s demonstrated commitment to hiring nursing staff; and</text></subitem> </item> <item id="H52ACD06E706E4CE496B42BD0BBEF84A6" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State agency granting a waiver of such requirements provides notice of the waiver to the State long-term care ombudsman (established under section 307(a)(12) of the Older Americans Act of 1965) and the protection and advocacy system in the State for the mentally ill and the mentally retarded.</text> </item> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="subclause">A waiver under this clause shall be subject to the review of the Secretary and subject to <internal-xref idref="H94F6B63C198146B48A58432D0D2A12C5" legis-path="(D)(iv)">clause (iv)</internal-xref> shall be accepted by the Secretary for purposes of this title to the same extent as is the State’s certification of the facility. In granting or renewing a waiver, a State may require the facility to use other qualified, licensed personnel.</continuation-text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8C461352221C4C23AE790A17C8D1D0EC"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Ineligibility</header><text>The State may not grant a waiver under this clause to a skilled nursing facility that—</text> <item id="HDB676726F28C4A929D12AB3190A68EB0" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been identified under the special focus facility program under subsection (f)(10) as having substantially failed to meet applicable requirements of this Act; or</text></item> 
<item id="HB31B4FC7449E4683AF9A2DE2AD9C8E5E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>during the 1-year period preceding a request for such a waiver, was found to have deficiencies that—</text> <subitem id="H89E335086440419EAF482DEEDBD9DD8B"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>resulted in harm to a resident; or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="HF8B2CDE9DD36437786E334C1B2512DE7"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>immediately jeopardized the health or safety of its residents.</text></subitem></item></subclause> <subclause id="H1D0EFED78A0D463A94EE2EC6C5DF53E8" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>A nursing facility may not receive more than 2 consecutive waivers under this clause.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H94F6B63C198146B48A58432D0D2A12C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Assumption of waiver authority by Secretary</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a State has shown a clear pattern and practice of allowing waivers in the absence of diligent efforts by facilities to meet the staffing requirements, the Secretary shall assume and exercise the authority of the State to grant waivers.</text></clause> <clause id="HBD23E2FF8CF14E4E9B96502700068CA4"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Rule of construction regarding State authority to establish higher minimum nurse staffing levels</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph may be construed as preventing a State from establishing or requiring skilled nursing facilities in the State to provide for minimum nurse staffing levels that are higher than the levels required under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA1BDD08FFA0C4866AC85AE1930352D36" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> 
<clause id="H6463B6D15E7F4A019257282143645A7A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Increased survey frequency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1919(g)(2)(A)(iii) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(g)(2)(A)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subclause id="HF27BC2235FE14C0B9A3B16A026B423E7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>Each</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subclause (III), each</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1DC62B7AC2CF4880A87E081C742F3F35"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD21E19A34E874F069B0BD95C61126F75"> <subclause id="HCF5476D4764D4CA089784C02785EE819"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Staffing level surveys</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, in the case of a nursing facility that is found not to meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (including such a facility that has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), such facility shall be subject to a standard survey not later than 3 months after the date of the previous standard survey conducted under this subparagraph.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HF75170C85A2849DFA728412A5704F978"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prohibition on admission of new resident; audits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1919(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subclause id="HB418DDC50CDB4DD694269F0CBB6845DC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>If a State finds, on the basis of a standard</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (10), if a State finds, on the basis of a standard</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDBA697C67C4447DE896D196BFD471678" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <item id="H67FCBC8FA86C42E6B43CBEDE968CD688" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>If a nursing facility</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (10), if a nursing facility</quote>; and</text></item> 
<item id="HA5C8040F14FF48E9BA666768A91E20A7" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>In the case of</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (10), in the case of</quote>;</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H8B6DE825664F4805AE8E12F9AE26E065" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<item id="HBB5F794E16814C17B47C6C8F257B921E" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>and the remedies described in paragraph (10)(B)</quote>; and</text></item> <item id="H50A8446009D34981A33DF2B9CCF59DD1" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>With respect to</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (10), with respect to</quote>; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H58812D31C7E04D5CA70AC8B3BF00C88D" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2B88445B3C4143AEA52FFA754FF5E8D5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HC870EEBC228946DF94252E75582E4BD7" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Special rule with respect to minimum nurse staffing requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H692E7DA8A84844E78657851CD4D7C9CF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, if a State finds, on the basis of a standard, extended, or partial extended survey under subsection (g)(2) or otherwise, that a nursing facility does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (without regard to whether such facility has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), the State shall—</text> 
<clause id="H858A7430527948E49C796236717F392B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deny any further payments under the State plan with respect to all individuals enrolled under such plan who are admitted to the facility after the effective date of the finding; and</text></clause> <clause id="H08194F90C7D843CA945207307AC1D095" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommend to the Secretary that the Secretary take such actions as described in <internal-xref idref="HD78AECF1B7EF460F950532D8EAB70F11" legis-path="(10)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD78AECF1B7EF460F950532D8EAB70F11" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Secretarial authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, with respect to any nursing facility in a State other than a State nursing facility, if the Secretary finds, or pursuant to a recommendation of the State under subparagraph (A) finds, that a skilled nursing facility does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (without regard to whether such facility has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), the Secretary shall deny any further payments to the State for medical assistance furnished by the facility to any individual admitted to the facility for the period beginning on the effective date of the finding and ending on the later of—</text> <clause id="H7DC3152875B24D21A1B7131943056837" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that is 180 days after such effective date; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H65900AC628AB4B18BC09314AF0416781" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary determines that the facility has come into compliance with such minimum staffing requirements.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC897F5C75CC240B8A8F3EBA0C6E6F536" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Relationship to other enforcement mechanisms</header><text>The remedies provided under this paragraph are in addition to those otherwise available under this subsection and shall not be construed as limiting such other remedies. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H148A285A436E4641B67E39B7D10807D9" commented="no">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
                            <header>Ineligibility for certain State directed payments</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall revise section 438.6(c)(2) of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), such that, beginning January 1, 2029, no State directed payment specified in such section may be made for nursing facility services furnished by a facility that does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subparagraph (D) of section 1919(b)(4) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(b)(4)</external-xref>), as added by <internal-xref idref="HDACB7D83B0B34D3BA5C248393E405CF6" legis-path="2.(a)(2)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> (including such a facility that has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subparagraph).</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="H284027C5949943F5A7F6E448D6A070D0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Application to transfer and discharge rights</header><text>Section 1919(c)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of the flush-left text the following new sentence: <quote>Beginning January 1, 2029, a nursing facility may not transfer or discharge a resident solely for purposes of meeting the minimum staffing requirements under subsection (b)(4)(D).</quote>.</text></clause> <clause id="HE1205CDB0718439682E91E856C541E8D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Notice of noncompliance to residents and guardians</header> <subclause id="HFB76004BFCD44D3284FA3175600207D9"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1919(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E43B26412694A288C82FA9E93BDECE0"> 
<paragraph id="HD87FF7655D1A49D09D419A1A89CD70BC"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Notice in the case of noncompliance with minimum staffing standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2029, in the case of a nursing facility that does not meet the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (including such a facility that has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection), such facility shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HD8711074A7EA4829B610D2A961232E7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prominently display at the entrance to the facility a notice that such facility does not meet such standards (and has in effect such a waiver, if applicable); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC64A191419C248CD8A15ECD086684C4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide each resident of the facility (or, where appropriate, the guardians or legal representatives of such residents) and members of their immediate families with a written copy of such notice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause> <subclause id="HC79BC469B1004F2DA642AF5000422AA7"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Nursing Home Compare website</header><text>Section 1919(i)(1)(A)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(i)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(and, beginning January 1, 2029, information on whether the facility meets the minimum staffing requirements of subsection (b)(4)(D) (or has in effect a waiver of such requirements under clause (iii) of such subsection)</quote> after <quote>staffing turnover and tenure</quote>.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72C73E413E204012B38EE05D430AC8F5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<clause id="H7A03A626AF2A444F9BF9DD73F97D79F3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Item (a) of section 1919(f)(2)(B)(iii)(I) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(f)(2)(B)(iii)(I)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or subsection (b)(4)(D)(iii)</quote> after <quote>subsection (b)(4)(C)(ii)</quote>.</text></clause> <clause id="HBE6E127146C1466B8751F501522D0F11" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (9) of section 1919(f) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r(f)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or subsection (b)(4)(D)(iii)</quote> after <quote>subsection (b)(4)(C)(ii)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE88C5E92B596414597D0C37472F290D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of timestamp on facility staffing data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128I(g) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7j(g)) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF6DFE0C3DF604B6E8F623E0F70EA0B76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H389922AA45DE4D578539865F088F435C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A0A12B38A9049B6A7B84DBDC5E702B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5876B78B57FC4B36B20E5362F0D4ACC2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H08109C0296314655A6A439BA90D0AC39"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning January 1, 2027, include time-stamped information on the hours worked per day by each certified employee in each category of certified employees referenced in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7991EC07869543EDB387516A72A81537"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128I of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7j">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7j</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H633A853B0E34430EB633784C4855262E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H951CABB42E0B4AE3BD27DE9DA14780FE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reports on facility staffing levels</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2034, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the minimum nurse staffing levels required under sections 1819(b)(4)(D) and 1919(b)(4)(D). Each such report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HF9750FACE3724972A84130A3E5178DEF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of the impact of such minimum nurse staffing levels on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D34B72959FD4CD19F5986229BA1F212" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resident safety;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC49961E40CA4B5A896257747DA1AC8B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>quality of care;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F5331DA50594A20A0B4FE68CBF96E47" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the rate of deficiency citations received by facilities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2204C6150024077B68A3ADB5C2AB16F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>wages, benefits, and employment retention of nurse staff; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FA59D4945EC48D09B24D2506739A3E7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations as to whether such minimum nurse staffing levels should be adjusted.</text> </paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

