<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HD8717CD36999497CA5041C6B6CFF0EAD" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>103 HR 1041 : Veterans 2nd Amendment Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1041</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to prohibit the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from transmitting certain information to the Department of Justice for use by the national instant criminal background check system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="H439E9E448EA64A498171626102D7EE80"><section id="HDB8F7B338B73462A9ED1BF72AD063431" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans 2nd Amendment Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1D21815F181747BE94650C190231DE05" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on Secretary of Veterans Affairs transmittal of certain information to the Department of Justice for use by the national instant criminal background check system</header><subsection id="HD2E43C31EB7346FDA29BCEFC59EDD784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/55">Chapter 55</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/5501A">section 5501A</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59C383FE992F4627AD17697B9CB37BDE" style="USC"><section id="HA962AF305F0A4551B822DF3C7434ED81"><enum>5501B.</enum><header>Prohibition on transmittal of certain information to the Department of Justice for use by the national instant criminal background check system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may not transmit to any entity in the Department of Justice, for use by the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/159">Public Law 103–159</external-xref>; 107 Stat. 1541), personally identifiable information of a beneficiary, solely on the basis of a determination by the Secretary to pay benefits to a fiduciary for the use and benefit of the beneficiary under section 5502 of this title, without the order or finding of a judge, magistrate, or other judicial authority of competent jurisdiction that such beneficiary is a danger to themselves or others.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA38A2DB415044FE0B86C1A685C256121"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of chapter 55 of such title is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5501A the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H6044BB8F1DD84F3288F2C300A8C7A114" style="USC"><toc><toc-entry idref="HA962AF305F0A4551B822DF3C7434ED81" level="section">5501B. Prohibition on transmittal of certain information to the Department of Justice for use by the national instant criminal background check system.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H4D88F3E69F004D55972730F4BCFF8334"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notification of lack of basis for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to have transmitted certain information to the Department of Justice for use by the national instant criminal background check system</header><subsection id="H4EF6E97DCA9B4E1AA8341C347C90D326"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such chapter (as amended by section 2) is further amended by inserting after section 5501B the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2760EEAB243B41649368750F9A1E9F0A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H01DEBEFC080E4D928A29D46EEA0D9F7C"><enum>5501C.</enum><header>Notification of lack of basis for transmittal of certain information to the Department of Justice for use by the national instant criminal background check system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall, within 30 days of the enactment of the <short-title>Veterans 2nd Amendment Protection Act</short-title>, and in accordance with section 103(e)(1)(D) of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901(e)(1)(D)</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/159">Public Law 103–159</external-xref>; 107 Stat. 1541), notify the Attorney General that the basis for the transmittal, on or after November 30, 1993, by the Secretary, of personally identifiable information of a beneficiary, solely on the basis of a determination by the Secretary to pay benefits to a fiduciary for the use and benefit of the beneficiary under section 5502 of this title, to any entity in the Department of Justice, for use by the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/159">Public Law 103–159</external-xref>; 107 Stat. 1541), does not apply, or no longer applies.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC193D106F9A445AAADF9BC7F4C6EEBA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter (as amended by section 2) is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5501B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC7A84F3CCCAF4B8B8F28D691E78BD01F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">5501C. Notification of lack of basis for transmittal of certain information to the Department of Justice for use by the national instant criminal background check system.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HFF81378CE44440B68E81013C32A4F294"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs that a person is mentally incompetent is insufficient to treat such person as a mental defective</header><subsection id="H2E2F99A0D0C74229BF952DE093B51F22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such chapter (as amended by sections 2 and 3) is further amended by inserting after section 5501C the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HA3621FF1B3C048229DCA916433C2B540" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE0E119872A4B439DA2250D3F49F6C19D"><enum>5501D.</enum><header>Determination of mental incompetence is insufficient basis to treat a person as a mental defective</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall not treat a person as having been adjudicated as a mental defective solely on the basis that the Secretary has determined that such person—</text><paragraph id="HA42F56F56C9145ADA3AE7DB7D5196335"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is mentally incompetent under section 3.353 of title 38, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulation); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52965929F2204205A669314815DBD5E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requires a fiduciary under section 5502 of this title.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H83D90A64AAC9437FA0C178CF02240933"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter (as amended by sections 2 and 3) is further amended by inserting after the item relating to section 5501C the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H1C167FBAEC3D40B7A05E8FF22EC67CD9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">5501D. Determination of mental incompetence is insufficient basis to treat a person as a mental defective</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260521" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 21, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

