<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25229-9C8-LL-K04"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 519 IS: Recognizing the achievements and contributions of the AH–64 Apache attack helicopter to the national defense of the United States and its allies and honoring the dedication, service, and sacrifice of the United States Army aviators, maintainers, and support personnel who operate and sustain the Apache.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 519</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the achievements and contributions of the AH–64 Apache attack helicopter to the national defense of the United States and its allies and honoring the dedication, service, and sacrifice of the United States Army aviators, maintainers, and support personnel who operate and sustain the Apache.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on September 30, 1975, the Apache attack helicopter prototype YAH–64 took its first flight, marking a defining milestone in the history of aviation and defense innovation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the AH–64 Apache was designed as a twin-engine, tandem-seat, heavy attack helicopter capable of providing close air support, deep strike, and reconnaissance missions under adverse conditions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since its first flight, the AH–64 Apache has become the most advanced, combat-proven attack helicopter in the world, amassing more than 5,200,000 total flight hours, including over 1,300,000 combat hours, in defense of the United States and its allies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the AH–64 Apache has undergone continuous modernization, from the AH–64A through the AH–64E, incorporating digital avionics, advanced sensors, and networked weapons systems to enhance survivability, lethality, and interoperability;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas production and sustainment of the AH–64 Apache have been carried out at facilities across the United States, with final assembly in Arizona and a supplier base across 46 States, reflecting decades of leadership of the United States in aerospace design, engineering, and advanced manufacturing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the AH–64 Apache has played a decisive role in major combat operations, including—</text><paragraph id="idc8779192c7fd411cb81b0b51a6572113"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Operation Desert Storm (1991), where it conducted the opening strikes of the Gulf War;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc98705f7ddf41beb8bff66a31f43c86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Operation Allied Force (1999), during the conflict in Kosovo;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47ad5ec721a24208954c308e70551299"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Operation Enduring Freedom (2001–2014), providing close air support and reconnaissance in Afghanistan;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c4f8d991d0a443dad23f2accdfdd27c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Operation Iraqi Freedom (2003–2011), supporting ground operations and counterinsurgency missions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb15cb8dbd1d410fa72fd9f18183a9a4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Operation Inherent Resolve (beginning in 2014 and ongoing as of the date of the introduction of this resolution), conducting precision strike operations against the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the AH–64 Apache attack helicopters operate from key United States Army installations around the world, including the United States Army Aviation Center of Excellence at Fort Rucker, Alabama, and 4 Army National Guard battalions;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whereas the AH–64 Apache also serves with 18 allied and partner nations, strengthening global security and coalition interoperability and continuing to prove the indispensable role of the AH–64 Apache on the modern battlefield, including in counter-unmanned system efforts;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the AH–64 Apache continues to demonstrate versatility, resilience, and decisive battlefield capability in combat operations around the world; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on the 50th anniversary of the first flight of the AH–64 Apache, it is fitting to recognize the extraordinary innovation, dedication, and service that have defined the aircraft and the individuals who have designed, built, and maintained it: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" commented="no"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idc7741f24b6154f7db53754041af174f0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements and contributions of the AH–64 Apache attack helicopter to the national defense of the United States and its allies;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6f6783d98fa94766853bbe3192500126"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the dedication, service, and sacrifice of the United States Army aviators, maintainers, and support personnel who operate and sustain the AH–64 Apache;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id244dafb96a1e4127ba4c0d11101addf8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>acknowledges the enduring role of the AH–64 Apache in ensuring that the United States maintains unmatched close air support and precision strike capability; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id385f1b52439543adb82ed470b833a93a"><enum>(4)</enum><text>respectfully directs the Secretary of the Senate to transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to the United States Army Aviation Center of Excellence at Fort Rucker, Alabama.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>

