<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFD98EE516AB24A19A0975D863FCF47C9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8523 IH: Public Lands Workforce Stability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8523</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit any reduction in force or involuntary separation at the Department of the Interior and the United States Forest Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA21123A98B3D423EB772B16F69E6BF62" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H12E952E1494043DB993711545B8F014C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Lands Workforce Stability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H1E9BA99C7DB646B6B04888AB5AC7FA68"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on reductions in force and involuntary separations at Department of the Interior and United States Forest Service</header> 
<subsection id="H2B40E4719E7E493485B15B68D84C83AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on September 30, 2030, without prior notification and approval of the chairs and ranking members of the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, no Federal funds may be obligated or expended to—</text> <paragraph id="H80336C3EC8654F7788BE2DC210531E0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">initiate, implement, or otherwise carry out a reduction in force within the Department of the Interior or the United States Forest Service; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2790DB7FC4B428BA9D5A5C40EE5E553"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out an involuntary separation of any employee in the competitive service, any career employee in the excepted service, or any career appointee in the Senior Executive Service at the Department of Interior or the United States Forest Service except for cause on charges of misconduct, delinquency, or performance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3F167FB81F8F46AEA187003E0855E53B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subsection (a), the terms <quote>competitive service</quote>, <quote>excepted service</quote>, and <quote>career appointee</quote> have the meaning given those terms in sections 2102, 2103, and 3132(a), respectively, of title 5, United States Code.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

