<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE85BEFBDE5644E93AC6AABECA9C4A8D8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8245 IH: Generate Recordings of All Child protective Interviews Everywhere Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8245</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260409">April 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support State efforts to record all child welfare interviews.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H23AADA4B813A49C2B2FAE3212D0494AC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA88F493EA4DA4D4695B006C1383C5DA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Generate Recordings of All Child protective Interviews Everywhere Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GRACIE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD8756E517D404E70B81D50B230005977"><enum>2.</enum><header>Child protective service interview recording grants</header> <subsection id="H6133FB908930460BB7BE0575AC7B0120"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Associate Commissioner may award grants to States for the purpose of assisting State agencies responsible for conducting child welfare interviews in recording and retaining all child welfare interviews conducted by such State agencies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H021356C12C06436BB1E1DEB857A3FEAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Associate Commissioner at such time and in such manner as the Associate Commissioner may require. Such application shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H2507109B0284446D97F316B734A97FDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State’s lead agency for the grant program and that agency’s current requirements involving the recording and retention of child welfare interviews;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19F299E8BF334895904672E6D1F452DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the challenges the State faces in developing, implementing, and monitoring requirements involving the recording and retention of child welfare interviews; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H515DA7A086E4449C9EA60CE39C649150"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how the State plans to use funds for activities described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H12D217CFE55646B8940C2BC50CCAC942" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H220B8142D0154212BA5E6CFCE73201C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts received under a grant under this section shall be used exclusively for costs directly associated with conducting and retaining for 5 years the recording of all child welfare interviews by a State agency responsible for conducting child welfare interviews, including initial interviews conducted during a family assessment to the extent practicable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E820DED42384A628C2D56D1EB3DCD69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recording requirement</header><text>A State receiving a grant under this section shall have a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice requiring all child welfare interviews conducted by the State agency responsible for conducting child welfare interviews to be recorded through electronic audio recording, body camera video, or any other reasonable means of recording.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEB9E60ECDACC4D9D9CBEC10AD80F4B06"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retention requirement</header><text>A State receiving a grant under this section shall have a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice requiring the recordings described in paragraph (2) to be retained and stored for not less than 5 years in a manner consistent with the protocols established by the State for such recordings, which shall include that—</text> <subparagraph id="H1EFA9FC7A1614985B9420D9C63FDBE29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a copy of such recording—</text> 
<clause id="HBC304D8A46474B7CAD5A9C5DA286D390"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to clause (ii), may only be released to appropriate government agencies investigating an allegation or prosecuting an offense relating to an allegation; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5325238EE4784402893E662B08D0ABDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon request by a caregiver or guardian in connection with a judicial proceeding, shall be made available to the caregiver or guardian, unless the court orders otherwise;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABC26ADDD2FA4FC292DE4BF7D8E6C7C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a penalty is imposed for a violation of the limitation described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HED62222A2C654D1DA7927504B1766676"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the retention systems of the State agency responsible for conducting child welfare interviews securely manage the storage and distribution of such a recording with access controls and role-based permission management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H20507F56F4D444D9A3B469071D2D9FBB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accountability</header> 
<paragraph id="HE820DF42DB3045D893B384BAAAA28657"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Records</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this section shall maintain such records as the Associate Commissioner may require to facilitate an effective audit relating to the receipt of the grant, the use of amounts from the grant, or outsourcing activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4A6FB7DDC3745F3940FF0736E3E4DA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access</header><text>For the purpose of conducting audits and examinations, the Associate Commissioner shall have access to any book, document, or record of the State agency that receives a grant under this section if the Associate Commissioner determines that the book, document, or record relates to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D07CE42720444F0B27D37347AD571FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the receipt of the grant; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H198016DD897C4E06B43E50E8AB78A9DD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of amounts from the grant. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97E27D9905BB4265836B24231DF9D1A9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H65A48C62A3894457A3523A1A76DAB204"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Associate Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Associate Commissioner</term> means the Associate Commissioner of the Children’s Bureau of the Office of the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E4531B17AD1441CA9AF3D1C138DBEBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child welfare interview</header><text>The term <term>child welfare interview</term> means a documented interview with any relevant parties, including a child or an adult, conducted by a State agency responsible for conducting child welfare interviews in order to elicit information regarding concerns of abuse of a child, neglect of a child, or other crimes against a child.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC453045BF6F840DCB8B0CCEBA6464802"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F71AC724788438C99ADAAFED4DDADFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each of the several States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0E57093A6D541ECBD48EA4EE6ACAB29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F800A9A5B6C46CCAA9271B4169BF97B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE902F68287CB46A8B170D4B4C6ADC776"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any territory or possession of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H149101E2B450489BBDB661D606F18174"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding and sunset</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031, the Associate Commissioner shall use not more than $30,000,000 of the amounts appropriated to carry out subpart 1 of part B of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/621">42 U.S.C. 621 et seq.</external-xref>) to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

