<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN26105-LK9-39-SYJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3850 IS: Effective Assistance of Counsel in the Digital Era Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3850</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To regulate monitoring of electronic communications between an incarcerated person in a Bureau of Prisons facility and that person’s attorney or other legal representative, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Effective Assistance of Counsel in the Digital Era Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ide3ad16db1f774841b2b2995e87242826"><enum>2.</enum><header>Electronic communications between an incarcerated person and the person’s attorney</header><subsection id="idf3f9f80e4e20463a96ec48e406723631"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="idbc9d34e6a9c54f6f90b4573e7d333897"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>agent of an attorney or legal representative</term> means any person employed by or contracting with an attorney or legal representative, including law clerks, interns, investigators, paraprofessionals, and administrative staff;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a7c80bc8f8148828286b803479a20a9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>contents</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7af3a44c49f34f51b57c73c1fad869c0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>electronic communication</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id6373BC59CC454F9597043F54514FE114"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62B82F4A359D45638FFBDD96ADB89D95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the Trust Fund Limited Inmate Computer System;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd826f6c93f334904945ffe2258944d03"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>incarcerated person</term> means any individual in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons or the United States Marshals Service who has been charged with or convicted of an offense against the United States, including such an individual who is imprisoned in a State institution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id49b3fb56198c4083bdc634d69f0fc36f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>monitoring</term> means accessing the contents of an electronic communication at the time that, or anytime after, such communication is sent; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c8586cb8d5245c0816c9f9a659ad68a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>privileged electronic communication</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id17882c13cb3140a09a739a46873485cd"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an electronic communication between an incarcerated person and a potential, current, or former attorney or legal representative of the incarcerated person that falls within the legally recognized scope of attorney-client privilege and is subject to the limitations or exceptions associated with such privilege; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id918e32d7c45c4be2b78fe92ff5c03fea"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an electronic communication between an incarcerated person and the agent of an attorney or legal representative described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9ac306d6a2614aa88b14de7655855bb5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on monitoring</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall issue a report regarding, establish guidelines for, and create a program or system, or modify a program or system that exists on the date of enactment of this Act, through which an incarcerated person may send or receive an electronic communication that excludes from monitoring the contents of any privileged electronic communication.</text></subsection><subsection id="id01cf0770708f40beb568845d1919d9bc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Features of program or system</header><text>The program or system created or modified under subsection (b) shall comply with the following:</text><paragraph id="id0270e369bfbe45ca94942753687192a3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Retention of contents</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons may retain, and provide access by an incarcerated person to, the contents of electronic communications, including the contents of privileged electronic communications, of the incarcerated person until the date on which the incarcerated person is released from the custody of the Bureau of Prisons or the United States Marshals Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida09a822397cb420194100d019401f09f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney-client privilege</header><text>Attorney-client privilege, and the protections and limitations associated with such privilege (including the crime fraud exception), shall apply to electronic communications sent or received through the program or system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6906cc3dfee045a1a6438860e1be7c9f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accessing retained communications</header><paragraph id="idF8517654AD9B4F0CA5AFF1300C29B1C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Privileged electronic communications retained under subsection (c)(1) may only be accessed by or provided to a person other than the incarcerated person for whom such privileged electronic communications are retained in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1540c856908408084a2b21951ab1d3a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney general</header><text>The Attorney General, or a designee, may only access such privileged electronic communications if necessary for the purpose of creating and maintaining the program or system created or modified under subsection (b), or any modification to the program or system. The Attorney General may not review the contents of privileged electronic communications pursuant to this paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideabdd8d7b7a14bdebee8c11719b99bd1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigative and law enforcement officers</header><subparagraph id="id9b52435e1f82484f98baf0f5148b6053"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Warrant</header><clause id="ide47f62a1626d4a7499d9dbd6c3c75790"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Such privileged electronic communications may only be accessed and the contents of such privileged electronic communications may only be reviewed by an investigative or law enforcement officer pursuant to a warrant issued by a court pursuant to the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure.</text></clause><clause id="id9fa4eefc8cd3468a8028527e40b81800"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>An incarcerated person may waive the requirement to obtain a warrant under clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="id7b8dcf0f8b7f4032934aa7a08e29bc4e"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>No application for such a warrant may be made to a court without the express approval of a United States attorney, an Assistant Attorney General, or a designee thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id947e050fa75d405ab9b4509d16a2f132"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileged information</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish procedures concerning the review of privileged electronic communications under subparagraph (A), which shall include the following:</text><clause id="id1207f04a40c24a7eabad6adcca887a9e"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Before the contents of such privileged electronic communications may be reviewed by an investigative or law enforcement officer pursuant to a warrant described in subparagraph (A), the privileged electronic communications shall be reviewed by a United States attorney, an Assistant Attorney General, or a designee to determine if a limitation or exception to the attorney-client privilege applies to any of the privileged electronic communications.</text></clause><clause id="id298a993206f8431eab0df165fb81953a"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Barring participation</header><text>A United States attorney, an Assistant Attorney General, or a designee who reviews privileged electronic communications pursuant to clause (i) shall be barred from—</text><subclause id="id5148ff40e5224c00bc6aff4ed4054733"><enum>(I)</enum><text>participating in a legal proceeding in which an individual who sent or received such a privileged electronic communication is a defendant; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idc72fd226596846b58cda12a44eff24ec"><enum>(II)</enum><text>sharing with an attorney who is participating in such a legal proceeding such a privileged electronic communication.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5ad7e251736f4ce3a954e7fbd830ba03"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Motion to suppress</header><text>Upon motion of a defendant, a court may suppress evidence obtained or derived from accessing privileged electronic communications or reviewing the contents of privileged electronic communications in violation of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2C97ECF0353C46F0B1F8C44A847B7164"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice until program or system is operational</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide written notice to each individual who is an incarcerated person at any time during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the program or system created or modified under subsection (b) is operational that the privileged electronic communications of the individual are subject to monitoring.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2456093A614E43B08D452612E4B3706C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph id="ida7d5f266fc0b4e0eb03cecc4a7ae2c79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inapplicability to non-privileged electronic communications</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the ability of investigative or law enforcement officers to monitor, record, access, review, or retain nonprivileged electronic communications of an incarcerated person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f0d992074c84cf09476244e8ae115a7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Verification of agent of an attorney or legal representative</header><text>Nothing in this section shall limit the authority of the Bureau of Prisons to establish policies that require a potential, current, or former attorney or legal representative to verify their identity, employment status, or licensure to practice law prior to being granted authorization to receive or send electronic communications from or to an incarcerated person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

