<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF76DA1FCBBAE4C2D8812E17742C86BFA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6273 IH: Stop Profiling Youth and Kids Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6273</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit market or product-focused research on children and minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2C93AE18BE6443D9BD5940C3B72320CC" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H211C960BE9914CA386F136486C6ACE7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Profiling Youth and Kids Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SPY Kids Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD773F09CE4104B0A91D896A378FB2EB9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7FDB787EF3C9497FB0D87FFB37D5745D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child</header><text>The term <term>child</term> means an individual who is under the age of 13.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H174EB2EBC630418B8E0AA0EB4DB8AC04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H972DE327EF244D8CB8EA8764C4882C26" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered platform</term> means a platform that is a website, software, application, or electronic service connected to the internet that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0284F4BFC04F458D8095E689CBD56C12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is publicly available for use by consumers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60992B95B227407F848CE2961D977F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enables the creation of a username or user identifier—</text> <clause id="HF8CDEA09CD604FA48D61A84056D2C10C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is searchable on the platform; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0725C6FC0D0E4F4EBA85B6273FB7757E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that can be followed by or is otherwise accessible to other users of the platform;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE21BD1E136354A5FAD97A4EED6704273"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as the predominant purpose of the platform, facilitates the creation and access to user-generated content through text, images, video, audio, or any other interactive medium;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H725794F556FA4DB4AD0405A0DC41BF05"><enum>(D)</enum><text>uses a design feature to promote user engagement on the platform; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44CE4D6EC81B44528527CC3DB48C33A0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>uses the personal information of the user to advertise, market, or make content recommendations.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H156175709F434E3DBD5BCA75DAA78576" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Design feature</header><text>The term <term>design feature</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H207E3AAB79414CAAAC5B77565A948B1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any feature or component of a covered platform that encourages or increases the frequency, time spent, or activity of a minor on the covered platform; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17BCC96A57194ADDAEC38882BDE2474E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any of the following:</text> <clause id="H211F0EFD38FB4AF5B2E317A39294438F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Infinite scrolling or auto play.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6E53A1C34A094C559292A7667B791B3C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Rewards or incentives based on the frequency, time spent, or activity of a minor on the covered platform.</text></clause> <clause id="H6B2B336FB0114187A02DFEF250134823" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Notifications and push alerts.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H95B35D4126C548EAB336452E54B1BD77" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Badges or other visual award symbols based on the frequency, time spent, or activity of a minor on the covered platform.</text></clause> <clause id="HCFE709D3DADE4AB6A496B79C210C9F4E" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Appearance altering filters.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BD9F18E1B4142D1AE738604A32B13DB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Know; knows</header><text>The term <term>know</term> or <term>knows</term> means to have actual knowledge or to have acted in willful disregard.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B6E6096BB014440840BD9F3721713EC" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Parent</header><text>The term <term>parent</term> means the legal guardian of a minor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D7462FB8BB849F8A8B6242C3B270DC0" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Personal information</header><text>The term <term>personal information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1302 of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6501">15 U.S.C. 6501</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9A8EFA840944B0E9B18CD6170F2AC99" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D2E3F503C654EB68F290210DAD8B14C" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Teen</header><text>The term <term>teen</term> means an individual who is over the age of 13 and under the age of 17. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BB6281D9A1D496E8FD96A8E55730632" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>User</header><text>The term <term>user</term> means, with respect to a covered platform, an individual who registers an account or creates a profile on the covered platform.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB77AD70CC9AD41E18F3A26C4ED9E6F0C"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Verifiable parental consent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>verifiable parental consent</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1302 of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6501">15 U.S.C. 6501</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H30AB0911255F47B1B745E4AF8AA6471D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Market research</header> <subsection id="H31D7F623CFA941DC9CCE8069C9A128B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition of research on children</header><text>A covered platform may not, in the case of a user or visitor that the covered platform knows is a child, conduct market or product-focused research on such child.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3424505D29A84921B63FDAB3E06381A2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on research on teens</header><text>A covered platform may not, in the case of a user or visitor that the online platform knows is a teen, conduct market or product-focused research on such teen, unless the covered platform obtains verifiable parental consent before conducting such research on such teen.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD32B3A22B3CA41DA8490A9A311C1BBE7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit the processing of personal information solely for measuring or reporting advertising or content performance, reach, or frequency, including through an independent measurement.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H767EC33E329540DCA2B32BED0D180CEC" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>4.</enum><header>Enforcement</header> 
<subsection id="H28CAC81962D7424F8B7267C58237B42B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H4FF776BE71E74C2684F58C07F2AEFC4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this Act shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF72C3EEA86384BEE8149D30DE9FEFE3B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the <act-name parsable-cite="FTCA">Federal Trade Commission Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act. Any person who violates this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC418554928F2400090CE8D546FF74046" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions by States</header> 
<paragraph id="H9F64DD74C33F454BA32979779679F45E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency of a State, has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of such State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of this Act, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate State court or an appropriate district court of the United States to—</text> <subparagraph id="H292726FD5DE446F190CF2566E36DCB54" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enjoin such act or practice;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3C0ECAB6FFBC4DC2B1109B863AC2D5E6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enforce compliance with this Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71F02807D6D0439CA1A00F961A21C59C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B44931E02464A638A313FC8A9BA21DA" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain such other legal and equitable relief as the court may consider to be appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84FBC4CD73124B2D8B9EED9918CFD725" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Before filing an action under this subsection, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State involved shall provide to the Commission a written notice of such action and a copy of the complaint for such action. If the attorney general, official, or agency determines that it is not feasible to provide the notice described in this paragraph before the filing of the action, the attorney general, official, or agency shall provide written notice of the action and a copy of the complaint to the Commission immediately upon the filing of the action.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H27299D84C4034561AFE5F4F7788526A7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority of Commission</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD65E4B7A94A14779A5FDA68C6A3F390A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On receiving notice under paragraph (2) of an action under this subsection, the Commission shall have the right—</text> <clause id="HE2BFC90D3FD6439D9DE37B62ECFFC241" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to intervene in the action;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEBAE47F9769D4D2DB6250D63571C7861"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF12755579E934CBDAC924A00CCE2BF19" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA6B455F60D64CB39E7DB87EFF506E27" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission or the Attorney General of the United States has instituted a civil action for violation of this Act (referred to in this subparagraph as the <quote>Federal action</quote>), no State attorney general, official, or agency may bring an action under this subsection during the pendency of the Federal action against any defendant named in the complaint in the Federal action for any violation of this Act alleged in such complaint.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H73BFF6FB499D41FF8423AFF299E19E1D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing a civil action under this subsection, nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent an attorney general, official, or agency of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general, official, or agency by the laws of such State to conduct investigations, administer oaths and affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H72A6A8000FCA43898EA6C4847A77B995" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to—</text> <paragraph id="H4BB9D8DAF2714E5FBD6B92D84EF77063" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>limit or impair the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/6501">15 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.</external-xref>) or any rule or regulation promulgated under such Act; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5073002E292744C48284FC7195A2F551" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>authorize any action in conflict with section 18(h) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(h)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="HD7EA387C704A45E4AB09EEAF022712F6" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to State laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No State or political subdivision of a State may prescribe, maintain, or enforce any law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision having the force and effect of law, if such law, rule, regulation, requirement, standard, or other provision relates to the provisions of this Act. </text></section> 
<section id="H22688AA9014C4DD081041300DE3925FC" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, this Act shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

