<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCA2E5D756C4746DD9657C511C4B673E4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8885 IH: Stop Taxpayer-funded Reimbursement for Unlawful Misconduct by Presidents Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8885</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to prohibit the use of appropriated funds, including the Judgment Fund, to settle or satisfy certain claims involving the President, political associates, or alleged governmental <quote>weaponization</quote>, to require repayment of unlawfully disbursed funds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4B6BDE1BE0CB4A26BFC8278751D495E7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFB3EE7B209654B13A8F198A343877A71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Taxpayer-funded Reimbursement for Unlawful Misconduct by Presidents Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STOP TRUMP ACT</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF42DCB1B240C453D969C8AB026EAA58F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of federal funds for political retribution claims</header> <subsection id="H34B3773E79924C139B0DFDACAFAAFF1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds, including amounts made available through the judgment fund under section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, may be obligated, expended, transferred, or otherwise used to—</text>
<paragraph id="H2A01F85BBBCB421FBD8F7917A1B7D67B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Settle, compromise, satisfy, or pay any claim brought by—</text> <subparagraph id="H77CE890CE16F46E7A8096B05C7028B4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The President;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCB52A1DDE78142AD9B9B6297B80C260C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any immediate family member of the President;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6C0BE7A843942019134CC6FB157A174"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any entity owned, controlled, or substantially affiliated with the President or an immediate family member of the President;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBD9950A43808401DB1AA7C1295B4F292"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any current or former political appointee of the Executive Office of the President; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB14808E267694874BC9FB7A49D203FA0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any individual or entity designated by the President for preferential compensation, including individuals who participated in the January 6th, 2021, domestic terrorist attack on the U.S. Capitol</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">where such claim arises from alleged political targeting, alleged <quote>weaponization</quote> of government, investigative activity, prosecutorial activity, law enforcement actions, tax administration, intelligence activities, or civil or criminal proceedings undertaken by the Federal Government; or</continuation-text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H16D49C03B0A54C14B3447D4F1D740210"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establish, capitalize, administer, or finance any compensation fund, claims commission, restitution program, reimbursement mechanism, or similar entity intended to compensate individuals or organizations for alleged governmental <quote>weaponization,</quote> political bias, selective enforcement, or retaliatory investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1F425CA996B4530BD56DBED1A64991F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on special compensation commissions</header><text>No officer or employee of the United States may establish, by executive order, memorandum, settlement agreement, agreement, consent decree, agency action, or otherwise, any board, commission, task force, adjudicatory body, or compensation authority authorized to distribute Federal funds based upon allegations of political targeting or governmental <quote>weaponization.</quote></text></subsection>
<subsection id="H602B2D9D8124489EBD91D5CDA1DBE8F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Voidness</header><text>Any agreement, settlement, memorandum of understanding, or obligation entered into in violation of this section shall be—</text> <paragraph id="HEA1DD10E60404F51B3FA56C14CF8F4BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>null and void ab initio;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7586A6C867CE485AAC5D0C2DFFC4CCD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>without legal force or effect; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F02FBEA48DF4F82A955730F408FC27C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>unenforceable in any Federal court.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H59CDEB9D67A94209B53B865D4AFD3B5F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conflict-of-interest restrictions</header>
<subsection id="H82DFBB3580B6432F82851B5DF8DBF305"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restriction on executive branch representation</header><text>The Department of Justice may not represent the interests of the United States in any litigation in which—</text> <paragraph id="H6BD261D6C418459A8F928A485E3314DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The President is a plaintiff or beneficiary; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H44192129C7AE4FBA88EFB32CA77BF341"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The relief sought includes monetary damages, injunctive relief, or settlement authority that could financially or politically benefit the President, the President’s family, or affiliated entities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HBF488C13914D4E8384BD58932A9054FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recoupment of unlawfully disbursed funds</header> <subsection id="H010BC0F8B81A4C94AC99360EAE541483"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory repayment</header><text>Any individual, entity, organization, trust, partnership, corporation, or other recipient that received Federal funds in violation of this Act, including funds disbursed prior to the date of enactment of this Act, shall repay the full amount of such funds to the Treasury of the United States.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H07F2A31F99FD47D990027E8619A98D94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Offset authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may offset any repayment obligation arising under this section against any Federal payment otherwise owed to the recipient, including tax refunds, grants, contracts, salaries, or benefit payments.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC1F93BEE35794252A5E53D054F333FE9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil recovery actions</header><text>The Attorney General shall initiate civil actions to recover amounts described in subsection (a). Such actions may include—</text>
<paragraph id="H6BC4E004846444C6881BC9B4DEFAC53E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Garnishment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDECF5CEBB3674B73AC13249ED03B1E94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Attachment;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE2724CA1A12A40EFBA2822CE5ED608BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Liens on real and personal property</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF891D3435CF843A2954E36B22F5FFE30"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Seizure of assets traceable to unlawfully disbursed funds; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB0486B8D6F62451DA037BEAB4D25DFC4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any other remedy available under Federal law</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

