<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B4B26385B164CEBBD15909F7620D5C0" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1248 IH: Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives from participating in prediction markets in certain cases, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1248</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit Members, officers, and employees of the House of Representatives from participating in prediction markets in certain cases, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="HD0FA6113A3BE4135841CAEFFEB0FB3B1"><section id="HCD5680500F724837983566BB06132240" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on prediction market trading by Members, officers, and employees of the House</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7FC242FA22584B91BD71CA6CA7309225"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating clause 22 as clause 23; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9207C76652624AF59E65E5B7D975F9B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after clause 21 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H98171FD041704C6DB51126C125854FD0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><rules-clause id="H90F54BADBA424F89903DCC2AC19DBF4E"><enum>22.</enum><rules-paragraph id="H2A3B74BF21D7402D9A0077F04421F3C3" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>No Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, or employee of the House may enter into, or offer to enter into, an agreement, contract, swap, or transaction that provides for any purchase, sale, payment, or delivery of an excluded commodity, as defined in section 1a of the Commodity Exchange Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1a">7 U.S.C. 1a</external-xref>), that is dependent on the occurrence, nonoccurrence, or the extent of the occurrence of a specific event or contingency.</text></rules-paragraph><rules-paragraph id="H74B21057793640ECA7D14F57F3CF4640" indent="up1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this clause shall be construed to apply to insurance for which the insured holds a lawful insurable interest or the making of a lawful sports wager.</text></rules-paragraph><rules-paragraph id="HEF6B1A4A186C40B9B9A481B9DE880793" indent="up1"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this clause, the term <term>sports wager</term> means the staking or risking by any person of something of value upon the outcome of a sporting event, including the outcome of any portion or aspect thereof, upon an agreement or understanding that the person or another person will receive something of value in the event of a certain outcome. </text></rules-paragraph></rules-clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H894518674DF34376A0C36FCC9067A6A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of the House of Representatives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the House of Representatives that the executive branch and judicial branch should establish restrictions similar to those added to the Rules of the House under section 1 relating to participation in prediction markets. </text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

