<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H20378A79ED7348879FDFA40BE904DA34" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1432 IH: Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of Health and Human Services to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the freeze on State-based Temporary Assistance for Needy Families, Child Care and Development Fund, and Social Services Block Grant payments for California, Colorado, Illinois, Minnesota, and New York.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1432</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Of inquiry requesting the President and directing the Secretary of Health and Human Services to transmit, respectively, certain documents to the House of Representatives relating to the freeze on State-based Temporary Assistance for Needy Families, Child Care and Development Fund, and Social Services Block Grant payments for California, Colorado, Illinois, Minnesota, and New York.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HCB73956C0E2C477BA96483C8FC1BBE20"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HBBF1AA5CD31F4804964C7F0B853483F8"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the President of the United States is requested, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services is directed, to transmit, to the extent that such documents are in the possession of the President or the Secretary, to the House of Representatives, not later than 14 days after the date of adoption of this resolution, copies of any document, audit trail, record, audio recording, memorandum, call log, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), written agreements, report, study, contract, staffing assignment, legal analysis or other communication in their possession, or any portion of any document, record, audit trail, audio recording, memorandum, call log, contract, staffing assignment, legal analysis, correspondence (electronic or otherwise), or other communication, that refers or relates to the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEA3A124C6C0E4F80A03EB4130564E13C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Communication between the Executive Office of the President and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) about selecting particular States and programs for a payment freeze.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D3E5365A8DE4306B86C140F68C928E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The tweet by HHS Deputy Secretary Jim O’Neill on December 30, 2025, freezing all Administration for Children and Families (ACF) payments.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H193C3B16643849F4BF658C2EA81350A4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Drawdown of Temporary Assistance to Needy Families (TANF), Social Services Block Grant (SSBG) and Child Care Entitlement to States (CCES) funding any time after December 30, 2025, by California, Colorado, Illinois, Minnesota, or New York, or any tribal grantee located in one of those five States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB8E3F8B2DA1408E99F1FF25608FBC38"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Warning letters, referrals to the Office of the Inspector General, or other disciplinary actions regarding alleged funding misuse by any of the five States between January 20, 2025, and December 1, 2025.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDD886AF3D0545CE959D73351FFFC7D0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Communication with grantees regarding submitting additional data and HHS plans for storage, use, and sharing of that data within and outside of HHS after January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H073337B7DBEC4F52B71870F7E531C72C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Contracts, staffing assignments, and instructions to contractors and any HHS staff (whether based in the District of Columbia or regionally) regarding the payment freeze.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DC7C49D87D24047879AF1ADE7042E04"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Contracts with States, Tribes, and Territories governing the HHS Payment Management System effective in 2025 or 2026.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D5D160AE72C468FA3923BB6B8B3AD70"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Meetings, discussions, or other actions involving the HHS Office of the General Counsel or outside legal advisors regarding use of the Payment Management system by grantees in the five States after January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

