<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDF7993C4793F419096D2E8EB76A787A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6840 IH: Advancing Readiness, Military Exchange, and National Integration with Armenia Security Partnership Act Security Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6840</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to certify that the Government of Azerbaijan has taken certain meaningful steps with respect to Armenia and the Nagorno-Karabakh region, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2A24DF3F60B345ADB05B389E13BF348A" style="OLC">
<section id="H7B35966499C54B55B25B3483D294201B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Readiness, Military Exchange, and National Integration with Armenia Security Partnership Act Security Partnership Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ARMENIA Security Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3E3368F3A0EF4777BE732BE77EA97C40" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of Security Assistance for Armenia</header> <subsection id="H63F1B015596446B88700264F63EC1C85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and not less than annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with each other national security agency such Secretary determines appropriate, shall certify to the congressional defense committees that the Government of Azerbaijan has taken meaningful steps towards the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7401BB1D43B5445A8B8D127909A7ACC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Uphold its commitments under the Joint Declaration.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5874973B2B664CFBAF4A108E29846AEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Completely withdraw all military forces from the sovereign territory of Armenia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0ED5F7A0F5354D468FC1D5BB28FBCCF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Unconditionally release all Armenian prisoners.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACA631E852C74BC3A935D8C9B7038D71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Cease engaging in hostilities towards Armenia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H73E3C696FD0C423287C28277CE5ABA19"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recognize a right of return for ethnic Armenians to their homes in Nagorno-Karabakh and commit to the preservation of Armenian cultural and religious sites in Nagorno-Karabakh.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB73695BA80F948A9A8F7702C00382EE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Security assistance review</header><text>If the Secretary of Defense cannot certify the information under subsection (a), such Secretary shall, not later than 14 days after the date on which any such certification is required to be made, conduct an immediate review of United States security assistance for the Republic of Armenia (hereinafter <quote>Armenia</quote>) to assess gaps in Armenia’s deterrence and self-defense capabilities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F7C6EAECD9D4386994DF0D939B31AB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the completion the review required under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Commander of the United States European Command and each other national security agency such Secretary determines appropriate, shall submit a report to the congressional defense committees that includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="HFBB39A9821F246E788CDA57E91100247"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the scale and nature of threats to Armenia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD39AE43742A34D6A9D516F6528A9230F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An evaluation of historical and current United States security assistance for Armenia including International Security Cooperation Programs, Foreign Military Financing, and International Military Education and Training support.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63089B7DED2D4CE2AA57C01B61DD8B58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identification of gaps in Armenia’s immediate and long-term defense needs, including defense articles, services, and military training.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF98474FD0EA24EABA5982EF7298355BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A summary of immediate steps the Department of Defense is taking to increase security cooperation with Armenia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB5655D79FC24A03AA4DE70D43E49CD2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recommendations for further increasing security assistance for Armenia to address shortfalls in Armenia’s self-defense capabilities to deter aggression.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1644DE55CE414EB1A6906F2C3437143A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>FREEDOM Support Act waiver disqualified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Defense cannot certify the information under subsection (a), the President may not, after the date that is 14 days after the date on which any such certification is required to be made, exercise the waiver authority provided pursuant to title II of the Foreign Operations, Export Financing and related Programs Appropriations Act, 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/115">Public Law 107–115</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/5812">22 U.S.C. 5812</external-xref> note) under subsection (g) under the heading <quote>Assistance for the independent states of the former Soviet Union</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H113B25646B1B4C0AA1788E2430F8C277"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> means the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

