<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HABCDB6FD42F740BEB6DCF11DE87B30F9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6998 IH: Renewed Hope Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6998</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260109">January 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance hiring authorities at the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA22188FB34A8475FAB93C148232138AE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD0501992F0BB4BC9881BB0A8A6268705" commented="no" section-type="section-one" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Renewed Hope Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EA9E3D053C04A01BD78926CA5F5EFE8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Image audio forensics hiring and training programs at the Department of Homeland Security</header> 
<subsection id="H0E42750AD33B4604AF6D0F2DE7F7CFBC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Additional personnel</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall hire, train, and assign not fewer than—</text> <paragraph id="HBC87473D654C4F4F8418E9902378663A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>40 forensics analysts to the Victim Identification Laboratory of the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of Homeland Security Investigations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B34D2FB15364F9A83E111BAD4AAC9AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>30 child exploitation investigators to the Victim Identification Laboratory of the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of Homeland Security Investigations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4410EC673E754698AB5A5B231494D3C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>130 additional forensics analysts and child exploitation investigators to support identification and rescue of victims of child sexual exploitation and abuse at Homeland Security Investigations offices of the Special Agent in Charge.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5E200319595E498BA78730699F4492C7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on reassignment of positions</header> 
<paragraph id="H673DA46778454C57823D3BC6AA1792C2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A position created under subsection (a) may not be reassigned to another component of the Department of Homeland Security that is outside of the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of Homeland Security Investigations or the offices of the Special Agent in Charge of Homeland Security Investigations, as applicable.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA665DB5584D4B21B68A5C2F6D54595D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reassignment of employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee serving in a position created under subsection (a) may be reassigned to another component of the Department of Homeland Security that is outside of the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of Homeland Security Investigations or the offices of the Special Agent in Charge of Homeland Security Investigations only if the employee elects to be so reassigned.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A3364DB71964330935CD8D950F9F93A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employment of experts and consultants</header><text>Section 890A of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/473">6 U.S.C. 473</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6E5181DDBBA54E40AB1CDADDB6F5D7E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (i); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8A53149F9FD4AFCB9F5D718E25146C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2975936A64B44C0A4FC60A4DAB08D1B"> <subsection id="HF763205327104EC8A5BAD22F99E4262B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Employment of Experts and Consultants</header> <paragraph id="H0F895ACDC74C41C6B71871271766B42F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In accordance with section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, at daily rates not to exceed the equivalent rate prescribed for grade GS–15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title, the Secretary may procure by contract the temporary (not in excess of 1 year) or intermittent services of experts or consultants to provide image and audio forensic analysis related to victim identification to support efforts to identify, locate, and rescue children seen in videos images and videos of sexual exploitation and abuse.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0420EA1109264FA78C5659D59D3725AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Placement</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate guidelines for assigning or detailing participants to positions at the Center, offices of the Special Agent in Charge, offices of the Resident Agent in Charge, and Attaché offices.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HEDEBE20CAE79427584D195337887DBE0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Deconfliction of child sexual exploitation and abuse investigations within the department of homeland security</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 890A(a) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/473">6 U.S.C. 473(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB05341A25B4446B0A56D1E1E63695FA5" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H503DB3DA37CE43438ADEBAB8DA8F5892"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall, with the concurrence of the directors of affected agencies within the Department, establish joint procedures to deconflict, coordinate, and synchronize child sexual exploitation investigations with the Center.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51C2D7546FD2423DA99C53F63C2F6188"><enum>(4)</enum><header>NCMEC coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Center may establish joint procedures with the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children to deconflict, coordinate, and synchronize child sexual exploitation investigations with the Child Victim Identification Program of the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89BECBEA0BDA4339A8EFCC14E0DFBE14"><enum>4.</enum><header>Victim identification training program</header> 
<subsection id="HF0871058B1344052ABB40EE8D39C73BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a Victim Identification Training Program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>) in the Cyber Crimes Center.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8302CF1FB724426AEC4DF42E0D8B625"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Program shall provide training used to identify victims of sexual exploitation and abuse to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6F9EEAE4E8104527BB67379F4613FECD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Homeland Security Investigations personnel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H279A62A0732A44169B4AF788797DE802"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Federal, State, local, Tribal, and foreign law enforcement agency personnel engaged in the investigation of crimes of child sexual exploitation and abuse within their respective jurisdictions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF7ABF8D28A642529F9DEB6491A902E1">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Civil service organizations engaged in the prevention of child sexual exploitation and the identification of abuse victims; and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EA3B138AC6B45449675F703E3AFA5B0">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Center for Missing and Exploited Children.</text>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAB90F82E555545348D04143CD7EADC1E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions of the Program shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HAB200332C65D40C89CC94F299D920A95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>annual training for participants focused on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8735F40D1B8D42A0930DDD43B6FABC7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training on the most current tools and techniques used in victim identification; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H526E98ECD70148FB825FFF5D67795F03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training on the capabilities of the Victim Identification Laboratory; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE75073158D1A4B73AA96B88B99C18327"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing personnel knowledge on how to conduct image, audio, and video enhancements.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA46A2AC7A67246C6BEA0DD476B933D3F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Direct hire authority for Homeland Security Investigations</header> <subsection id="HE4BEF9C6EFE54452A553C8FC8FEFD5C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Direct hire</header> <paragraph id="HB78DA63945304D458FBD2DF56957FDCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the head of Homeland Security Investigations may appoint, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 (other than sections 3303 and 3328 of such chapter) of title 5, United States Code, qualified candidates to the positions described in section 2(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01706B59A9F242708C5ED5AF1EAA2D51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority under paragraph (1) shall not be available to the head if, during any period, at least 97 percent of such positions are occupied.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1960787C03904D3E81A0A1FA3AEAAEB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act and for each of the 4 following years, the head of Homeland Security Investigations shall submit a report to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives, the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and any other relevant congressional committee of jurisdiction. Each such report shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4D178FAAB76144729C2046CB1691186F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The total number of individuals appointed by the head under this section during the preceding year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H395DC36C567B42BE831EADF418B62EA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the direct hiring authority under this section is being used by the head.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H995FD6973A8246BDAF9AC809BBF2730B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements of each of sections 2 through 4 of this Act, and any amendment made by such sections, shall be carried out not later than the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section> <section id="HA794F18DE8E64A0EAD1356B973625B7E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Privacy protections for victims</header> <subsection id="HDFB6847137A345A791C28640599C2E4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered person shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4CCC3E2614644013B1C665352B705185"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">keep all identifying information and documents concerning a victim of child sexual exploitation or abuse in a secure place to which only individuals working to identify and rescue victims of child sexual exploitation or abuse have access; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA7D5493CD7541BCADD5C5B6543A78CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not disclose or use any information or documents concerning a victim of child sexual exploitation or abuse other than for the purposes of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D77089B78B84703B4FB07D5E40E77A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>investigating or prosecuting individuals for crimes of child sexual exploitation or abuse;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0CFBAD50E9848759255E159C1702D04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>connecting victims—</text> 
<clause id="H5C259AAA12E3490A9DDD843486F3B26C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to licensed and trained trauma informed medical professions; or</text></clause> <clause id="HFAA39185582E4F9B94CF6B26E569BC75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with Federal resources available through the Office of Victims of Crime at the Department of Justice;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CBCCE393D3F4871A65B8B8EFA0E9119"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complying with any mandatory victim reporting requirements; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF714D0A3CA97458EB18C32B5461B64C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sharing information with other law enforcement personnel for the purpose of investigating or prosecuting individuals for crimes of child sexual exploitation or abuse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA582CCB096354EB89E55ED0DC1098BF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered person defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered person</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H8955AEF47D47406597AEA1E872F7FEC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Federal, State, or local law enforcement officer; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC15D47FC1C949F28C27329C859AC19E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other personnel of the Department of Homeland Security,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">working in, employed by, or detailed to the Child Exploitation Investigations Unit of Homeland Security Investigations or to the offices of the Special Agent in Charge of Homeland Security Investigations.</continuation-text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

