<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H608010FFA5454FA8913CFB2E8F90C8AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8600 IH: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to temporarily suspend certain fuel excise taxes for fuel separated during periods in which the national average price of gasoline exceeds $3.99 per gallon, and to prohibit certain credits or deductions for oil and gas companies during such periods.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8600</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to temporarily suspend certain fuel excise taxes for fuel separated during periods in which the national average price of gasoline exceeds $3.99 per gallon, and to prohibit certain credits or deductions for oil and gas companies during such periods.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C60C606E0C94CE4B9D3C408C465BDD1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA01FF1025AC04016AC31722E3884A863" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Suspension of tax on removal, entry, or sale of certain fuel; suspension of certain credits and deductions for oil and gas companies</header> 
<subsection id="H06EC45D49E2E4EB8AEDE54344F787DD2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="H00E78A820C244E7BBA9794608B1CB585"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4081">Section 4081</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE81DA2EFC1A74C238338887AC5F7B382" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HB9B7DDD2BFCA44C79E716D5895CF5885"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Partial suspension of tax during certain periods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any month during which the national average price of gasoline exceeds $3.99 per gallon, the tax imposed by subsection (a) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by 1 cent for each cent of such excess average price.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC1173179BDE41C48347DAD7E8377A3A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfers to Trust Fund</header> 
<subparagraph id="HAA3B1D38B5EE4612B054069DE6E34C5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall transfer from the general fund to the Highway Trust Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund established under section 9508(a) of such Code amounts equal to the reduction in amounts credited (but for this subsection) to each such Trust Fund by reason of the partial suspension under section 4081(f) of such Code (as added by paragraph 1 of this section).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD817EA2EF1A34DA993C5A1CA19EB2BB5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Coordination rules</header> <clause id="HD47FD4B7549E4762BFD51EEDE4E7111E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund under subparagraph (A) shall be treated for purposes of sections 9503(b)(1) and 9508(b)(2) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HACB2C75A44FE48A79643FB1090878F66"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Highway Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Highway Trust Fund under subparagraph (A) shall be treated for purposes of section 9503(b)(1) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code which are not attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFC6A8ADDEE804B3B977E51997146C964"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Intangible drilling costs</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 263(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>This section shall not apply with respect to any costs incurred during any month described in section 4081(f).</quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H54896F4089FF484D8A7CBDAC007BB5B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enhanced oil recovery credit</header><text>Section 43 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3D15EE1B9A2A4B56851DED4F9C4F8966" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HBD680D4E7EA3438AB4C6E8A0B7380F3E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Credit not applicable to costs paid or incurred during disqualified periods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section for costs paid or incurred during any month described in section 4081(f).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H170AE9EDAD3148718DBE6FC98993068B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Marginal well credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 45I(d) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1EA49307F8B042E597055FA42E510AD8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H06B9AFC8F25A483DB54742677654A6FA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Production during disqualified periods excluded</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section for production during any month described in section 4081(f).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC2E0F2112A7C4DF3B0680D4581A44432"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2025.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

