<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT26254-J90-2Y-GTJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4193 IS: Wildfire and Grid Reliability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4193</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a grant program to improve the reliability of the power grid and reduce the risk of wildfires caused by power lines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire and Grid Reliability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id492AF398763946C5BCAD440617474E7A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Wildfire and grid reliability program</header><subsection id="idE821B5B9176E4DE38F659B4A58B55C8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id540859F9BC0248069E8F791D26AC2722"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an electric utility, including—</text><subparagraph id="id3AD35281432F4FB98817F646F1BAF991"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a publicly owned electric utility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB39398B6200A481C872292096A2C0266"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a municipal electric utility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id052B5C01796240129117B5D9D3367256"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a cooperatively owned electric utility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id02E8921DA33F423C94A2EE95C8A2FA86"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an investor-owned electric utility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA60710E378134386A9AB750F075E024D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a Federal agency or federally owned corporation that is an electric utility (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBD67F6E93443402DA2D86CDF9875A48D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Power line</header><text>The term <term>power line</term> includes a transmission line or a distribution line, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4BEF76FA4C944A84B850CF928200EEA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the program established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15a5c5c3fff14141b845d42c7c66c244"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reliability</header><text>The term <term>reliability</term>, with respect to the power grid, includes the ability to withstand natural disasters, such as earthquakes, ice storms, wind storms, snow storms, heat storms, and other natural disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEB1677A660CE4AA7A81B6FFCCA2F833A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idE1B0619498EA4E0BA1483C726965DED8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish within the Office of Electricity a program under which the Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities to carry out activities that—</text><paragraph id="id98CEE6099DE04156B1D30B98B6C13872"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are supplemental to existing power grid-hardening efforts of the eligible entity planned for any given year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF15C2BA78DC54D74B79E33B827E338A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are designed to enhance public safety; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id195E5006FD9A4E6296B5B53A60CDC123"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id9C32E954577B4D9AAFD10D65D40C0415"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce the risk of any power lines owned or operated by the eligible entity causing a wildfire; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="id566A8986DDFE47C1B9F9B019EF366C31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase the reliability of the power grid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="idCFAFA014EF6947D59A11B51E4C9EE3E0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph commented="no" id="idB6BC99DE5F774C9880A0430F43E8ABD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under the program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id7B1D4BF9FA3A43E69C482BCC95A8D5E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>As a condition of receiving a grant under the program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary as part of the application of the eligible entity under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="id7FF30B25F4894313BD4FCD74153D6930"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a wildfire mitigation plan, if the eligible entity seeks a grant for purposes of implementing a project or otherwise carrying out activities to reduce wildfire risk, as described in subsection (b)(3)(A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="id12C37FA8E8B64E88A3951458224C3ADF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a report detailing past, current, and future efforts by the eligible entity to improve the reliability of the power grid if the eligible entity seeks a grant for purposes of increasing the reliability of the power grid.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idCE02A2BB61164841BF481871D8AE0C7A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text>An eligible entity may use a grant provided under the program—</text><paragraph id="id297a3c9a2031443c9c541fca8720d46a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for the undergrounding of new and existing power lines and circuits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a24dab9f40547e79c02d4ce23fe530c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to harden overhead power lines with fire resistant or more resilient equipment, such as steel poles and covered wires;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89eb6ff6556b40d8876b72cdcc3d07be"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to replace obsolete overhead conductors and underground cables;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida61432b11ed34510982eb1cecd8bfdb3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to install fast-tripping protection systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf4c4b8b04d594162b8921b72f92bf97f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to construct and operate 1 or more weather monitoring stations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f18d36af0dc4af98b69ccd2c4f40706"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to install fault location equipment or early fault detection equipment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc9fae2d72114dbcacc3222f25a0cda4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>for the relocation of power lines to roadways;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD3A35182D8BA4846848F14AEB88180F6"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to carry out vegetation or fuels management activities in accordance with Federal, State, and local laws (including regulations);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF6F53ED1A2F64D508CF0EE204641B029"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to install technology or equipment to mitigate hazards from or to animals and related damage to the power grid;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11A9A4FF958647F1BD40F01AFD5611AF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to install cameras, sensors, or other technology that provides real-time information about conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddf488e99c8f54841bb3d465033942df7"><enum>(11)</enum><text>to install technology to detect downed conductors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0F433B21ACDF4A86A202A341058DF29D"><enum>(12)</enum><text>for the installation of electrical facilities necessary to sustain targeted microgrid operations, including storage for the integration of distributed energy resources into power grid operations, for the benefit of community resilience following a main power grid outage;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id463C44E11C8B412286FFEBFCE61C43A5"><enum>(13)</enum><text>to harden facilities, substations, and other systems for seismic events; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id962FA5E0352D4DD394F861E47D09C491"><enum>(14)</enum><text>for other, related power grid upgrades to reduce the risk of wildfire ignition or damage from natural disasters.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9E862669A1D54613A6D0833EB49119C0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In making grants under the program, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that, in the determination of the Secretary, will generate the greatest community benefit in improving power grid reliability or reducing the risk of wildfire ignition from power lines or equipment relative to the cost of the project.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6A7C981A91F84BA7B1B1AB3E3CB2A639"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Set asides</header><paragraph id="id20E88383A7BB4B2689A9F7583775B910"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Wildfire set aside</header><text>In making grants under the program, the Secretary shall ensure that not less than 40 percent of the total amounts made available to eligible entities under the program are made available to eligible entities that seek a grant for purposes of implementing a project or otherwise carrying out activities to reduce wildfire risk, as described in subsection (b)(3)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA2B67783C9B74FF1AD1D4CF88CD075FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Small utilities set aside</header><text>In making grants under the program, the Secretary shall ensure that not less than 20 percent of the amounts made available to eligible entities under the program are made available to eligible entities that sell not more than 4,000,000 megawatt-hours of electricity per year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id590B125EBE124B4094D88A7397A1FC9F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><paragraph id="id33F319E4EDBA42B9AC3F76009BE21130"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), as a condition of receiving a grant under the program, an eligible entity shall provide matching funds in the form of cash or an in-kind contribution in an amount equal to not less than 100 percent of the amounts made available under the grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7DBD263D1F8B4CF383540B0A97D2D81D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for small utilities</header><text>With respect to an eligible entity that sells not more than 4,000,000 megawatt-hours of electricity per year, as a condition of receiving a grant under the program, the eligible entity shall provide matching funds in the form of cash or an in-kind contribution in an amount equal to not less than <fraction>1/3</fraction> of the amounts made available under the grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2D9698D6C8094B3F9DDFA2150B0C7738"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Existing efforts</header><text>On approval by the Secretary, amounts expended by an eligible entity on power grid reliability or wildfire risk mitigation efforts during the 1-year period ending on the date on which a grant is received under the program shall count toward the matching requirement described in paragraph (1) or (2), as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id782CD6F8A82D4059B999796DC75AD85A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal power marketing administrations</header><text>Any amounts made available to a Federal power marketing administration pursuant to a grant under the program shall be nonreimbursable.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcc9d4d470da5477aa1efc7df5f050a97"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance and support</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1a3093f9fd394f48b12c12815913d726"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using amounts made available to the Secretary to carry out the program, the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id15ca5b7a56dd41be93b47b4a78d43e5c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide technical assistance to—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9bade7e7a80f4545908b395813a65c11"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligible entities seeking to prepare an application under subsection (c); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54ef1787940b4576891e0f76ec44c38c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>eligible entities to which the Secretary has provided a grant under the program; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfdd4ee30be8142e89631d1f3ef9945b4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide grants to eligible entities for the hiring or retention of individuals to provide and support, on a professional basis, assistance (including technical assistance) and informed decisionmaking in the planning, financing, and implementation of 1 or more activities described in subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcf6359faf0af45918fc40fed51ab4794"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>Grants under paragraph (1)(B)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42544bf7c1444b6fbd2bdc55db91c6e1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be counted toward a set-aside described in subsection (f); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9ad85029f5c2496ca40e0e84c69abe9f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be subject to subsection (g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1F2DE9F557EB40F8A1C59A2BE00B6A65"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report describing the manner in which, and the extent to which—</text><paragraph id="idCB0420CD22D64102A8E425673B96995F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the reliability of the power grid has increased under the program during the period covered by the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6BA643A4B68B444AB815B51720912723"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the risk of wildfires caused by power lines has been reduced under the program during the period covered by the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAD8ABB0E194B4953BA1B6F58BAE2A587"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the program $15,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2036.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

