<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H850AFE74F6834A9AAAE84B4DE76E76C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9090 IH: Advancing Menopause Care and Mid-Life Women’s Health Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9090</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve menopause care and mid-life women&#8217;s health, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9D0A8E3401104D0B86E4BEEF6744BBB3" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8360AA77819E4BA5BBB91C1D9A1CB20F"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2A717938C15402587FDD67791A892E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Menopause Care and Mid-Life Women’s Health Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAFC73B80B2E4429A98CAB09FCFE68241"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H8360AA77819E4BA5BBB91C1D9A1CB20F">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H50B1904A7E3E4A35BE6297B50EA329BE">Sec. 2. Research with respect to menopause and mid-life women’s health.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H8CB4012DC188400396A6D27DC81E5A1F">Sec. 3. Public health promotion and prevention.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HD2E698F58FF54CD7B75DE630234F1E64">Sec. 4. Public health awareness, education, and outreach program on menopause and mid-life women’s health.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HBC6D3549692E4E03BEEC035EC8F1727E">Sec. 5. Training programs to improve care and treatment of menopausal symptoms.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H86567CCBE75D43FDBF64A20B0F9C803C">Sec. 6. Centers of excellence in menopause cause and mid-life women's health.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HDE0E0275D4F04587BDD07520D0D58331">Sec. 7. Reporting requirement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H6C217DC1DA42454AAC74590ABE74E2F4">Sec. 8. Coordination.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H50B1904A7E3E4A35BE6297B50EA329BE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Research with respect to menopause and mid-life women’s health</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0E52D7C5D3749A0AFDEC8205E3967B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">NIH research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/281">42 U.S.C. 281 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H46EA8FE7756045898EC854B58BBC71DB"> <section id="H101DBB40F4FC4AA4B2929C429AC985B5"><enum>404P.</enum><header>Research with respect to menopause and mid-life women’s health</header> <subsection id="H7FA91F8C9F2E4F98BD38A28D25039575"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research and innovation</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H66366C8C9C0E4C5289291607C1A8DFE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of NIH, acting through the Director of the Office of Research on Women's Health, shall coordinate and expand research activities conducted by all institutes, centers, and offices of the National Institutes of Health to develop and implement Federal research programs with respect to—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FBAB460A3A24070A5885436DC9250FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the symptoms and trajectories of changes across perimenopause, the menopausal transition, and the postmenopausal period on women’s physical, oral, mental, behavioral, and cognitive health; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7B2035F99F540F190CABF95BF1EE1C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the prevention of related adverse health outcomes among women during the menopausal transition and the postmenopausal period;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H13B1A0025DDE47ED8FD5F9BDB6EE2041"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the known health disparities that are observed with the menopausal transition, including between rural women and urban or suburban women; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF9159785FCF048FC9EEFBAFB63CFCC08"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the development of integrated, collaborative approaches to menopause care, which may involve non-pharmacological and pharmacological treatments. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H620277D0CF8A4E12A0E1402F7EC5D309"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director of NIH shall award grants to eligible entities to support—</text> <subparagraph id="H25B0A7CCF14E428DB3009FB47E0E65F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>biomedical and public health research and innovation in the development of new treatments, and diagnostic testing services for perimenopause and acute and chronic menopausal conditions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H907BBDE29B0848DEBF7E07F202B1C0B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>researchers and clinicians engaged in clinical and translational research on perimenopause, menopause, and mid-life women’s health; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8A069990CB94ABFAC957C6F1113B716"><enum>(C)</enum><text>researchers and clinicians developing and testing the effectiveness and implementation of evidence-based integrated, collaborative approaches for caring for mid-life women in the perimenopausal, menopausal, and postmenopausal periods of life.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C44120CAC0A4BF488C902EF7A865B09"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (b), an entity shall meet such criteria as the Director of NIH may establish, and shall be—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6C56CD55F314757BBB200001EE2B2F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accredited entity that offers education to students in various health professions, such as―</text> 
<clause id="H8E9CE1D8EEF6467C814949D44F878284"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a teaching hospital;</text></clause> <clause id="H5F47ACF18BA348379D92C382EDA9EA12"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an accredited school of medicine, osteopathic medicine, dental medicine, nursing, or pharmacy, or a physician assistant training program, including a historically Black college or university (as defined by the term <quote>part B institution</quote> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 or described in section 326(e)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965) or other minority-serving institutions (as described in section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965));</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0D02E7055D6940039BCE15E9EE7F2D57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a certified behavioral health clinic with an accredited medical or nursing residency program;</text></clause> <clause id="H976FE1E3C1A245DFB11580DA9E8B9FE8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an accredited public or nonprofit private hospital with an accredited medical, dental, or nursing residency program;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3A8E4EAE383049AFADDEBE88D06EB566"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an accredited nurse practitioner residency program that includes and accredited nursing residency program; or</text></clause> <clause id="H18570D776EFC48FDA59E69F9551190C1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a related accredited program engaged in the care, treatment, or management of menopausal symptoms; </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B48EE2D57144A3B844AF980379661AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an academic research institution or other nonprofit research institution;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6592ADD3022F4E239C94503F145A3CF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a small business; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H257B36D081BE4D068B22271D16850EFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>such other entity as the Director of NIH may determine appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H921F778E48304AC3A39F5DDB7B07B4AA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research, condition, and disease categorization</header><text>The Director of NIH shall designate, in the Research, Condition, and Disease Categorization, new categories for chronic or debilitating conditions among women, to analyze and coordinate current and future research on perimenopause, menopause, menopausal symptoms, and postmenopausal short-term and long-term effects of such symptoms and conditions on mid-life women’s health.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8470C897D3454D9F8DF9168A9A395A36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Director of the NIH shall coordinate and expand Federal research programs and activities to study acute and chronic menopausal symptoms and new pharmacological or non-pharmacological treatment approaches for such symptoms, including—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ADF7533795D4EF893DA1C4AEEB26048"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">vasomotor symptoms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD401BF934C8486FBF65039380239F18"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">osteoporosis;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87E14937850348D892D461BA718FD56F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sarcopenia;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C77EEDF8D614E798FE363CBC0672CE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">temporomandibular disorders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D3F9EC3FE524E1AB0676C6ABF10ABA0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">joint and nerve pain;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC57D8330A1546889CDCD1DF4EC8565A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trauma, anxiety, depression, mood disorders, and related mental and behavioral health conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB9827BFA8ED4480B57F1A71E7826BA7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>cognitive problems and dementia;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43D059AB7E834E9B9395EF8760056C69"><enum>(8)</enum><text>heart disease and other cardiovascular conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D9A5552C2F44427BDBFB4DC3FE3DC1D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>genitourinary conditions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F12B325FBA14551A17E4FCD825F5766"><enum>(10)</enum><text>alopecia;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6FCC0CC3B444D23A0D89399B6897B35"><enum>(11)</enum><text>vision or hearing impairments;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84742A305D684192B2B00EBD43704797"><enum>(12)</enum><text>diabetes, digestive, and metabolic disorders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8FE5644A0294628A25853B377B62C2C"><enum>(13)</enum><text>chronic sleep deficiency, insomnia, and related sleep disorders;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9874CB31368470BB5154C82C3AAE90E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>pelvic floor disorders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28E1DA903F9B4D5BA43B442949234A6C"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">oral health management;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15CE293D0F424FD2AF29ADB76870E983"><enum>(16)</enum><text>co-occurring chronic conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2F0B1E30788489B92288E226F4BF4CD"><enum>(17)</enum><text>co-occurring menopausal transition symptoms and cancer symptoms; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAD2F5D0FD5A42E4A1DA287B5BA7F757"><enum>(18)</enum><text>other menopausal symptoms and related conditions, as the Director of NIH determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H644C0E47CB2349B1873D1C406E057A22"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Translational research</header><text>The Secretary shall expand translational research activities to accelerate translation and implementation of Federal research on perimenopause and menopausal symptoms and facilitate equitable, evidence-based delivery of integrated, collaborative perimenopause, menopause, and postmenopause care and related mid-life women’s health services. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFAC970EEDB784A3FABD8AF2654DF6965"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Outreach and engagement</header><text>The Secretary shall expand outreach and engagement activities with accredited schools of medicine, institutions of higher education, and research institutions to support Federal research activities with respect to menopausal symptoms.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H5F2E4BAEE1EB49EE922B152101EA5E11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public health research and data reporting activities</header><text>Part A of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2F57CE853D742FD9CF427395ECC4545"> 
<section id="HEAE82E7DD9B444C1A70E2AC8D8845470"><enum>310C.</enum><header>Research relating to mid-life women's health</header> 
<subsection id="H28F07CB5A29D42A99690E935A23DEF79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public health research</header><text>The Secretary shall expand research activities with respect to the severity and duration of perimenopausal, menopausal, and postmenopausal symptoms and related chronic conditions affecting mid-life health outcomes among women, including mental and behavioral health outcomes. In carrying out activities under this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with existing programs and activities of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5AFD5DA363584F979ED7486EFC5D474E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Health care quality research</header><text>The Secretary shall expand research, program evaluation, quality improvement and implementation activities to improve health care delivery for the care, treatment, or management of perimenopause and menopausal symptoms and related chronic conditions, including data collection with respect to preventive services that support mid-life health outcomes among women and address barriers to care and the development and testing of evidence-based integrated, collaborative approaches to care during the menopausal transition.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBB4BC6A609604378825A737C9DB798FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dashboard</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and maintain a dashboard for the reporting of data on menopausal symptoms and mid-life health outcomes among women gathered through public health surveillance activities and the testing of integrated, collaborative approaches to care with respect to screening, testing, treatment, and prevention services, and the impact of this section and section 404P on such efforts.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H982A78AC4AAD4B1CB726A35B184BF981"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Occupational health research</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct research activities and expand data collection with respect to workplace stressors related to severe acute or chronic menopausal symptoms, physical injury, or other adverse health outcomes among women, including traumatic stress, anxiety, depression, and related mental and behavioral health conditions. The Secretary shall review existing evidence, identify gaps in services, and develop evidence-informed recommendations for related public health interventions and support services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE6A13BF3A48B49059239760095C33206"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement new interagency research initiatives or programs to address menopausal symptoms.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HF90B86770AEA4CF5BB76585474F15860"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out sections 404P and 310C of the Public Health Service Act, as added by subsections (a) and (b), respectively, there are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031. </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8CB4012DC188400396A6D27DC81E5A1F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public health promotion and prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB97101EDB07D44AFAB9E816618765EEB"> <part id="H657DBEA368E94E158952013EE0232CB6" style="OLC"><enum>X</enum><header>Activities to promote mid-life women's health</header> <section id="H2D756822493846B8AB7138147DA1E552"><enum>399PP.</enum><header>Public health promotion activities</header> <subsection id="HC3268896D37F42CBA834F288AEB1BD62"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Chronic conditions and public health promotion</header><text>The Secretary shall expand public health promotion and prevention activities with respect to perimenopausal, menopausal, and postmenopausal mid-life women’s health symptoms and chronic conditions described in section 404P(c), and other related conditions and adverse health outcomes, at the discretion of the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF136B24DAE8D4AD388ACF8103D45BA8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Early detection, diagnosis, and treatment</header> 
<paragraph id="H67579CB057FF4309BE7CCFC043D361FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to improve the early detection, diagnosis, and treatment of perimenopausal, menopausal, and postmenopausal symptoms and support public health activities to expand access to quality care services and improve mid-life health outcomes among women.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6123BA9F764413994E7EC50DDDBABB1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), an entity shall―</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA10C55C3A40C44B5BC45512F704067AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4D09E8A10C6488EAC437FFA43DDC7C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State, local, Tribal, or territorial public health department;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EAE30B188E2473B9FC6B1DF4F78F51D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accredited entity that offers education to students in various health professions; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF8736CC751648BBBBBF57CD3194BAC1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other type of entity, as the Secretary determines appropriate; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93CDAF471E51431E83D0538B2AEF78FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H43A39FAE783A4FEBBE4EFEE093664868"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Care coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b)(2) to support care coordination and care planning activities, including such activities otherwise supported under this Act, and expand access to quality primary care and specialty care services to improve symptoms and chronic conditions described in section 404P(c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14038A3585E64356A42CA986DBFF2EB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mental health and substance use prevention</header><text>The Secretary shall develop recommendations and best practices to—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H09ABED9595214773BF07AE8646692DFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase access to mental and behavioral health care services and substance use disorder prevention services for women experiencing perimenopause or menopausal symptoms; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD6D98C59459C47CE83404BE562CE91C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand substance use disorder treatment, recovery, and support services for women experiencing perimenopause, early menopause, menopause, and postmenopause, and related symptoms and chronic conditions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA6408989350A430FA1D1CA0A7D0633BD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Health care delivery</header><text>The Secretary shall develop recommendations and best practices for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2C934986D1BF4161AC0FA370CE3D3920"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reducing health disparities in the management of perimenopausal and menopausal symptoms and conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F7C3F136CA24F9883F8B8990CEB36C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the prevention of adverse health outcomes in the mid-life and menopausal transition;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE1F3001B56F48489675F689166AE2B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improving mid-life women’s access to perimenopause and menopause health care services through integrated, collaborative approaches to care; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H589CF804C10E48008629C8741094E64E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing patient-centered perimenopause, mid-life, and menopause counseling and treatment through pharmacological and non-pharmacological treatments.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H65E45909CAC442E086243FD16AF6649E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Safety and effectiveness</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out and support—</text> <paragraph id="HE1A01C3D87914F99A0DC10E3C357ED7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>outreach and engagement activities of the Department of Health and Human Services with health care providers on perimenopause and menopause and mid-life women’s health;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H825C3B320D5042699B2A246346757E26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oversight efforts to assess the safety and effectiveness of new treatments and diagnostic tools for mid-life, perimenopause, or menopausal symptoms, including devices that use artificial intelligence; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE330BE28C5E24932B9818DC8DBEED1E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support existing activities of the Department of Health and Human Services to enforce privacy protections for patients.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H4B569F6832794649B2747FEA4024FAA8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HD2E698F58FF54CD7B75DE630234F1E64"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public health awareness, education, and outreach program on menopause and mid-life women’s health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part X of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>), as added by section 3, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CE4CB3F35914753BA6EA23D1383E9E2"> 
<section id="H1766CACE149D476BBD31825372A7E367"><enum>399PP–1.</enum><header>Public health awareness, education, and outreach program on menopause and mid-life women’s health</header> 
<subsection id="HCAD521471F034C9E922C3DAB04CE7B7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and carry out a national awareness, education, and outreach program relating to menopausal symptoms, mid-life women’s health, and related care, treatment, and preventive services directed at patients, health care providers, first responders (such as emergency medical service providers), and related stakeholders. Such awareness, education, and outreach program shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF17C4D2D1CDF49178729594DE2632BEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>disseminate educational materials and provide technical assistance for health care providers and patients to support engagement about perimenopause and menopause care and treatment options for menopausal symptoms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE545D2E6BB64E2BB3E88E1F0F0F568F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>help such providers to identify risk factors and prevent injury and adverse health outcomes among mid-life women with menopausal symptoms; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6AAF4C9ADF64BF68518A407BA143B15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>address barriers to related care and treatment services for mid-life women.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9597C6AB6A2B4383889E5F6BFADC81AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H25A0E7E079DF4709B4CCC355568F2867"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct outreach and education activities related to perimenopause and menopause and mid-life women’s health that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5DED148D013A4AC385F6DAC76D2F8E0D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include evidence-based information; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3116878D01184EB296DEE8AE5A8F29A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are culturally appropriate, in the case of such outreach and education activities for Indian Tribes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14A07D19B9964EB2A9523C5B329EB94A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide opportunities for State, local, Tribal, and territorial public health departments to customize public health awareness, education, and outreach materials for their populations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E48AE95881244F58979B109E48266A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prioritize populations in areas affected by known health disparities and barriers to care, including rural and underserved areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC041556E054F40BE8E254833901C12F9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with existing awareness, education, and outreach programs and activities of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H50356BDDAC6A4BAD9C19BD14933B12B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Online resources</header><text>The Secretary shall develop, operate, and maintain a website to provide educational materials in accessible formats for health care providers, patients, and caregivers, regarding perimenopause, menopause, post-menopause, and mid-life women’s health. Such educational materials may include—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H7952D8B04C4B437796B4A2E1E808BE5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>webinars, continuing education modules, videos, fact sheets, infographics, stakeholder toolkits, or other materials in formats as appropriate and applicable; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H1138055127F744D7B3D41010E345D66B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>tailored for health care providers, patients, caregivers, and other audiences, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H5DD5589CC416450F906BAD4F6CBD0E31"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HBC6D3549692E4E03BEEC035EC8F1727E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Training programs to improve care and treatment of menopausal symptoms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294">42 U.S.C. 294 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 757 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294f">42 U.S.C. 294f</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H24E3F476402241F1B92B1647A917249C"> 
<section id="H22E2A06CE184435A806B6A1B9B96B237"><enum>758.</enum><header>Training programs to improve care and treatment of menopausal symptoms</header> 
<subsection id="H8607FF528B054EBF802A245F55D82C8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants To train health professionals</header> 
<paragraph id="H0F1969AE9F7246D59D05B183233AEEB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities for the purpose described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A276C78581040A69CBEE8286BE8F8BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be used to develop, establish, or expand training programs (including accredited residency programs, fellowships, or other related clinical training) for physicians, dentists, registered nurses, advanced practice registered nurses, physician assistants, pharmacists, other health care providers, and students and trainees to improve care, treatment, or management services for perimenopause, menopausal symptoms, and related chronic conditions affecting women in mid-life.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22A34510B0324C2D9093F2AC786551C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an entity shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA9F7EA9A3A09431CBB5B945A096434AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be—</text> 
<clause id="HA07105F49EF44523B86A6BB309BD8051"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an accredited school of medicine or osteopathic medicine;</text></clause> <clause id="HA1073755477C460E878066DE0A01FF66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an accredited school of dental medicine;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3440B62EEEB6417CB5A8AC591F8D685F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an accredited school of nursing;</text></clause> <clause id="H7B53C1D09018447F9559BAA0E1E240BB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an accredited school of pharmacy;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA295ABD1227949E89C26A208B506C4CF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an accredited public or nonprofit private hospital;</text></clause> <clause id="H2C513FC0AF604960A1E6856C2D1F4B1A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>an accredited medical or dental residency program;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5AE495E122C3401489456E2B119A9E51"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>an accredited advanced practice registered nurse residency program; or</text></clause> <clause id="H161AA4D9E59B4851BB63E4A4FAC6A06B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a related training program for clinicians, allied health professionals, or social workers that interface with affected populations, which may include hospitals and research institutions, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC0B1069C76C43C9B75D62392526C869"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDB6E83A9FF074C8B8B46FE59D6EBBD82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training opportunities</header><text>The Secretary shall expand outreach activities to support and expand training programs, fellowships, and other opportunities for students, faculty, and trainees (including continuing medical education) or establish new training opportunities to address barriers to access to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1E46BFBD5BD14A23A08832AB7006D419"><enum>(1)</enum><text>primary and specialty care services to support mid-life women’s health; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98923A4F13A34226BB0CF7E628A51BBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>early detection, diagnosis, treatment, and care services for perimenopause, menopausal symptoms, and related chronic conditions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEBA1B93D4D6B4842AAEF3D86EF433820"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with existing awareness, education, and outreach programs and activities of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26BFD767592A41BEB9D7B740C1C19814"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H86567CCBE75D43FDBF64A20B0F9C803C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Centers of excellence in menopause cause and mid-life women's health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part X of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 4, is further amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFBC26258E2AC4FBBB5BA4EB286C09BE1"> <section id="H27E0961A0C954F8B93A9E6958A41E6ED"><enum>399PP–2.</enum><header>Centers of excellence in menopause care and mid-life women’s health</header> <subsection id="H8B39837A968F4ACB94F619A9F6A1AB23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall designate eligible entities as Centers of Excellence in Menopause and Mid-Life Women’s Health, and award grants to such entities, for purposes of improving professional training resources for health care providers on mid-life women’s health with respect to the care, treatment, and management of perimenopause and menopausal symptoms, and related support services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H79B8E52E4E774BC38190906578264293"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a designation and grant under subsection (a), an entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="H9AEB7C2BE94E47FB98343A0BB8B50D23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be an accredited entity that offers education to students in various health professions, or such other type of entity, as the Secretary determines appropriate; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6ED5D888C7B457695B5FD38F5B139D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrate community engagement and partnerships with community stakeholders, including entities that train health care providers, social workers, or other health professionals, community health centers, health systems administrators, certified behavioral health clinics, and research institutions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86BCB76A42B4443D9040FCE0D063FC38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HED303D847FBD4308BFFDDA08C50DD7E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>An entity receiving an award under subsection (a) shall develop and distribute evidence-based resources to health care providers, patients, and public health departments regarding the care, treatment, and management of perimenopause and menopausal symptoms during mid-life. Such resources may include information on—</text> <paragraph id="H39DC8BB0F7F64769B35C716F7B3FC0D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advancements in the evidence-based treatment or management of perimenopause and acute or chronic menopausal symptoms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDA7DCE5F4354C64974A0CBA763DD736"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the prevention and treatment of related chronic conditions across different patient populations to support mid-life women’s health; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F13B4212D60411EAE13B2E7AFA2FEDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other topic areas that are relevant to the objectives described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H67175A1795D5479E823DF0EB9128A313"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall take into account regional differences among eligible entities and ensure equitable geographic distribution between rural and urban areas.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05393642E63A45B2A939704D1E5AD30E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall prioritize eligible entities that provide services in a health professional shortage area designated under section 332 or to medically underserved populations, as defined in section 330(b)(3). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCCE2541E63C64F47A39C822F7783F693"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Each entity receiving an award under subsection (a) shall submit an annual report to the Secretary on the activities carried out using such award. The Secretary shall evaluate each project carried out by an entity receiving an award under this section and shall report the findings with respect to each such evaluation to appropriate Federal agencies and public and private entities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF53A14CFEC3B4714B70FACFDBC7F6F09"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HDE0E0275D4F04587BDD07520D0D58331"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header> 
<subsection id="H38F8AA0F431F4F78ABCAEFD1CA15B0AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on activities carried out under this Act</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the Committee on Finance, and the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a report describing the progress of activities carried out under this Act and the amendments made by this Act. Each such report shall contain—</text> <paragraph id="HFB06AF46EF97448E91855C4236475DE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information with respect to Federal research activities related to perimenopause and menopause and mid-life women’s health, including information related public health awareness, education, and outreach activities, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF751DD2A283C42908DD8BD61655B3022"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data and knowledge gaps, or other barriers, related to research, diagnostic testing, and pharmacological and non-pharmacological treatments with respect to perimenopause, menopause, menopausal symptoms, and related health conditions and outcomes in women’s mid-life;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF87862CCA6FE4BC8A54B536754EF7BA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>data or information related to barriers to health care and support services among women experiencing perimenopause or menopausal symptoms and conditions and outcomes in rural and underserved areas; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H021DFB21E87C4E2E9440D69344DBA4CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data or information related to barriers to training opportunities and resources for health care providers serving women experiencing perimenopause or menopausal symptoms and related conditions and outcomes in rural and underserved areas;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB2F50551CEB4742936D4691687227D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations and best practices for health care providers and public health departments to expand access to integrated, collaborative approaches to care and increase public awareness and understanding of menopausal symptoms and related chronic conditions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CC4E62B5AC04C3481DC9E9F1BFE52AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information about related Federal activities, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCAE10AD974F64A3D832F9B895035EB83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on access to care and treatment</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall release a report on known health disparities, barriers to access to care, and management and treatment services, with respect to perimenopause and menopausal symptoms and related conditions, and recommendations to reduce any such disparities and barriers for women in mid-life.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE468143D49FF4E16B7189835FC1074CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6C217DC1DA42454AAC74590ABE74E2F4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall coordinate activities carried out under this Act (including the amendments made by this Act) with other existing Federal efforts relating to menopausal symptoms, mid-life women’s health, aging, or public health promotion carried out by the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate. </text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

