<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H33DC17B788D040598AF7801E8105D861" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9679 IH: Recovery, Enforcement, and Damages to Assure Confidential Treatment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9679</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide a private cause of action for exposure of personally identifiable information of victims or victims’ personal or medical files or similar files the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy in releasing documents under the Epstein Files Transparency Act.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H6829C0CF8C31446DBE3C99CF3D228D8A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0E3737B2C0034AC5AAD1D55469189617" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recovery, Enforcement, and Damages to Assure Confidential Treatment Act</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>REDACT Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H4695E33446E84A1FAE814651C0426B7C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Private cause of action for exposure of personally identifiable information of victims or victims’ personal or medical files or similar files the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy in releasing documents under the Epstein Files Transparency Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2 of the Epstein Files Transparency Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/119/38">Public Law 119–38</external-xref>; 139 Stat. 656) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF991B0C4EF04553848365094AE50C0C"> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FB7E0DD74CD465B8CB550CFFBB1624A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Private cause of action</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58279A02ED5A43B3AD0D6D7D2D2F7599"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H3F1BCAD575A54943843CEFBA5612C49E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Instance</header><text>The term <term>instance</term>, with respect to a violation of this section, means each discrete act constituting a violation of this section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C73C3E793204464965B74117C2CB484"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Violation of this section</header><text>The term <term>violation of this section</term> means a failure, in releasing documents under this Act, to withhold or redact personally identifiable information of a victim or a personal or medical file of a victim or another similar file of a victim the disclosure of which would constitute a clearly unwarranted invasion of personal privacy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2DE7589803949CD980784E5B9B4D7B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>Any person aggrieved by a violation of this section may bring a civil action against the United States if the violation of this section was committed by an officer, employee, or agent of the United States or of any Federal department or agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B82272E2BB24D6C9FAB603E524DDDD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relief</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF59C645A9BFA432E92124491925EA0BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a person prevails on a claim under this subsection, the court shall award—</text> <clause id="H4F6D206DCA1A41E9B5A3476B183D78B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each instance of a violation of this section, the greater of statutory damages of $50,000 or the amount of compensatory damages, including damages for pain and suffering and emotional distress;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8A04FF72274A48D3B602A407C2DDE5C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonable attorney's fees and costs of litigation; and</text></clause> <clause id="HA6C51AB32D9946D2874F824EF7D0DD49"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such injunctive or declaratory relief as may be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H349B02F0C3634F619878A23B0C224AAD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preliminary relief</header><text>Upon motion by a person bringing a claim under this subsection, a court may award such preliminary injunctive relief as the court determines appropriate with respect to the claim.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8469BA5F577448D9B400466CB909693A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver of sovereign immunity</header><text>The United States expressly waives sovereign immunity with respect to actions brought under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3696868CFFC94B6193F96EE2C9F7C638"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Period of limitations</header><text>A civil action under this subsection may not be commenced later than— </text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07CFEC5357214D688AE374AFFD60BE79"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5 years after the applicable person first obtains actual notice of the violation of this section; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAD093C6BF5444A3D99F8630999BF8C04"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a violation of this section with respect to which the applicable person first obtained actual notice of the violation of this section before the date of enactment of this subsection, 5 years after such date of enactment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54217B536EEE4F318448B5716C29150D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This subsection shall apply to any violation of this section occurring on or after November 19, 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


