<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H12AAA34AE9CC4A4C8E9D42C94EBA715D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8097 IH: Home Team Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8097</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To keep professional sports franchises in their home communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5CCDF8363712426FBFA961E93FF53010" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HF796DA661A1A4DDB99D7F4541B7396E0"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Home Team Act of 2026</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H9E0B4FC2DA02426EBC275C108DD27DFD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H054B28719E0F4A05BFDF964E4A6C8673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Professional sports franchises have a significant economic and cultural impact on their local communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F06C04EA6F24E6BAA12EC8CA1B46EEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The relocation of a professional sports franchise abandons the home community and fan base of the franchise that is largely responsible for the growth and development of the franchise.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF59704A64EF43D5B1C0AE699B7E9AC9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of public funds, through a negotiated relocation or threat to relocate of a professional sports franchise, to pay for new sports stadiums have a substantial and detrimental effect on State and local governments and their taxpayers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50221152DC224C34BD575E4162828EDB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The building of a stadium to secure a franchise in their new community may displace local residents with little consideration to their needs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E0EDB6DF0AE48C1AB05B428B1799879"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Article I, section 8, clause 3 of the Constitution of the United States grants Congress the power to regulate interstate commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1817F6DD034046D4991C633FCB69325F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Professional sports franchises have a substantial and direct effect upon interstate commerce because—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1AED8346D7D64FAAA933D68C580E7318"><enum>(A)</enum><text>professional sports games are broadcast on television and streamed around the country and across the world;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31F92B48409842A6AC845D39BC565353"><enum>(B)</enum><text>visiting teams and fan bases travel from State to State to compete in or watch games, purchasing tickets for travel, lodging, food, and other items; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C59959F8E8A40CB99C7EC5795F07AF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>American professional sports leagues, recognizing the interstate nature of the revenues generated by the professional sports business, have agreed to revenue sharing models, whereby the revenue generated from a local game is shared amongst all the sports franchises in the league across States and for Canadian sports franchises as well.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H6EF67F56443641109470F1FD62AA94F8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on community ownership bans and opportunity to purchase</header> <subsection id="HCB81BDF47F194909992ADE599115FE73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A league, operating in or affecting interstate commerce, may not, as part of league requirements or agreements—</text>
<paragraph id="H94054B8FF462492CA5DA8EE803E629BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibit ownership of a franchise by a government entity or members of the general public; or </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2123D5CB906F493EA940F0805F1B4BFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit the transfer of a franchise to a government entity or members of the general public.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H60BEFEE8BDD949DD925066962CD51FCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Opportunity to purchase</header> 
<paragraph id="H3A453BBCE8014DBBBD3054FB5A5C63C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3), a franchise owner may not move the franchise from their home community, across State lines, or eliminate the franchise unless the franchise owner offers an entity specified in paragraph (2) a fair opportunity to purchase such franchise. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7BEC125244B44E69B5173519BC06E62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>A fair opportunity to purchase a franchise pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be provided, in descending priority, to the following entities: </text> 
<subparagraph id="HC0CB76ECFD0B45AB965A9A638FBEF885"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local government entity or a home community cooperative.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08F683A53B64460BA084967C5E9A72D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization that operates in the community or a public-private partnership composed of a local government entity or State government entity with a home community cooperative or nonprofit organization headquartered in such unit of local government or State.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBFA6DF3BE76C44C5B357CC5D252ACC15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A private person, private consortium, or company that resides in the community or operates in the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H161C0D5F702D4A6EB3F16D2E428326EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fair opportunity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, a franchise owner shall—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2262F5412AA48FCBC7035D76A372D71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide proper notice regarding the proposed new location of the franchise or proposed franchise elimination;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB977B1CF9D464E59912A56BBA53B2CF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offer the franchise for purchase for fair market value; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC2D75E32DA34331A1E84CF094DFACB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accept an offer made by an entity described under paragraph (2) if that offer is the amount that is a fair price as determined under subsection (c) or more than that amount. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFAF6F554CA694E76AD767DD1EC337B57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appraisers</header> <paragraph id="HB1FA05D1076747CEA89395053BA97B87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appraisers</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a team of professionally trained appraisers to evaluate a fair price for a franchise.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H910C1D56E1CC47CB870D5CF57210629B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The evaluation of a fair price undertaken pursuant to paragraph (1) shall deduct from the appraisal amount the total amount of any government payment, credit, or subsidy provided for the construction of any stadium where the franchise played the majority of their home games.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H84491DDABB4843E0BE4C70C32EB5BF2D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HF06DFB46CB644897BA4146C656C67353"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalty</header><text>The Attorney General shall assess against a franchise owner in violation of this section a fine of $30,000 for each day the owner is in violation of this section. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H8AEF15A6B9C24176B4C5A44B2A2449DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A unit of local government or a State may bring a civil action for violation of this section in an appropriate district court against a franchise owner for injunctive and monetary relief. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B54C3F50DBE4AD7B538567142EEC2BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header> <paragraph id="HBC2442D18CFD44E6A0B29033DC3677AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt, diminish, or interfere with the right of employees to collectively bargain over terms and conditions of employment. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67AF70901A26467487EC19235ED99D75"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Existing agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to preempt, diminish, or interfere with a collective bargaining agreement that is in place on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H70D1BBA056EE43228A76239562540E20"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF97F1FDE078C40BBB5ECDC6CAF454F2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community</header><text>The term <term>community</term>, with respect to a franchise, means the metropolitan statistical area, as determined by the Office of Management and Budget, in which the franchise plays the greatest number of regular season home games within its league.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54C9248F1AEC40E385AD7E5FB19FA931"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consortium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>consortium</term> means a group of private investors created specifically for a particular transaction of acquiring a sports franchise.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E39EC27132E4670BABCF7F45DB20820"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Franchise</header><text>The term <term>franchise</term> means a member professional sports team of a league.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DE1DC2C31294C3C8CE1CCFCAC006605"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Franchise owner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>franchise owner</term> means a person who owns a franchise.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H961D7011B0D64DE7983E9386F8EC67E9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Home community cooperative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>home community cooperative</term>, with respect to a franchise, means an autonomous association of persons united voluntarily to meet their common economic, social, and cultural needs and aspirations through a jointly owned and democratically controlled enterprise that is based in the community in which the franchise plays the greatest number of regular season home games within its league.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2D2850BE28B4B129AF14053A174B826"><enum>(6)</enum><header>League</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>league</term> includes the National Football League, the National Basketball Association, Major League Baseball, the National Hockey League, Major League Soccer, the Women's National Basketball Association, and the National Women’s Soccer League.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD46E3C0034AF417996F2E3AF2EF99B49"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Local government entity</header><text>The term <term>local government entity</term>, with respect to a franchise, means any unit of local government with jurisdiction over land use decisions in the location in which the franchise plays the greatest number of regular season home games within its league.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45B8BD7E6F694BBC873511DD9F83BFE4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means any organization registered as a public charity by the Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF37BC19EF05042AC9B6E03C18B35A532"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Private company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>private company</term> means a business entity the securities of which do not trade on public markets.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D96F86E5A3E4F069B0B149CE2E9B452"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Proper notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>proper notice</term>, with respect to proposed relocation or elimination of a franchise, means notice that is provided not later than one year prior to the commencement of the season in which the franchise is to play home games in the proposed new location or the date of franchise elimination to all interested parties, the news media, and on all social media platforms of the franchise, and includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5E48F1017B144064BB6362C17D8FAE5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identification of the proposed new home location, if applicable;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFB139357E1D4891AA5E3372F2B2BA02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the reasons for the proposed relocation or franchise elimination; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC373B7A7AB9B44A09F2AB40070366B8F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date on which the proposed relocation or franchise elimination would be effective.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBFB96AEF74F450695CA337298CC9BDA"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Social media platform</header><text>The term <term>social media platform</term> means a website or internet medium that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H55936DCD0F9E461D93DBF7FF2D8B46DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>permits a person to become a registered user, establish an account, or create a profile for the purpose of allowing users to create, share, and view user-generated content through such an account or profile;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H703D49C7BCA445CF8B810B26596BE56C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enables one or more users to generate content that can be viewed by other users of the website or medium; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H300AD288FC3049DEA51B6F661C362985"><enum>(C)</enum><text>primarily serves as a medium for users to interact with content generated by other users of the website or medium. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

