<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAA610C074E3943EA81EDDF4FDC36BDE4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1235 IH: Recognizing the 51st anniversary of Black April and the Fall of Saigon on April 30, 1975.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1235</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 51st anniversary of Black April and the Fall of Saigon on April 30, 1975.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, since 1975, hundreds of thousands of Vietnamese fled the Vietnamese communist regime, resettled in the United States, and built vibrant communities across the United States which contribute to the rich diversity of the Nation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on April 30, 1975, the Republic of Vietnam was overthrown by Communist forces in an event known as the <quote>Fall of Saigon</quote>;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, every year on April 30, Vietnamese-American communities across the United States observe <quote>Black April</quote> as a solemn day of remembrance;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas <quote>Black April</quote> is known as <quote>Tháng Tư Đen</quote> in the Vietnamese language;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Fall of Saigon led to the forced displacement of millions of Vietnamese who sought refuge across the world;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 1975, Congress passed the Indochina Migration and Refugee Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/23">Public Law 94–23</external-xref>), allocating roughly $455,000,000 to facilitate the evacuation and resettlement of refugees from South Vietnam fleeing political persecution, oppression, and economic hardship;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas members of the South Vietnamese military fought side by side with the United States Armed Forces and troops from other allied nations in defense of the ideals of democracy, freedom, and human dignity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the evacuation of thousands of Vietnamese and Americans during Operation Frequent Wind stands as one of the most significant humanitarian efforts in modern United States military history;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States carried out multiple subsequent aerial evacuation missions, including Operation Babylift, Operation New Life, and Operation New Arrivals, which collectively evacuated tens of thousands of Vietnamese refugees to the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the journey of Vietnamese refugees was marked by immense hardship, with many enduring perilous ocean voyages, time in refugee camps, and struggles of cultural adaptation;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Vietnamese Americans persevered to build new lives and contribute to the social, economic, and political fabric of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Vietnamese Americans have continuously advocated for freedom and democracy in Vietnam, and spoken out against human rights abuses by the Vietnamese Government;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Communist Party of Vietnam continues to hold one of the worst records on human rights in the region, violating religious freedom, obstructing freedom of press, restricting its own citizens’ freedom of speech and assembly, and detaining prisoners of conscience;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, the Vietnamese American community numbers over 2,300,000 people, becoming an integral part of American society and excelling in diverse fields such as public service, business, science, education, medicine, and the arts; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the customs of traditions of Vietnamese Americans are celebrated and deeply woven into the fabric of our Nation: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H5842ECAA5EF740778B5179BBC9E14E41"> <section id="H192F5D825AA74BC48BC4BD94139BEA28" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H75F9CF759F494826BD3A53A7649F41E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the significance of the 51st anniversary of Black April and the Fall of Saigon on April 30, 1975;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C6F7F62C8D842D29375C06066D93A89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>honors the contributions of Vietnamese Americans to the United States over the last 51 years and their tireless commitment to upholding freedom, human rights, and democracy in Vietnam;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67DE296849A240B1B88FF1C90B8B7711"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the commitment of the United States to upholding the values of democracy, human rights, and freedom for all people, including in Vietnam where people continue to seek enhanced civil liberties and freedom of press;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EB708FA47B3460E903ADC89D6633008"><enum>(4)</enum><text>honors the service of members of the United States Armed Forces and the Army of the Republic of Vietnam who fought in the Vietnam war, including those who gave their lives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3228F3AD90DF450D9661172304E9420E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>honors the memory of the Vietnamese who lost their lives in search of freedom and democracy while attempting to flee communist Vietnam; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29803E8344134E4A9F2E26097012399F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages all citizens of the United States to solemnly observe Black April and the Fall of Saigon, remember the more than 58,000 United States soldiers and 260,000 Army of the Republic of Vietnam soldiers who served and sacrificed in the name of freedom, and honor the contributions of the Vietnamese American community and the indomitable spirit of the Vietnamese diaspora.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

