<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FRA26017-0VD-9L-X15"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4279 IS: Protecting Proper Life Insurance from Abuse Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4279</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260413">April 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prevent the abuse of life insurance tax rules, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id0a34239913324221b9ae0c98600c356f" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Proper Life Insurance from Abuse Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PPLI Abuse Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id0bc9573be7e34ababf29224afb802383"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tax treatment of private placement contracts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd86451a1756446bba558aa80edff2c85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/79">Chapter 79</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 7702B the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCA14ED1EB83447CBB81FFD9CF4C91DA4"><section id="id0A101809C664427DB4989AF43EF634A9"><enum>7702C.</enum><header>Treatment of applicable private placement contracts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id23d4291730d04802aaf2110c5bc41711"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, an applicable private placement contract shall not be treated as an insurance or annuity contract for purposes of this title.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b59eac4d1d9446f9da89079a33f27d8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable private placement contract</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfaf90561b7a34cecb3fa8600afc7efac"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable private placement contract</term> means any private placement contract if the requirements of subsection (c) are not met with respect to any segregated asset account described in section 817(d) to which amounts received under such contract are allocated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1F1B00B507914DCFA71B94CA57EA950E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private placement contract</header><text>The term <term>private placement contract</term> means any contract—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c734a5cf0c64e11a3c08f8f6fdf32c5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which, without regard to this section, would be treated for purposes of this title as—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd5eb09d906a428b9c4b79b11bea3519"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a life insurance contract under section 7702 or an annuity contract under section 72, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9299e83f7c74a639913dd35217430fb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a variable contract (within the meaning of section 817(d)), and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA16D2400991E43C799237675CA72AF18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which the holder of the contract is required, for purposes of obtaining a registration exemption under securities laws as in effect on the date of enactment of this section (including the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Investment Advisors Act of 1940), to make a representation that such holder—</text><clause id="idED9983B1FD0B4C3E8DBA0678038A8C59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has a specified minimum amount of income or assets,</text></clause><clause id="idE602EBFACEAA4921B44AA3BC6CFA0E68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has completed a specified minimum level of education, or</text></clause><clause id="id127BF6A353CD4C0C817B002C77F42E92"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>holds a specific license or credential.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16010923c7b1402fac44125c54eb34a3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules for foreign issued contracts</header><text>In the case of a contract issued outside of the United States which is directly or indirectly held by a United States person, if, without regard to this section—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7c16f7a768164b1c8665dff9eed24b3e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such contract is a life insurance or annuity contract under the laws under which it is issued (or, unless otherwise provided under regulations, would be such a contract if issued in the United States), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id870f5f480df9473b8f956e10be83086d"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc172c2dafcf44d53a0a5c2277d6ed259"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an annuity contract, or a contract providing insurance on retired lives (as described in section 807(c)(6)), the amounts paid into or out of such contract reflect the investment return and the market value of 1 or more assets (other than assets in the general accounts of the issuer or reinsurer), or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd122b21751c4a60979bb62c160b7ad6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a life insurance contract, the amount of the death benefit (or the period of coverage) is adjusted on the basis of the investment return and the market value of 1 or more assets described in clause (i),</text></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">such contract shall (without regard to whether or not the requirements of subsection (c) are met with respect to such contract) be treated as an applicable private placement contract for purposes of this section (and, for such purposes, the assets described in subparagraph (B) with respect to such contract shall be treated as a segregated asset account with respect to such contract).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24a00d7ab8cc44db9a3a921b1aea21a8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Permanent treatment</header><text>A contract, once treated as an applicable private placement contract under this section, shall be so treated for all subsequent periods without regard to whether it continues to meet the requirements to be so treated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2b3e496f41b4f87aba235b26629f50a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations for assets in segregated asset account</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9d51e866d5a4b5ca19bdf7248c667aa"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements of this subsection are met with respect to a segregated asset account only if—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf9be90f205d468981eeaee28302a25e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the assets in such account support at least 25 private placement contracts, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfc0a9b05afc04f4f880610c257bdd5eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of each of the contracts supported by such account—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6fce629d1e6f4a83a73cdd2c9b3eb3be"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the value of such contract is supported by each of the assets in such account (and not by any asset not in such account), and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7978d61b5344e0dab4e95f1bff4c74f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the proportion of each such asset supporting such contract is the same as the proportion of each other such asset supporting such contract.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcab845b2a1af48afb7d38e1a83e68646"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregation of contracts held by persons</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaffdd53ba8fe432b8480bd13d0fbc337"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All private placement contracts held directly or indirectly by the same person, or a related person to such person, shall be treated as 1 private placement contract.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc7d2653ccd7c4a588ad1daa83f892646"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Related person</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id70bddebd0cbc4d7099805c4ab11de88b"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person shall be treated as related to another person if they bear a relationship to such other person described in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id59c35dd574c04917bafe47eeff749053"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Members of family</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), sections 267(b) and 707(b)(1) shall be applied as if section 267(c)(4) provided that the family of an individual consists of a husband and wife and members of a family described in section 1361(c)(1)(B), except that the applicable date for purposes of clause (ii) thereof shall be the date the segregated asset account is established.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06f4e02bc802412f998e6be2ed571b8f"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Members under common control</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), a rule similar to section 108(e)(4)(C) shall apply.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6967cac0639f4d74ac8806940463ded5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of holders of contracts</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3252a9c23c97497e9418af8e3057a9ef"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ownership of assets and income</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2f78f8e979ea49c6a4c38f1242173049"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>In the case of an applicable private placement contract, the holder of such contract shall be treated as if the holder—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3db6a839544249f89b55af50988f6f6a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>held its share of the assets in the segregated asset account supporting such contract, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31ea0a8132164aa9bc45673cce6dca6b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>received or accrued directly its share of any amount of net income, net loss, or credit earned or accrued with respect to such assets (without regard to whether any amount is actually distributed).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0397b7a74cac47849cc1d456cd089f1c"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Net income or loss</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0733a93eaa7146ee855bdd3d9d17026a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Net income</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>net income</term> means, with respect to any assets supporting a contract—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id044d09c73f6446b492b523f254a8b9aa"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount (if any) by which the aggregate amount of income (including interest, dividends, or gains) with respect to such assets is greater than</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe6860ce900544d5b37767ef4f7e7517"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the deductions allowed under this title which are directly connected with the production of such income.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea1daae91d214645b7ed5ffadd059778"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Net loss</header><text>The term <term>net loss</term> means, with respect to any assets supporting a contract, the amount (if any) by which the amount under clause (i)(II) exceeds the amount under clause(i)(I).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b8b54d519fc40b8b5fbf99be509df49"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Amounts not taken into account</header><text>No deduction shall be taken into account under clause (i)(II) (including for reserves, fees, or mortality charges) which—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id912e029aebf749ecbc72115e62684236"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is taken into account by the insurer or reinsurer of the applicable private placement contract, or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id124bebaf164e40609fcb3eb77cf98fef"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would be so taken into account if such contract were treated as a life insurance or annuity contract.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34b2869a5d3e41e182d9c494e295526f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Taxable year of cessation</header><text>If a life insurance contract or annuity contract ceases to be such a contract by reason of this section in a taxable year after the taxable year in which issued, amounts described in subparagraph (A)(ii) for all preceding taxable years shall be treated as received or accrued during the taxable year in which such cessation occurs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide26ae02e28434606b89d76564d9b60da"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distributions</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e86b8db5edd472188dfecbe18591b8a"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Any excess distribution received by a taxpayer from an applicable private placement contract shall be included by the taxpayer in gross income as ordinary income.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc58ecba79415444f9e32aaefdf36ac3b"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess distribution</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>excess distribution</term> means, with respect to any applicable private placement contract, any applicable distribution to a taxpayer to the extent that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1c15c555a1ba4a278a404b2bb16e138c"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of such applicable distribution, when added to the aggregate amount of applicable distributions made with respect to such contract (whether or not made to such taxpayer) for all periods preceding such applicable distribution, exceeds</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf768cbf551a04baf82804dcea9d9a1df"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the applicable adjusted basis in such contract immediately before such applicable distribution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4406e58010eb42ca8a4a0e9f43712c62"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable adjusted basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable adjusted basis</term> means, with respect to any applicable private placement contract as of the date of any applicable distribution, the sum of the premiums and other amounts paid by any person with respect to such contract as of such date—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2bd462e6e2e44a9d882ddbc08f53a9d7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increased by the aggregate amount of net income includible in gross income under paragraph (1) with respect to such contract (whether or not includible by the taxpayer) for all periods preceding such date, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9d0df2133dd7430abc184d9bfc55cb2c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>decreased by the aggregate amount of deductions for net losses allowable to any person under paragraph (1) with respect to such contract for all periods preceding such date.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1afd9af23f6b4ac5b297a004d1bbd04d"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Applicable distribution</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>applicable distribution</term> means, with respect to any applicable private placement contract, any payment by reason of the death of the insured, any payment in the nature of an annuity payment, any withdrawal, the distribution of any loan proceeds, and any other similar distribution or payment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbea5db890c9b4586818788370015116b"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Assignments, etc</header><text>In the case of the transferee of a transfer for valuable consideration by assignment or otherwise of an applicable private placement contract (or an interest therein)—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68fc897932d942ea87dbe630b5ebe9b7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the premiums and other amounts paid by the transferee with respect to such contract shall be the sum of the actual value of such consideration plus any premiums and other amounts subsequently paid by the transferee, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb898f0c99c6e4e21ae60693a38bb366e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amounts determined under subparagraph (C) with respect to such contract shall only include amounts included in gross income, and deductions of, the transferee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id267ceae9035947aab2499bb9d553eea0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Tax treatment of issuers and reinsurers</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6151fb8f80e844ebbd189aa4269501c9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an issuer or reinsurer of an applicable private placement contract (including a reinsurer with respect to mortality risk for such contract)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id346ea1fa31304d07b4e1d8fa7a15e130"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">premiums and reserves with respect to such contract shall not be treated as life insurance premiums or reserves, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id99c0457bfead4da7aa501d53f73e89f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding section 446(a) or part I of subchapter L of chapter 1—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ab074f4fcad4ca8850a0308afd8fa50"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">premiums, expenses, and fees with respect to such contract which, without regard to this section, would be taken into account in determining life insurance taxable income shall be so taken into account, but</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf60f330c9ff64cedb534646fb57da139"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amounts so taken into account shall be determined under the accrual method of accounting described in section 446(c)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1abec8ffd4e54f15931212e948a88b53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts issued by foreign issuers</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), an applicable private placement contract issued by a foreign insurer or reinsurer and to which section 4371 applies (without regard to this section) shall continue to be treated as a contract to which such section applies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide6fccb69e9594614adbb3d838d3ac371"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations and other guidance as are necessary to carry out this section and section 6050AA, including regulations or other guidance—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf6051eccd144e8284f2bdcd5d08b543"><enum>(1)</enum><text>preventing the avoidance of the application of this section through related parties, accommodation parties, passthrough entities, trusts, or the allocation of assets other than through segregated asset accounts,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id589b726502ae45e4b28574634ee7da55"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing that an asset account or set of assets not meeting the requirements of section 817(d) shall be treated as a segregated asset account meeting such requirements if such account or set of assets achieves substantially the same results as such a segregated asset account or if such treatment is otherwise necessary to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of this section,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7063df3eedfc453995eb5e327da0cd52"><enum>(3)</enum><text>preventing the taking into account of items more than once,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbdd236ac3f08454d8362d8de4c35297d"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing rules for determining whether 1 or more persons are indirect holders of applicable private placement contracts, and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idafe300e84a3b4c75a51dd496f40a27e3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing rules for the application of this section in cases where there is more than 1 holder of an applicable private placement contract or where applicable distributions are made at the same time to 2 or more persons with respect to such a contract.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id02781961b4494b65bb45573cfb776229"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/79">chapter 79</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7702B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF6962C68443440F4A8CEAE842461C883"><toc><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Section 7702C. Treatment of applicable private placement contracts.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id611263efc09441c1bcf2fe3762697be5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9a702622666b4f93aa69c761ac2a5614"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to contracts whether issued before, on, or after such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a5609c87b5e4e8b9ccd5a281384f64e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transition rule</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall not apply to a contract issued on or before the date of the enactment of this Act which (without regard to this paragraph) is an applicable private placement contract under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7702C">section 7702C</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section) if, before the end of the 180-day period beginning on such date of enactment, such contract—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebcc0792b7144a1faad14d601d61a8df"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is exchanged for, or converted to, a life insurance or annuity contract that is not such an applicable private placement contract, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaaf16edb028a417c8be0cd92c3d9fb44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is cancelled or otherwise liquidated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idbd1beac2fbe5410bb1da16aa10b056a9"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="id26C65CE9B5A44008BB3720F121E69CB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6772fcd862de40228f89e3275dd6dcda"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Return requirement</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaae928cb82454d639dc35c0c9dfa911a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart B of part III of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idCCE7B877C1B54C419E3E0EF8A6326346"><section id="idDE9C54BF7F9F48E1B1E4AC6CFFE2E3DE"><enum>6050BB.<?LEXA-Enum 6050BB.?></enum><header>Returns relating to applicable private placement contracts</header><subsection id="id443C4E592649405B8B0A78D67F5B69F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74ae3112a1dd4c919093b2ee610b33e1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every reporting issuer, shall, not later than the applicable date, make a return (in such form as the Secretary may prescribe) with respect to each applicable private placement contract issued or reinsured by the issuer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc616c257589842f08175196a861f7592"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such return shall set forth—</text><subparagraph id="id8B9ADC481CBD4DB7A731CDEAE90BB044"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, address, and TIN of the reporting issuer,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0b6a1c9616b04bb383848a8f6634c53e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name, address, and TIN of the holder of the contract,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcad074dd24624ad6b0a9172e91ca6932"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the applicable adjusted basis (as defined in section 7702C(d)(2)) in the contract of such holder (determined as if an applicable distribution were to be made as of the applicable date),</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b342ae0426f43778f6ee3f8f0be34d6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other contracts which are supported by the segregated asset account supporting such contract,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9216cbac12d24aa5adf5c88faf71ae10"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the name, address, and TIN of the holder of any contract described in subparagraph (D) who is related (within the meaning of section 7702C(c)(2)(B)) to the holder of such contract, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id41239F845850455F9B3560EC84C6849C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id799ac94c761a498fbf4603bec8649618"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable date</header><text>For purposes of this section, the applicable date means, with respect to any applicable private placement contract, 30 days after the later of—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b6f818ff3e443b6a766ecbcc400097b"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79148fbe149d44ac96f4e7cabc49231b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date the contract first became an applicable private placement contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id745802d290a743d08ef32e8375f7f04d"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6c1683719cdb47ff811e241772982f60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Every reporting issuer shall file an annual return with respect to each applicable private placement contract issued or reinsured by the issuer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e5b51482e354d5b99dc5cba34115f1b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Time for filing return</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The return under paragraph (1) shall be filed at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id20d7831c22f9473288316613501dd8c3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information included</header><text>A return filed under paragraph (1) shall set forth—</text><subparagraph id="id7D25E9F1545A429EA741A3996BE68DBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, address, and TIN of the reporting issuer,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idDD0B82211EEF42DD8C71FE333411F145"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name address, and TIN of the holder of the applicable private placement contract,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf636e07059c04a0e9a86f4a644334705"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the name, address, and TIN of each person receiving an applicable distribution (as defined in section 7792C(d)(2)) under the contract if such person is not the holder of the contract,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5d96f696eed4af882c319f0a5bef2ea" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the amounts for the taxable year of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0557d97754345438e1b8e9ac45de297"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">items of income, loss, deduction, and credit for the year with respect to the assets of which the holder is treated as the owner by reason of section 7702C(d)(1),</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f96e25e3f294efead16cfaa5e718317"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of any applicable distribution (as so defined) under the applicable private placement contract and the portion of such distribution which is treated as an excess distribution (as defined in section 7702C(d)(2)),</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47b9f8e9ea904b63b929f71cc391e7aa"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the holder’s applicable adjusted basis (as defined in section 7702C(d)(2)) in the contract as of the date of each applicable distribution made during the reporting period and as of the last day of the reporting period (determined as if an applicable distribution were to be made on such day), and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9640cd2b333e446b8e8a1607c16b0df4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of a reporting issuer described in subsection (d)(1)(B), premiums or other amounts paid or received by any person pursuant to any reinsurance or risk-shifting arrangement described in such subsection, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3CE6E517A41B4739B99232365C15BDCC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id556215dae05443aeba583d298f5b42cb"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Statement To be furnished to taxpayers with respect to whom information is required</header> <paragraph id="idc79681babfce4d70a394827c4110d79b"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>Every person that is required to make a return under subsection (a) or (b) shall furnish to each person whose identity is required to be set forth under subsection (a)(2)(B) or subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (b)(3) a written statement showing—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id9e60e02e9de945d080dcd5f39a9e3d55">
                      <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the name, address, and phone number of the information contact of the person required to make such return, and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id4411b62a240a4a0eb5455877a63df809">
                      <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the information required to be shown on such return with respect to the person to whom such statement is required to be furnished.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                  </paragraph>
                  <paragraph id="idd8eaea31c58b40f1a002494fd4b3359a">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Furnishing of information</header>
 <text>The written statement required under paragraph (1) with respect to any return shall be furnished to the person on or before January 31 of the year following the calendar year for which the return is required to be made.</text>
                  </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbd29ee040ba2470484f43853d34109a2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ac7d713894e4508ab50d3299d492495"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting issuer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>reporting issuer</term> means any person who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7715f99f32ce481387c13dd64ba5fe8d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issues a life insurance contract or annuity contract which is treated as an applicable private placement contract, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb4f5ccccbfa14e0a9e9c012dccf34616"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reinsures, or shifts risks with respect to any portion of, an applicable private placement contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14e04f7a870646f39258ed0aaaee805e"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicable private placement contract</header><text>The term <term>applicable private placement contract</term> has the meaning given such term under section 7702C.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id15c17326e74647bf91dd2ea09bbed54f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id734dcf088dd14a2d8645d3f6d7c3e7c4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Failure to provide initial return</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part I of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/68">chapter 68</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idFB638D6788034C14ADB85EBDB794DDF6"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ef6d4fc29ec428d9168b01f25ebc34e"><enum>6720D.</enum><header>Penalty for failure to report applicable private placement contracts</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffb3224ace3847558afd22918a6a89fe"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Imposition of penalty</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a98bfebe6ce49168c8bf08f4e8495d7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Any person required to make a return under section 6050BB(a) who fails to file such return with the Secretary before the applicable date shall pay a penalty equal to the amount determined under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc5a3661b1753423cb4ca5d87ef226507"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount of penalty</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8fb238b3cac486199c71e3a4ef11047"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the penalty determined under this paragraph is the sum of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebabc9be76b74eab97c51c06949272ce"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,000,000, plus</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbda5d57064be4f599a7ecc879dc489c6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an additional $1,000,000 for each penalty period ending before the date on which the failure described in subsection (a) has been corrected.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id96FFD746CD7047ACB48A680F65E2E219"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalty period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>penalty period</term> means each period of 30 days beginning after the first 30-day period beginning with the applicable date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dd319ba9bb349e0962218a4eaad88e3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>applicable date</term> has the meaning given such term under section 6050BB(a)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1D811597938A4818B54E6756C7F97DEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1820A5B414BA4BEAAB6A72FDB317C13C"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Persons subject to insurance regulation</header><text>In the case of a person—</text><subparagraph id="idF7AF5C84D19D4D448CAFE40A264FBD7D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is regulated by an agency or entity under foreign, State, or local law, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC0F72E483583446F8181C81A60F4E09E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is required to pay a penalty under this section,</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">the requirement to pay such penalty shall be disclosed to such agency or entity. Failure to make a disclosure in accordance with the preceding sentence shall be treated as a failure to which this section applies.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ac03d1c17cb45b08168b75527362684"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Persons subject to Securities Exchange Act of 1932</header><text>In the case of a person—</text><subparagraph id="id8D9B1546A5E44C2EA2D0AC730A9B1482" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is required to file periodic reports under section 13 or 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 or is required to be consolidated with another person for purposes of such reports, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idACF64C4F7B9A4CF6BEE3DB9C56EDD4F8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which is required to pay a penalty under this section,</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph" commented="no">the requirement to pay such penalty shall be disclosed in such reports filed by such person for such periods as the Secretary shall specify. Failure to make a disclosure in accordance with the preceding sentence shall be treated as a failure to which this section applies.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id616bae6ab60c45bbb14f9f894dadaf05"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to make annual returns or payee statements</header><clause id="idE2AF5087160344E1B136F5D18E9FF91A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Returns</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6724">Section 6724(d)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xxviii), by inserting <quote>or</quote> at the end of clause (xxix), and by inserting after clause (xxix) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id28C886D86273488189C383B8CAABC372"><clause id="id20803F6E4C8F49379B37395062AD3525"><enum>(xxx)</enum><text>section 6050BB(b),</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="id385C37F5C9294680ADB6E25205F0889A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Statements</header><text>Section 6724(d)(2) of such Code is amended—</text><subclause id="id5383E4FF7BB3402FB2E0ED409EA73565"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (NN) and (OO) as subparagraphs (OO) and (PP), respectively, and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6F0A4922A3724A3B93FCFD04833903B7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (MM) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7357D8901838447A8C0C568C41F49255"><subitem id="id6A80D82B15CA4EF9B720409791B2B2BA"><enum>(NN)</enum><text>section 6050BB(c).</text></subitem><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id560406e883ea4ba2927ac48ae89175b6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide47d71cb24cb4d35906f9c3df694e6f0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The table of sections for subpart B of part III of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 6050AA the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id132aa32b-8cb1-456d-b879-8e4a72989e9c"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="idDE9C54BF7F9F48E1B1E4AC6CFFE2E3DE">Sec. 6050BB. Returns relating to applicable private placement contracts.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id25b4f9f1d0a24f6e9cae50603134a03e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The table of sections for part I of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/68">chapter 68</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="id2b386336-2c77-4b1d-83fe-4539cba4851d"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="id7ef6d4fc29ec428d9168b01f25ebc34e">Sec. 6720D. Penalty for failure to report applicable private placement contracts.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id172c320312af4bdabdf8bdef64b6e162"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rules relating to foreign account tax compliance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31002fbf2e284f9c859f7c370ac4e72f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Insurance companies treated as financial institutions</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida97707e787cf4c62b15df9f3e23bf0e4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1471">Section 1471(d)(5)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6597D376EDB742BCA2D15FD3670C3621"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2982137395264ee19ca1862aaccaf070"><enum>(D)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, holds itself out as a life insurance company.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9382598224d746988b374215239f369a"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of certain corporations as foreign financial institutions</header><text>Section 1471(d)(4) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(determined without regard to any election made under section 953(d))</quote> after <quote>foreign entity</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide026fb04481c44a3b2d77faec0118d73"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on authority to exclude</header><text>Section 1471(f)(4) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>(other than an entity described in subsection (d)(5)(D))</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id19b60eb72ae7429f94ab46a3c2c912b3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private placement contracts treated as financial accounts</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1471">Section 1471(d)(2)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (C) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3B0844C55C2C41E094EB7999633AFE19"><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1709b61dbcba4f6686d6236814a73a3d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any contract which is described in section 7702C(b)(3) and any separate segregated asset account that holds assets supporting such a contract.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ff0b730c12545589922b376c489f6d2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional limitation on exceptions</header><text>Section 1472(c)(2) of the of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>(other than payments to an entity described in section 1471(d)(5)(D))</quote> before the period at the end.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31351284538f4742857ba2156476157a"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to payments made after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

