<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF52D95507C714A8187DEB9C74692F500" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1325 IH: Expressing support for May 2026 as “American Stroke Month” and encouraging all to learn the warning signs of stroke, understand their personal risk factors, and take action to improve stroke prevention, response, and recovery in our communities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1325</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for May 2026 as <quote>American Stroke Month</quote> and encouraging all to learn the warning signs of stroke, understand their personal risk factors, and take action to improve stroke prevention, response, and recovery in our communities.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas stroke is the fourth-leading cause of death and a leading cause of serious, long-term disability in the United States, and each year approximately 800,000 people in the United States experience a stroke;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas stroke can happen to anyone, at any age, and recognizing stroke warning signs and calling 911 quickly can significantly reduce death and disability from stroke;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the stroke warning signs acronym B.E. F.A.S.T. helps people recognize the symptoms of stroke: Balance loss, Eye or vision changes, Face drooping, Arm weakness, Speech difficulty, and Time to call 911;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas high blood pressure is the leading risk factor for stroke, and managing blood pressure along with healthy every day choices such as eating well, moving more, and not using tobacco or nicotine can significantly reduce stroke risk;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas having a stroke increases the risk of another one, and understanding personal risk factors and working with health care professionals to manage those risks can help prevent future strokes; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, during <quote>American Stroke Month</quote> in May, the American Stroke Association’s Together to End Stroke® initiative, works to educate communities that stroke is largely preventable, treatable and beatable: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H811714B2A55949E6ACB1DECD8FE86DA9"> 
<section id="HC74996970B8E4D22AEC170E7ADA9FC41" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives expresses support for <quote>American Stroke Month</quote> and encourages all to learn the warning signs of stroke, understand their personal risk factors, and take action to improve stroke prevention, response, and recovery in our communities.</text></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

