<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO25867-TX2-2V-W7P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3500 IS: Hydropower Licensing Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3500</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Federal Power Act to require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to annually submit to Congress a report on the status of ongoing hydropower relicensing applications.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H2FFD6A492C144D43BD54E5A14D2333B4"><section section-type="section-one" id="H73CD63B998F6472495C3FB63611299AE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hydropower Licensing Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB38A9B44D6A74025951BBC670FA2589D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual licensing status report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part I of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/792">16 U.S.C. 792 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB4547AB8598E4F71880CC9188E6A4AF6"><section id="H03F0DAAC003042228F765C5D1A8C1940"><enum>37.</enum><header>Annual licensing status report</header><subsection id="H436F303E6A494CD5A2C0299C1A53001A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the status of—</text><paragraph id="HD14C6515ED0E4F05829C8CE3E30BA04C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the licensing process for each new license, and for each subsequent license for which sections 14 and 15 have been waived, for which the existing licensee has notified the Commission under section 15(b)(1) at least 3 years prior to submission of the report that the existing licensee intends to file an application for the new license or subsequent license, but the new license or subsequent license has not yet been issued under section 15; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE2B87C134E6414BB4BD0D6B19D88732"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the licensing process for each original license under section 4(e) for which a citizen, association, corporation, State, Indian Tribe, or municipality has notified the Commission, pursuant to applicable regulations, at least 3 years prior to submission of the report that the citizen, association, corporation, State, Indian Tribe, or municipality intends to file an application for the original license, but the original license has not yet been issued under section 4(e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA62B1AAFD95A4BFCB72A45C04315B9D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to the licensing process for each new license and subsequent license described in that subsection and the licensing process for each original license described in that subsection—</text><paragraph id="HBE9A15BE12544E14A8E7A7B87F968804"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date the notice of intent described in that subsection was provided to the Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1233765112B84AE59F393D188F4BA9C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any docket number assigned with respect to the licensing process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2F0778DC6A04436B853EE1129B0F176"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether any application for the new license, subsequent license, or original license, as applicable, has been filed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H098EE2885D7C4F7784B628052F743B4C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding the status of the application, including the date the Commission anticipates the Commission will issue the original license, subsequent license, or new license, as applicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4906AEB39BCA4807A6832E9F7789351F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date of any upcoming proceeding or other meeting relating to the original license, subsequent license, or new license, as applicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3831AB4730E843F3896F81A3B9A52B0E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any ongoing or completed actions required of the existing licensee, citizen, association, corporation, State, Indian Tribe, municipality, Commission, any fish and wildlife agency referred to in section 15(b)(3), and any other applicable agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AB29F65130B46F6BFE81978DBF3E411"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disaggregation of information by license type</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information included in each report submitted under subsection (a) shall be disaggregated by whether the information relates to a new license, or a subsequent license, issued under section 15 or an original license issued under section 4(e).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

