<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV25M71-8CN-KC-0GS"><form><distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 98</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S348">Mr. Paul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Venezuela that have not been authorized by Congress.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="id18bc6a984ef84ebdb523e2528b8f2fe7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="iddba55de0631249fab7672c7eadb55cf6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8, clause 11 of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide010d67b3f12441e949fdb62c36695ac"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war upon Venezuela or any person or organization within or operating from Venezuela, nor enacted a specific statutory authorization for use of military force within or against Venezuela.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbef10429282d40c6841b9596e0f3d521"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The use of military force by the United States Armed Forces within or against Venezuela constitutes the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities within the meaning of section 4(a) of the War Powers Resolution (50 U.S.C. 1543(a)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a14c2fd4e8d453b84a684423cbee8ce"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (50 U.S.C. 1546a) provides that any joint resolution or bill to require the removal of United States Armed Forces from imminent engagement in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures of section 601(b) of the International Security and Arms Export Control Act of 1976.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id575aa8c60fe545efa5ae29bbad8fc4fe"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of the use of United States forces for hostilities within or against Venezuela</header><subsection id="id4290aa8c424244748a3de362189f97f6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (50 U.S.C. 1546a), and in accordance with the provisions of section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976, Congress hereby directs the President to terminate the use of United States Armed Forces for hostilities within or against Venezuela, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or specific authorization for use of military force.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9d7696beaa584c8aa80fec044da5889f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the United States from defending itself from an armed attack or threat of an imminent armed attack.</text></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution>
