<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HFF5ECB253DF0480CAF821FBEA33967CF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7995 RH: Chafee Opportunities for New Networks and Existing Connection Trust Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 559</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7995</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–642]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as printed in the House of Representatives on March 19, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To update the purposes of the John H. Chafee Foster Care Program for Successful Transition to Adulthood to reflect research and the input of youth with lived experience about the importance of long-term relationships to future success.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HWM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HCAA3FFDECABC4E4DB037EFBC95096A83"><section id="H042CB712DE95443F8A353D8712F93C3C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chafee Opportunities for New Networks and Existing Connection Trust Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CONNECT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF7652AD6DECF4EE68F593D11D763BEDC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Updating the purposes of the John H. Chafee Foster Care Program for Successful Transition to Adulthood</header><subsection id="H818240CD064847F6BD244C02960637C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Updating of purposes</header><paragraph id="H5D17F28CED374B8B850CA0B4FA330A19"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 477(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H2069E44985284D31B6AB0B7A606D40D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89F0A0F471C44542B07EA406628B1820"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (3) through (7) as paragraphs (3) through (8), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H689E707581A046519AFA6D55BBD80003"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>conducted—</quote> the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H68D681BFD0334191A8BED26D7BF288F1" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HWM00"><paragraph id="H85C7E194A5EA431F9E8342EC1AB0A228"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to help children who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older to develop and maintain sustained, supportive relationships with adults (including kin or fictive kin who are not serving as placement), mentors, and peers (including peers who have experienced foster care), with a goal of providing multiple and varied paths to reduce isolation and ensuring that the youth develop lifelong connections and support networks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF4C57143B854BD2A775E602D923B13F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support youth still in foster care who have experienced foster care at age 14 or older in exercising the rights referred to in section 475A to participate in developing their permanency plan and receive written information about available services and steps the agency is taking to support the plan, as well as to facilitate pre- and post-permanency peer support, mentoring, connections with kin, and referrals to additional appropriate programs and services to help youth achieve their permanency goals;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E3C808EFB7442929FAA09641814B18C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H58BAE452C2DC4F1B80A79062009A0237"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act and after consulting with youth with lived experience in foster care, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue guidance to States and Tribal child welfare agencies regarding the purposes set forth in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 477(a) of the Social Security Act, that includes, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="H5A35C453DA0A4E8181BDEFF1125DB7EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examples of services and support eligible for Federal funding under part B of title IV of such Act, under part E of such title as part of completing and following the case plan requirements provided for in section 475A of such Act, or under section 477 of such Act, including individual youth support, family support, and peer support to engage youth during reunification, guardianship, or adoption proceedings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58F3D0D09CAA4471862178EB16F46C7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>best practices for facilitating peer support, mentoring, and the development and maintenance of lifelong connections, including practices that support sibling, tribal, and community connections, including minimum qualifications and training for persons providing mentoring and peer support;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42C63A02E2A7445E905D7B364C5D4C04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>standards of outreach to and notification of eligible youth, including youth with a planned permanent living arrangement, to ensure referrals to appropriate programs and services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B303E33D9C144EAAA857AEDB9AA8833"><enum>(4)</enum><text>protocols for documentation of support and relationship-building activities under section 477 of such Act that are required by section 475A of such Act to be included in a child's case plan, sufficient to permit review under the case review system described in section 475(5) of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

