<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H10024FB5A81C4118BF960E5AAED51051" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6547 RH: Least Cost Exception Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 405</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6547</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–474]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260202">February 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260202">February 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on December 10, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to provide an exception to the least-cost resolution requirement, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H62137241BD57499F92328748E53E56B7"><section id="HFDA9D2F5B25F4740A7FD062517D807DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Least Cost Exception Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0D35BD5C3775482C9405367430A60316"><enum>2.</enum><header>Least cost resolution exception to avoid further concentration among global systemically important banking organizations</header><subsection id="HE957CA9C772E45BC8898750C356E8AAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13(c)(4) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1823">12 U.S.C. 1823(c)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE68031DE35DC44F29ACE39A9255F20F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by inserting <quote>except as provided in subparagraph (I),</quote> before <quote>the total amount</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H412C20DB257E4BEB831229C32CE85BD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)(i), by inserting <quote>and except as provided in subparagraph (I),</quote> after <quote>appropriate,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E1C0618C7EF43E2BE1A5CB4877CA93C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H83FA920CF8C44CFBA47FB7B94410348F" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><subparagraph id="H23AE008235B5447186B45450FBB1C17C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Least cost resolution exception</header><clause id="H0903C07223524126B8EA297EC0CBC897"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an exercise of authority by the Corporation described in subparagraph (A), the Corporation may, at the discretion of the Corporation, select an alternative method of exercising such authority that is not the least costly to the Deposit Insurance Fund, if—</text><subclause id="H5901CB6CFD1548D9AEE5B2B1BD5C9962"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Corporation determines that the selected alternative complies with the requirements of clause (iii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8B678185C4D14DDAA86E00812196DB70"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Corporation and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, after consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, determine that the potential additional risks to the Deposit Insurance Fund of the selected alternative are outweighed by the reasonably expected benefits of limiting further concentration of the United States banking system in global systemically important banking organizations.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H006D1F1DD3F04B40A74F7630684B54B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Maximum cost to the Deposit Insurance Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subparagraph, the Corporation, by rule, shall establish criteria for determining on a case-by-case basis the maximum allowable cost against the net worth of the Deposit Insurance Fund that may be utilized to account for any determination under clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="H3DD33BE85314417C885288978F33802C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Requirements described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements for the selected alternative described in clause (i) are as follows:</text><subclause id="H633CC5663408463CA15733FE0AE73DA0"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The selected alternative is least costly to the Deposit Insurance Fund of all alternatives that do not involve a transaction with a global systemically important banking organization and that do not exceed the cost of liquidating the insured depository institution.</text></subclause><subclause id="HEA816E4385CE45F2A0317F3BD7C61E9B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The difference between the cost of the selected alternative and the cost of a covered alternative is less than the maximum cost to the Deposit Insurance Fund specified pursuant to the rule adopted under clause (ii).</text></subclause><subclause id="H120849408D7D40EB98E34B00DB1505D0"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a selected alternative that involves another person purchasing assets of the insured depository institution or assuming deposit liabilities of the insured depository institution, such person agrees to pay an assessment to the Corporation comprised of payments—</text><item id="H1E56C03A872C4FCF8D7942316E89F142"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made over a period to be determined by the Corporation, but which may not be less than 5 years; and</text></item><item id="H628ABD92CDC7435C9685B47ECC90C26B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in an amount that takes into account, on a case-by-case basis, criteria the Corporation, by rule, shall establish, including a realistic discount rate, the aggregate amount equal to the difference calculated in subclause (II), and any bid inconsistent with the purposes of this Act, with such rule to be established by the Corporation not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subparagraph.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H929733633CF5404F9D50BFB2D9DB5845"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after selecting an alternative described in clause (i), the Corporation shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing an analysis of the economic difference between the cost to the Deposit Insurance Fund of the selected alternative and the cost to the Deposit Insurance Fund of the least costly alternative that would have been selected absent the application of this subparagraph.</text></clause><clause id="H298CAD6B867145EB93FF8D3127C020FA"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Cost determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All cost determinations required under this subparagraph shall be made in accordance with subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text></clause><clause id="H7CBD2A844EDD4BA6BD6455C8DDD40DAC"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph:</text><subclause id="H9D5250DAF2B54C1FA26A31E829574C1B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Covered alternative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered alternative</term> means a method of exercising authority described in subparagraph (A) that is the least costly to the Deposit Insurance Fund of all such methods that involve a sale of all or substantially all assets of the insured depository institution to, and assumption of all or substantially all deposit liabilities of the insured depository institution by, a global systemically important banking organization.</text></subclause><subclause id="H32BEE3B5BFDF46C38D0EC3A63BA7D37E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Global systemically important banking organization</header><text>The term <term>global systemically important banking organization</term> means a global systemically important BHC (as such term is defined in section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor thereto) and any affiliate thereof.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52EC79DFB00C4444B668BE7297F13D84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 13(c)(4)(H) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1823">12 U.S.C. 1823(c)(4)(H)</external-xref>) does not apply to the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>February 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

