<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BOM26286-X9F-MJ-M6T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4567 IS: Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide enhanced student loan relief to educators, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H510C28B31B6F4B4199BC472663F9C7C6"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEABC80EF4ED642D1BE832EFF3AFC50D3"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7ABA10F9E74E4E728DCC976DA60A0F41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loan forgiveness and cancellation for educators</header><subsection id="H9711C797B67D417E81BD0250F5EBA1F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhanced teacher loan forgiveness under the FFEL program</header><text>Section 428J of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-10">20 U.S.C. 1078–10</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE091B8F65D7455D8918E895399894C7"><section id="HC8856303620B45698465C02B87E5EE10"><enum>428J.</enum><header>Loan forgiveness for educators</header><subsection id="H1399C2619EA841DA93D34E966DDCEEC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this section to enhance student access to a well-prepared, diverse, and stable educator workforce by eliminating debt burdens for educators in return for service teaching and leading in high need schools or early childhood education programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9363137F6D2428E9A6970FEB71F9D6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall carry out a program, through the holder of the loan, of assuming, as required under subsection (c), the obligation to repay a covered loan for qualifying educators engaged in qualifying service. A qualifying educator may apply for the program under this section after the Secretary has begun carrying out the program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4116B9A3830F47B3A47468561326BBA1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Forgiveness of covered loans</header><paragraph id="H5F8E66A8B5BB4953B7C1D117E27A7C28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Forgiveness of loans upon completion of qualifying service</header><subparagraph id="HD2B9409005944B2881B823F174685CD0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>For each qualifying educator who has completed 5 years of qualifying service (including any qualifying service, as defined under this section as in effect after the date of implementation of the <short-title>Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</short-title>, that may have been completed or performed before or after such date of implementation, or a combination of qualifying service), the Secretary shall assume the obligation to repay an amount equal to 100 percent of the aggregate of the loan obligations (including interest and fees) on all covered loans that are outstanding as of the date of completion of such fifth year of qualifying service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFBDEB6446A94557926A38F093E5CCEB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The years of qualifying service required under subparagraph (A) may be consecutive or nonconsecutive, and the qualifying educator may elect which years of qualifying service to use for purposes of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B504AA7C78E409AA4D7B95B59B20338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monthly loan forgiveness</header><text>Upon application by any qualifying educator who has a covered loan and who is engaged in qualifying service, and in addition to any loan forgiveness under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with such qualifying educator, under which—</text><subparagraph id="HEC092EC9DDDD49D98525BACF692BB16A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the period of qualifying service (for qualifying service that occurs after the date of implementation of this Act), the Secretary agrees to assume the obligation to repay the minimum monthly obligation on all covered loans of the qualifying educator, based on the repayment plan of the qualifying educator, for—</text><clause id="H414B7A0668E146F987A3BF4710CD1BAA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each month of qualifying service; and</text></clause><clause id="H655E027AB9B34BD09E63C898A99B2B68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any summer or other school or program year calendar breaks scheduled by a high need school or early childhood education program during a school or program year in which the qualifying educator is engaged in qualifying service;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48003419CD6F41658CE7A0DAFB7199A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the period of qualifying service, the assumption of the monthly loan obligation provided will serve as a monthly payment, considered paid in full by the qualifying educator, based on the repayment plan of the qualifying educator; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97A8E01964B04CE08ADB5E52753C3FD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the period of qualifying service, each monthly obligation that is repaid by the Secretary under this paragraph on a covered loan shall be deemed to be a qualifying monthly payment made by the qualifying educator under section 455(m)(1)(A) for purposes of the loan forgiveness program under section 455(m), if applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H451757764DA84A48ABB3D58D7CE7DCA0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and make publicly available an application for qualifying educators who wish to receive loan forgiveness under this subsection. The application shall—</text><subparagraph id="H577AEDB76F2F431299139AF9C488EC4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be available for qualifying educators to file for loan forgiveness under paragraph (1) and for monthly loan forgiveness under paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1F15B851CDC4BD19ADCB01FB18741F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include any certification requirements that the Secretary determines are necessary to verify qualifying service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D4E833A7CED463B8C506967DF5F54C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for the verification of the qualifying service—</text><clause id="H592E8A0FEA24481783542F4B0BB3E68A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an early childhood educator or an elementary or secondary school teacher serving in a high need school, by a school leader or the administrator of a local educational agency, educational service agency, Bureau of Indian Education, Native Hawaiian education system, or State educational agency that serves the school (or the administrator’s designee);</text></clause><clause id="HD3D5B892B32E44EA90DC74DCFD8B0ADD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an early childhood educator serving in an early childhood education program, by the director of that program (or the director’s designee);</text></clause><clause id="HCDF237EAF42D400E8DCA7D9B38A8DC3D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a school leader serving in a high need school, by the administrator of a local educational agency, educational service agency, Bureau of Indian Education, Native Hawaiian education system, or State educational agency that serves the school (or the administrator’s designee);</text></clause><clause id="HAD708D54BEB04A63B52FA220C15695E0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of a director of an early childhood education program, a leader of the entity overseeing the early childhood education program; and</text></clause><clause id="H1ABE2526E48E4D1CA61D361B37C70FD4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in the case of a family child care provider or the director of an early childhood education program that operates as a standalone center-based program (for example, a case in which the center is not part of a larger company) that is an early childhood education program, by self-certification with supporting documents, such as a business license, a listing with a public child care resources and referral organization website, or proof of participation in a Federal child care or preschool subsidy program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87AF72476C3B42FB8718B2E76B7223CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Parent plus loans</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCDDE31D8E3804A6489C0ABF92EEE9AB3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Parent PLUS Loan on behalf of a student who is a qualifying educator</header><text>A borrower of a parent loan under section 428B issued on behalf of a student who is a qualifying educator shall qualify for loan forgiveness and any other benefits under this section for the qualifying service of the student in the same manner and to the same extent as the student borrower qualifies for such loan forgiveness and other benefits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7994C1BC79CE49EA94EA555B80F4941A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Parent PLUS Loan borrowed by a parent who is a qualifying educator</header><text>The borrower of a parent loan under section 428B issued on behalf of a student who is not a qualifying educator shall also qualify for loan forgiveness and any other benefits under this section for qualifying service if that parent borrower is engaged in qualifying service and meets the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1C68B82D9B54875B2B2B9C8E89F65FD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recipients of Prior Forgiveness</header><text>A qualifying educator who received loan forgiveness under this section as in effect before the effective date of the <short-title>Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</short-title>—</text><subparagraph id="HAE595640F79E41FF99B55ADB11C7DD15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be eligible for loan forgiveness of covered loans in accordance with paragraph (1), including any remaining covered loans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D4FEA6EAF4B425BA015635CDAD8D5A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may count the service completed that qualified the qualifying educator for previous loan forgiveness as qualifying service for purposes of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2CAC65E00964AF5B7A2DD62578E8053"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition on requiring repayment</header><text>A qualifying educator shall not be required to repay any amounts paid under this subsection if that qualifying educator who engages in qualifying service ends the qualifying service before the end of a school or program year, or before the end of the 5-year period described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D41ED3DBD534E34A6629C4A7476BC0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBE204B47ADC14E44B4550BAFFBDEA725"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize any refunding of any repayment of a loan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H822673AB39894C84BC6AEBAEE7C0E058"><enum>(f)</enum><header>List</header><paragraph id="H68B9089B6C9343368B625A0BE33012B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HCA9623207DB04AABAAA3EAC223A45975"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as soon as practicable, produce and make publicly available a list of high need schools and early childhood education programs for purposes of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5659D97FB994A768AD7D8F6B59D2BA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>annually update such list; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63BDE2EFE49D4684997294DC1D884212"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify State educational agencies, local educational agencies, educational services agencies, and State agencies that oversee early childhood education programs of the benefits to educators employed by the entities detailed in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10ABCD1510A345CFBFD4D3596A765C9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List from previous year</header><text>If the list of high need schools and early childhood education programs in which a qualifying educator may perform qualifying service is not available before May 1 of any year, the Secretary may use the list for the year preceding the year for which the determination is made to make a determination about whether an individual meets the requirements for qualifying service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80352FCFE451428E8A904B82E3EA9299"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional eligibility provisions</header><paragraph id="H69E34BFAEF8F4F259E9A91EC457FA714"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Continued eligibility</header><text>Any qualifying educator who performs qualifying service in a school that—</text><subparagraph id="H992B0A41EBB34BC0A52622248562427B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a high need school in any school year during such service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C3A879B6A454D70AEC0262ECB55E629"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in a subsequent school year fails to meet the definition of a high need school,</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">may continue to serve in such school and shall be eligible for loan forgiveness pursuant to subsection (b).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5A8DA03C9EB459B88967E466A3DA7A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prevention of double benefits</header><text>No qualifying educator may, for the same service, receive a benefit under both this section and—</text><subparagraph id="H46344D203EDF4791AC4A38DF2EE5BC6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 428K; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CE38C099EEE416584450187764E7C89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subtitle D of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12601">42 U.S.C. 12601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01DF0F3E0234458EA25F11581501E1B1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No penalty for promotions</header><text>Any qualifying educator who performs qualifying service in an early childhood education program or high need school and who is promoted to another position within that early childhood program or high need school after 1 or more years of qualifying service may continue to be employed in such position in such program or school and shall be eligible to count the period of employment in such position as qualifying service for loan forgiveness pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FD3C5C827174B7DAD3276D646917BBF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HFF88421D9FED4320B973EB12A2D97CDE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau of Indian Education funded elementary or secondary school</header><text>The term <term>Bureau of Indian Education funded elementary or secondary school</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE6654BD23580444287867A4989C94B2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school or dormitory operated by the Bureau of Indian Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA421941789634A29B0E2C3D88CC83C84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school or dormitory operated pursuant to a grant under the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2501">25 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFAE9DA92054432BAE208640F653457C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school or dormitory operated pursuant to a contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H336BA3AEB70E4DAFB6236D412A92CB66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau of Indian Education early childhood development program</header><text>The term <term>Bureau of Indian Education early childhood development program</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H261E0492DCDD4B1A8A1798C2F18509B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a program operating under a grant authorized by section 1139 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2019">25 U.S.C. 2019</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1217B5B7A99849DCAFB188C2CE8E654E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an early childhood education program operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education (including Family and Child Education programs at schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Education authorized under section 1121 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2001">25 U.S.C. 2001</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6995FC7B5EE74A11B7636A4C922CE16F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered loan</header><text>The term <term>covered loan</term> means a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC55CF5B297BB4CE4AE4FE2BFD4432077"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H6EF37FEDB64046A2B6CB9A465D9B9453"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a high-need early childhood education program as defined in section 200;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F8627E7FB294B64BA2EEAC3B7AAC1DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Head Start program (including an Early Head Start program) carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD454C3D63E444E09B97766A955EBA51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an early childhood education program, as defined in section 103;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H704B0D8592084BB2B9C504C12EA98E22"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Bureau of Indian Education early childhood development program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88DAFC5CE925497A889A9B759DB207D9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian education system early childhood education program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H440820FEB94D4DF2ABBEAE8B236567F5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Tribal early childhood education program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCBD46C3929246CA8599B69980029271"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a provider that receives funds under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858">42 U.S.C. 9858 et seq.</external-xref>) (including such providers that are center-based and family child care providers); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA577F2B9F769441EB039E8C6B0059E1E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (G).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2DDD0A56C134CF397031927D1348977"><enum>(5)</enum><header>High need school</header><text>The term <term>high need school</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HFC58CC65A5F94CB9A85AECF0F47B1274"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public elementary or secondary school—</text><clause id="H3F8E3D6BE21642BE8131160B0F8A3512"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to which the number of children meeting a measure of poverty under section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, exceeds 30 percent of the total number of children enrolled in such school; and</text></clause><clause id="HB1E528C20FCC47418A03455ED64A4BE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is served by a local educational agency that is eligible for assistance pursuant to part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD26A13A2613E469AB8651237F81F6BDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public elementary or secondary school or location operated by an educational service agency in which the number of children meeting a measure of poverty under section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 exceeds 30 percent of the total number of children enrolled in such school or location;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8C31F1E1B97499EB082CFD207FED966"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a public elementary or secondary school identified by the State for comprehensive support and improvement, targeted support and improvement, or additional targeted support and improvement, under section 1111 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADB3F74EDBC54CE29AE7BF6B9A08D640"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Bureau of Indian Education funded elementary or secondary school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEFEC5AC6BC54054B68C340FD1D861DD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school operated by a Tribal educational agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF487170A7C2D4990A0536DF4C7CCD689"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian education system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A40F84B9AF04C3C935AF5C0BEC59811"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this subtitle pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC3D4AC339FD434DA73A33129E997B1E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Native hawaiian education system</header><text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian education system</term> means an entity eligible to receive direct grants or enter into contracts with the Secretary under section 6205 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7515">20 U.S.C. 7515</external-xref>) to carry out the authorized activities under that section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1894633D4E4446CB7C996EC9573F35C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Qualifying educator</header><text>Subject to subsection (i), the term <term>qualifying educator</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H657EB68298184209BD946EB4F61D0C08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school teacher who—</text><clause id="H01E6AD1ECABD40C98E8F11B5872D6BB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has obtained full State or Tribal certification and licensure requirements for such employment; and</text></clause><clause id="HBE4E87A02FFA4701ABDCDFC0A9AFBF9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not had such certification or licensure requirements waived on an emergency, temporary, or provisional basis;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8942265FA2E2429688411793644BB90B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an early childhood educator who provides care or instruction to children;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H307622DB8ECB45429303ED14D14FB06A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a school leader of an elementary or secondary school who—</text><clause id="H3E43232A3F1049A7B1B2D99081DB3AFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has obtained full State or Tribal certification and licensure requirements for such employment; and</text></clause><clause id="HB87DF47632F74D9288EFA2BEF976DDD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not had such certification or licensure requirements waived on an emergency, temporary, or provisional basis; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187ABE66C8BB4FEBA398D52EE63CF987"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an early childhood education program director (including a family child care provider).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H776B5DE4604F451B815D2D9F92AD3E78"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualifying service</header><subparagraph id="H921EA60422EB4C67B3AFFD63E0A90A17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>qualifying service</term> means—</text><clause id="H1ACCA5C897914FC9A716CFF4C9708FB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a qualifying educator described in subparagraph (A) or (C) of paragraph (8), employment as a full-time qualifying educator in a high need school; and</text></clause><clause id="HD87C3712BE644D3FB4DEC0C1C8141C3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a qualifying educator described in subparagraph (B) or (D) of paragraph (8), employment as a full-time qualifying educator in an early childhood education program (including school-based programs).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCFD7694ED784574AB28D0A03C5AAB0A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In the case of a qualifying educator who is unable to complete a full school or program year of service, that year may still be counted toward the required qualifying service period under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) if—</text><clause id="HD628EF194875441BB7EE6E2D455CD396"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the qualifying educator completed at least one-half of the school or program year;</text></clause><clause id="H40DF15D9ACC4437AB52A79C61A3E90D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the employer considers the qualifying educator to have fulfilled the contract requirements for the school or program year for the purposes of salary increases, tenure, and retirement; and</text></clause><clause id="H1E7BA022E45742F98CF166FF4EA4A182"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the qualifying educator was unable to complete the school or program year because—</text><subclause id="HC7A501CF047641849B3096439F0D07AA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the qualifying educator returned to postsecondary education, on at least a half-time basis, in an area of study directly related to the performance of the qualifying service;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9DD4D48A7CB64638A88188345525278A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the qualifying educator experienced a condition described in section 102 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="H4C1B0CAA339B4A93BF45EE15A54C68BB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the qualifying educator was called or ordered to Federal or State active duty status, or Active Service as a member of a Reserve Component of the Armed Forces named in section 10101 of title 10, United States Code, or service as a member of the National Guard on full-time National Guard duty, as defined in section 101(d)(5) of title 10, United States Code; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H61FA2EEE4BD542B0BA4DD9FBBE42255E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the qualifying educator resides in or is employed in a disaster area, as declared by any Federal, State, or local official in connection with a national emergency.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07E29DE3AF234820856CFFED5D54670E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>School Leader</header><text>The term <term>school leader</term> has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44724F9FC7254840B9EB40D6ACA8CC72"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Tribal early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>Tribal early childhood education program</term> means any of the following programs:</text><subparagraph id="H27AFC83E709F44E1AF8739872AEBE71B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An American Indian or Alaska Native Head Start or Early Head Start program carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC91BA076D4A434A830D9A06CFD7C342"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A Tribal child care and development program carried out under the Child Care and Development Block Grant of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858">42 U.S.C. 9858 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6B270F76D2548B9928FD0DFBC6C630B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A program serving children from birth through age 6 that—</text><clause id="H89DCC065D25B41A4BDB85869BEC8B948"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receives funding support from the Native American language preservation and maintenance program carried out under section 803C of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991b-3">42 U.S.C. 2991b–3</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HCEEBF9571EBC477FBA67CED8B7672E90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a Tribal prekindergarten program;</text></clause><clause id="H5E839914AE684CA0999890542916A34E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a program authorized under section 619 or part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act; or</text></clause><clause id="HAFF59BBF5F944033A2783531181A4498"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is a center-based or group-based early childhood learning or development program that the Secretary determines shall be included under this definition, after receiving a request from an Indian Tribe.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDECA2385260A49649114C8446E902327"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Tribal educational agency</header><text>The term <term>Tribal educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term (without respect to capitalization) in section 6132(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H161969BC7D314F3480AA7C332B906D47"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Year</header><text>The term <term>year</term>, when applied to service as a qualifying educator, means a school or program year as defined by the Secretary or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E46E39958D34D6086081A62FE5AE1E9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>An educator that provides instruction or curricular development in an Alaska Native, American Indian, or Native Hawaiian language or a Native American language as defined in the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2902">25 U.S.C. 2902</external-xref>) shall be considered to be a qualifying educator regardless of whether the educator has achieved full State or Tribal certification and licensure requirements for such employment.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF0C50413797E42599821BF6AC59854B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhanced teacher loan cancellation under the Direct Loan program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 460 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087j">20 U.S.C. 1087j</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0406A324A144790A64FE375F72BFC76"><section id="H1CBBC598CBF44682A80D3116C31F326D"><enum>460.</enum><header>Loan cancellation for educators</header><subsection id="HB71E31D5BBE3471E8EF16652C584DBBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>It is the purpose of this section to enhance student access to a well-prepared, diverse, and stable educator workforce by eliminating debt burdens for educators in return for service teaching and leading in high need schools or early childhood education programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3ED8BF75F36F4EC98F88AC9C7E659125"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall carry out a program of canceling, as required under subsection (c), the obligation to repay a covered loan for qualifying educators engaged in qualifying service. A qualifying educator may apply for the program under this section after the Secretary has begun carrying out the program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A56E2357E6242618B4836BBC39FEC6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cancellation of covered loans</header><paragraph id="H8B175C42CFD24BFD904F4F1402E14FF5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cancellation of loans upon completion of qualifying service</header><subparagraph id="H020CD98D475C41438E58B73540FAE804"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>For each qualifying educator who has completed 5 years of qualifying service (including any qualifying service, as defined under this section as in effect after the date of implementation of the <short-title>Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</short-title>, that may have been completed or performed before or after such date of implementation, or a combination of qualifying service), the Secretary shall cancel an amount equal to 100 percent of the aggregate of the loan obligations (including interest and fees) on all covered loans that are outstanding as of the date of completion of such fifth year of qualifying service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33CBEC2025DD441293A1DDA169DCE423"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The years of qualifying service required under subparagraph (A) may be consecutive or nonconsecutive, and the qualifying educator may elect which years of qualifying service to use for purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77B35CBA358C469386731C0CCED91456"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monthly loan cancellation</header><text>Upon application by any qualifying educator of a covered loan who is engaged in qualifying service, and in addition to any loan cancellation under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with such qualifying educator, under which—</text><subparagraph id="HC7A0720D97D049BE96E32EE6414BC088"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the period of qualifying service (for qualifying service that occurs after the date of implementation of this Act), the Secretary agrees to assume and cancel the minimum monthly obligation on all covered loans of the qualifying educator based on the repayment plan of the qualifying educator, for—</text><clause commented="no" id="H33A5FF0676DD4F47885AD6E4F84D1B9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each month of qualifying service; and</text></clause><clause id="HA47CB961A0F54513A84DC8947968F1F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any summer or other school or program year calendar breaks scheduled by a qualifying school or early childhood education program during a school or program year in which the qualifying educator is engaged in qualifying service;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49873593041247F7BC266F24D19E077F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the period of qualifying service, interest shall not accrue on the qualifying educator’s covered loans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCD8049C926343F298C9223E2B0689EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the period of qualifying service, each monthly obligation that is cancelled by the Secretary under this paragraph on a covered loan shall be deemed to be a qualifying monthly payment made by the qualifying educator under section 455(m)(1)(A) for purposes of the loan forgiveness program under section 455(m), if applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34E377BD886A4BC7AF7E94A63182D0AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and make publicly available an application for qualifying educators who wish to receive loan cancellation under this subsection. The application shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC045C4BD0B9B403D9826B76B9CE2AFA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be available for qualifying educators to file for loan cancellation under paragraph (1) and for monthly loan cancellation under paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54397B3DEC0F4FD39BAA17596349746A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include any certification requirements that the Secretary determines are necessary to verify qualifying service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H665B9C78C75F4F85ACAE82FAE2924CB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for the verification of the qualifying service—</text><clause id="H690846CE45F44A00925E32C315394801"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an early childhood educator or an elementary or secondary school teacher serving in a high need school, by a school leader or the administrator of a local educational agency, educational service agency, Bureau of Indian Education, Native Hawaiian education system, or State educational agency that serves the school (or the administrator's designee);</text></clause><clause id="H0B1F9F013D2D43EEBF1BDF332417F408"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an early childhood educator serving in a early childhood education program, by the director of that program (or the director’s designee);</text></clause><clause id="H8DEDCC94E2FD4B95B983E458BACCA1B4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a school leader serving in a high need school, by the administrator of a local educational agency, educational service agency, Bureau of Indian Education, Native Hawaiian education system, or State educational agency that serves the school (or the administrator's designee);</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H3B183EEEBC414DB280F8FFF6900B9A45"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of a director of an early childhood education program, a leader of the entity overseeing the early childhood education program; and</text></clause><clause id="HA7FA07F444934853933B2BE9791AC159"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in the case of a family child care provider or the director of an early childhood education program that operates as a standalone center-based child care program (for example, a case in which the center is not part of a larger company) that is an early childhood education program, by self-certification with supporting documents, such as a business license, a listing with a public child care resources and referral organization website, or proof of participation in a Federal child care or preschool subsidy program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFC2CBF771464B2F8C89FD8DF78C7160"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Parent plus loans</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD988981C36514C9786BB96A8B2D3DBCB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Parent PLUS Loan on behalf of a student who is a qualifying educator</header><text>A borrower of a parent Federal Direct PLUS Loan issued on behalf of a student who is a qualifying educator shall qualify for loan forgiveness and any other benefits under this section for the qualifying service of the student in the same manner and to the same extent as the student borrower qualifies for such loan forgiveness and other benefits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB3F034B331EC415E860CB22BB855C5F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Parent PLUS Loan borrowed by a parent who is a qualifying educator</header><text>The borrower of a parent Federal Direct PLUS Loan issued on behalf of a student who is not a qualifying educator shall also qualify for loan forgiveness and any other benefits under this section for qualifying service if that parent borrower is engaged in qualifying service and meets the requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A5450C4201E4A04B74DC9FCC277F352"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recipients of prior loan cancellation</header><text>A qualifying educator who received loan cancellation under this section as in effect before the effective date of the <short-title>Loan Forgiveness for Educators Act of 2026</short-title>—</text><subparagraph id="H6E4E6B5E2E154827B71F5F762E90810F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be eligible for loan cancellation of covered loans in accordance with subsection (c)(1), including any remaining covered loans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0259FF2B797643819E5D0FE1F5E180C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may count the service completed that qualified the qualifying educator for previous loan cancellation as qualifying service for purposes of subsection (c)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C5B0090C863418395EE3E5B839EC28A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition on requiring repayment</header><text>A qualifying educator shall not be required to repay any amounts paid under this subsection if that qualifying educator who engages in qualifying service ends the qualifying service before the end of a school or program year, or before the end of the 5-year period described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE41739A3D32240308EB3174C17E24503"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary is authorized to issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF5E2604C7A5E4F6AB560105D7D3DFB58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize any refunding of any canceled loan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BB3BB6AD8B745F286AFBE0701B979F0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>List</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H41178A7E5E7144829DBDA361122A8BCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H41DE0409271148768EFFA6E7D18BF636"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as soon as practicable, produce and make publicly available a list of high need schools and early childhood education programs for purposes of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD22B29A37904C58AFB2831556A0F562"><enum>(B)</enum><text>annually update such list; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE73F99AAC59148E9B0AF59835B8BC89A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify State educational agencies, local educational agencies, educational services agencies, and State agencies that oversee early childhood education programs of the benefits to educators employed by the entities detailed in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2804D31B5D44E64874E58B5871CEF65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>List from previous year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the list of high need schools and early childhood education programs in which a qualifying educator may perform qualifying service is not available before May 1 of any year, the Secretary may use the list for the year preceding the year for which the determination is made to make a determination about whether an individual meets the requirements for qualifying service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H947078E06B1543419462132D821A6D9D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Additional eligibility provisions</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HC8A2CE044AD54E79AAD62EBA36DAEDDF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Continued eligibility</header><text>Any qualifying educator who performs qualifying service in a school that—</text><subparagraph id="H376485AFE72F49ADBED58202D94E559C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a high need school in any school year during such service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CFEF7D773A64ABD85C8378475AA2394"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>in a subsequent school year fails to meet the definition of a high need school,</text>
 </subparagraph><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="paragraph">may continue to serve in such school and shall be eligible for loan cancellation pursuant to subsection (b).</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA2872DC18B4A65A6F7235712C5CBC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prevention of double benefits</header><text>No qualifying educator may, for the same service, receive a benefit under both this section and—</text><subparagraph id="H7495FA7DF03944E8B211DEEAD02BF522"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 428K; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DA0BD0E715F4D2BA623EF2DCD0734AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subtitle D of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12601">42 U.S.C. 12601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8429F48C02474345B19039339BBFFBFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No penalty for promotions</header><text>Any qualifying educator who performs qualifying service in an early childhood education program or high need school and who is promoted to another position within that early childhood program or high need school after 1 or more years of qualifying service may continue to be employed in such position in such program or school and shall be eligible to count the period of employment in such position as qualifying service for loan cancellation pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1342374D8AA94DAC8FB2E806BA2137DC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0FD29976FACF4E36BEA4A0F52EB465D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau of Indian Education funded elementary or secondary school</header><text>The term <term>Bureau of Indian Education funded elementary or secondary school</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0FA26E9CB5AA4F58B8E9702B8567EDC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school or dormitory operated by the Bureau of Indian Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9847D9EA62346FEA265AFE7DB0E548F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school or dormitory operated pursuant to a grant under the Tribally Controlled Schools Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2501">25 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6BB70B75E5E4CBA9E487064DF864FA5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school or dormitory operated pursuant to a contract under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17B2A151B2EC41ECB5DFA4F968C3597C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau of Indian Education early childhood development program</header><text>The term <term>Bureau of Indian Education early childhood development program</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H540C0DDA6E88432FB91FDCE3A9AC7A27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a program operating under a grant authorized by section 1139 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2019">25 U.S.C. 2019</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2CB5E973F644D7D9323F6D13FD9A5EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an early childhood education program operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education (including Family and Child Education programs at schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Education authorized under section 1121 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2001">25 U.S.C. 2001</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0090487AC00D420DBE5C9C6E66684CAF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered loan</header><text>The term <term>covered loan</term> means a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5952EFE12B7248C886A4D04AA46807D7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H031743D78D8C4CD8B7D186C58CF3E8E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a high-need early childhood education program as defined in section 200;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8B1CCB3AF55425A9E45D541CF9A524D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Head Start program (including an Early Head Start program) carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC74118D42A047F4ACB5DF975A105837"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an early childhood education program, as defined in section 103;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEF93BA4DD97470F8554303E10355A64"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Bureau of Indian Education early childhood development program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA15CFD93AE79467AB81A948DA296D28B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian education system early childhood education program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H762A8A9CCB534BCF80CD3FCD2C9C89C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Tribal early childhood education program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DC2A61A0B264F79ADF6E4B0E624CC93"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a provider that receives funds under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858">42 U.S.C. 9858 et seq.</external-xref>) (including such providers that are center-based and family child care providers); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB7E4249C21EB488889EA64BA45EFEF87"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in any of subparagraphs (A) through (G).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7E365ED992E4EDD96DED4DE3F460617"><enum>(5)</enum><header>High need school</header><text>The term <term>high need school</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9526DCFB01AB43809C718196C1823A3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public elementary or secondary school—</text><clause id="HEB5253F106134AC1990F54558EA85064"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to which the number of children meeting a measure of poverty under section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, exceeds 30 percent of the total number of children enrolled in such school; and</text></clause><clause id="H1166FCE93C754074A14C88A32978A7D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is served by a local educational agency that is eligible for assistance pursuant to part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0EA58E61778741EEBC5B0E7C9E2F5BFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public elementary or secondary school or location operated by an educational service agency in which the number of children meeting a measure of poverty under section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 exceeds 30 percent of the total number of children enrolled in such school or location;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H175B6F553164433A8D837A11910E480C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a public elementary or secondary school identified by the State for comprehensive support and improvement, targeted support and improvement, or additional targeted support and improvement, under section 1111 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF396B2B012DF45799F353C5634400AD0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Bureau of Indian Education funded elementary or secondary school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97F27EA4B7F04CBC9CDB452260107E5F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school operated by a Tribal educational agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AF200202ACE467A9DC1B106A303940B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian education system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A55AB58A43C443092C57044CB158EE3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this subtitle pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD067396D3894E719B1F69F00222C59E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Native hawaiian education system</header><text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian education system</term> means an entity eligible to receive direct grants or enter into contracts with the Secretary under section 6205 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7515">20 U.S.C. 7515</external-xref>) to carry out the authorized activities under that section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3706755B03684F1E8669DACF61903EFE"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Qualifying educator</header><text>Subject to subsection (i), the term <term>qualifying educator</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1F104D695C7348338166C602D0FEC9B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school teacher who—</text><clause id="HA5921383228948279B312CB34549F6B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has obtained full State or Tribal certification and licensure requirements for such employment; and</text></clause><clause id="H144C6C769595493B89B66FCA613DFED8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not had such certification or licensure requirements waived on an emergency, temporary, or provisional basis;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5659F57754348BAB45FEDC8983F2F22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an early childhood educator who provides care or instruction to children;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F99E9F83FB4401AB66A0482EE8A19B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a school leader of an elementary or secondary school who—</text><clause id="H66EACBFF929D48E8A351EE9E721BC5EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has obtained full State or Tribal certification and licensure requirements for such employment; and</text></clause><clause id="H98DF3848707C47B5B1EB8B9800F62C50"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not had such certification or licensure requirements waived on an emergency, temporary, or provisional basis; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8F39D167A4F4A7A91EF83F446B8B24A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an early childhood education program director (including a family child care provider).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD13F71B0E2EF4FCCA2661B1EA565D3F8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualifying service</header><subparagraph id="H8ADB4C29A8004EE881DEB5B998F3A2DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>qualifying service</term> means—</text><clause id="HDFF941BB4A744728A23CDB13CA532566"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a qualifying educator described in subparagraph (A) or (C) of paragraph (8), employment as a full-time qualifying educator in a high need school; and</text></clause><clause id="H3ADF6F99E54B4B80B4E734DCF55B5465"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a qualifying educator described in subparagraph (B) or (D) of paragraph (8), employment as a full-time qualifying educator in an early childhood education program (including school-based programs).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD94AE8A8273C4A868C136006B4D7EBFA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In the case of a qualifying educator who is unable to complete a full school or program year of service, that year may still be counted toward the required qualifying service period under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) if—</text><clause id="H465245AFDE4B486AA4DD349169F092E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the qualifying educator completed at least one-half of the school or program year;</text></clause><clause id="HA23A2D0C6F6049A4B408008DBB062203"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the employer considers the qualifying educator to have fulfilled the contract requirements for the school or program year for the purposes of salary increases, tenure, and retirement; and</text></clause><clause id="HBF51BF83692A40DF85DC3C2D973EBF91"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the qualifying educator was unable to complete the school or program year because—</text><subclause id="H214212EDF3FD4C2A8D90D49D1471C41A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the qualifying educator returned to postsecondary education, on at least a half-time basis, in an area of study directly related to the performance of the qualifying service;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCA41CB24B8C34BFCA8FBC177773ACD0B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the qualifying educator experienced a condition described in section 102 of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612</external-xref>);</text></subclause><subclause id="H9678FC65B11C4AC1B6096B0DBCFFF9F9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the qualifying educator was called or ordered to Federal or State active duty status, or Active Service as a member of a Reserve Component of the Armed Forces named in section 10101 of title 10, United States Code, or service as a member of the National Guard on full-time National Guard duty, as defined in section 101(d)(5) of title 10, United States Code; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H60F75D38C95143A88280B62DD8A45031"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the qualifying educator resides in or is employed in a disaster area, as declared by any Federal, State, or local official in connection with a national emergency.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB110E354519B47ACA6B2BD56083F0EE5"><enum>(10)</enum><header>School Leader</header><text>The term <term>school leader</term> has the meaning given that term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE0436751D7240C68401579ABA82692F"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Tribal early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>Tribal early childhood education program</term> means any of the following programs:</text><subparagraph id="H131C5570DF9D409099123C1A98665215"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An American Indian or Alaska Native Head Start or Early Head Start program carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1998F57905C48E3A91B4A67C173A429"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A Tribal child care and development program carried out under the Child Care and Development Block Grant of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858">42 U.S.C. 9858 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H065BD441A57E4C2A87C3B95E30BBCAEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A program serving children from birth through age 6 that—</text><clause id="H79CDFA58CA344A719A377A47D35FF5F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receives funding support from the Native American language preservation and maintenance program carried out under section 803C of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2991b-3">42 U.S.C. 2991b–3</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H2136C57C4D0C4F179157DA4F9AC7669D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a Tribal prekindergarten program;</text></clause><clause id="HE6C9B46EC7D545578DEAF26AFC94E0EA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a program authorized under section 619 or part C of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act; or</text></clause><clause id="H2AFB4CAD337642D682E9EFE5D7AD3464"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is a center-based or group-based early childhood learning or development program that the Secretary determines shall be included under this definition, after receiving a request from an Indian Tribe.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF07693B6860F4C04A74A7A3C424CDC12"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Tribal educational agency</header><text>The term <term>Tribal educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term (without respect to capitalization) in section 6132(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C989E1041984EB38D047B18EFEC3D56"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Year</header><text>The term <term>year</term>, when applied to service as a qualifying educator, means a school or program year as defined by the Secretary or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB039CEE245F4C2AAB6BC8A907B25044"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>An educator that provides instruction or curricular development in an Alaska Native, American Indian, or Native Hawaiian language or a Native American language as defined in the Native American Languages Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2902">25 U.S.C. 2902</external-xref>) shall be considered to be a qualifying educator regardless of whether the educator has achieved full State or Tribal certification and licensure requirements for such employment.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H942A6A595ED3436B851BCC30F5E47CBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date; Program name</header><paragraph id="H0D4217D6C7BD4517B69CC9CA90DEA5F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsections (a) and (b) shall take effect on the day that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48BA199AB2EB4F87BB5C1651DE71116C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program name</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The programs under section 428J and 460 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by subsections (a) and (b), shall be known as Educator Loan Forgiveness Programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H631BDB23233544C2847B386FE4623809"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 455(m)(4) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 428J, 428K, 428L, or 460</quote> and inserting <quote>section 428K or 428L</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H0C3D8DC70A054FC7B0E57401AB1FB75E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notice to borrowers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the Secretary of Education implements the programs under this Act, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall take such steps as may be necessary to inform high need schools and early childhood education programs (as defined in section 460 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, as amended by this Act), Head Start programs (including Early Head Start programs) carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>), early childhood educators and program directors (including family child care providers and program directors), public school teachers, public school leaders, Bureau of Indian Education school teachers, Bureau of Indian Education school leaders, Native Hawaiian education system school teachers, Native Hawaiian education system school leaders, local educational agency leaders (such as superintendents), local educational agencies, educational service agencies, educational service agency leaders, chief State school officers, State educational agencies, students attending institutions of higher education, and other student loan borrowers, of the amendments made by this Act to the loan forgiveness and loan cancellation programs under sections 428J and 460 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-10">20 U.S.C. 1078–10</external-xref>; 1087j), including an explanation of how loans accrued before the date of enactment of this Act may qualify for loan forgiveness or loan cancellation under such sections, as amended by this Act, and an explanation of how service performed before the date of enactment of this Act may count toward qualifying service requirements for purposes of such sections, as amended by this Act.</text></section><section commented="no" id="HF35F441FD1B947C48F72B031808298CF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Waiver of negotiated rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this Act and any amendments made by this Act, or any regulations promulgated under this Act or under such amendments, the Secretary of Education may waive the application of negotiated rulemaking under section 492 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1098a">20 U.S.C. 1098a</external-xref>).</text></section></legis-body></bill>

