<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3BA7A907C3DD4C479A7263D658ED5809" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8613 IH: To providing access to certain memorials on Federal property during Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000482">Ms. Fedorchak</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To providing access to certain memorials on Federal property during Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H74550C2F237B4FEB8DB74C294E2E5D2F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3770351C56494A1FB149CEA6DBA4ECED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Providing access to memorials on Federal property during Government shutdown</header> 
<subsection id="HC0F9BB76A6904E629E1BC0C2E79F031B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During any lapse in appropriations with respect to a Federal agency, such agency shall provide access to any memorial (in this section defined as any site of commemoration, including a memorial or cemetery) that is—</text> <paragraph id="H95AAD4A96C9A4571891C33EBC4E348DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not funded by the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECAE75051E1E44C1B1D7C526F271CB9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">generally accessible to the public through a Federal facility (or other real property) of the Federal agency when such agency is not subject to a lapse in appropriations</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE1DE5190EB9049F5A51AE7A62659B338"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excepted from furlough</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Federal employee whose official duties relate to providing access to the public to a memorial described under subsection (a) shall be deemed, for purposes of section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, services for emergencies involving the safety of human life or the protection of property.</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

