<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0056EFC1E84D4100AEFBD312A89DC17E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6395 IH: To implement a strategy to relocate the headquarters of the United Nations, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6395</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To implement a strategy to relocate the headquarters of the United Nations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE18C695EBBCB47B09B2C7123DBDED027" style="OLC"><section id="HFDBFF41FE6E24F988BE6E28029B1B966" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Relocation strategy required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall develop and implement a strategy to renegotiate the Agreement between the United States of America and the United Nations regarding the headquarters of the United Nations (signed at Lake Success, New York, on June 26, 1947) in order to—</text><paragraph id="H8B969A441ACE4849A6811F443C9D4150"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify a list of options for alternative locations for such headquarters within the United States, based on a series of factors to be developed by the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31BEA5699CE24D11B50638EE3CCED97B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to enter into negotiations with appropriate counterparts of the United Nations to renegotiate such Agreement as necessary for the relocation of the headquarters to one of the listed options;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA10229A2643C40118DA414A2E85C89CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide such notifications or consultations as may be appropriate to facilitate the ratification of such amended Agreement by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9913A96BA8248A78723B964F9D33247"><enum>(4)</enum><text>take such steps as may be necessary to relocate the headquarters in accordance with such ratified amended Agreement.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H41771A2CF4F941068EEB4987EDED912C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Implementation and report</header><subsection id="H31A3CC6DD06C4EAD95EEE3AF66306CFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prompt implementation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement the strategy required by section 1 as promptly as practicable upon its development.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBD04A205EE4A4192B115DB7679729409"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a notification upon completion of the development of the strategy required by section 1 that includes—</text><paragraph id="H59D44216657B45F5960FDE61370F26D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an anticipated timeline for the prompt implementation of the strategy as required by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6845D5A55E4913AF9162A5E0A60131"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the intended next steps for relocating the headquarters of the United Nations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

