<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HD4B4514DD2D5495AA8B2AC93D11CC4EC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 4307 EH: Enhancing Detection of Human Trafficking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4307</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to train certain employees of Department of Labor how to effectively detect and assist law enforcement in preventing human trafficking during the course of their official duties, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HDC2EA52017B0464BBD7D7A9B43203836">
<section id="H8DE48083B87E4650B1BFE35C4337EA84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Detection of Human Trafficking Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H271520C30933461AAB3ECC46EF747085"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of human trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>human trafficking</term> means any act or practice described in paragraph (11) of section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></section>
<section id="H14D95C352CCB49A7A99C54FE7F7417DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Training for Department personnel to identify human trafficking</header>
<subsection id="HE21EDB5F9A5E4F28931FADE8840DC05A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall implement a program to provide the training and periodic continuing education described in subsection (b) to employees of the Department of Labor whom the Secretary determines should receive such training or education based on their official duties. In making such determination with respect to employees of the Wage and Hour Division, the Secretary shall consider the training and education needs of such employees operating in a State with a significant increase in oppressive child labor (as defined in section 3(l) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203(l)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4B479EA35E6B4D48B1FEB21E50802120"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Training and continuing education described</header><text>The training and continuing education provided under the program referred to in subsection (a)—</text>
<paragraph id="H267152EEB8EC4703B6939DFB5DA93133"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be conducted through in-class or virtual learning capabilities; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83CC3742E5FF4D65A8C332F7D2357EC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H2709EB3319364BEAB25238EB3F1ED48A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training or continuing education that— </text> <clause id="H891855146EB34278BB45FF3C5A9E868E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is most appropriate for the particular location or professional environment in which the employees receiving such training or continuing education perform their official duties;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4A4C01AA62E54BFF8ADF85CE5497A477" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>covers topics determined by the Secretary of Labor to appropriately reflect current trends and best practices for such location or environment; and </text></clause> <clause id="H5DC14B29140F471686361908EAF330AD" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text>
<subclause id="H32BC83ACCA724E7DA5847574CFDC2E74"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the provision of current information on matters related to the detection of human trafficking to the extent relevant to the official duties of such employees, and consistent with privacy laws;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD29B433D02734B70BC54F4FC4962D5BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>methods for identifying suspected victims of human trafficking and parties who may be suspected of the trafficking activity; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H894DB64BBB124C8B9A4EFE2DE4A6A6C3"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a clear course of action for referring potential cases of human trafficking to the Department of Justice and other appropriate authorities, in accordance with best practices for protecting the rights of victims of human trafficking, including appropriate collaboration with victim advocacy organizations, Federal agencies, and State and local officials; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD6B9B4ACE7434031B6654AFE3A77A906"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of the training or continuing education by such employees after the completion of such training or education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H9E63A3F2DDB14EED8D5610930CCA8C7A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the Secretary of Labor first implements the program under section 3(a), and each year thereafter, the Secretary of Labor shall submit to the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, a report on—</text> <paragraph id="H6C9139D1F32B4FD2BD12568643F25339"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the training and continuing education provided under the program for the preceding year, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD585D545BAFF40B48C510081B5560397"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation (including the overall effectiveness) of such training and continuing education; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6FEEDA3F03546E185FED2C45DEC9EDC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of individuals who have completed such training or continuing education; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H26A5F76FE5F34454BA580908E70C6343"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of cases related to the detection of human trafficking, which were referred to the Department of Justice and other appropriate authorities during the preceding year by the Department of Labor, and the processes used by the Department of Labor to accurately measure and track the response of the Department of Justice and other appropriate authorities to such cases. </text></paragraph></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260303" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives March 3, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

