<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA215B0E7BAE7495597E60E28BF620565" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-joint" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 136 IH: Amending title 36, United States Code, to direct the President to issue an annual proclamation establishing Democracy Day.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 136</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260106">January 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) submitted the following joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Amending title 36, United States Code, to direct the President to issue an annual proclamation establishing Democracy Day.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on January 6, 2021, insurrectionists carried out a violent attack against the United States Capitol in a failed attempt to disrupt and harm lawmakers certifying the outcome of the 2020 Presidential election;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the assault on the United States Capitol resulted in multiple deaths and physical harm to over 140 members of law enforcement;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the tremendous bravery displayed by law enforcement officers helped ensure the successful and democratic transition of presidential power;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the transition of presidential power has remained an unbroken tradition for more than 220 years and is a hallmark of American democracy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas democracy is fragile and requires eternal vigilance to maintain it; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas January 6 would be an appropriate day to designate as Democracy Day: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H973BF62F999C4CEF970FED984BA2F998"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5A9C1E08F1D14A47B36D15FAC8D4DE1B"><text>That <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/36/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 36, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of contents for such chapter accordingly):</text> <quoted-block id="H460CCFD79243483296241800544233D3" style="OLC"> <section id="HF9E0C85B966344BEA42FF686BC6EA01B"><enum>149.</enum><header>Democracy Day</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall issue each year a proclamation—</text> 
<paragraph id="H06ED3F0A640D4EB8BA2EC9BAEE02AC47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designating a day as Democracy Day;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59D46CA147EF48EFBFDA6E5C857FFC42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calling on State and local governments and the people of the United States to observe Democracy Day with appropriate programs and activities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEA1F6D20DB34268A0A54B0A31EA3E24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urging civil and educational authorities of States, counties, cities, and towns to observe Democracy Day through appropriate programs and activities.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

