<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCDAA2DCC08C64B6C97CD8BBA57FA246C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7565 IH: Food for Palestinian Children and Families in Gaza Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7565</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure sufficient food assistance for the civilian population of Gaza.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9869B0071CCF4E0F810C243DDA96AAFE" style="OLC"><section id="HFE657CFA6022458F8FB21BFEAC23073B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Food for Palestinian Children and Families in Gaza Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H10B03F30BAB745CC91AE10F7CFF96D6D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Ensuring Sufficient Food Assistance for the Civilian Population of Gaza</header><subsection id="HAFC691C54BB94F43B9B185E7D31B19FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall certify and report to Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HA0BD84FA7A7D46569D18441F77923E0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>oversight policies, processes, and procedures have been established by the Department of State, as appropriate, and are in use to ensure that sufficient food assistance is being provided to the civilian population of Gaza to ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="H63268D26579A4EA1A7667C3F1FA4FB31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all children in Gaza are able to eat at least three nutritious meals each day; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75FE026781FD4BD0B67F28FB000DD678"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all other civilians in Gaza are able to eat at least two nutritious meals each day; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C48FA8FB8AE4CFB998AF68931E45995"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such policies, processes, and procedures have been developed in coordination with the World Food Program, the United Nations Relief and Works Agency, and other appropriate United Nations agencies, other bilateral and multilateral donors, international nongovernmental organizations, the Government of Israel, and representatives of the Palestinian people, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD7A0FF30D074D3D98509C54C4E8A521"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Oversight policy and procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall submit to Congress, concurrent with the submission of the certification required by subsection (a), a written description of the oversight policies, processes, and procedures for the distribution of food assistance in Gaza, including food assistance provided by the United States, food assistance provided by other bilateral and multilateral donors, and food assistance provided by international nongovernmental organizations, and the role of the Government of Israel in the oversight of such assistance.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB73D26A34F941328AF24928AB4BA808"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Requirement To report</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall provide a report to Congress, which shall be made available to the public, not later than 30 days after the certification required by subsection (a), on how much food assistance is being distributed in Gaza, how many children and adults are being served in Gaza, the donors that are providing the assistance, and how the food is being distributed.</text>
      </subsection><subsection id="H8A8D83A952F44E1CADC06E68BBDE60A2">
        <enum>(d)</enum>
        <header>Requirement To inform</header>
        <paragraph id="HF8F66E54BA3E40B9BDC87E87549BA855">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State shall promptly inform Congress of each instance in which food assistance that is made available for Gaza, for the purposes described in (a)(1), has been denied entrance into Gaza or has been diverted or misused in Gaza.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HFD7A616B3A8E404C9CE154185DDE6A38">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Matters to be included</header>
 <text>The Secretary of State shall include in the information required by paragraph (1) the type of assistance, the donor that provided the assistance, a description of the incident and parties involved, and an explanation of the response of the Department of State, as appropriate.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

