<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD14AEA2AC21B41BCB592451834018BDA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9379 IH: Affordable Homes for Veterans Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9379</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify processing timelines for applications for the assumption of a loan guaranteed by the Department of Veterans Affairs, to require the Inspector General of the Department to conduct an assessment of loan servicer compliance with such timelines, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H35030DC698DB42ACA17024E2D0F558E3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD1D8D5E04EC142EFB88302F4521CB4DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Affordable Homes for Veterans Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H8ABC9A31C0494433B0CEA724151B9B0E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of 45-calendar-day processing requirement for applications for Department of Veterans Affairs home loan assumptions</header> 
<subsection id="H514F00DEC83A4F87968B8A51D19F965D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">Chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3710">section 3710</external-xref> the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2EE900A79E2245A587427A936280092A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H685CC63D516C4704B2461EE56E2AE5C7"><enum>3710A.</enum><header>Processing timelines for loan assumptions</header> <subsection id="H297C0BF5FDC34396A480BD0F2B59C31A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Processing requirement</header><text>The servicer of a loan guaranteed under this chapter shall process and render a decision on a complete application for the assumption of such a loan within 45 calendar days of receipt of such complete application. The requirement under this subsection shall apply regardless of whether the servicer—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3E4C3303EB2847F784992C190A95D0EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is authorized to approve loan assumptions independently; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF3F28A057BB5463EB569E2101BC6A12B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is required to submit an application for a loan assumption to a regional loan center of the Department for approval.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBC6768D59C9F4446974C6FCF49658C0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Complete application defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>complete application</term> means an application that includes all documents and information required by Department regulations for review and approval.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H0606A3D75FDF4848A1EAF1514E78CBE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/3710">section 3710</external-xref> the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H2E3AE70EA7814FFC9229095B14D9DB3B" style="OLC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">3710A. Processing timelines for loan assumptions.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF76AFB27E8B9429B874117EF4FF1DDF0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidance on timelines for servicers of loans guaranteed by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall update guidance and communications materials for servicers of loans guaranteed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, to clearly state that—</text> <paragraph id="H41EB206AD96B44C59B20431F946D3AB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the 45-calendar-day processing timeline established in section 3710A of title 38, United States Code, as inserted by section 3, is a statutory requirement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CBA93F0667745E881DD89DD0CBF11E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>servicers may not threaten, suggest, or imply to individuals who are potential assumers of such loans that the processing timeline will exceed 45 calendar days as a reason to discourage assumptions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAEFA9A672A44B46A279A6B31547EC11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any communication made by servicers regarding processing timelines must be consistent with the statutory requirement.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF4D33BD9AF8343E7A83AE8B3F8645BD8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Office of Inspector General assessment</header> 
<subsection id="H05449C2FD6404625859E44B2D0B54328"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs, in consultation with the Comptroller General of the United States, shall conduct an assessment of each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H584B9F4F51554A618E739350032C9777"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the three-year period preceding the date on which the assessment is commenced, the extent to which servicers of loans guaranteed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, processed applications for assumptions of loans guaranteed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, within the 45-calendar-day timeline required by section 3710A of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 3.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H032719C5EFA74709B8B0AE9E136AC093"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The average processing time for applications for assumption of loans guaranteed under such chapter that are submitted to servicers of such loans and regional loan centers of the Department, disaggregated by servicer and by region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H611E3C4A6DBB4308AE32BB19857C7E47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The frequency and nature of communications by servicers of such loans to individuals who are potential assumers of such loans regarding processing timelines, including instances in which servicers suggested or implied that processing would take longer than 45 calendar days.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A81EC2F5B5E4CEF810812DC70349817"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The denial rates for applications to assume such loans, compared to the rates of approval and withdrawal of such applications, including an assessment of whether extended timelines may be discouraging applicants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA470E8D46BEA46C88E1709AC26F3303C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The comparative denial rates between applications to assume such loans and applications for new loans guaranteed under such chapter, including an assessment of whether assumptions are being subjected to higher or more stringent approval standards than new loans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B7369EC95FD481393952A15F2136BAF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any evidence of discrimination or disparate treatment of individuals who submit applications to assume such loans compared to individuals who submit applications for new loans, including differences in underwriting standards, required documentation, creditworthiness thresholds, or timelines based on borrower characteristics.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2963AA3D33234664842A5A5EF1838E0D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any barriers within the operations, staffing, or systems of servicers of such loans that prevent timely processing of applications to assume such loans.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53BAF97C979841DCBEB2F993D15290E1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The adequacy of Department oversight of the compliance of servicers of such loans with assumption processing requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD966599323F54FA9915A9F752B67FB88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9D02319BE9F042BEBEC0FA72F48B42BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the assessment required by subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01D6522DB9DE4D0DA9028CCD64A7C55A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of any servicers of loans guaranteed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/37">chapter 37</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, that fail to meet the 45-calendar-day requirement under section 3710A of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 3, on a consistent basis;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17AC10664CDF4973B5021853C3730417"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of denial rates for applications to assume such loans compared to denial rates for applications for new loans guaranteed under such chapter, including an identification of any disparities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA18BDFF4C334F91939C59A671B45B86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of whether assumptions of such loans are subject to higher or more stringent underwriting standards, creditworthiness thresholds, or documentation requirements than new loans;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D04F1AABD904A3FB7C622A011139C5C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>findings regarding potential discrimination or disparate treatment of individuals who submit applications to assume such loans;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0801BAED5D544E3AAFB788857B82DCA1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recommendations for enforcement mechanisms to ensure the compliance of servicers of such loans with applicable requirements; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D99A55277864600A31F07C264F20E26"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an identification of any additional legislative or regulatory changes needed to improve the processing of applications to assume such loans and ensure equitable treatment compared to applications for new loans.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD9EBFC238A0046409E034C4240A9314E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public data</header><text>The Inspector General shall make publicly accessible the anonymized data collected for purposes of conducting the assessment required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

