<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HDCFDD97BC89943628C3385F42B253CAE" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2259 : National Strategy for School Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2259</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the development of a national strategy to secure elementary and secondary schools against acts of terrorism, and ensure domestic preparedness for and the response to terrorism, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H22AB1E5097154FF58DE71E24FE666D37" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H8056B2490A1D4DF1A06F7260A316D18E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Strategy for School Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA9CE08383C8C4945A6E68CC01359F4D7"><enum>2.</enum><header>National strategy to secure schools from threats of terrorism</header><subsection id="H6033BD61CE124979A6D40F11F132F25F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle A of title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/651">6 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H408B83CAD2BE4B598DA336DCF03E3AFF"><section id="H13DFE675F33F4AC695E9ED26E3932166"><enum>2220F.</enum><header>National strategy to secure schools from threats of terrorism</header><subsection id="H1BE5F3E525BF4134B8EE27CEA3D501EC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist in the domestic preparedness for and response to acts of terrorism and to coordinate Federal efforts to secure elementary and secondary schools (as such terms are defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)), not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, in consultation and cooperation with the Secretary of Education and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies and departments, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a national school security strategy (in this section referred to as the <quote>strategy</quote>). The Secretary, in consultation and cooperation with the Secretary of Education and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies and departments, shall brief such committees on the strategy.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE2208CC0741148DA8D586FAC49A2E883" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates and briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation and cooperation with the Secretary of Education and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies and departments, shall, if appropriate, annually through 2033 update the strategy, and brief the committees specified in subsection (a) concerning any such update. If there is no such update for any given year, the Secretary shall submit to such committees a certification attesting thereto.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2C206C2462514ED08C2C48EFDE84CA4F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The strategy, including any updates thereto, shall—</text><paragraph id="HEBE5D8BBDD594C5BA79E1A10D95ACE1B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>account for and describe all Federal programs, projects, activities, and authorities including associated spending levels, to secure elementary and secondary schools from acts of terrorism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H530D9D6C2C874A9CBDB5102E7D127ED6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify specific school security vulnerabilities related to acts of terrorism within the United States, and delineate goals for closing such security vulnerabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H671B84BCC54D496199704441E78098E7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describe actions to be taken to achieve such goals and the means necessary to do so, including steps to reform, improve, and streamline existing efforts to align the current threat environment to elementary and secondary schools; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED11CC3CBEA2415B858CC5F5435B1AF0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">build upon existing or ongoing evaluations and avoid unnecessary duplication by reviewing the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of other appropriate working groups, committees, commissions, or entities established by the Department related to efforts to secure elementary and secondary schools against terrorism within the United States, and ensure domestic preparedness for and the response to terrorism.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H70AACB911E84439EB3E2C88678422FC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2220E the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD11D08A4918943F2A968A5BAC283CBED" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2220F. National strategy to secure schools from threats of terrorism.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20251119" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 19, 2025.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

