<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EHF25B11-1YS-FT-CTT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3562 IS: Disclosing Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3562</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to amend the rules of the Commission relating to disclosures by advisers of private funds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Disclosing Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id382727da50e34440b8a91b60d6c9cf53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enhanced disclosure requirements for advisers of private funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 204 of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-4">15 U.S.C. 80b–4</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9012a8487d15433c9869d21a5c626f83"><subsection id="idd64739efbbc0466283d10ee23fac65f3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Enhanced disclosure requirements for advisers of private funds</header><paragraph id="idfee79f1a187549fc8075d627455aeea4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="id40586651c6504dacb9d67ca3c9fa6696"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term>—</text><clause id="idc3d1c10efa04406daf48ada44fce4e3f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code; and</text></clause><clause id="id19724a7fa383485d835792463be2962c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a jurisdiction that the Commission, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury, determines to be subject to the political and legal control of a covered nation, as defined in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id22298aabe0a744d19e828792604302e6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered investment adviser</header><text>The term <term>covered investment adviser</term> means—</text><clause id="id96367ed1a4ed440587a2ed6b103233a3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an investment adviser required to register with the Commission that, together with all related persons, has at least $150,000,000 in private fund assets under management; and</text></clause><clause id="id10accda56a534d24a170329295111a55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an investment adviser relying on the exemption from registration provided under subsection (l) or (m) of section 203.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id090f887045a6442e9217b78ce2c3873d"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Private fund asset</header><text>With respect to an investment adviser, the term <term>private fund asset</term> means an asset under management by the investment adviser that is attributable to a private fund.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3c905d2a67134af5b83a7fc3d45eadf4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Related person</header><text>The term <term>related person</term> has the meaning given that term in the form described in section 279.1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3a630bf49b34405a2928e275293dff2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subparagraph id="idb773670e883246c382699b977c3b8376"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each covered investment adviser shall file an annual report with the Commission stating the total private fund assets in countries of concern attributable to the private funds advised by the covered investment adviser, which shall be broken down by the percentage of those assets in each country of concern.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ca8cb5b93434905ac8652b5192127cb"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>For the purposes of subparagraph (A), the Commission shall determine whether a private fund asset is in a country of concern based on—</text><clause id="id01e8c437e5ac4db79b1fb27f03a78eb9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of capital that is invested in an entity (including a subsidiary of an entity)—</text><subclause id="id0fdb7daae6194b8a888efc5ac6c76bbc"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that has a physical presence or employees in that country of concern; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id29e16bd6f19542f087b55dab7a229180"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the plurality of the sales of which are from that country of concern; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id83d0a3f424ce4db6adb8f4fb6bcfb68b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proportion of the total assets and liabilities of an entity described in clause (i) that are located in that country of concern.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3206a5c3ccd45a68797564e92b78b6e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting by Commission</header><subparagraph id="id46fed145addc4665a3631f2e1d957692"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Publicly available reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the Commission shall prepare and make publicly available a report containing a list of covered investment advisers that, for the period covered by the report, have disclosed to the Commission more than 0 private fund assets in at least 1 country of concern.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4788202c5bd046eb815b51d16a6f4884"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>Each report prepared and made available by the Commission under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="idc11cfb3d44c84fac8854ebafd7323c4f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be aggregated by a covered investment adviser; and</text></clause><clause id="id60d84124f1ee42e982e3340fe6e8bfd0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include the percentage of private fund assets disclosed by a covered investment adviser, as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idacfd72ce3e0843169ca7ee3f10bbbd4f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Exempted transactions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78a">15 U.S.C. 78a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 13A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m-1">15 U.S.C. 78m–1</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0281c3d59567444a9e8b8f601610e512"><section id="idcf389ec0bb2844b19095fe6ecbe34b57"><enum>13B.</enum><header>Disclosure requirements relating to certain exempted transactions</header><subsection id="id5e19bc8c6a5441c9b4bc15d3244fc5d2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id60d8a598fb9b44a0b7cb0924e503888e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beneficial owner</header><text>The term <term>beneficial owner</term> means a person that is determined to be a beneficial owner under section 240.13d–3 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4cec5e19faa1488eb213c1822299ed55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term>—</text><subparagraph id="ida7a9a71e4a9c4eeaa0da5b5473cb4357"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc5b6da9de15c41cab1db9ec7872b538b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a jurisdiction that the Commission, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury, determines to be subject to the political and legal control of a covered nation, as defined in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide92c5147bfd64c3a9a54ec86171e1462"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered exempted transaction</header><text>The term <term>covered exempted transaction</term> means an offer or sale of a security that is—</text><subparagraph id="ide6f1d2a95c3b412fb3e7de18289ba618"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exempted under section 4 of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77d">15 U.S.C. 77d</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id36015dc2c6fe4a6b9b0882e84c20dbde"><enum>(B)</enum><text>structured or intended to comply with—</text><clause id="id63a9c777431547f3a38134a57f5aeabc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>section 230.506(b) of title 17, Code of Federal regulations, or any successor regulation;</text></clause><clause id="id139a4ac44baf4fe9b49252dc872a5380"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sections 230.901, 230.902, and 230.903 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulations; or</text></clause><clause id="ide8906961e8fd4289a7df0e4d6156e566"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>section 230.144A of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd6065e62614546e2a6d6b2b628d077ac"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><paragraph id="id9d2bfdb1790d48b79e766d42b5bc12cd"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in the case of an issuer that conducts a covered exempted transaction described in paragraph (2), that issuer shall provide to the Commission, at such time and in such manner as the Commission may prescribe, the following information:</text><subparagraph id="id6c96d98763334a0bae5271eea1178559"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The identity of the issuer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id199fcacb636b4cc7bda87acf05176e6f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The place of incorporation of the issuer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id32bfcc17e74c4678a36eaf659538e90b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the issuer is associated with at least 1 consolidated entity, the plurality of the assets of which are in a country of concern.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d23048ce91a4f069162019d5984e5da"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Whether the issuer is associated with at least 1 consolidated entity that is incorporated in a country of concern.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id57b0f913653048c594fe8644a5f6b577"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The amount of securities sold pursuant to the covered exempted transaction and the net proceeds to the issuer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id65c789fabf4d4c81a8791ce001be72c7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The beneficial owners of the issuer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2a37bca2972547529ec482d7ccd1ef4a"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The intended use of the proceeds from the covered exempted transaction, including each country in which the issuer intends to invest those proceeds, which shall be broken down by the percentage of net proceeds by industry within each such country.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id67346f6a394049d98ff8e12a2bef102c"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The exemption the issuer relies on with respect to the covered exempted transaction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd3fe7688305547e79e78f4abdde5f433"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Particular covered exempted transaction described</header><text>A covered exempted transaction described in this paragraph is, with respect to the issuer offering or selling the security that is the subject of the covered exempted transaction, either of the following instances:</text><subparagraph id="idf56b4d41b19344b59f77d321ac34cf27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An offer or sale of securities in an amount that is not less than $25,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf7a1a970ce6e47e9902c7a92af5a3e3e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An offer or sale of a security such that the offer or sale, together with all covered exempted transactions by that issuer during the 1-year period preceding the date on which the issuer offers or sells the security, constitutes offers or sales in the aggregate of an amount that is not less than $50,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1662983906c245db9ac15f283259ffb8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To revise and promulgate rules, regulations, and forms</header><text>The Commission shall, for the protection of investors and fair and orderly markets—</text><paragraph id="idd2e607c09f2b432f9d590fd2e02e4783"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revise and issue such rules, regulations, and forms as may be necessary to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a2fe58134314f79b66e34c284934503"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue rules to set conditions that limit the future use of covered exempted transactions for issuers that do not comply with the disclosure requirements of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id35c99c473eea4ed39895ad4cbcabaea5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>This section shall apply with respect to any covered exempted transaction that occurs on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id049f73bd0c114443bceea684e95c476c"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Commission shall, on a quarterly basis, prepare and make publicly available a report that includes all information submitted by an issuer under this section during the quarter covered by the report, if that issuer—</text><paragraph id="id9c2fb56ab4254b678186e0df0399c753"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is—</text><subparagraph id="id4b9afc29c81b45f3b13ce45e8710a353"><enum>(A)</enum><text>incorporated in a country of concern; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id076b0c1487f241ee9d64f6124629197e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporated outside of a country of concern and is associated with at least 1 consolidated entity—</text><clause id="id87881d1fda0a4f74b9c9f65594fa4830"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the plurality of the assets of which are in a country of concern; or</text></clause><clause id="id51c9fa75af9847ba83576335a9b5c7e2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is incorporated in a country of concern; or</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb87cb2d56f9148d08c56ceba0368e8f2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>discloses in a filing made pursuant to this section that the issuer intends to invest the proceeds from a covered exempted transaction in a country of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

