<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B3AB743AA6C49859AA2B0489806F50B" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 945 IH: Congratulating Vermont Green Football Club on winning the United Soccer League Two National Championship.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 945</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating Vermont Green Football Club on winning the United Soccer League Two National Championship.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text> Whereas, on August 2, 2025, Vermont Green Football Club (in this preamble referred to as <quote>Vermont Green FC</quote> and the <quote>Boys in Green</quote>) secured a 2–1 win against Seattle’s Ballard Football Club at Virtue Field in front of approximately 5,000 fans, securing an undefeated season and earning the team its first national title and the nickname <quote>The Invincibles</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this win marks the second year in a row that a Vermont-based soccer team has won a national championship;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas several players from the University of Vermont’s 2024 Division I National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) men’s soccer championship team further represented the Green Mountain State through their play with Vermont Green FC;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, having only entered United Soccer League's (referred to in this preamble as <quote>USL</quote>) League Two in 2022, the Boys in Green were undefeated across 24 matches and earned a first-place finish in the Northeast Division in the 2025 season;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Maximilian Kissel scored the winning goal for Vermont Green FC in the championship game, just 8 months after doing the same for the University of Vermont in the 2024 Division I NCAA championship game;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Vermont Green FC has shown a commitment to building a soccer community that reflects the values of Vermonters;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas fans of the Boys in Green and all Vermonters congratulate Vermont Green FC for its well-deserved championship and for representing the values of everyday Vermonters;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Vermont Green FC has solidified Vermont as a soccer State, as its victory was the product of hard work, dedication, and belief; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Boys in Green made Vermont very proud: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H6AB64AC75E014CAFBF97F2991AF1D1A6"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H87453B4AC7AA4CB39C2C26D6233CF98B"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H055BC66C42574F3681798ECEDA585F32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>congratulates the Vermont Green Football Club (referred to in this resolution as <quote>Vermont Green FC</quote>) for an incredible season and for winning the United Soccer League Two National Championship;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC2697B3F50647A8901FE49D7A68CDBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the achievements of all players, coaches, and staff who contributed to the team’s success; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE41E7E719874DF3AA7E2F230D01737C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>respectfully requests that the Clerk of the House of Representatives transmit an enrolled copy of this resolution to—</text> <subparagraph id="H71B9C01E70334109ADB965D83D896031"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the head coach, Chris Taylor;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H866CC043318445AF941EDFCFD821254C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sporting director of the Vermont Green FC; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H297560EC39C24020AD7949042A518F72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Vermont Green FC founders, Sam Glickman, Patrick Infurna, and Matthew Wolff.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

