<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H294458EFD5224AF798A1A4987639A6C6" public-private="public" resolution-type="constitutional-amendment" star-print="no-star-print" key="H">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HJ 199 IH: Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to temporarily fill vacancies in the House of Representatives to further the continuity of Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code display="yes">IA</distribution-code>
        <congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session display="yes">2d Session</session>
        <legis-num display="yes">H. J. RES. 199</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
        <action display="yes">
            <action-date date="20260702">July 2, 2026</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</sponsor> (for himself and
                    <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>) submitted the following
                joint resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type>
        <official-title display="yes">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United
            States to temporarily fill vacancies in the House of Representatives to further the
            continuity of Congress.</official-title>
    </form>
    <resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFA7982AF0D264B1782F865474D8C29F4">
        <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5EFCBA47B3FA4426A3E571FDEE6F62A7">
 <text>That the following article is proposed as an amendment to the Constitution of the United States, which shall be valid to all intents and purposes as part of the Constitution when ratified by the legislatures of three-fourths of the several States within seven years after the date of its submission for ratification:</text>
            <quoted-block style="traditional" id="HCA767E3214464408A02F000B41271CDB" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                <constitution-article id="H570A0D0640BC4C12BCF310645753D0AE">
                    <enum> —</enum>
                    <section id="H682F3E0F44C54C3C8511DAB2CF947A2A" section-type="section-one" display-inline="no-display-inline">
                        <enum>1.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immediately after taking the oath of office, an individual who is elected to serve as a Representative in the House of Representatives shall provide the House of Representatives with a list of at least five designees to take the individual's place in the event the individual dies prior to the expiration of the individual’s term of office. The individual shall ensure that the list only contains the names of designees who meet the qualifications for service as a Representative in the House of Representatives. </text>
                    </section>
                    <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA04E3D035B74A99A55E6ADD0B52E94D" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>2.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event of the death of a Representative, the chief executive of the State involved shall, not later than 10 days after the date of the death of the Representative, select an individual from the most recent list of designees provided by the Representative whose seat is now vacant, as provided by section 1, and the Speaker of the House shall immediately fill the vacancy with the individual selected. An individual designated to take the place of a Representative shall serve until another Member is elected to fill the vacancy pursuant to a special election.</text>
                    </section>
                    <section id="H9583369FE0304BE1BF041B67F23A74C2" section-type="section-one">
                        <enum>3.</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period of an individual’s service under section 2, the individual shall be treated as a Representative in the House of Representatives for purposes of all laws, rules, and regulations, including for purposes of section 1. In the event of the death of an individual designated under section 2, the chief executive of the State involved shall select an individual from the most recent list of designees provided by the individual designated under section 2, as provided by section 1, and the Speaker of the House shall immediately fill the vacancy with the individual selected.</text>
                    </section>
                </constitution-article>
                <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
        </section>
    </resolution-body>
</resolution>

