<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H53AE63CE10AE48709D97FF1AE73B8D42" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9389 IH: Nutrition Education and Chronic Disease Prevention in Community Health Centers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9389</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize funding for nutrition education and chronic disease prevention at federally qualified health centers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24AF7652839F4ECA80EDB01187B37BB8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAAF85CC9CBA34E0F9AFF74B9423B23BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nutrition Education and Chronic Disease Prevention in Community Health Centers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC75BF3FAE9EC4B5BBA48B52F4F2C778A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Nutrition education and chronic disease prevention at federally qualified health centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 330 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2BB950FDC6104366BABB2DDA4D09A22A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (r) as subsection (s); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73A762B91EFE460B80BFBCBC07DB6E24"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (q) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA417A994C36A4295BF2566CA59B1F1EB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H9EF112E09634487EBE9B4CC64BF0E206"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Nutrition education and chronic disease prevention initiative</header> 
<paragraph id="H5386290629A54F3688AD7A8C49D0844D">
              <enum>(1)</enum>
              <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall support health centers in integrating and expanding evidence-based nutrition education and counseling into primary care delivery and workforce training.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92F94F657B6A4C969F0408127B572AA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary may utilize existing funding, made available under section 10503(a)(1) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to award a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, and may provide technical assistance, to a health center for—</text> <subparagraph id="HF26E3A3661304F4DA8C896550941CE1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>patient-centered nutrition education and counseling services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF00B54BF56794E69ABEB593581328ACA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integration of nutrition assessment and dietary counseling into chronic disease management;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF2284985AC74D4EB120EC038549F3BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training and continuing education in nutrition science and dietary counseling for health center providers in health centers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H69801FBC31A844A7AD6F5A4F4F96EC89"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining interdisciplinary models of care that incorporate registered dietitians, community health workers, and other appropriate professionals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50965DF328704D7091C8C85D187A841A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>developing culturally and linguistically appropriate nutrition education materials; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31087CCC63E74DE89C7099AE2A86D43D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>evaluating clinical and cost outcomes associated with nutrition interventions.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H64725B031F414812B3FA0CCC3C5D8C52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participation of affiliated entities</header><text>A health center may affiliate with an academic medical center or medical school in carrying out activities receiving assistance under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H223D7A46A38E40E5AE374A7B2B9B4745"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making awards under this subsection, the Secretary shall prioritize health centers serving populations with high rates of diet-related chronic disease, food insecurity, or other nutrition-related health disparities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F314D972B784DA6B1F4DB488850C76B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available to carry out this subsection shall supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, local, or private funding used for similar purposes.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20F631946F35484DAE0E372088DB0C1E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of the Nutrition Education and Chronic Disease Prevention in Community Health Centers Act of 2026, and annually thereafter through fiscal year 2031, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="HDD569FEED57142E1909D6F7BE678C5F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describes the use of funds under this subsection;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8802A89E1644198A6C3B264292C47DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluates improvements in patient outcomes related to chronic disease indicators attributable to activities receiving assistance under this subsection;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6CF4BEFA7BD64B169A1AB0F995C09006"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assesses improvements in workforce training participation and competency development attributable to activities receiving assistance under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4F739A3EDD04351A42043F1FF568E65"><enum>(D)</enum><text>estimates potential cost savings to Federal health care programs attributable to nutrition interventions receiving assistance under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

