<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9B182FCDCC5541B9996D0F97457F4C10" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7860 IH: Stop ACA Enrollment Fraud Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7860</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to address fraudulent enrollments in the Exchanges.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H041DF63EEB3D42EA808EF11E0CE959A3" style="OLC"><section id="HEB9A5BDA923E47208F6B34BD70B90A6E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop ACA Enrollment Fraud Act of 2026</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HD978EA2CDE114E6A8259B1226328D8B3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preventing duplicate enrollments in Exchanges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1411 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18081">42 U.S.C. 18081</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H15619643B9C348BA8C6A59AEE549F180" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3FD9F533FB5A461EB7FA59199CBF81B1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Preventing duplicate enrollments</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H6AD98B21A61C4DFFAFF1B5ED10562943"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, as part of the program established under subsection (a), a process for identifying whether the social security number provided by an individual who is to be covered in the individual market by a qualified health plan offered through an Exchange is identical to the social security number of any enrollee in any Exchange under this title enrolled for the same period in which such coverage is to be effective; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DF4BC5D3039416A8532EBF0E200F369"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case that identical social security numbers are so identified under <internal-xref idref="H6AD98B21A61C4DFFAFF1B5ED10562943" legis-path="(j)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, take such actions as are necessary to ensure that duplicative advance payments of premium tax credits under section 1412 are not made with respect to an individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD34CDF08DD4045CB839EB09C7A5CDF9F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ensuring consent for agent and broker enrollments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1312(e) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18032">42 U.S.C. 18032(e)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H11B31B43DC5B48D69E2DEFA504BCD321"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA70B3BD99274E5CBE0F38E391B15E36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>The Secretary shall establish</quote> and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE1CD0B289DBF4E079D05E1AF926EB1EC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H8F22B3A64A114DC9940312C202F2F29D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD08667B4E1D74233A69F7F1BE56FAD92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB0EEBCDBB1664CC1B3947402AC2F69B0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE23BA171921E49B192CE26AA2FA37AA5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consent</header><subparagraph id="H27C2BE8E5D31449FB715F5B2CACE7C95"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The procedures established under paragraph (1) shall provide that, with respect to the enrollment of individuals and employers in qualified health plans in the individual or small group market offered through an Exchange for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2027, no such enrollment made through an agent or broker is effectuated prior to such individual or employer (as applicable) consenting to such enrollment through the mechanism established by the Secretary under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACB3B1F325564981B53DB35E996C2ECD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consent mechanism</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the mechanism described in this subparagraph is a mechanism established and operated by the Secretary under which an individual or employer gives consent with respect to an enrollment of such individual or employer described in such subparagraph. Such mechanism may not accept an attestation of such individual’s consent provided by the agent or broker enrolling such individual or employer as evidence of such individual’s or employer’s consent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

