<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF77449497C0F4D379724D3D688C8EB2A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7830 IH: Women Expansion of Learning and Labor Safety Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7830</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require hospitals to develop discharge plans for pregnant individuals as a condition of participation under Medicare, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD8412B4E4E7E473B940320BD2771C1C5" style="OLC"><section id="H3EB33FD3BC0E454584FAD1A4AD849251" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women Expansion of Learning and Labor Safety Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WELLS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD67047FD946F4411B6D230C408AD7A85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring hospitals participating in Medicare to develop discharge plans for pregnant individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1866 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395cc">42 U.S.C. 1395cc</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBE2140B070134932841A7B80B21EBA82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HC2231EBD5B804EC2A9E55AC55751B493"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (X), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD6A042DB0464E6AADB015085C115F2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Y), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55679F59D99C44F2AD70DB3547E0F2F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF3526F8AE9E34C4186A03346AB427A9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H4CBC426D16A24896B7C7004817876D7B"><enum>(Z)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning January 1, 2027, in the case of a hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital, to comply with the requirements described in subsection (l)(1).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2550696D1C34A17B15CD4FF4270FE58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAB2B7611D9C14D7D9BF1225A3372170D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H920EAAE9FFB64B23B4ECF4048FFBF227"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Discharge plan requirements for pregnant individuals</header><paragraph id="HFF49D0615CDA4CD99DD5FDD2706B4C2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(Z), the requirements described in this paragraph are, with respect to a hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital, that the hospital—</text><subparagraph id="H3424D2AA0BF345B8B4806FCE06A19373" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for the development and implementation of a discharge plan meeting the standards under <internal-xref idref="H735021F4496B40B2823FA666FC826EC2" legis-path="(l)(2)">paragraph (2)</internal-xref> with respect to any individual (whether or not eligible for benefits under this title) admitted to the hospital who—</text><clause id="H6071EE38844B457499080A6CCF26E2FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is identified as pregnant;</text></clause><clause id="H9CDB6C0D197E42D98F25FF1923586CB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is experiencing signs or symptoms consistent with labor, which may include contractions; and</text></clause><clause id="HB89C40E1E65D493B8DC36C136D2A2BF6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is expected to be discharged from the hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital prior to delivery, as determined based on the documented clinical judgment of the treating physician or practitioner at the time that such discharge is contemplated;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC95818EC43747569D6AAEF57D53F038"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes such discharge plan in the individual’s medical record; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CE50BDA61754704ABF7C981936FBA5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides for such discharge plan to be discussed with the individual (or the individual’s representative) prior to discharge.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H735021F4496B40B2823FA666FC826EC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discharge plan standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A discharge plan for an individual described in <internal-xref idref="H3424D2AA0BF345B8B4806FCE06A19373" legis-path="(l)(1)(A)">paragraph (1)(A)</internal-xref> meets the standards under this paragraph if such plan includes at least the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H3CC0EFF6D4774C5BBA9A2A3E9DDC0D9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A clinical justification for the discharge.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE978380A08BE4ABFA444AE9503F5F6AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of travel distance and time between the primary residence of the individual and the hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H436B92EAD63B46A4924E199CE7ACC012"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Verification of reliable transportation between the primary residence of the individual and the hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BDF0F4A934F43DFA3A02DAAA2756AC8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of a back-up hospital or facility at which such individual may obtain labor and delivery services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9FA9529646C493298BC6164F1888987"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Confirmation that the plan was reviewed and approved by a qualified medical professional (as defined by the Secretary through regulations).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07747456A19544E7A5E583A6308A2462"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Confirmation that the individual (or the individual’s representative) has received the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (D), that such information was provided in the primary language of such individual (or representative), and that such individual (or representative) confirmed their understanding of such information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88C69F09975B4EA49A64115318901BEE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting or otherwise affecting the discharge planning requirements otherwise applicable to a hospital, critical access hospital, or rural emergency hospital under this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H32917E71BFC34B9C8BEF8026F6574F7A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rural maternal and obstetric care training demonstration grants</header><subsection id="H0397DEF1D4DF40A5BB0BFB8F4F00514B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first section 764 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294s">42 U.S.C. 294s</external-xref>; relating to rural maternal and obstetric care training demonstration) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBD84985D986D449692B2C5E6BBB79E4B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H60DB21A5D74B4CCAA897BD2ACF53C0F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4320CF7E62F49BCA081295B52B4C293"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41CBD6FA7D9340C4ABA07F8C0EAEE614"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE0508511CD8F4C5B8BAC98E2099297FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H337AE7F09E404801BEAA60D087229B9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall use the grant funds to provide racial bias training as part of such training program; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4530D5572751484D82EFA280CFF68618"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (e) and (f), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBBD163091B7408CB9F2B24334EA12E8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CB0FB8EAD5E4D7AAD64224082930B6C"><subsection id="H82379DBFC657495FB9C741F63600CFB0" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Minimum performance milestones</header><paragraph id="H803C921D852944C088C8FAC740AFA92D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Beginning with the grants awarded under this section for fiscal year 2027, the Secretary shall establish minimum performance milestones that grant recipients must meet during a fiscal year as a condition of remaining eligible for funding through such a grant for any subsequent fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5C277DDE587435AA516D10753476DAD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Milestones related to percent of staff trained</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The minimum performance milestones referred to in paragraph (1) shall include milestones related to the percent of all staff of the grant recipient that are trained, or that receive refresher training, with support from a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0AA0113C22D41B8A55AF40AB9954EC3" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="HF694034D98FA47DE97D751D651A5F552" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">report</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">reports</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65F59BFD158948BB91FB7DBB72EFBF2D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B), by striking <quote>the report described in paragraph (2)</quote> and inserting <quote>the reports described in paragraphs (2) and (3)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5212C46B52584D28B813C5D32DA3C86D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC747A63DD2F2451882E6A886B1B0C1BE"><paragraph id="H6079C1E676514DC6AA00CBD65388D283" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2027, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H7EBFFA4519154F9483D6A7FC8AA9C1BD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>updates to the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H938814FC18CA47F2866E675D8D661BB5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>additional information regarding the grants under this section, including—</text><clause id="H41414ED4A394451DAEE89A6D78C4AE97" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of the entities receiving such grants;</text></clause><clause id="H854A9828B4F64129823F42331E53E9BF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number and amount of such grants;</text></clause><clause id="H20732B4DA01548DEB49B4F9711A0CE74"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether training supported by such grants was delivered in-person, virtually, asynchronously, or through some other format; and</text></clause><clause id="HF0C96AE4BC6646F1B678B57596ACEC5D" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">descriptions of the geographical coverage of such grants, the number of providers trained under such grants, and patient-level metrics linked to such training (such as changes in clinical outcomes, patient experience, and racial disparities). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6ADDF682AD694E8F88912241B5768393" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The second section 764 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294t">42 U.S.C. 294t</external-xref>; relating to programs to promote mental health among the health professional workforce) is redesignated as section 764A.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3E6B77989A4C40C5AD4DB69B81EDCF62" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Multi-center implementation science initiative for maternal health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall establish a multi-center implementation science initiative for maternal health to rigorously evaluate different training models for health care professionals (including in-person, virtual, simulation, and cohort-based) and the impact of such models on provider behavior, patient outcomes, and maternal health disparities.</text></section><section id="HC3B6234B4C4146DCB6AA71824535ACC5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Maternal health dashboard</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop, maintain, and make publicly available on the websites of the Department of Health and Human Services an interagency maternal health dashboard, which shall include maternal health outcome metrics from agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services and the data collected as part of the initiative under section 4, such as data related to maternal mortality and severe maternal morbidity, the number and outcomes of discharges of pregnant individuals prior to delivery from institutions, and data on Federal investments in maternal health research.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

