<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD310A1DA99CC41E5B7DF8CBBA30743F8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6654 IH: Veterans Affairs Management and Oversight of Software Assets Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6654</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and implement a comprehensive policy for managing software assets throughout the Department, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1AA6F09538FC40378635E5745D75F596" style="OLC"><section id="H96C71D8DCED0442B85A480A7228E8120" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Affairs Management and Oversight of Software Assets Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VAMOSA Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC029C3677164439B9ECDF6BCE80D5A88"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department-wide software asset management policy for the Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H33353A17AC284001ABBF959CB400AFA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HEF4B5DA428DA42E893A319184EB13E31" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HED6F210F9D254805955D8C3ED3FEFC3B"><enum>534.</enum><header>Department-wide software asset management policy</header><subsection id="HC3985B57BADA416981C8E3A99E46F3CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure coordination between the Chief Information Officer and such other officers as the Secretary considers appropriate to establish and implement a comprehensive policy for managing software assets.</text></subsection><subsection id="H523133B2503847C3A4B78E3AF040FDF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum elements</header><text>The policy required by subsection (a) shall, at a minimum, provide for the following:</text><paragraph id="H4ABF9B60CBDB41B1B550A7ACCCA7DA5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maintaining a comprehensive inventory of software assets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48BB02684B5A4BBFB98BC1FD011CCAF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assessing interoperability and license restrictions with respect to those assets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA469E235FD1645858759662DCAD84155"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Identifying and eliminating waste, fraud, and abuse, including by regularly comparing the inventory maintained under paragraph (1) against purchase records, subscription records, vendor billing records, and contract files to identify discrepancies, over-procurement, redundant purchases, unauthorized use, and under-utilized licenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9803A4538C5940C2B31EA0FCC0BAD26B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Requiring that the Chief Information officer coordinate with the relevant officials in the Department regarding any significant acquisition of a software asset.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55B4C0668FBF48DC9FB4128DB68A3B18"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Adopting cost-effective licensing strategies, including enterprise-wide agreements where practicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3157FEDF633C4580A03E2E3DAE66BA76"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Measuring and enforcing compliance with license terms.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF4ED95152944F97A0BB10E54018BF9F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reviews and updates</header><text>Not less than once every three years, the Chief Information Officer, in consultation with the Chief Financial Officer and any other appropriate officials of the Department, or their designees, shall review and update the policy.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDBAE5D073A914717926B02C4B16F2BF3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that each employee responsible for acquiring, managing, or implementing software assets receives training no less often than annually on matters relevant to their duties, including such matters as—</text><paragraph id="HA42E0924460F4F358F42ADC5CD1B79CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">negotiating contract terms to minimize vendor-imposed restrictions on deployment, data access, and transferability;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEA3F76A58D84AD69033F0A15E7C810B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the differences between acquiring commercial software and custom software development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8287FEA55BED47E58546F6844C0FA53E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluating cost models for seat-based, consumption-based, enterprise, or scalable license structures.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40E4D902995B454E87D0E11229F5DEA7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of existing resources</header><text>This section shall be implemented using existing personnel, systems, and funds. This section does not authorize additional appropriations or the establishment of a new program, office, or organizational entity.</text></subsection><subsection id="H369F2660DD1C47D2A1A8C634B9C162B9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Secretary shall include, in the annual report submitted to Congress under section 529 of this title—</text><paragraph id="H374A799765994B239676C737B7412B36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of any substantive updates to the policy made during the preceding year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E38BC3B07BF4A9DA716D5545E93C12E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimate of cost savings realized from implementation of the policy during the preceding year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB6A2BF2341C4536A88F7C5ED4280284"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H957FB2EA158D4F988CFB78EDAAF0CB1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>comprehensive inventory of software assets</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HC4B32762416540F0BD0BAB7F2F6040E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="HD3C6FF710DFB4EFB9512D70319634509"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the comprehensive inventory of software licenses required by section 2(b)(2)(A) of the Making Electronic Government Accountable By Yielding Tangible Efficiencies Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/210">Public Law 114–210</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/11302">40 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref> note) and any directive issued by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget under that Act; and</text></clause><clause id="HA902E74EBE66453797A2663A1E814ECF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a comprehensive inventory of all other software assets (as defined in this section); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1777A4C42E0949FB948994B177C6EC3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reflects all accounts, subscriptions, tenants, deployments, and associated license or usage entitlements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A320370F2C94C28B2B436F3D9DCF733"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>software asset</quote> means any software, software-as-a-service (SaaS) product, cloud-based service, platform service, or application programming interface (API) service for which the Department incurs a cost to acquire, license, subscribe, operate, or maintain, whether hosted on Government-managed or vendor-managed infrastructure. The term includes any associated software license, subscription, usage right, seat entitlement, capacity allocation, or consumption-based entitlement that governs access to or use of such software functionality.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97D18322F29C482696E30C0BF70F2A71"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The requirements and authorities of this section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of the VAMOSA Act.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB5625E2410ED4DA5A35E1DBCEEA5ACBE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 533 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2C486CD216214A249E1988597BA9D2E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">534. Department-wide software asset management policy.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H24476AD466FF49259157F050AAC21402"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report evaluating—</text><paragraph id="H2E0F45BCA8C043AD850DEDB37455557D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Department’s implementation of section 534 of title 38, United States Code, as added by this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84BEB6B55FE84434B02FC50F09275C53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost savings achieved and duplication reduced; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BDC72E698104B6492F867D4CF8BAE9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the degree of operational independence and conflict avoidance in any contractor support used to perform inventory management or entitlement reconciliation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

