<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-ELM26085-K1W-ML-802"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 804 ATS: Commemorating the tenth anniversary of the 2016 West Virginia floods.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 804</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the tenth anniversary of the 2016 West Virginia floods.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 23, 2016, several rounds of thunderstorms brought severe rainfall throughout West Virginia;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the <quote>thousand-year event</quote> resulted in devastating floods across the State and flash flooding caused 23 fatalities;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the Governor of West Virginia declared a State of Emergency in 44 of 55 West Virginia counties and the President declared a major disaster under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>);</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas the storms inflicted catastrophic damage, estimated at $1,200,000,000;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas more than 500,000 people lost power, and thousands of homes and businesses were either damaged or destroyed;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas roads and bridges were washed out, and multiple schools were completely destroyed;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas communities across West Virginia were entirely underwater;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas countless first responders and neighbors stepped in to protect residents of affected communities; and</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas West Virginia communities have shown great resilience and strength to rebuild homes, businesses, schools, and other sites affected by the floods: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idf57c958c05034621ab92b45d826d4c6c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates the tenth anniversary of the floods in West Virginia on June 23, 2016; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id793e992d19224987b0a80baa223174df"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">honors the West Virginians who lost their lives and those who were affected by the floods.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

