<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-LIP26630-MMY-P3-8RY"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4950 IS: Institute for Telecommunication Sciences Codification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4950</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to codify the Institute for Telecommunication Sciences, to direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to establish an initiative to support the development of emergency communication and tracking technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H743EB44E072240AE8334FF69F5F5EDB8"><section section-type="section-one" id="H1BB87A999A9149EEB2F5C6931BC116E4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Institute for Telecommunication Sciences Codification Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ITS Codification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9BACAF4883BA464486DDEA6868E6BD32"><enum>2.</enum><header>Institute for Telecommunication Sciences</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/901">47 U.S.C. 901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8EEF285A3D0441CBB91405B1489BFC9B"><section id="H0A3792830E7240F68FF0B5B5E973B0DF"><enum>106.</enum><header>Institute for Telecommunication Sciences</header><subsection id="H52AA86919C2A46E3A1779CD1DE34231D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7B72E06A1204222A9981129CBC83E23"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>Federal spectrum</term> means frequencies assigned on a primary basis to a Federal entity, as defined in section 113(l).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4CB70FE089347D9B1C529D898935B19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Operation</header><text>Under the authority provided to the Assistant Secretary under section 103, the Assistant Secretary shall operate a test center to be known as the Institute for Telecommunication Sciences (referred to in this section as <quote>ITS</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE231FEABC1A484E83C6A80E23D289C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions</header><subparagraph id="HE230987874B6449EB372EDD389AC1BAC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to any functions delegated by the Assistant Secretary under subparagraph (B), ITS shall serve as a laboratory for the executive branch of the Federal Government to—</text><clause id="H38D7FFD7A3D443D69150928A16BDFE48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>study radio frequency emissions, including technologies and techniques to control those emissions and interference caused by those emissions;</text></clause><clause id="H836B528B9D224013B2BC164DBB74602D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>study spectrum propagation characteristics;</text></clause><clause id="HBC54A2A00CC14016B62FADA5475A3A7A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conduct tests on technology that enhances the sharing of electromagnetic spectrum between Federal and non-Federal users;</text></clause><clause id="H6F9F4F29E5A643D38CAB9873EACC49E8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>examine the interference tolerance of Federal systems operating with, or using, Federal spectrum, in collaboration with other Federal laboratories examining such issues;</text></clause><clause id="HA7F044A3E68A48A59A2CBB5535094042"><enum>(v)</enum><text>analyze activities relating to access to Federal spectrum by non-Federal users and the sharing of Federal spectrum between Federal and non-Federal users; and</text></clause><clause id="HA94A36B910C441D9AAD273B35043D055"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>conduct such other activities determined necessary by the Assistant Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE70A224AF17467F88DD12699B533C7E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary may delegate to ITS the specific functions assigned to the Assistant Secretary under section 103(b)(1), as they relate to the responsibility for the performance of the communications and information functions of the Secretary, pursuant to that section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4CBFA70B6AB4B09BBB0CF120BD7D43C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Agreements and transactions</header><text>In carrying out the functions described in paragraph (3), the Assistant Secretary, acting through the head of ITS, may enter into agreements, as provided under the following authorities:</text><subparagraph id="HAA6828E82FFC468D91A34A7D2480B117"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 11 and 12 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3710">15 U.S.C. 3710</external-xref>, 3710a).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8653700B3A0245158FD283C0BA5B229D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 1535 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3913BF64451146B8B530F8FAEF8080B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Sections 207 and 209 of title 35, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E3245B976B341EE9F7CF3B0AE3F635B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The first undesignated section of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to authorize the Department of Commerce to make special studies, to provide services, and to engage in joint projects, and for other purposes</quote>, approved September 25, 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/412">Public Law 91–412</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC54F1CB32CBF4B65AC1A734B99C0EA84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency communication and tracking technologies initiative</header><paragraph id="H52294A47C59F443F851B7A4D33911D80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, acting through the head of ITS, shall establish an initiative to support the development of emergency communication and tracking technologies for use in locating trapped individuals in confined spaces (such as underground mines) and other shielded environments (such as high-rise buildings or collapsed structures) where conventional radio communication is limited.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H703D90C454F14FD395DC5C3273729BC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In order to carry out this subsection, the Assistant Secretary, acting through the head of ITS, shall work with private sector entities and the heads of appropriate Federal agencies to—</text><subparagraph id="H662D6E6F4B3F4D81A241E11937CA94FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>perform a needs assessment to identify and evaluate the measurement, technical specifications, and conformity assessment needs required to improve the operation and reliability of emergency communication and tracking technologies described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H675A96369F9D4C809700CEFF827CA78D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support the development of technical specifications and conformance architecture to improve the operation and reliability of emergency communication and tracking technologies described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BF2AE7033F441ACB03E551A3E971577"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report on the assessment performed under paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

