<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H75B6B1FF5D5945AE988B97223CEE314B" resolution-type="house-resolution"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1225 IH: Original Resolution Commending the Islamic Republic of Pakistan for its efforts to facilitate peace between the United States and Israel with Iran</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> 
<session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1225</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Commending the Islamic Republic of Pakistan for its efforts to facilitate peace between the United States and Israel with Iran.</official-title> 
</form> 
<preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this resolution may be cited as the “Original Resolution Commending the Islamic Republic of Pakistan for its efforts to facilitate peace between the United States and Israel with Iran”;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to Reuters, thousands of individuals have lost their lives as a result of the ongoing conflict between the United States and Israel with Iran, reflecting the significant and tragic human toll of the war;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas this number represents more than a statistic; it represents the lives of men, women, and children who cared for and were cared for in turn by their families, friends, communities, and nation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR), up to 3.2 million individuals have been displaced from their homes as a result of the ongoing conflict, placing severe strain on regional stability and international relief efforts;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas at least 13 members of the United States Armed Forces have been killed in action and more than 399 have been wounded so far, underscoring the direct cost of the war to U.S. servicemembers and their families;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the financial cost of the war to the United States has reached extraordinary levels, with credible estimates indicating expenditures of approximately $1 billion per day;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas an end to this conflict would benefit not only the countries currently at war and others in the Middle East, but also nations across the globe that have been negatively affected by the consequences of this war, especially on energy supplies and petroleum products worldwide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas several countries have attempted to mediate an end to the conflict between the United States and Israel with Iran, though only Pakistan has emerged as the key mediator, playing an integral role in facilitating negotiations;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Pakistan is seen as a neutral third party by all participants in the conflict, as well as a secure and reliable location for peace talks;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Pakistan has borne hardship, enacting citywide shutdowns to accommodate diplomatic delegations as a result of its peacemaking efforts;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Pakistan has clearly demonstrated its desire to facilitate an end to the war between the United States and Israel with Iran;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas further escalation of the conflict, including but not limited to United States ground forces being deployed in Iran (boots on the ground), would create strife, disunity, and turmoil within the United States of America; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas while there is still much work to be done to achieve a just and fair conclusion to this war that ensures a lasting peace, Pakistan has played an essential role in enabling constructive dialogue to bring about such a conclusion: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H8A2A5BEF30CA45F69BBED946A9FEE36D"> <section section-type="section-one" id="a1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header> <subsection id="s1"><enum></enum><text>This resolution may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Original Resolution Commending the Islamic Republic of Pakistan for its efforts to facilitate peace between the United States and Israel with Iran</short-title></quote>. </text></subsection></section> 
<section section-type="subsequent-section" id="a2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commending the Islamic Republic of Pakistan</header> 
<subsection id="s21"><enum></enum><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="p1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>acknowledges and commends the Islamic Republic of Pakistan for its efforts to facilitate a lasting peace between the United States and Israel with Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</resolution-body> 
</resolution> 


