<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H10F58B263B3E4D218575277BFE9CB2E9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8355 IH: Accountable Produce is Medicine Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8355</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test a model to reduce chronic diseases by using accountable produce is medicine.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC1D9E2BC17504D84995D95F7CE42AB29" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H38A6A78E21C64D3185B77BD23B5A42A1" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accountable Produce is Medicine Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HADF68CD5219A4139A221824B36B9A07C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H26F23A3876C841FBAE6E0BB09799A78A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">diet-related chronic diseases are a leading driver of health care costs in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C73FEAFD4C7468BA9CDA1EA339C8235"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evidence-based food is medicine interventions, including medically tailored meals, medically tailored groceries, produce prescriptions, and nutrition counseling, have the potential to improve health outcomes and reduce health care expenditures;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H312670E4BD104982B5DFE47B1FEE3440"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation should, to the extent practicable, incorporate such interventions, as appropriate, into models tested under section 1115A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DDA5C03F1FE47F2A8D9E81D2DF35627"><enum>(4)</enum><text>incorporating food is medicine interventions into Innovation Center models may improve quality of care, reduce costs, and support the prevention and management of chronic disease.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H872A6C03F71E49A29EFBA91BA408057E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requiring the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test a model to improve outcomes for patients with chronic diseases by using accountable produce is medicine</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1115A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8E07E6A381B842B581C69B4BC8E94D00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(A), by inserting <quote>, and, beginning not later than the date that is 180 days after the enactment of the <short-title>Accountable Produce is Medicine Act of 2026</short-title>, shall include the Accountable Produce is Medicine Bundled Payment Model described in subsection (h)</quote> before the period at the end; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D8B458714CD458B81E504FF185F0BAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H364A5BFF56084FA1BF900F2008A3D377" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H42523D2CC3AE4247B9A81F377C5DE702" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Accountable Produce is Medicine Bundled Payment Model</header> <paragraph id="H380CBC6BD01F4C0F868A89B3BE06CA99" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(2)(A), the Accountable Produce is Medicine Bundled Payment Model described in this subsection is a model under which bundled payment is made under title XVIII, title XIX, or title XXI, as appropriate, for selected programs to furnish Accountable Produce is Medicine services to eligible individuals.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB36400692EDD429B99B362CC04DC3632" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection of programs to participate</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9C9FDBF8B0D14A00A976C0B3413990DE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Selected programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select to participate in the model described under <internal-xref idref="H380CBC6BD01F4C0F868A89B3BE06CA99" legis-path="(h)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> at least 5 eligible programs, each to participate for a period of not less than 2 years, that the Secretary determines have the capacity to satisfy the requirements described in <internal-xref idref="H328133B1591642A9A929D105C498CC86" legis-path="(h)(3)">paragraph (3)</internal-xref>. In this subsection, each such eligible program so selected shall be referred to as a <quote>selected program</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC54484258DF949859A193D93EC60543C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting eligible programs under <internal-xref idref="H9C9FDBF8B0D14A00A976C0B3413990DE" legis-path="(h)(2)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall give priority to any such program that furnishes (including through an arrangement with a provider of services or supplier or other entity) fresh, frozen, or minimally processed fruits and vegetables without added sugars, sodium, or saturated fats (except those occurring naturally), and other plant-based, nutrient-dense foods, including nuts, seeds, intact whole grains, beans, and lentils.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H328133B1591642A9A929D105C498CC86" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minimum program requirements</header><text>Under the model under <internal-xref idref="H380CBC6BD01F4C0F868A89B3BE06CA99" legis-path="(h)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, a selected program shall comply with each of the following requirements:</text> <subparagraph id="HB7CED47519874817B50704F91E65834B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Screening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The selected program shall screen individuals who are referred to the program by a physician, hospital, or other health care provider, to determine whether such individuals are eligible individuals.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB84AD2F0227643C4B0FB3CE9E9A8EB3C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Accountable Produce is Medicine services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is determined by the selected program under <internal-xref idref="HB7CED47519874817B50704F91E65834B" legis-path="(h)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> to be an eligible individual, the selected program shall, for the 1-year period following such determination (subject to <internal-xref idref="H78DEF100A68F41A7A3085E6DB3BE99B5" legis-path="(h)(3)(D)">subparagraph (D)</internal-xref>), make available (including through an arrangement with a provider of services or supplier or other entity) to such individual the following services (in this subsection referred to as <quote>Accountable Produce is Medicine services</quote> or <quote>APIM services</quote>):</text> <clause id="H5671D20DAD76462BAD0260D5CE3321FB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A personalized health risk assessment and personalized prevention plan services.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H11C52DDF158E472893C62EF594F5F161" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Care coordination services.</text></clause> <clause id="H5EF8F8BACC154E9DBF5C8BDA2AAE61CE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Telehealth services related to chronic disease monitoring, education, and follow-up.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB53CFA7877D140CABDF7DB07506FB14C" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Remote patient monitoring items and services that are clinically appropriate for chronic disease monitoring and facilitate a timely response from a provider in the case that significant changes in such data are detected.</text></clause> <clause id="HA5969253AFD14A1D92EDB509A1821913" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lifestyle modification programs, including nutrition counseling provided by a registered dietician or other qualified provider, exercise programs, and smoking cessation counseling.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H66B124732FC7426F8BB934C8415BAF5A" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Healthy, nutrient-dense foods meeting such standards as the Secretary shall determine, with preference given to produce grown within 250 miles of the selected program or through the use of regenerative agriculture.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D64A7A81C8D4AE9BA52D243A6337152" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Collection of health data; reenrollment assessment</header><text>In the case of an individual who is determined by the selected program under <internal-xref idref="HB7CED47519874817B50704F91E65834B" legis-path="(h)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> to be an eligible individual, the selected program shall—</text> 
<clause id="H1D3837F9D2A7401FAB2D600BFCC2A083" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">track the APIM services that the individual has received from the program under the model;</text></clause> <clause id="HF61100D9412B45ABB9EDC7C6571F9080" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>regularly evaluate the individual’s engagement with the program and adherence to program requirements;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51685BE6D46C4462A3BFCAE3C1F2D58F" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on a quarterly basis collect from such individual updated weight, blood pressure, and blood glucose measurements, and any other measurements determined appropriate by the Secretary; and</text> </clause> <clause id="H40E13BCDF92D488DBCA3A716E15317A2" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the end of the 1-year period described in <internal-xref idref="HB84AD2F0227643C4B0FB3CE9E9A8EB3C" legis-path="(h)(3)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>—</text> 
<subclause id="H9EE2B9B6565C4D5C9F7472C0C668239B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>evaluate the measurements collected under <internal-xref idref="H51685BE6D46C4462A3BFCAE3C1F2D58F" legis-path="(h)(3)(C)(iii)">clause (iii)</internal-xref>;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H0C33A58E9617429ABDAEAD26BA72C34C"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Secretary such data as the Secretary determines necessary for purposes of evaluating the health care cost savings achieved for such individual during such period; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1C5184F3A9E546D497DDB15EFF37F05C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>provide for an additional determination under <internal-xref idref="HB7CED47519874817B50704F91E65834B" legis-path="(h)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> as to whether such individual remains an eligible individual.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78DEF100A68F41A7A3085E6DB3BE99B5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Disenrollment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual who is determined by the selected program under <internal-xref idref="HB7CED47519874817B50704F91E65834B" legis-path="(h)(3)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> to be an eligible individual, if the selected program determines (in accordance with standards established by the Secretary) before the end of the 1-year period described in <internal-xref idref="HB84AD2F0227643C4B0FB3CE9E9A8EB3C" legis-path="(h)(3)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref> that such individual is not adequately engaging with the program or is not adhering to program requirements, the selected program shall terminate the individual’s participation in the program and may not furnish any additional APIM services to such individual under the model.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC087F1CE72D243CEB5B853FC7C4779BE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Payment</header> 
<subparagraph id="H89FA1B6860B4405CBA37F35553C1B585" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine the form, manner, and amount of bundled payment to be provided to selected programs under the model under <internal-xref idref="H380CBC6BD01F4C0F868A89B3BE06CA99" legis-path="(h)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> and, beginning in the third year in which such model is carried out, may require that selected programs assume financial risk for performance under the model.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCEC0B9F42D94700B3757FCB8104CEF9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>APIM services furnished by a selected program to an eligible individual shall be provided without application of deductibles, copayments, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing under the applicable title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE26958A2627640FFBF7B5307E16DAE17"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The model described in <internal-xref idref="H380CBC6BD01F4C0F868A89B3BE06CA99" legis-path="(h)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> shall be carried out for a period of not less than 5 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H101785B3A7D44B718539FCDFE6E2ECA7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3C034E8CE7B94D65B4B275A7C9EBB84A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>The term <term>eligible individual</term> means an individual—</text> <clause id="H00036C466AAA4D68BAD4E94E7763F334" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who is—</text> 
<subclause id="H079EB679E84E4996922FA498D77613F5" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>entitled to benefits under part A of title XVIII or enrolled under part B of such title;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H51933D8F37E54F92AF890C35E0C759D2" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>enrolled under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H2C15BF576D1347D0A1073050BD9D162A" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>enrolled under a State child health plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XXI;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H39BA2178B89742A5A2B1E87DBDBF1E56" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who resides in a medically underserved area (as designated pursuant to section 330(b)(3)(A) of the Public Health Service Act), a rural area (as defined in section 1886(d)(2)(D)), a health professional shortage area described in section 332(a)(1)(A) of the Public Health Service Act, or another area determined appropriate by the Secretary;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4E7E97684BAC49FEB249E743E7CAC935" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has diabetes, obesity, cardiovascular disease, hypertension, malnutrition, or any other disease or chronic condition that the Secretary determines appropriate;</text></clause> <clause id="HCF2F8880256A402A80582AF2366CCAE6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the clinical judgment of a physician or other health care professional, who would benefit from participation in the model;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H393E0DFF0ABB49E58D61B281BA6EC3A5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>who the eligible program determines to be prepared to participate in the model; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3EE65C9228244C32ADBD01CC6AF7263D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is not already receiving items or services that the Secretary determines are substantially similar (and duplicative in purpose and clinical function) to the APIM services described in clause (v) of <internal-xref idref="HB84AD2F0227643C4B0FB3CE9E9A8EB3C" legis-path="(h)(3)(B)">paragraph (3)(B)</internal-xref>.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE6B3F0403A5245FFA5251B42F470E4F2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible program</header><text>The term <term>eligible program</term> means a provider of services or supplier enrolled in the program under title XVIII, title XIX, or title XXI.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H993F1D7447564EE9B24DEAAED534BC42"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regenerative agriculture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>regenerative agriculture</term> means a conservation management approach that emphasizes natural resources through improved soil health, water management, and natural vitality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

