<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F2886222D8C4BE09620F266B2906CF7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6479 IH: Puerto Rico Affordable Care Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6479</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require the establishment of an Exchange in Puerto Rico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F37AD89F5EE4945A64FD3BE5BA28723" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H991A54FA9B9C4868B5AFBA4A03356008" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puerto Rico Affordable Care Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC883B62E1086447EB2300CC65B4B6893"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring the establishment of an Exchange in Puerto Rico</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1304(d) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18024">42 U.S.C. 18024(d)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and, beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Puerto Rico Affordable Care Act of 2025</short-title>, Puerto Rico</quote> before the period.</text></section> 
<section id="H14AB88AD04DD4F2DB15BAF08E1AE7D5E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ensuring application of health insurance market reforms in Puerto Rico</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding the letter sent by the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to the Commissioner of Insurance of Puerto Rico on July 16, 2014, relating to the applicability of certain provisions of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg et seq.</external-xref>) in Puerto Rico, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, apply such provisions to health insurance coverage (as defined in section 2791 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91</external-xref>)) offered in Puerto Rico.</text></section> <section id="H25A74BFC4E194D88AF1E1731720FA929"><enum>4.</enum><header>Application of premium tax credits in Puerto Rico</header> <subsection id="HEC52700C7B5B40269CB79462A0662D3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">Section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i) and by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H865C10AAF5F6425D9B38EEAA9D72B371" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H776C2E7BFD09462294CAF6A65065F836"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Application of tax credit to residents of Puerto Rico</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsections (b)(2)(A), (b)(3)(C), (b)(3)(D)(ii), and (c)(2)(A)(i), Puerto Rico shall be treated in the same manner as a State.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H321746690ADF43CB98F89E456AB8CA22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to months beginning on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

