<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG26B29-0M5-ST-D6R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4682 IS: Ultimate Human Responsibility in Defense Systems Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4682</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish requirements for human judgment in the use of force by autonomous weapon systems used by the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ultimate Human Responsibility in Defense Systems Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id1710fe8acb5b42c9b33d45e5f38df981"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idb1ad0792219a43ce867459eec4458d28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Autonomous weapon system</header><text>The term <term>autonomous weapon system</term> means a weapon system that, once activated, can select and engage targets without further intervention by a human operator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4ac1259b235b45eea53983eab5a0c93d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6bca298b3c3e41379b40924cf11d4443"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Ultimate human responsibility</header><text>The term <term>ultimate human responsibility</term>, with respect to a weapon system, means the ability of a human commander or operator to exercise informed human agency—</text><subparagraph id="id09ad14920eaf4aaba7462268e8b1ed7f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to understand the operational context of the weapon system through training, capacity building, and integration of design and testing features that strengthen human understanding and effective oversight;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide2f089c24d39430d81fd11a0f1b10940"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to supervise, intervene in, or terminate the use of force by the system, thereby guaranteeing human responsibility when appropriate given system design; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11483c64e9464e8a931dd5f61dc4f406"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with all applicable United States law and international law, including applicable treaties, weapon system safety rules, the law of armed conflict, and rules of engagement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb7569d391d04115a8fd2bfd9f8dcc66"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of force</header><text>The term <term>use of force</term> means the application of kinetic lethal or non-lethal military force against a target.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idbea3849454154415b9d4b0649c901871"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirement for human judgment in autonomous weapon systems</header><subsection id="id10cece3d638c4a5d9d6c68ad494151ad"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Policy requirement</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45e04248b446408db7e715ada87f6d70"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that any autonomous weapon system or artificial intelligence capability developed, acquired, or operated by the Department of Defense—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id222bb7b4f0c444d7871ddcec6efe1263"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is designed and employed in a manner that enables commanders and operators to exercise ultimate human responsibility over the use of force; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf3bd0956201e484db09e9b101350fe10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is developed, fielded and employed using ethical and legal principles that would delineate unlawful uses of artificial intelligence; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id53dd0e11d7ac4844969962e97f4e0443"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop technical and operational and organizational guidelines around the use of artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id17d433805fce433e845d8cef514e9be4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design requirements</header><text>To meet the requirements under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that any autonomous weapon system or artificial intelligence capability described in such subsection, to the maximum extent practicable—</text><paragraph id="id7d0822ab36cd4b1aa2f4dfc8bc9beff9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allows human operators to supervise the operation of the weapon system during mission execution when appropriate given system design;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id50a4734978c94621a3ef91db9c2c9096"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes mechanisms that allow commanders or operators to intervene in or terminate the use of force by the weapon system during mission execution when appropriate given system design;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf8f3f6c094ee4df89d62d1a1e2986fe9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes fail-safe mechanisms to enable manual control when autonomous systems are degraded, jammed, spoofed, or under adversarial attack when appropriate given system design;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41233c61e11548b5be56288e69118425"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides sufficient information regarding weapon system status and decision logic to enable operators to understand, oversee, and exercise functional control over system behavior;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1b9c88bafe543c3a52bd1667db599a9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>maintains records of relevant target selection data, decision logic, and human operator actions sufficient to enable post-engagement review of compliance with the requirements under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideb4c9e4f789141539f4326bda9cf5f32"><enum>(6)</enum><text>operates consistent with applicable United States law and international law, rules of engagement, the law of armed conflict, applicable treaties, and Department of Defense policy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id69236731244943f594ead21c005401a7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Operational oversight</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc2dde1ab0b54e60b7d06c839f1dcab1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures to ensure that commanders and operators are rigorously trained to appropriately supervise autonomous weapon systems or artificial intelligence capabilities in operational environments, including regular proficiency assessments in manual target identification, threat assessment, and engagement procedures, to ensure operators can effectively execute missions using other capabilities when autonomous systems are unavailable or unreliable.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc6e1ec25c5a4e94a28168aba79b815b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting mechanism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The procedures established under paragraph (1) shall include a mechanism for operators of autonomous weapon systems or artificial intelligence capability to report, without fear of reprisal, concerns regarding weapon system reliability or the adequacy of human-machine interfaces.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idfd399b342503466783574ae2f060302e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review and certification</header><subsection id="idc7833a191b3a4255babbb8fbe1542e7a"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Senior-Level review</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7406d327edeb4140afa67be83d0c7ff3"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before fielding an autonomous weapon system capable of independently selecting and engaging targets without human supervision, the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation shall conduct a review to certify that the weapon system complies with the requirements of this Act.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id217ac1a04fbc4a6ab1bf4900759cc0fe">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Independent assessment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each review required under paragraph (1) with respect to an autonomous weapon system shall include an independent adversarial testing (<quote>red-team</quote>) assessment that evaluates the vulnerability of the system to adversarial manipulation under operationally realistic conditions, including degraded and electronic warfare contested environments (such as jamming and spoofing), communication disruption, and adversarial manipulation.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="ida2a42614a3894971a5cca9ed52f99549"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification requirement</header><text>No autonomous weapon system described in subsection (a) may be fielded by the Department of Defense unless the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation certifies that the weapon system—</text><paragraph id="id6f36d3d46bba4f8fbd29204530dbfe67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>allows for ultimate human responsibility with respect to the use of force; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfab271404ffd44d8819a64be06db8f0a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has been tested to verify secure, safe, and reliable operations that meet the reliability standards of the Department for weapon systems, including retesting following any significant software update or change in operational environment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb9e4a4b29d7c4d9bab035baca3f7fff3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Testing standards</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40e83ef8b16e40b89eb3edc5611c3816"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation shall publish on a publicly available website standards for the testing and evaluation of artificial intelligence components in autonomous weapon systems, including benchmarks for reliability, robustness, security, and human-machine team performance.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id680fbbe9228b466a80d694db50e36193"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standards required to be published under paragraph (1) shall be published in unclassified form to the maximum extent practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id3f51c2767f184fe5892d9f847962c10c"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual reporting to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and semiannually thereafter until the date that is six years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="idd5db4666cc87475a865a5b75ee0dcf5d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of autonomous weapon systems in development or fielded by the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e62c543fc5e4120992343ef09b798b3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>steps taken by the Secretary to ensure compliance with the requirements of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide30c5d0eb93544b081ebf5e3ecec2b5f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such recommendations as the Secretary may have for legislative or administrative action relating to human judgment in autonomous weapon systems.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida9a542ff65364215aa5def42a199cc7b"><enum>6.</enum><header>Autonomous weapon system incident repository</header><subsection id="id3d13bfe06b924c66ace621c320476773"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish and maintain a centralized repository for reporting, collecting, and analyzing incidents involving autonomous weapon systems and artificial intelligence capabilities used by the Department of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection id="id3d1cd8f6387b4e6394b5f514618e42d0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The repository established under subsection (a) shall be used—</text><paragraph id="idfeb6e9389f554179ac5a327b84a6cb30"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to document operational incidents, weapon system failures, unintended weapon system behaviors, or near-miss events involving autonomous weapon systems and artificial incident capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb5e670aa46df48328db4dd5c0c317b10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to enable the Department to identify systemic risks, software errors, or operational vulnerabilities associated with such weapon systems and capabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1bf0c4ad612c42cdbdb15431916e820e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to promote institutional learning and improvement in the design, testing, and operational employment of autonomous weapon systems and artificial intelligence capabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idde7f6a9529684b3aa98cdc5cfeb6940c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall establish procedures requiring the reporting of incidents described in subsection (b)(1), including—</text><paragraph id="id9ac21748b7244eff9fe989c49b589fb2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operational malfunctions affecting the use of force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd323ebc986a34f15903e076e2de565f6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unintended or anomalous weapon system behavior;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06673aeb5c654059a06e698d795b59e5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>instances in which autonomous weapon systems or artificial intelligence capabilities selected or engaged targets inconsistent with commander intent or rules of engagement, regardless of whether engagement was ultimately executed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01de1954850c4cf8844788324de5ef34"><enum>(4)</enum><text>human-machine interaction failures affecting command or operator control; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9114977784f419fbe96adf8eb580959"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other safety-related events determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="iddef5f4a0b4f943db81cf4656f77d66d1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safety reporting model</header><text>In establishing the repository under subsection (a), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, model reporting practices on aviation safety reporting systems used to identify and mitigate systemic risks in complex operational environments.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida38f908d04c94a80892b97d648e6e848"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Analysis and dissemination</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that information collected through the repository established under subsection (a) is analyzed to identify trends and lessons learned, and that appropriate findings are disseminated across the Department of Defense to improve system design, training, and operational procedures.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd2f198e4090c4cb69e978cbcb1acedbf"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Protection of sensitive information</header><text>Information contained in the repository established under subsection (a) shall be handled in accordance with applicable classification, operational security, and national security requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="id108e91f861174ef0ae42e32ac291a24a"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Congressional briefing</header><text>Not less frequently than semiannually, the Secretary shall provide to the congressional defense committees a classified briefing on trends, systemic risks, and corrective actions identified through the repository established under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d9d56414b2848a48b80c0d58fdd84cc"><enum>7.</enum><header>Training pipelines</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81b377c5c0a64cb09d9586e4d7c91481"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall develop formal training pipelines for autonomous systems of the Department of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ca1dd6eb11e479a991598fddc6806c8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The formal training pipelines developed under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id0861e8ce5c4746b5bcfe5a461f7b5c74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Specialized training tracks for operators, commanders, and system supervisors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idba441cb2d68b470fb9236e2a4c139ce5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Certification in human-machine teaming, not just system operation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida90a5bdd56344a1ab826ecc5f05a45c8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mandatory training in denied and contested environments, such as loss of global positioning system, electronic warfare, and degraded communications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida0c6861eb82e497ea70590219c64eed4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Integration of autonomous systems into Combat Training Center rotations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd11ff2d462349efaf31fda2e4c1d5f3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Continuous retraining tied to software updates and system changes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idcc3024fdc5c441d9ac1a1e946dd852a2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Civilian harm mitigation and response office</header><subsection id="idb8784ef2d1834e93ba45f318eabc1d55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish within the Office of the Secretary of Defense an office to be known as the <quote>Civilian Harm Mitigation and Response Office</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="idaa41307c9ffe4a0399a3d813f159fbd7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Office is to develop, oversee, and coordinate Department-wide policies, practices, and capabilities to prevent, mitigate, and respond to civilian harm resulting from military operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1ebf7bfa6514486886b7ee68111f6104"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Office shall—</text><paragraph id="id75ddffd20b20451ead213a585e56082a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement policies and guidance relating to civilian harm mitigation and response;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0ea65e7ec26244a79dff368dbef33e65"><enum>(2)</enum><text>oversee the integration of civilian harm mitigation practices into planning, targeting, and operational processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id93ac36b0a897435fa603890955e43499"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate assessments, investigations, and responses to incidents involving civilian harm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc60e3729e3b3465394949023e22ffac0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support training and doctrine development across the Department; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a234ead2843424683833eca533761ac"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide regular reports to Congress on civilian harm mitigation efforts and outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4ff4b510c3c8482a9103cca5513c67e6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Office shall be headed by a senior official designated by the Secretary of Defense.</text></subsection></section><section id="id7e36a413cbe54e97aa2ced8b8925fab9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit the development or use of autonomous weapon systems designed to intercept incoming threats where human supervision remains part of the operational design.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

