<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E3AB46FCE634280B3D5C8FA540A6D2F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9697 IH: Cyber Letters of Marque and Reprisal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9697</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260715">July 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President of the United States to issue cyber letters of marque and reprisal, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H34DB28DDAE1040FA9DA8A61733FADE67" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE598ACA3EA1D4A64A4AF9B2C0435936C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E4E298412014E1785643A9B3F1B6518"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cyber Letters of Marque and Reprisal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA24BE2A1C68145A484F3BCC644922D69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HE598ACA3EA1D4A64A4AF9B2C0435936C">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H4FCF04C072C548B4806853D81CB2E414">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H88C574D2AAFE47289A7EAC8E553E5E40">Sec. 3. Purpose.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H8213AFA9F13C4E3E9BC17AB952787D3B">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HCE9ACA7B3246414BB285EE73500F4092">Sec. 5. Issuance of letters of marque and reprisal.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H4C4FA6EF7DA64ACFA28E6699E0203044">Sec. 6. Reciprocal invocation of letters of marque and reprisal.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H2DA2514F016B4402ABE2C8D7858913C1">Sec. 7. Requirements and qualifications.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HC7AAC018BEC84E9FA1F1F9EA653D963E">Sec. 8. Protection from liability.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="H4FCF04C072C548B4806853D81CB2E414"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC44C6EA848E749DCAA958FD8A877D092"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause 11 of section 8 of article I of the Constitution of the United States grants Congress—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H965F9A74A995440892FBFAF6A531B14D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the power to <quote>grant Letters of Marque and Reprisal</quote> to punish, deter, and prevent acts of aggression and depredation and other malign acts committed by foreigners against Americans through cyber-enabled means; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD77D5B38F404A81A5A4C58EC20276DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the authority to make <quote>Rules concerning Captures on Land and Water</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8185AB921F1D4EEB877E50EA66394B90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Digital assets have become a core component of the global financial system and are used daily by millions of Americans for payments, savings, remittances, and commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BF59FAE92B34494973A1F609DBD577D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Americans are losing billions of dollars annually to crypto-enabled scams, fraud, ransomware, hacking, and theft. Seniors and other vulnerable populations are disproportionately harmed, with many victims losing life savings through schemes that exploit the speed, scale, and cross-border nature of digital assets.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8885008060AB4301B37176643BE7FD44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Cybercriminal organizations, transnational criminal networks, and state-aligned actors increasingly rely on digital assets to steal, launder, and move funds at global scale, financing ransomware attacks, sanctions evasion, weapons proliferation, terrorism, and other threats to United States national security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF63DC05C7791450FB1B7CBE5BDC3D60C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Digital asset financial crime is unfolding at machine speed. Funds can be stolen, laundered, and cashed out globally within hours, far outpacing traditional compliance and enforcement frameworks.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H88C574D2AAFE47289A7EAC8E553E5E40" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H397C1D2C1E7D45A0982D4237A68B5189"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to authorize the President to issue cyber letters of marque and reprisal to commission private persons and entities to conduct limited cyberspace operations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H82C4DA557FEE4A7E9D6A8D03A91FAD55" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to deter and disrupt real-world and cyber command and control structures and cyber operations against the United States, entities within the United States, or persons within the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD900A20D1CAC4438A1F7E44F42CC69F0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to deter and disrupt cyberthreats, provide for compensation for successful private action modeled upon historic privateering on the high seas, and modernize such ancient tactics to deter modern threats;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H64EF0682CF0D4D218A67F3257D08B9FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to facilitate the return of stolen funds to American victims of cyber-enabled crime; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H790DAF2BED4240B9B226B3C4E33ECAEB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to empower the private sector to protect victims, disrupt illicit networks in real time, and ensure that lawful digital asset innovation can continue to grow safely.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H8213AFA9F13C4E3E9BC17AB952787D3B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1CD905E5AF0F43E7A48B1D88A4600E5A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cyber letter of marque and reprisal</header><text>The term <term>cyber letter of marque and reprisal</term> means a Federal commission authorizing a private entity to conduct specified cyber operations against designated targets in accordance with the conditions and restrictions imposed by the President pursuant to section 7.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B4147E0D2E445379E71554EEF28CC9D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cyber operation</header><text>The term <term>cyber operation</term> means actions conducted in cyberspace, including—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7570264327B45D7A717F8A01BF846E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cyber exploration, including intelligence collection;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38B79A54BBDF4BD2AABADDA04B83D436"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data recovery;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEF655089C9347208BDA2CBDE35F9169"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information operations;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB024BA4C07B455CA856D8D3248790B2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">asset seizure (including digital assets and cryptocurrency);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CD4842EBFA44CB19566C7DA53157F21"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disruption of malicious infrastructure;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD46FB6C99B934879AA7897091E823D09"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actions in support of government operations or other entities operating under a letter of marque;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF2A628AAEEF4DB097874B0A6B30F72B"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">combating cybercrimes; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB8011B3CF494C8996F95688389731CE"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other proactive actions intended to disrupt, degrade, deny, or destroy information systems or networks belonging or affiliated with designated cyberthreats.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA59BB14D4F141DE9C363B327A1A0EBC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cybercrime</header><text>The term <term>cybercrime</term> includes any offense described in section 1028, 1028A, 1029, 1030, or 1343 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H18F85AE098074DDD98909437D4E08AD5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Designated cyberthreat</header><text>The term <term>designated cyberthreat</term> means a foreign individual, group, or entity identified by the President as—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05F2529471AA4A8EAAD35578D77E422F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">responsible for, or a sponsor of, cyberattacks against United States persons or assets owned or controlled by United States persons; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A357CFD9C304A7ABB95040874220FBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">listed in a public registry in accordance with applicable law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HCE9ACA7B3246414BB285EE73500F4092"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of letters of marque and reprisal</header> <subsection id="H6089B511B0C043B881E0D3E21A5A3EF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority of the President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, or a senior official designated by the President in accordance with section 301 of title 3, United States Code, is authorized to commission, under officially issued letters of marque and reprisal, as many privately equipped persons and entities as the President determines may be required, with suitable instructions to such persons or to the leaders of such entities to employ all means reasonably necessary to conduct cyber operations to disrupt, degrade, seize, and repatriate the assets, property, or infrastructure located outside of the geographic boundaries of the United States and its territories, of a designated cyberthreat.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HDC0E0D0D99014F9C9076B3E6DB6DC835"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Security bonds</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A751332C7134798BA3E61B89B882D63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may not issue a letter of marque and reprisal without requiring the recipient to post a security bond in an amount the President determines to be sufficient to ensure the execution of such letter in accordance with its terms and conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4DBD4CA1F56467FA97DE1C9EFCF242A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forfeiture</header><text>If the recipient of a letter of marque and reprisal violates the terms of such letter, the recipient shall forfeit part or all of the posted bond, in accordance with the terms of such letter.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEA2832188649491EB25D6383362E044E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>Any person or entity receiving a cyber letter of marque and reprisal may not knowingly conduct any operations relating to such letter against any United States citizen or entity.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H768EFD676E264C65A1FE9783FB680BE5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recordkeeping requirement</header><text>Any person or entity receiving a cyber letter of marque or reprisal shall keep a log of all activities conducted and assets seized pursuant to such letter for a period of not less than 5 years.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H60423791604B4EBDA484F6D93C44C1F2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recovered assets</header><text>In issuing cyber letters of marque and reprisal, the President may require up to 15 percent of the total assets recovered by each holder of a cyber letter be forfeited to the United States to fund a bounty program to sustain future cyber letter of marque and reprisal operations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCDECDBEB80B24D9787CD03A4B56BE189"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Bounties</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1CDA4CFAD084B61A3F8C1D2377F2854"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President is authorized to use funds recovered through cyber operations to establish bounties claimable by holders of cyber letters of marque and reprisal.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B03D07198A74EEEA07ADE76F654F5A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>A person or entity without a cyber letter of marque and reprisal may recover up to 5 percent of the total assets recovered from a designated cyberthreat as a reward for providing information leading to such recovery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H31C397DCF1884E9E908D0E7AC8C15AAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disposition of funds</header><text>Any funds recovered through cyber operations that are not expended pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2) shall be deposited into the Crime Victims Fund established under section 1402 of the Victims of Crime Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20101">34 U.S.C. 20101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE5BB81B3A01C40409BBA7DBC5F70853C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limited offensive operations</header><text>Holders of cyber letters of marque and reprisal are authorized to conduct limited offensive cyber operations, including the use of malware and other offensive tools targeting digital infrastructure (including hardware and software to conduct cyber operations) to the extent necessary to carry out such cyber operations.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4C4FA6EF7DA64ACFA28E6699E0203044"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reciprocal invocation of letters of marque and reprisal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If Congress authorizes the use of traditional letters of marque and reprisal for activities at sea, on land, in air, or in space, a holder of a cyber letter of marque and reprisal shall be authorized to conduct operations at sea, on land, in air, or in space to the extent permitted by the President under section 7.</text></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2DA2514F016B4402ABE2C8D7858913C1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Requirements and qualifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President, to the extent reasonably necessary, may issue guidance for—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50AE108B39F74F31AFAB87616E169AAD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirements and qualifications required to receive a cyber letter of marque and reprisal under section 5; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D52ABDC8B674AB99FC744543E9F461C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which a holder of a cyber letter of marque and reprisal may conduct operations at sea, on land, in air, or in space pursuant to section 6.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC7AAC018BEC84E9FA1F1F9EA653D963E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Protection from liability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No cause of action shall lie or be maintained in any court against the holder of a letter of marque and reprisal for any act of such holder that is expressly authorized by such letter.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

