<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H967581EF8EF64A699B583B55AA788496" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8925 IH: Job Corps and Skilled Defense Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8925</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000604">Ms. Goodlander</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to align the Job Corps program with the defense industrial base, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA040859156E47D19B7957A37BFB47C1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4753C87408054E47ABD4AAB30FDC9529" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Job Corps and Skilled Defense Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBBE27EDFE3B241EDBBB075D73A314875" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alignment of Job Corps with the defense industrial base</header> <subsection id="H0DD1A8F471B840BCB7E0C45D28702DEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the National Imperative for Industrial Skills program of the Department of Defense (or a successor program), shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H53A567862E37412883F552DE0925669E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that military recruits who are ineligible for enlistment as a result of the requirements of section 520 of title 10, United States Code, are made aware of opportunities to enroll in the Job Corps program authorized under subtitle C of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3191">29 U.S.C. 3191 et seq.</external-xref>) to receive training that—</text> <subparagraph id="HC324F7517FF74025B5A97B6AE5132D27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prepares enrollees for employment as skilled industrial workers in the defense industrial base in the State or local area in which a Job Corps center is located and, to the extent practicable, in the State or local area in which enrollees intend to seek employment after graduation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32D15660C4214EA88BCE5FE12D2AE6BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes programs of advanced career training described in section 148(c) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3198">20 U.S.C. 3198(c)</external-xref>) at existing Job Corps centers or at new Job Corps centers in close proximity to a shipyard or other defense industrial base suppliers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6E8BFDEECC5411DACDBEA3332DDDF04" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address shortages of skilled industrial workers in the defense industrial base by supporting the Job Corps program in offering training that aligns with the needs of the defense industrial base, including through investments in curricula development, equipment, and facilities. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8A95256B4BD2419994FAE1AA2BD14415"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension of shipbuilding workforce development special incentive to job corps</header> 
<paragraph id="H2EEDFA11F1CF4AE28D521E208DA78014"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 8696(b)(2) of title 10, United States Code is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0F972FA794B440AF9379D7913003103D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HFA0CED4ECDAD4889A96A68CD7649254D" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Job Corps program authorized under subtitle C of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3191">29 U.S.C. 3191 et seq.</external-xref>) or an operator of a Job Corps center described in section 147 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3197">29 U.S.C. 3197</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC6C41352DCC4784BCF68FEE06C098DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8696(c)(2) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H23584DC64C94486D80333940C10A0742" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HCCD4FBFE68A5496781F0AFAECFF28922"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Job Corps program authorized under subtitle C of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3191">29 U.S.C. 3191 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H292319D8E0584B3896A12A8B975AECA8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Job corps conforming reforms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 158(f) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3208">29 U.S.C. 3208</external-xref>) is amended— </text> <paragraph id="H4D6AC303F18C47599840E541DCCDD983" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>may accept on behalf of the Job Corps or individual Job Corps centers charitable donations of cash</quote> and inserting <quote>(or the Secretary of Agriculture, as appropriate) on behalf of the Job Corps, or individual Job Corps Center, on behalf of such center, may accept grants, charitable donations of cash ,</quote>; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8320E6D9857C45FFBEA4807E017968F9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following: <quote>Notwithstanding sections 501(b) and 522 of title 40, United States Code, any property acquired by a Job Corps center shall be directly transferred, on a nonreimbursable basis, to the Secretary.</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H94DA4B7FF5CA4857AF99392A98CA5D8D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Operations</header><text></text> 
<paragraph id="H36D8D58D237A496DA023BC76AE8908A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local authority to realign trades</header><text>Section 151 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3201">29 U.S.C. 3201</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HE58E3D74888240838048ABA0AB9A67EF" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HADC9D072692B42508751ABA4EC1F70D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Local authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the limitations of the budget approved by the Secretary for a Job Corps center, the operator of a Job Corps center shall have the authority, without prior approval from the Secretary, to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE0492898394B4E93B6B4CB7DB2C82C7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hire staff and provide staff professional development;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H929CD6DE357441ADA0C75CD27C567AFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>set terms and enter into agreements with Federal, State, or local educational partners, such as secondary schools, institutions of higher education, child development centers, units of Junior Reserve Officer Training Corps programs established under section 2031 of title 10, United States Code, or employers; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B742B4C033A457FB9DC46DC84D8DF74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engage with and educate stakeholders (including eligible applicants for the Job Corps) about Job Corps operations, selection procedures, and activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4232E8B55C94C9D8F797410137713FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Streamlined enrollment of veterans and military recruits into the defense industrial base</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 144(b) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3194">29 U.S.C. 3194(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H34B8B9AC512A48DD894AB428C6DF09BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and certain other armed forces members</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">veterans</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9A455DB2852439A95C79943B8DA67D0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or a member of the Armed Forces eligible for preseparation counseling under section 1142 of title 10, United States Code</quote> after <quote>a veteran</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

