<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO26093-0LX-6H-W4X"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3736 IS: Dakota Mainstem Water Supply Project Feasibility Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3736</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to determine the feasibility of constructing a project to supply municipal, rural, and industrial water to the Dakota Mainstem Regional Water System service area in the States of South Dakota, Iowa, Nebraska, and Minnesota, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dakota Mainstem Water Supply Project Feasibility Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idF65FA64A39984A76BC3F7B267A34BD7F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8e950bf149a4d9e80be8e5dd665482e"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dakota Mainstem Regional Water System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Dakota Mainstem Regional Water System</term> means the Dakota Mainstem Regional Water System, Inc., a nonprofit corporation established and operated substantially in accordance with the reclamation feasibility standards to serve as a non-Federal project entity for purposes of the cooperative agreement entered into under section 3(a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ideb34b1c4bf084463bca6de057cc66020"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reclamation feasibility standards</header><text>The term <term>reclamation feasibility standards</term> means the eligibility criteria and feasibility study requirements described in part 404 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1569CA29DC4643BEB90182CD3FF91655"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id16f4b18687b94834b7ae520ca644c95e"><enum>3.</enum><header>Dakota Mainstem water supply project feasibility study</header><subsection id="idf1e3e88b4e2b48069289a4bc3c3f1d1d"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph id="id8966735335534d2ca874d5470d894d8a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Dakota Mainstem Regional Water System, through a cooperative agreement, may undertake a study to determine the feasibility of constructing a project to supply municipal, rural, and industrial water to the Dakota Mainstem Regional Water System service area in the States of South Dakota, Iowa, Nebraska, and Minnesota.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id816b230413b2462092cda46c9eea2cc3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The study under paragraph (1) shall comply with the reclamation feasibility standards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3771f8b11e494a8589d4b2b1103945f3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the total costs of carrying out the feasibility study under this section shall not exceed 50 percent.</text></subsection><subsection id="idae3db56de5d34810b82c0f31eec11d51"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide259cc3fd4c446738007d39150691f7b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>The authority provided by this section expires on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

