<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0DB0CD95828B4EDFAB16D7D3373A2B4B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7510 IH: Preventing Research Ownership Transfer to External Competitive Threats (PROTECT) Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7510</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain foreign governments from acquiring intellectual property rights of research conducted by United States universities, faculty, staff, or students, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA7A0EC8BB3884607A45D08B475794CD0" style="OLC"><section id="H37A8B037EF5544F695B7D1E3D9FFAA93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Research Ownership Transfer to External Competitive Threats (PROTECT) Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB70ECBB0B28D46039E59D08FF11D5B62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H512CD560B72743A987DF1021C303275B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered foreign government</header><text>The term <quote>covered foreign government</quote> means the government of any prohibited nation, including any agency, instrumentality, or entity controlled by such government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF50FB3FDDFB745CC8848246ED15AD9F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered research</header><text>The term <quote>covered research</quote> means any research, invention, discovery, or intellectual property developed or conducted, in whole or in part, by a United States university, or by any faculty member, staff member, or student affiliated with such university.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE284A6BEC26541E9827C16EC0F1C3932"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designated foreign terrorist organization</header><text>The term <quote>designated foreign terrorist organization</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32E3F61EA96E458A8CE6DAAC181E3D48"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intellectual property rights</header><text>The term <quote>intellectual property rights</quote> includes patents, copyrights, trademarks, trade secrets, know-how, data rights, and any other form of proprietary information or rights related to covered research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H536FEA104EAA41E9B2A79486E47083C9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibited nation</header><text>The term <quote>prohibited nation</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA6F5FBEB57C4FC089EF8893C7A4C63F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States university</header><text>The term <quote>United States university</quote> means any institution of higher education as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>) or section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>), headquartered in the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H156D95FDCE7D4C3FBE48F47618199F39"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on acquisition of intellectual property rights</header><subsection id="H04B85D18C9C948DBA263774808EFCF07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No United States university, or any faculty member, staff member, or student affiliated with such university, shall enter into any contract, agreement, license, sale, transfer, or other transaction that grants, conveys, or otherwise provides a covered foreign government with any intellectual property rights in covered research.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC656A75058AE42CDBB688B6324A6629C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall apply to any transaction entered into on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3605A6368E25433BA16E3D3226E9AEB6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibited nations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The term <quote>prohibited nation</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HD1DC099D4B514A3DBEC15B607CE266CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Russian Federation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE20C65401A44E4DAE775AFC142FBC1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9FE620295DA4658BF143183C11FC920"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A905EB6801047CCB00268C3CC0779E9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any nation that is engaged in armed conflict with the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H269F9C36B3C3470F81894CAA87677A5A"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>any nation that harbors, financially supports, or otherwise cooperates with a designated foreign terrorist organization;</text>
            </paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4FFDD742544012AAE08D06448297D4">
                <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>any nation designated as a State Sponsor of Terrorism by the U.S. Department of State; or</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HE0E53E42DB4F47B387B87D23B5A95DCF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any other nation that the Secretary of State determines poses a threat to the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H103EDF4956164E50B3EE466AF7926F50"><enum>5.</enum><header>Penalties</header><subsection id="H9277C50D98184518ADC6A2007AB3818D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Violations not endangering national security</header><text>Any United States university that violates section 3 shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $500,000 for each such violation, if the Secretary of State determines that the violation does not endanger the national security of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7C39C6DD2E864D63869D6C6241316A63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Violations endangering national security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any United States university that violates section 3 with respect to covered research, in general, or covered research related to critical energy or defense issues, which may affect the national security of the United States shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000,000 for each such violation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2FAD000B76194AD1BF82DE8221AE4A8E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Seizure of funds</header><text>In the case of any violation under subsection (a) or (b), any funds or other consideration received by the United States university in exchange for the intellectual property rights in the covered research shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture to the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA181A773C5FB48B49B3A8F5E90AC984C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall enforce the penalties under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFC737C428EA2445588B90C65DF0E9E14"><enum>6.</enum><header>Determinations by Secretary of State</header><subsection id="H38D8E92A279342F5A46E26BF50D30FBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any determination required under this Act, including determinations regarding prohibited nations under section 4(7), the level of threat to national security under section 5(a) or 5(b), or whether covered research relates to critical energy or defense issues under section 5(b), shall be made by the Secretary of State.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C13A936ED6A407F97E341CA06EFF2FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Finality</header><text>Determinations under subsection (a) shall be final and committed to agency discretion. No such determination, finding, or action under this section shall be subject to judicial review, except to the extent required by the Constitution for colorable claims of violation of constitutional rights.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEB1B35238864451F8711F8EDFD09DB78"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, and the application of such provision to other persons or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

