<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8345BBE8882A43539CE711464B8E5D03" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6588 IH: Priority Response for Veterans Impacted by Disasters and Emergencies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6588</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251210">December 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to expedite the processing of claims for disability compensation by veterans affected by major disasters.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H84E88C01A5624E2FA6267114B7C96E92" style="OLC"><section id="HA8E63B6F9D464C9A81A83CF38F8AB5A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Priority Response for Veterans Impacted by Disasters and Emergencies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROVIDE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA6658791BE67428D8FE68279402D2162"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H057782F173714B1981DE4C214D352184"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Veterans Affairs sets forth criteria for priority processing of veterans’ disability claims by the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80C3A188AF634C2A86593D1CB390B831"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such criteria include veterans affected by extreme financial hardship, homelessness, terminal illness, and participants in the Department’s Fully Developed Claim program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A1FE1AED6D54B8AA837F69E01C63C7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Currently there is no process in place to prioritize the disability claims of veterans affected by major disasters such as fires and floods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C30F4C2774A4E76BAF3EDB6A942200A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Priority claims processing for veterans affected by major disasters will significantly help such veterans begin rebuilding their lives.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H90518C65923E4A9397FC5C2BD955E77F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Priority Claims Processing in the Event of a Major Disaster</header><subsection id="HF197666563934FCBB64D11285C56AD7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe regulations setting forth criteria for priority processing of a claim for compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code. Individuals whose claim shall be eligible for such priority processing shall include—</text><paragraph id="H651E25089C504FA1B6650AAC14A50FEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">veterans affected by extreme financial hardship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F44AFBDBBD3449399D183F9B6C579AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>veterans affected by homelessness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F30372835D144CA9DE58D8B9F9C966B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>veterans diagnosed with a terminal illness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0EA237FC426412C9C1A15BAF8BF9124"><enum>(4)</enum><text>participants in the Department of Veterans Affairs Fully Developed Claim program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D36A914CB174C7C8E1E6EE09FE9F793"><enum>(5)</enum><text>veterans who live in an area for which the President has declared a major disaster under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7259B371D05477D91405699830F7D12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special considerations for claims processing in the event of a major disaster</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe additional regulations relating only to subsection (a)(5). Such additional regulations include—</text><paragraph id="H6E1D3C550AD743028703E668745E58DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing flexible evidence requirements for veterans unable to meet the ordinary evidence requirements for such a claim due to a major disaster; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD99753A2559E475DA61695120CEB6F2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a flexible filing deadline for such a claim.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EFA2C1038264E5683E0DDA064FC6BC7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to veterans of eligibility for priority claims processing</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall post a permanent notice to veterans on the Department of Veterans Affairs website of the categories of eligibility for priority processing of such claims, including the changes to such categories made pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

