<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC5FD97BBA354AC1B80C1CA7B080E22A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6269 IH: Modular Housing Production Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6269</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to conduct a review of Federal Housing Administration construction financing programs to identify barriers to the use of modular home methods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E858C4FAC9E4CBEB043349513AB07E6" style="OLC"><section id="H9ED9710F2D0741E8BE84454805CD0CC4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Modular Housing Production Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H15276237D6E546C691A0DB4AEF14824D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modular Housing Production Act</header><subsection id="H29A6C76D65224B03BE98197B108095A2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H097293C516CF46A4861FDCF1C68A8AA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Manufactured home</header><text>The term <term>manufactured home</term> has the meaning given the term in section 603 of the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5402">42 U.S.C. 5402</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H538FE310BA4542B88311477B4751B856"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modular home</header><text>The term <term>modular home</term> means a home that is constructed in a factory in 1 or more modules, each of which meet applicable State and local building codes of the area in which the home will be located, and that are transported to the home building site, installed on foundations, and completed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EDCC874967D46BD9B7709735180D24B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92350AA3BA43476C8B887BF0E59C1255"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FHA construction financing programs</header><paragraph id="H375436A1134342E59EE85D5C2A7618F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a review of Federal Housing Administration construction financing programs to identify barriers to the use of modular home methods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C2A7823B9747DF985B8412FEAEEA2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting the review under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H9AF6C31292CB463198E6C55644BDC2A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify and evaluate regulatory and programmatic features that restrict participation in construction financing programs by modular home developers, including construction draw schedules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D88A9342E9E47A295DD54E22B3A4D7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify administrative measures authorized under section 525 of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1735f-3">12 U.S.C. 1735f–3</external-xref>) to facilitate program utilization by modular home developers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB5D0338D30C4C32A0FF9CB4869E12A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall publish a report that describes the results of the review conducted under paragraph (1), which shall include a description of programmatic and policy changes that the Secretary recommends to reduce or eliminate identified barriers to the use of modular home methods in Federal Housing Administration construction financing programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6429AFEB0E5B458B97E94CA300DB95E5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><subparagraph id="H23C730AEA0EB4B51B05BF54836146B31"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which the Secretary publishes the report under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall initiate a rulemaking to examine an alternative draw schedule for construction financing loans provided to modular and manufactured home developers, which shall include the ability for interested stakeholders to provide robust public comment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC3B0B1B7BE0494E9EB6B75FA2737A48"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>Following the period for public comment under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H641BBCC4C25D46229C43B26491EE3813"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issue a final rule regarding an alternative draw schedule described in subparagraph (A); or</text></clause><clause id="HE41B781870714BF2932789C9718330EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide an explanation as to why the rule shall not become final.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00FF278518D340429F558516F7462D60"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standardized uniform commercial code for modular homes</header><paragraph id="HDB2F76E404174F6DB4E18855CF36A175"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Award</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant to study the design and feasibility of a standardized uniform commercial code for modular homes, which shall evaluate—</text><subparagraph id="H1F66141F201241DCB4AA7F176B128FF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the utility of a standardized coding system for serializing and securing modules, streamlining design and construction, and improving modular home innovation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A6CBA1F870E4F6CB18C222AB9CAE0AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a means to coordinate a standardized code with financing incentives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01F3BB794A954C10A2A40E930423DFCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such funds as may be necessary to carry out paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

