<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG26C01-LVF-L9-N3M"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4740 IS: To amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to improve transparency, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4740</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to improve transparency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id68e7fe937c274e02861a3c688c8a68ce" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Public release of Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court opinion related to section 702 certifications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">As soon as practicable, but not later than 14 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall, in consultation with the Attorney General, publicly release the Memorandum Opinion and Order of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court dated March 17, 2026, regarding section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a</external-xref>), with such redactions as may be necessary to protect intelligence sources and methods.</text></section><section id="id909f21c9a7f24ac0a464a03f09108037"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports to Congress on sensitive queries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 702(f)(3) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881a">50 U.S.C. 1881a(f)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idad2b336552884d82b6d7078078ff8190"><subparagraph id="id4796f10a1eea48109055776b78e97e86"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an annual report on the number of—</text><clause id="idff6f686c88c24eefa88af6c1f288885c" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>requests to conduct sensitive queries in the year covered by the report;</text></clause><clause id="id9fe6da9e79da435292dd0536f75ded38" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>requests to conduct sensitive queries that were approved and denied in the year covered by the report; and</text></clause><clause id="id9a29df3c8f024f50ba352f2bc3657c4b" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>sensitive queries conducted in the year covered by the report, with such numbers disaggregated by the subclause of subparagraph (D)(ii) under which the requests were made or the sensitive queries were conducted.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id157bccfe6b8c4311ae3fa87764d8c95d"><enum>3.</enum><header>Declassification of significant decisions, orders, and opinions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 602 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1872">50 U.S.C. 1872</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd931f813979d442f9a7992c707099fec"><subsection id="id4c8cc84e18c4435a897ff53c90ea18d1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Declassification required</header><paragraph id="id6fcf75c54c35472c9300127a68cefa9d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Attorney General, shall—</text><subparagraph id="idee6c6f89570b48a7aa6e695f0ff847cf"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a declassification review of each decision, order, or opinion issued by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review (as defined in section 601(e)) that is described in paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f9cbcad96ba4b939831d995b4b5ecfc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consistent with that review, make publicly available to the greatest extent practicable each such decision, order, or opinion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id56d84fee11954d3bbd86214fe4faf75f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>complete the declassification review required by subparagraph (A) and public release of each such decision, order, or opinion pursuant to subparagraph (B) by not later than 180 days after the date on which the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review issues such decision, order, or opinion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id421bac293287453d80014d28e45b680f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Decision, order, or opinion described</header><text>A decision, order, or opinion issued by the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review that is described in this paragraph is any such decision, order, or opinion issued before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act that—</text><subparagraph id="ide6e1935039464a2ebaac14e4491b4b3d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes a significant construction or interpretation of any provision of law, including any novel or significant construction or interpretation of any term;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5d3620388f54c7695d868b7ab4f5c3c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>involves a sensitive investigative matter (as defined in section 103(i)(12)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcf295ddaddf24026b935c0218e6ba8ae"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has been nominated for a declassification review by an amicus curiae appointed by the court.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id704e37fc9431417ab06850e7327a41cd"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of sensitive investigative matter</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>sensitive investigative matter</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idf4452e59278e4826a78016a465a83f87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an investigative matter involving the activities of—</text><clause id="id5469fab3cda846ddb031f398be57764e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a domestic public official or political candidate, or an individual serving on the staff of such an official or candidate;</text></clause><clause id="id28fec2adc6f14f02bc423ff4a120f9d8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a domestic religious or political organization, or a known or suspected United States person prominent in such an organization; or</text></clause><clause id="ide4ecb4a76b514360af14fedf8d8f42af"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the domestic news media; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf332526ab3554c7ca9cca3483b039997"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other investigative matter involving a domestic entity or a known or suspected United States person that, in the judgment of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court or the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court of Review, is similarly as sensitive as an investigative matter described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idd6f0cfc81e50424cb63a69f8603e1cf9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reports on violations of law or Executive Order</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 511 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3110">50 U.S.C. 3110</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4fc566d8b1a74332b92c95a5bf2f03a5"><subsection id="id0ed9043c13a741b2b52c25a0e57839de"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><paragraph id="idb8dc81c235bc449596110105320c58c5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of National Intelligence shall make each report submitted under subsection (a) available to the public on an internet website, with such redactions as may be necessary to protect sources and methods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id774a7119737f4f7b96a0a88235692ba6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retroactive report publication</header><text>With respect to a report submitted under subsection (a) prior to the date of the enactment of this paragraph, such report shall be made publicly available pursuant to paragraph (1) by not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6a8280a795eb4fafafee75f7f29b6bae"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Department of Justice report</header><text>The Attorney General shall, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence, submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a version of the report described in subsection (a) that addresses violations of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id59fa9030399e43d7b000fdcc71187b06"> <enum>5.</enum> <header>Transparency related to United States person queries outside of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (FISA)</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 603(b) of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1873">50 U.S.C. 1873</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
            <paragraph id="id89b111e6a17b4623abc740b37b2d9dec">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (6)(C) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="idcb7942f9dc504059a3d447061684986a">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (7), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id3b98d370eeff49fa939df046ac69d6e4">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4275dba664e54c0a9108715a3cd37cbe"> <paragraph id="idad610ff3a074438da1fe674c8dcb48fa"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>a good faith estimate of the number of United States person search terms and queries, by each element of the intelligence community, used to retrieve information acquired pursuant to Executive Order 12333 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3001">50 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> note; relating to United States intelligence activities), or successor order, outside of this Act.</text>
                    </paragraph>
                    <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
                </quoted-block>
            </paragraph>
 </section><section id="iddc686aa12a4945fab4c56a0674c5326a"><enum>6.</enum><header>Five-week extension of section 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act</header><subsection id="id1cbfb433d4b845b48f948f44ed6c2c6e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of repeal date of title VII</header><text>Section 403(b) of the FISA Amendments Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/261">Public Law 110–261</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="iddb439772514a47a49a02a2cae7121170"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1881">50 U.S.C. 1881</external-xref> note), by striking <quote>June 12, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>July 17, 2026</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideeae4aa5a1b149e6b54abf86d2961492"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/2511">18 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref> note), in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>June 12, 2026</quote> and inserting <quote>July 17, 2026</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8d17e2929ba04af39218de7f9c0fed1f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall take effect on the earlier of the date of the enactment of this Act or June 11, 2026.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

