<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BCCD81CBC944E9DBAFAFA2E0B4ED471" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7058 IH: Foreign Adversary AI Risk Assessment and Diplomacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7058</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001098">Mr. Hamadeh of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to conduct assessments of the risks posed to the United States by foreign adversaries who utilize generative artificial intelligence for malicious activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB8DA8883A0ED44BA8BCFFECF381D8DD9" style="OLC"><section id="H72570BEEA49D4E6A9492B6CF0724536C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Adversary AI Risk Assessment and Diplomacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H59E7A8B5F96841958D0F120DDD3E6674" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H379CA428645A4CEA9581EF1D93ABC116"><enum>(1)</enum><text>while generative artificial intelligence has the potential to provide substantial societal and economic benefits when developed and used responsibly, the increasing use of generative artificial intelligence by foreign adversaries may represent a national security risk, and the challenges posed by such use is not well understood; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H749052EFD1D54751BA179AB2D1EFA222"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, must take diplomatic steps to recognize, assess, and address the use of generative artificial intelligence by foreign adversaries, including through bilateral and multilateral engagements and the promotion of responsible state behavior in international fora, to reduce the national security risks to the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H86C15288D96349E595A361CA083C3868"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assessments of the risks posed to the United States by foreign adversaries who utilize generative artificial intelligence for malicious activities</header><subsection id="HD5402B435891434C8E1089DD747B4D13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for three years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies as appropriate shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an assessment of the risks posed to the United States by foreign adversaries who utilize generative artificial intelligence for malicious activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H71AFC5C3E0DB4F4BA620E0989C40EF19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each assessment under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H10A3EDBC809B4CD083035DF113F1C346"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of incidents during the preceding calendar year in which foreign adversaries have utilized, or attempted to utilize, generative artificial intelligence for malicious activities against the United States and its allies, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H88CD29EEEC5C4F77B8815E410214A41D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To disseminate or produce synthetic media, including foreign anti-United States propaganda or conduct foreign malign influence operations targeting the United States, its citizens, or its allies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD46B3E401A9A40089AFF910E6B3227F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To enhance their ability to develop or deploy chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear weapons.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48A891E9A9D84615B3D05D244EDF3923"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To facilitate malicious cyber operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEECCA11F0DC4C4BB9FE6AB14ACDC5F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To develop or enhance other military, surveillance, or intelligence capabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403A017649CD4F1D82897FA9141F7E2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An analysis of emerging trends in the use of generative artificial intelligence by foreign adversaries, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB382F143956545CD9885C601F6C29D6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The extent to which such activities may be attributable to specific foreign adversaries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C595846C72B4A56943DDD40BDD58653"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The implications of such trends for United States foreign policy, diplomatic engagement, and the development of United States and allied-led international norms and standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC3D116E68B406C92F83F409841F07F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations to mitigate and counter the risks posed to the United States and allies by foreign adversaries who utilize generative artificial intelligence applications for malicious activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C60990294104C6AAABD9C54125678CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each assessment under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex only for the protection of intelligence sources and methods relating to the matters contained in the assessment. The Secretary of State shall post on a publicly available website of the Department of State the unclassified portion of each assessment.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC908A033D36848FBB1D7BB3EEF2AD84E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HFE08A3CF9DA546B3A51071EA657D62C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD3FA42821E4D03BAADF266E255AA15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002(3) of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A80F9B6DD024DDBA9D0F675A5DECFD0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign adversary</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary</term> has the meaning given the term <term>covered nation</term> in section 4872(f) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H979E85A8651D42579CFA652AADF9C894"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Generative artificial intelligence applications</header><text>The term <term>generative artificial intelligence applications</term> means the class of artificial intelligence models that emulate the structure and characteristics of input data in order to generate derived synthetic content, including images, videos, audio, text, and other digital content.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

