<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4473F758312141EEB80D01CA423E08ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6919 IH: Save Our Girls from Sex Trafficking Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress> <session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6919</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251219">December 19, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To combat child human trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HDA25DF2E9CFD4AE9BB58BF7480C02B42" style="OLC">
<section id="HC2B2EE429A6D4DEDA766B3FD928DFCDC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Save Our Girls from Sex Trafficking Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H36BC1C8CCC484E4994B7F9AD665B8430"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency task force on domestic child human trafficking</header> <subsection id="HB45BC41E59814B42A6A808F3B2AD5257"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall establish an interagency task force on domestic child human trafficking (as such term is defined in section 203(k)(3) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20703">34 U.S.C. 20703(k)(3)</external-xref>)) with the Secretaries of Health and Human Services, Treasury, Labor, Education, Housing and Urban Development, and Homeland Security.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7370B7DB45794C33B9F467CE8C63832D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The task force established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB8C22272C61E47458C67405CCEC68841"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collaborate with industry experts to decrease child human trafficking, including through demand reduction, prevention, and awareness education; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H058718DC7E704113B838D8FA18E106D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate holistic, victim-centered services and victim-centered law enforcement response, including through education, law enforcement identification of survivors and connection to service providers, screening arrested youth to determine whether they are victims of child sex trafficking, diversion of victims of child human trafficking to non-judicial rehabilitation services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H26B74E1F14984524B95D53DEF291D465"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on child human trafficking</header> <subsection id="H91209AC291E64D61864D9C1FE2640E44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a study on child human trafficking, which shall include—</text>
<paragraph id="H4EAA1DB94A304677AE81FE88E7161E72"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how and why children enter the sex trade;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6CED35DF922410AB4B5C60D23B38FC7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>profiling sex traffickers, minors vulnerable to being trafficked, and those who purchase sex from children;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C74B750178341F1AB1B30848529BA13"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the physical and psychological effects of child human trafficking on survivors; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC578E36D1A814F19ADB55087852AE5BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of large events on the child human trafficking market.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H77FED113C23F4A7782641DB1A9107E45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit a report that contains the results of the study conducted under subsection (a) to Congress.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFB434106A3C847209DF517026341B469"><enum>4.</enum><header>School grant program</header> <subsection id="HC485CC7B07DB4C46B6A5F39252372548"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education is authorized to make grants to local educational agencies to educate children about child human trafficking.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H349F85DC02524C769AA8CD9EAF8699E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A local educational agency seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5BEB2A3D330543E983304C058090DE01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recipients of grants under this section shall collaborate with organizations that have an expertise in a victim-centered approach in identifying and responding to child human trafficking.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HE7004D8DC7D144369C78BC053603261E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Foster care grant program</header>
<subsection id="H9079A3E58A7F46BE81D8E0E55AEA9919"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services is authorized to make grants to agencies that have custody of, or provide services to, foster children to educate children about child human trafficking.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F434217E1F2476DB742BE5581A7A4AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An agency seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1AA9136791CB448380A7F7AC6B3F45F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recipients of grants under this section shall collaborate with organizations that have an expertise in a victim-centered approach in identifying and responding to child human trafficking.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC42EBBBFFE644CE98F9866256366534A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Law enforcement grant program</header> <subsection id="H98CD289B54294CE49A66211C59A92E14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to make grants to States, units of local government, and Tribal governments to—</text>
<paragraph id="H25FA02055153404698FD098B5BD627D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train law enforcement officers and prosecutors on how to identify victims of child human trafficking;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FF18A80D82E4F10BFCFEA8AD439F071"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create pre-trial diversion programs for victims of child human trafficking; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H536AB7E49CDF4F358AFF2BD9600AD7B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide protection for victims of child human trafficking who testify against their exploiters.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8B4CA0FA315D4BCF90BA2E361ECA95B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The chief executive of a State or unit of local government seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H8561B7456FD6409E91B5E7DA508960C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional amount authorized</header><text>The Attorney General may increase the amount by up to 20 percent that a grant recipient would otherwise receive under this section in the case of a recipient that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5892EED20C3E4D19B5FD42C508D8CE65"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will collaborate with a victim-centered multi-disciplinary team organization with expertise in responding to child human trafficking;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H3B5584195EDF4A5B8600A764775FFFFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a pre-trial diversion program or a program that identifies sex trafficked minors for operations purposes; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3449D530A5BC4104AF3E8984CD423096"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have in place a policy not to prosecute or otherwise punish victims of child human trafficking.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HD67F1996E6EE4D019EE6F8BE5C10896B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Job training grant program</header>
<subsection id="H2AA38ABBACDA424F81964BF85832E274"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor is authorized to make grants to nonprofit organizations to provide job skills training and assistance in finding job opportunities for survivors of child human trafficking and children at risk of being trafficked.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H29BEDCACCF854D57BF607E48E583C05C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit organization seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H2CE463C534E5423AB652FBEE5ECD4E91"><enum>8.</enum><header>Long-term care grant program</header>
<subsection id="H53FBD487FF274119AC95D2D5B6B4606C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary of Health and Human Services is authorized to make grants to nonprofit organizations to—</text> <paragraph id="H3CE8B28AFA5D44079D420E7450D4108D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide long-term care facilities for victims of child human trafficking;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H606617B0307E4088B72998E768550121"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide long-term counseling and evidence-based trauma-informed mental health services for victims of child human trafficking; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FC900757DB840DEA2A594EED79AD192"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide long-term and transitional housing for victims of child human trafficking.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9F808A8D35C24419AB09609462F74640"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A nonprofit organization seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

