<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H58842150C4014DC2A4270F852835511E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7704 IH: VA Call Center Multi-Factor Authentication Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7704</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000139">Mr. Van Epps</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require call centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs to use multi-factor identification to verify the identity of callers in connection with high-impact veteran or beneficiary actions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF466DADA8714417A977A7FC497CB3DD5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H659DD274A28A41DB8F5A9AB71308C27D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Call Center Multi-Factor Authentication Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HCDD2C44A0444411BAB248A93020928D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Multi-factor authentication required to verify the identity of callers to Veterans Affairs call centers in connection with high-impact veteran or beneficiary actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5722(b)(3) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Such controls shall include the use of multi-factor authentication by Department call centers in connection with high-impact veteran or beneficiary actions to verify the identity of the caller and confirm that the participation of the caller in connection with the action is in fact appropriate. As used in the preceding sentence, an action is high-impact if an impersonator could cause real, durable harm to the veteran or beneficiary, such as by diverting funds, manipulating access to accounts, or disclosing sensitive information.</quote>.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill> 

