<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB7A7028F2A834F0DAF3DC2034864230F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8863 IH: To amend title 5, United States Code, to add certain employees of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to the definition of employees in fire protection activities for the purpose of compensation for certain illnesses and diseases deemed to be proximately caused by employment in fire protection activities.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8863</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260515">May 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to add certain employees of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to the definition of employees in fire protection activities for the purpose of compensation for certain illnesses and diseases deemed to be proximately caused by employment in fire protection activities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3BE6965B91D9413FBC8877802B25766A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H402C3E15EC634334B0E11995EBEAF58A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Compensation for certain illnesses and diseases deemed to be proximately caused by employment in fire protection activities for certain employees of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives</header> 
<subsection id="H67F69DFE46FE437CBB4B8E28ED584873"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Employees in fire protection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8143b of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H9DF3C76D0DD6491A9A3A82BB8370AD4A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H7C15DB3E200742D29F2195F6F9CD4E7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain employees of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, a Certified Fire Investigator or a member of the National Response Team within the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives shall be deemed to be an employee in fire protection activities. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H35015B37845B430DB5BF0A4A9EADC3F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to claims for compensation filed on or after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

