<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E93BF73212A4FCAAC1A296A9E85085E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8973 IH: Sergeant Rafael Peralta Medal of Honor Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8973</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to award the Medal of Honor to Sergeant Rafael Peralta for acts of valor during Operation Iraqi Freedom, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE1A3A8F9D9A54AF09B5EE0EDC98ABA32" style="OLC"><section id="H046C9D1CC81645F7A63E44550C4B30C7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sergeant Rafael Peralta Medal of Honor Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H58F8D4589715429B8E8971D45DD03953"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; Sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H5D6793E29DAF46EFA230AF88AA8CC958"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H569484B1BBC44C3B93AD8B72819768B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On November 15, 2004, during combat operations in Fallujah, Iraq, Sergeant Rafael Peralta, United States Marine Corps, served as a squad leader with Company A, 1st Battalion, 3rd Marines, during Operation Iraqi Freedom. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DA65D5EAE0D4AE984DEBC8456DBD00B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During a house-clearing operation in the Second Battle of Fallujah, Sergeant Peralta was mortally wounded by enemy gunfire while leading Marines engaged in close-quarters combat against insurgent forces. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E92C9421A2F4C5382DF0BDA878F4D2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Moments after being mortally wounded, an enemy grenade landed in the room occupied by Sergeant Peralta and fellow Marines. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D9D06D1C14941D7986D9C9834850437"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Multiple eyewitness Marines reported that Sergeant Peralta consciously and intentionally pulled the grenade beneath his body, absorbing the blast and shielding nearby Marines from death or serious bodily harm. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H592457018C1A4BCC84667DC9CB0D2FB6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The actions of Sergeant Peralta reflected conspicuous gallantry and intrepidity at the risk of his life above and beyond the call of duty, in keeping with the highest traditions of the United States Marine Corps and the Armed Forces of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7362E23607C44CC3A46C3DE32488E908"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HC2B9E17C84FD46EEBDB4D2C5CFB9AF61"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sergeant Rafael Peralta’s actions on November 15, 2004, exemplify the highest ideals of duty, courage, and sacrifice; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA06E107764DD44B99B320315541446AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Marines whose lives were saved by the actions of Sergeant Peralta continue to bear witness to his valor and selflessness; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8008D3CFC7D44CBEA077BF96D2CCE43B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States owes a solemn obligation to ensure that acts of extraordinary heroism receive full and fair consideration for the Medal of Honor regardless of administrative delay or statutory limitation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD63171F95A4D45AA97707148F6EC7B51" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization for award of Medal of Honor to Sergeant Rafael Peralta</header><subsection id="H159ABE8481C849089F53EBDAC6896CC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the time limitations specified in sections 8298(a) and 8300 of title 10, United States Code, or any other time limitation with respect to the awarding of certain medals to persons who served in the Armed Forces, the President is authorized to award the Medal of Honor, under section 8291 of such title, to Rafael Peralta for the acts of valor described in subsection (b). </text></subsection><subsection id="HFBCC2075FC03409D93863FC1789EC0AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acts of valor described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> The acts of valor described in this subsection are the actions of Rafael Peralta as a member of the Marine Corps in Fallujah, Iraq, on November 15, 2004.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

