<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73B8D3C5AEDA4BCFA5D82AD87B553776" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 913 IH: Expressing the opposition of the House of Representatives to any grant of commutation, clemency, or pardon to federally convicted child sex trafficker Ghislaine Maxwell, who refuses to take responsibility for her crimes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 913</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251125">November 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing the opposition of the House of Representatives to any grant of commutation, clemency, or pardon to federally convicted child sex trafficker Ghislaine Maxwell, who refuses to take responsibility for her crimes.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Ghislaine Maxwell is a federally convicted child sex trafficker and co-conspirator in Jeffrey Epstein’s years-long, multibillion dollar international child sex trafficking ring;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Ghislaine Maxwell was sentenced to 20 years in prison for her role in a scheme to sexually exploit and abuse multiple minor girls with Jeffrey Epstein over the course of a decade;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Ghislaine Maxwell was previously found guilty of conspiracy to entice minors to travel to engage in illegal sex acts, conspiracy to transport minors to participate in illegal sex acts, transporting a minor to participate in illegal sex acts, sex trafficking conspiracy, and sex trafficking of a minor;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Ghislaine Maxwell has served just three years and four months of her 20-year sentence, or 1/5th of the total time she was sentenced to serve for her crimes;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Ghislaine Maxwell has refused to take any responsibility for her crimes or express any remorse or contrition for her crimes, but rather has continued to lie about the crimes she committed and facilitated;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Ghislaine Maxwell, rather than showing contrition or remorse for her crimes, has instead demeaned and disparaged the victims who she trafficked and exploited when they were children; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Ghislaine Maxwell fails every requirement considered by the Department of Justice’s Office of the Pardon Attorney in making clemency recommendations to the President: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H7267EB94C6F04478A0C4A9BF4BBCDC6C"> <section id="H5FE23EC767E745EEB9C7058F238815C6" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H33EC240DA3CA4CE8B0E72FF05C347B4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">opposes any grant of commutation, clemency, or pardon to federally convicted child sex trafficker Ghislaine Maxwell, who refuses to take any responsibility for her crimes and continues to lie about them;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H234A519D857546EAB15EA2BE28E95749"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reiterates its support for the survivors and victims of Jeffrey Epstein and Ghislaine Maxwell; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H075D505864BF4A1691D3702B80132586"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reaffirms the need for the full and complete release of the Epstein files.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

