<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBF9F2827C1AE4BE9B355F91BEF8CA2BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9077 IH: Hormone Health Data and Research Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9077</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the National Institutes of Health and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to evaluate hormone variability and hormone testing, respectively, in women with respect to perimenopause.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2D24AB8E440E49AA8203250027557F7E" style="OLC">
<section id="H6C3AF2E229C243889A5485EB1EA8E172" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hormone Health Data and Research Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9F96C1171DE24C2EAE9CEE8C2694BA6E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Studies on hormone variability and hormone testing with respect to perimenopause</header> <subsection id="HCDCFD8C72FB04F9187C30DE103047D5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>NIH study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall evaluate any evidence published on or prior to the date of enactment of this Act that relates to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEC5747FF191C450F97E4D7AFF8AE73BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the variability of hormone levels in a woman before such woman experiences symptoms of perimenopause; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FD2AAC5358944FA8874DF2A5E10072B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any baseline pattern in such variability.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD35C4192374D4F3985C3B89DDC525405"><enum>(b)</enum><header>U.S. Preventive Services Task Force study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the United States Preventive Services Task Force, shall review any evidence published on or prior to the date of enactment of this Act related to the clinical utility of hormone testing, including whether baseline information obtained on the hormone levels of a woman before such woman experiences symptoms of perimenopause meaningfully informs the diagnosis or management of perimenopause for such woman.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H02E12E6ADB574BE98770CAC42ADE3AEB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after enactment of this Act, NIH and USPSTF shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and Senate, the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate summarizing findings, identifying evidence gaps, and providing recommendations for future research or clinical guidance.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

