<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H043830B1497846B18F3D6256517C12DB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5888 IH: UNtaxed Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251031">October 31, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000575">Mr. Rogers of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for limitations on the implementation and enforcement of a global carbon tax with respect to the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H64239B89D40147428E0D01476310A578" style="OLC"><section id="HAA4D005D638E45A2A4ADA4FBFECD1EE6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>UNtaxed Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1DDA71462443415088FF8FE355F9065A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on United Nations taxes, tariffs, fees, or other such penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No tax, tariff, fee, or other such penalty may be levied upon United States citizens or United States companies by the United Nations or any organization, specialized agency, commission, or other formally affiliated body of the United Nations, unless such tax, tariff, fee, or other such penalty is imposed under an agreement that is in effect with respect to the United States and the Senate has provided its advice and consent to ratification of the agreement.</text></section><section id="H53CAFE075699485D9C79845C644CE0BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on funds relating to global carbon taxes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for—</text><paragraph id="H00B3137567E64FEA87085B660EF94D90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assessed or voluntary contributions of the United States to the United Nations or any United Nations-affiliated body that would be used to impose a global carbon tax; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B84FD7D90FB457EB2DF5FA01127AA62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implementation or enforcement of such a global carbon tax.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB24794EC72FB45AAB0548F7EA8A4B3F9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>global carbon tax</term> means a tax imposed under a global fuel regime that—</text><paragraph id="HEE308C39FCDD46FFA753406571D0A223"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requires owners or operators of vessels to reduce the level of greenhouse gases emitted by the vessel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A06DDCD67004E99B855D3A33B7FCCE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>imposes such a tax at set costs with respect to such level of emission of greenhouse gases.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

