<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2F19A815D9304D9090F18D653A7D164C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6658 IH: Ban on Self-Interested Contracting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6658</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit covered Federal awards for certain special Government employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H39F922A0221345E583597B6E4646377B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H93424753C4E646A4A9F1EB21A6E10F0F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ban on Self-Interested Contracting Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BASIC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H6C0DFE6B302F4269B826E3AE2AB3F5A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on covered Federal awards for special Government employees</header> 
<subsection id="HDB81E497D3174A6EB713150AFECD6C57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/11">Chapter 11</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/220">section 220</external-xref> the following (and conforming the table of sections of such chapter accordingly):</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H9BD09E1FECD8418F9322CE4D746B8133" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H60E633125EA846369F245F6165088F81"><enum>221.</enum><header>Prohibition on covered Federal awards for special Government employees</header> <subsection id="HA152FBF0BFFA453BBD018A93909F85C7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (c), any special Government employee who knowingly demands, seeks, receives, accepts, or agrees to receive or accept, directly or indirectly, any covered Federal award offered or issued by their employing agency shall be subject to the penalties set forth in section 216 of this title.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H63AADD177F7642E19F704B76BC815EDE"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), a special Government employee indirectly demands, seeks, receives, accepts, or agrees to receive or accept a covered Federal award if—</text> <paragraph id="H41B975A85BA6458897EE793E2436DB68"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such award is given, with the employee’s knowledge and acquiescence to the employee's parent, sibling, spouse, child, dependent relative, or a member of the employee's household because of that person's relationship to the employee or the employee’s spouse, minor child, or general partner; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H53C898F391AB41809800F976938BDD10"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such award is given to any organization with whom the employee is an officer, director, trustee, general partner, or employee, or is negotiating for, or otherwise has an arrangement for employment, if—</text> <subparagraph id="H13C783F671134972BD33FA54F5BD945B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employee will aid or assist the organization in seeking, negotiating, or performing any part of the work under the covered Federal award; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6504E60ADEE14CA6920677673DCE05DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the employee will receive any compensation traceable to the covered Federal award.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE3E5B41EC998400CA272C2A9AB8B6583"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) does not apply to a special Government employee who—</text> 
<paragraph id="H725FAF92F39846758D3624AF44E99807"><enum>(1)</enum><text>only serves as a member of an advisory committee;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7ADBD22383FB4C1C8032087EAF9A9461"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has duties comparable to the duties of an individual in a position at GS–10 of the General Schedule or lower; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2F899AA3CE54BBF86681146C8C04F38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has a position designated exclusively for students.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB46BD1F940B64C8EB5C31A1B6A6D38A4"><enum>(d)</enum><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H436B4A1395E9484A880011393E38992E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>advisory committee</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1001 of title 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H512005078F2F40A08DA30A8B00DB975B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered Federal award</quote> means a contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other contract-like instrument, including an agreement entered into pursuant to other transaction authority, that awards to the recipient on an annual basis an amount that is more than $1,000,000.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H112D987DA32E43E8937FFED3563C44D0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Revisions required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this section, part 3 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation and part 200, Code of Federal Regulations, shall be revised to prohibit any officer or employee of an executive branch agency or department from awarding a covered Federal award if to do so would violate section 2(a) of this Act in accordance with this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H639B52402E0C496ABEB65F828EB804B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Office of Government Ethics shall issue regulatory guidance on this section and the amendment made by this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8B8722ECE982419DB8D61B03E7B76037"><enum>3.</enum><header>Publication of certain information relating to special Government employees</header> 
<subsection id="H09D0013DB570430E93303A0BCEC66A0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Position data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3330f(a)(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0975550F5E604B6AA408BAC82557C176"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14829C8FFAFB464994CF3126F664596E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (B) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DDCD19296584CB3B9319A3B4821FAC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H7436488868B24E049364FA15F9BE52E4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H252323D97D8C45CB85DBCF2261C10C7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any special Government employee (as that term is defined in section 202(a) of title 18), but not including any such employee who—</text> <clause id="HAC6F0187FB0E41ED98680FA0E2FC0DB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>only serves as a member of an advisory committee;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB8085DD491254DCE8A0AB78C75F9E7BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has duties comparable to the duties of an individual in a position at GS–10 of the General Schedule or lower; or</text></clause> <clause id="H516CE4438A9D44F1A313F5A8EF8046DE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has a position designated exclusively for students.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5DC4079A41D4A77ABB6CC7A9B68B8EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Financial disclosure reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/131">chapter 131</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, including section 13109, each Executive agency shall make publicly available any financial disclosure report filed by a special Government employee with the Executive agency after the date of the enactment of this Act, using the procedures established under section 13107 of such title, except that this subsection shall not apply to any financial disclosure report that is filed by—</text> <paragraph id="HB7B6A85B150744CD90FA61559A4267F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 13107(a) of such title; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H344BF4A5A78749C195AB1BA4612A26C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a special Government employee described in subsection (c) of section 221 of title 18, United States Code (as added by section 2(a) of this Act).</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> <section id="HF1D948AD830E47EB83605B560490294B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Database of special Government employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1103 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H58479D66357F4AD5B1AAE52D5EDCE8B0" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H7DB0F5164B034A39A41DC62ABD0128BA"><enum>(d)</enum> 
<paragraph id="H22FC88FC2F2A4F9FBD7699EDEA83E0F9" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered individual</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H4828EA832B814682A44B4FF172E2800A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an individual who is a special Government employee who is not serving on an advisory committee; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE3BC6058728429BA1B6208AD3085FF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include an individual described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 13107(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71D1A12AB5AE45B3ABAFDB2C5B9AA068" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director, in coordination with the Office of Government Ethics, shall maintain to the extent technically practicable, keep current, and make available to the public over the internet, without a fee or other access charge, in a searchable, sortable, and downloadable manner, an electronic database that contains the name of each covered individual, a rolling tally of the number of days the person has served as a special Government employee, and a description of why the individual was designated as a special Government employee rather than a regular employee.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

