<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5395A773FEB547D7873E1725545874D2" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1282 IH: Recognizing the 75th anniversary of the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists and its critical role in advancing the practice of obstetrics and gynecology and the health and well-being of patients through excellence in clinical practice, education, advocacy, and research.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1282</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260513">May 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 75th anniversary of the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists and its critical role in advancing the practice of obstetrics and gynecology and the health and well-being of patients through excellence in clinical practice, education, advocacy, and research.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists (ACOG) was founded in 1951 and is the leading professional membership organization for obstetrician-gynecologists;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, as of its 75th anniversary, ACOG represents more than 62,000 health care professionals nationwide, who provide essential obstetric and gynecologic care to patients across the Nation;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas ACOG members live in and provide obstetric and gynecologic care to millions of United States citizens in every congressional district;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, for 75 years, ACOG has supported members in their delivery of exceptional, respectful, science-based, and patient-centered care to patients across their lifespan and has served as a trusted source for accessible, reliable obstetric and gynecologic health information;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas ACOG and its members have championed initiatives to improve maternal health, reduce maternal and infant mortality, protect the patient physician relationship, and protect access to health care for all individuals;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas ACOG works to ensure a well-supported obstetrics and gynecology physician workforce, and to create a stronger, more sustainable practice environment for obstetrician-gynecologists and their patients no matter where they live; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the 75th anniversary of ACOG offers an opportunity to recognize its historic contributions and reaffirm Congress’ commitment to advancing the health of patients: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H8E94EE0746424CEAA083D7DAFE94E6B5"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H725AEC2AC5CA42D787CCAE37558F5062"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE65F1A4BDAE04B9A8BEEC17A9291EB7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>celebrates the 75th anniversary of the founding of the American College of Obstetricians and Gynecologists;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70B0DC35B4704A89BA73F4F1079B8E4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends its members for their dedication to preventing maternal deaths and adverse health outcomes, reducing health care costs, and improving the health of patients;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBAD4ED7C39D40EFBA63F113CAC00C44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes its service and leadership at the forefront of obstetric and gynecologic care; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H18EC6636393148FDBE9953BBB6E21578"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commits to supporting the continued advancement of obstetric and gynecological health, investing in women’s health care and research, and strengthening access to critical obstetric and gynecological care for patients across the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

