<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE737C4AE2CFF408B906C599BBE96C1BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6339 IH: District of Columbia Special Elections Home Rule Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6339</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251201">December 1, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to permit the District of Columbia to establish the timing of special elections for local office in the District of Columbia.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFD5BB35EF90C44A4AE7130204D7A4A05" style="OLC"><section id="H36E7DF6C433E4BC2951F886AE78D1D32" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>District of Columbia Special Elections Home Rule Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD3A9A5472237477490680F62DC0902C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Timing of special elections for local office in District of Columbia</header><subsection id="H69C5156C22BF4EB8B96B3E9BB0D6062C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Council</header><paragraph id="H19F79FE649E241EF9A4D8394162B3372"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first sentence of section 401(b)(3) of the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (sec. 1–204.01(b)(3), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows: <quote>To fill a vacancy in the Office of Chairman, the Board of Elections shall hold a special election in the District in accordance with such procedures, including procedures establishing the time of the election, as may be established by law of the District of Columbia.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87681928B8F248EDB6730387B6032B8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members elected from wards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first sentence of section 401(d)(1) of such Act (sec. 1–204.01(d)(1), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows: <quote>In the event of a vacancy in the Council of a member elected from a ward, the Board of Elections shall hold a special election in the District in accordance with such procedures, including procedures establishing the time of the election, as may be established by law of the District of Columbia.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4F02E07D5144D82AD3F719CD48C9AC3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Members elected at-large</header><text>The second sentence of section 401(d)(2) of such Act (sec. 1–204.01(d)(2), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>and such special election</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>and such special election shall be held in accordance with such procedures, including procedures establishing the time of the election, as may be established by law of the District of Columbia.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H693FAAE6896B4F448A0814E7DCA026C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mayor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first sentence of section 421(c)(2) of such Act (sec. 1–204.21(c)(2), D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows: <quote>To fill a vacancy in the Office of Mayor, the Board of Elections shall hold a special election in the District in accordance with such procedures, including procedures establishing the time of the election, as may be established by law of the District of Columbia.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB3389072B64F4BAB9364B3BC4EA3CF17"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Attorney General</header><text>The first sentence of section 435(b)(1) of such Act (sec. 1–204.35(b)(1), D.C. Official Code) is amended by striking <quote>the Board of Elections</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>the Board of Elections shall hold a special election in the District in accordance with such procedures, including procedures establishing the time of the election, as may be established by law of the District of Columbia.</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H77BA15E6AC174251BD2031FC6DF755DE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply with respect to vacancies occurring after the expiration of the one-year period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

