<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-MEE26106-27V-TL-6DC"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 803 ATS: Congratulating the 2025-2026 Carolina Hurricanes for winning the Stanley Cup.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 803</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Congratulating the 2025-2026 Carolina Hurricanes for winning the Stanley Cup.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the Carolina Hurricanes dominated their rivals throughout the 2026 Stanley Cup playoffs, finishing the playoffs with a postseason record of 16-3;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on June 14, 2026, the Carolina Hurricanes defeated the Vegas Golden Knights in the Golden Knights's home arena in game 6 of the Stanley Cup Final, winning the series 4-2;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with this victory, the Carolina Hurricanes won their second ever Stanley Cup, coming 20 years after their first Stanley Cup;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the team was led by legendary Head Coach Rod Brind’Amour, who, 20 years ago, was captain of the team during their first Stanley Cup run;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Captain Jordan Staal scored 6 goals in the Stanley Cup Finals, including at least 1 goal in each of the first 5 games of the series, and was awarded the Conn Smythe Trophy as the most valuable player of the Stanley Cup Playoffs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this winning season was also made possible by General Manager Eric Tulsky and every member of the Carolina Hurricanes organization;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there have been reports of <quote>Storm Surge</quote> across the Carolinas since game 6 as the <quote>Caniacs</quote> celebrate their hard-earned victory; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Carolina Hurricanes are active in their community through programs supporting children and families, military servicemembers, and public safety personnel across North Carolina: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H93DB97E9E142494A917C284B241FFE52"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the Senate congratulates the 2026 Stanley Cup champions, the Carolina Hurricanes.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

