<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE0EAE2BE729446E09C4C2471AB4E461D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9565 IH: Enhanced Counter-Narcotics Detection and Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9565</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, to implement large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology at land ports of entry identified as high risk, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0E624B48AEA946BEBD8FE618DC3DBD1C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF8BF5452242B46E888A8F2E5F60F8115" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhanced Counter-Narcotics Detection and Technology Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H3B3422B22DD8455989181B4432DF5888"><enum>2.</enum><header>Large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology at land ports of entry identified as high risk</header> 
<subsection id="H00FD8DBAAA16435B831C59E1AB990114"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle B of title IV of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/211">6 U.S.C. 211 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H37FD347F268E460EAD2B9EE328A048FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H65C12814986C4AF8987BFB784A918574"><enum>420.</enum><header>Large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology at land ports of entry identified as high risk</header> <subsection id="H0995B67E36BD40ADAA601D4C062CC8D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commissioner</quote>), shall establish an annual process to identify the land ports of entry that, on the basis of drug seizure volume, are either of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2ABFB09157D54D38A8F69233D636C3F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>At or above the 70th percentile of all land ports of entry with respect to the northern border of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB194139BD7EC42AB87201C669D06255A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At or above the 70th percentile of all land ports of entry with respect to the southern border of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7CF44DA65825426E883C7E6B7F034070">
              <enum>(b)</enum>
              <header>High-Risk port</header>
 <text>A land port of entry identified under subsection (a) shall be referred to as a <quote>high-risk port</quote>.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3C7B4B9D93E84C91B7DB362F0D97E52B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than one year after the Commissioner identifies a high-risk port under subsection (a), the Commissioner shall carry out the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA9543939506C4B83AAE66AC1959DE770"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Implement in the screening of cargo at such port large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology, unless the Commissioner determines, based on metrics and criteria established under paragraph (2), that such technology is not effective.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA50EB4A91D4D4BBF8DF05CFD2350D3E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establish metrics and criteria for determining the effectiveness of such technology.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H82C99C19CB764EB3B153A590C7265A06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Screening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than one year after large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology has been implemented at a high-risk port pursuant to subsection (c)(1), the Commissioner shall utilize such technology in the screening of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC16D6D4F4856482B94AE02B02BF31863"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not less than 40 percent of the passenger vehicles entering the United States through such port and for which such technology is feasible for such screening.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE2A61D21478346969DBA3451E2527071"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not less than 70 percent of the commercial vehicles entering the United States through such port and for which such technology is feasible for such screening.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H56A57CC011CD42D8B3BB37D1601B0694"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Commissioner shall ensure relevant personnel of U.S. Customs and Border Protection receive training on any large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology implemented pursuant to subsection (c)(1).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H1E19056EDAA847B1A0C25068F8DCF657"><enum>(f)</enum><header>New technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology has been implemented pursuant to subsection (c)(1) and annually thereafter, the Commissioner shall seek to identify technology that satisfies the following requirements:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3C7ECFFE0C7D4FF89F3F9536BEF28E6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Has not been so implemented.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF27EEFAAC4574A2AAB3AB6BFE8EB9959"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Has potential to improve the screening of cargo at high-risk ports.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8343D7ECD5B440EEA26DA67A0C3E12D0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology has been implemented pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (c) and annually thereafter, the Commissioner shall submit to Congress a report that includes information relating to the following for the annual period covered by such report:</text> <paragraph id="H9D5CB162DCF24B7BB579A18D20D99D38"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The effectiveness of such technology, based on metrics and criteria established under paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EE49275161A4EF18A35FDA9D8A4B428"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The technology, if any, identified pursuant to subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H355FE1B75599458AAB0ED7A32DC7DC80"> <enum>(h)</enum> <header>Large scale, non-Intrusive inspection technology defined</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology</term> means an x-ray, gamma-ray, or other passive imaging system, that satisfies the following requirements:</text>
              <paragraph id="H63A577B9D72342879881D6C317874C92">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Can be utilized to inspect cargo for contraband, hazards, and anomalies that indicate potential threats.</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="H51DF9B1C40E14BA3998A4DB61DB70192">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Any other requirement the Commissioner determines appropriate.</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4422284E249A4F8B8C79CCFFEF654CF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 419 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA57E6F33026040ECA3148D3D824F2752"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 420. Large-scale, non-intrusive inspection technology at land ports of entry identified as high risk.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

