<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C2EA4BBF6DB4706B9A7F67F078C8053" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8321 IH: Artemis Accords Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8321</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000596">Mrs. Luna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote peaceful space exploration, expand participation in the Artemis Accords, establish norms for safe and sustainable space activities, and advance national security and economic competitiveness through leadership in space.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF0C63C477220457F832F05B926A22835" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H456CF378A43049F8A563ACF722D7320C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Artemis Accords Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5D3D41FB63C84F7F8F262EFC80BF99EE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings: </text> 
<paragraph id="H6987E1175B2C40AAAFEDD9409A067BCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has long been a global leader in space exploration, scientific discovery, and the development of technologies that benefit both national security and economic growth.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6E1534F00B744149F29275BE0CDB969"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Artemis program, led by the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), represents the next phase of human space exploration, including returning humans to the Moon and establishing a sustainable presence for future missions to Mars.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H844B45C941124A29ADBCF00B4BBB3F5C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Artemis Accords were first introduced in 2020 by NASA, in coordination with the Department of State and seven other initial signatory countries, including Australia, Canada, Italy, Japan, Luxembourg, the United Arab Emirates, and the United Kingdom.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H063D813A197743E89937231B2F9C817F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Over the last five years, the Artemis Accords have expanded to 61 signatories. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF502492158D4AD79537172F49A0F435"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Artemis Accords reinforce the commitment by signatory nations to foundational space law instruments—including the Outer Space Treaty, the Registration Convention, and the Rescue and Return Agreement—while also promoting best practices and norms for responsible civil space exploration and use.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC405570021BD41B588D77E0A41522216"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7D8096E99544486EA41E14E798BA339B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote the peaceful exploration and use of outer space, including the Moon and other celestial bodies, consistent with international law;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1D7F60208BA4C3A84BCF2988249E7EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to strengthen international cooperation through the Artemis Accords as a framework for transparency, compatibility, and responsible behavior in space;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBBDD4AE6DD7450E9A0DCFA04DF43C3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to maintain United States leadership in civil space exploration, scientific discovery, and commercial space development;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94E1FD1771D24C3F8F0FC3080E2A68F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support the development of norms and standards that ensure the safety, sustainability, and long-term viability of space activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H741FF54B82FF498D926D36BD00EDC959"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to expand participation in the Artemis Accords among allies and partners, particularly in strategically significant regions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC15CFD297C94634AE97BA1B6E06D17A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to counter efforts by strategic competitors to shape space governance in ways that are inconsistent with democratic values, transparency, and the rule of law; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58DE58E22BD04B11BD112F973CF832B2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to advance United States national security, economic competitiveness, and diplomatic engagement through sustained leadership in space exploration initiatives.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H6519EEC14CF94943B33D0F50B3A86258"><enum>4.</enum><header>Special Coordinator for the Artemis Accords</header> <subsection id="H330F439665304042A3CCB597BE1D1419"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State is authorized to establish, carry out, and broaden the Artemis Accords espousing the principles set forth in section 3. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H952C6697BC4247DAB1073E4A35B8F4F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special Coordinator</header><text>There shall be a Special Coordinator for the Artemis Accords, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of State and shall report to Assistant Secretary for Oceans, International Environment and Scientific Affairs. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H562DA6A6B6224E77B21794D9E9AADB4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Special Coordinator shall be responsible for—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA53CD0864ED443D9BF7849840CE28B82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>leading diplomatic efforts to expand participation in the Artemis Accords;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H695FB7C74D6945E6AB7A5EC0D5F4AAEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinating United States engagement with foreign governments, international organizations, and commercial partners regarding civil space cooperation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9E80E13C82B4159AE73E0718E35C37D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting the development of international norms governing lunar activities, space resource extraction, and space traffic management;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E198D072F054F688721986ED0DA95A3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinating with relevant United States agencies, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF230A7C1C20049F7B06AFC2BA4D5B632"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9FF14EB6EAB84C9A83A28E3CDA09863C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94AA547EF7694F3C8CF3218040D22CA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B62AAD228D544D989F3002FBDEEFA08"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Office of Space Commerce;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33135712F7C149C4BE34CF6B706B0654"><enum>(5)</enum><text>engaging with United States industry stakeholders to advance public-private partnerships in support of the Artemis program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4366BF687B845068CE4D9BA30E5C9BF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>advising the Department on strategies to ensure that United States leadership in space is aligned with broader foreign policy and national security objectives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6059810EAAC047EA846F4A569D128CB9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header> 
<subsection id="H733EE07C263F41DBA312305931A9F4B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for four years, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of NASA, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HE1F7FC2D458B4014B50A6D200B7B2FAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of countries participating in the Artemis Accords and any new signatories during the reporting period;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB3213803BD84CB8AF72FFF1B3F68C01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of diplomatic efforts undertaken by the United States to expand participation in the Artemis Accords;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H961DD81368E64B88AEB305E116B023FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of compliance by participating countries with the principles of the Artemis Accords;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F1DED02B65B46C5A16A0104A9E2A451"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of ongoing and planned cooperative activities related to lunar exploration and other space missions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E3BEAB5BE874E35AFCF3464A16BD9E5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an evaluation of the role of United States commercial entities in Artemis-related partnerships;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H79FCBDAB60E74FBBB54B15B29892B617"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an assessment of challenges to international cooperation in space, including geopolitical competition, regulatory barriers, and technological compatibility;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B496D9D740446479D7BF2289DB3CCBC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of efforts by the People’s Republic of China and the Russian Federation to influence global space governance and how such efforts impact United States interests; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB9FA909B35B4404986D433C1D6F9EA7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>recommendations to strengthen United States leadership in international space cooperation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFA23BD3D25AC4777B2EFA2A7723957D0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H836E7E151AF441C4A4F1D0C4FC83FE7A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Strategy</header> 
<subsection id="H449A8B2E12A84016AE81F91E499B56FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H40514BEBD18B42CAA6E795C85BAA731B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-earth orbit satellite technology is crucial for maintaining United States leadership in the 21st century in both military and civil technology domains;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0689197CEAE641E4A5CD790622ABC7D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>low-earth orbit satellite technology has potential to serve as an anti-censorship and pro free speech technology around the world;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF814CBF990B4418E87DC1118E18F44D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>low-earth orbit satellite technology has incredible humanitarian potential to connect hundreds of millions people to the internet and the modern global economy; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H352F1CC5744643829EB7192DFD73C886"><enum>(4)</enum><text>instruments of the United States Government should be used to promote the export, use, and potential of American low-earth orbit satellite technology. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H07B10FE7AB1040BDAFE78198C3273C7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Chief Executive Officer of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Director of the United States Trade and Development Agency, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a strategy on the integration of low-earth orbit satellite technologies and high-altitude platform systems into United States foreign policy.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEC4319F1537141EEBA38DAAA387A9056"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required by subsection (b) shall include efforts and plans to—</text> <paragraph id="H24B9494E5C334684A0FD2D1EA61E461C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use feasibility studies to promote low-earth orbit satellite technology as a form of connectivity;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H141823B8D9274518A2D8A994D61BA12A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offer loans, guarantees, insurance or other financial products to help countries procure low-earth orbit satellite technologies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32ADD6C32E4247C488E816F94160ABCF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>directly provide low-earth orbit satellite technologies to countries when consistent with the United States’ national interest;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1328FF792ABF4A2180D08CDB9DAC3A76"><enum>(4)</enum><text>regulate, as appropriate, the export of controlled low-earth orbit satellite technologies to ensure continued American technological leadership and the misuse of the technology inconsistent with our policies and values; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FD96042E0FB4856BEF84BC78846CA6A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>impose possible restrictions on strategic competitor’s alternatives to American low-earth orbit satellite technologies. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD25EECEDEFAC4373BB28CD09204E7E52"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

