<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C31A258CE0C4291BD46AB318A72B05F" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1217 IH: Expressing support for the citizens of the United Kingdom as they continue to face assaults on their rights to free speech and freedom of expression.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1217</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the citizens of the United Kingdom as they continue to face assaults on their rights to free speech and freedom of expression.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas the right to free speech and freedom of expression, guaranteed by the First Amendment to the Constitution, is critical to upholding the fundamental underpinnings of democracy in the United States and in democracies around the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas freedom of speech and freedom of expression foster conversation, debate, and understanding;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas citizens of the United States should not have their rights to free speech or freedom of expression restricted by any foreign government;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Prime Minister Keir Starmer and other officials of the United Kingdom have taken actions that censor, imprison, or otherwise punish their own citizens for exercising their rights to free speech and freedom of expression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the refusal of Prime Minister Keir Starmer and other officials of the United Kingdom to halt mass migration into the United Kingdom has contributed to social unrest and prompted citizens of the United Kingdom to express their displeasure with such policies online;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Toby Young, founder and director of the Free Speech Union, and his organization have experienced an influx of members as a result of citizens of the United Kingdom facing consequences for exercising their rights to free speech and freedom of expression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in September 2025, more than 100,000 individuals assembled in London to protest the violations of their rights to free speech and freedom of expression;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas oversight by the Committee on the Judiciary has revealed that the government of the United Kingdom seeks to censor United States-based platforms and legitimate criticisms of its policies;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Online Safety Act grants government regulators broad authority to regulate forms of expression that they arbitrarily deem offensive or improper;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas London Metropolitan Police Chief Mark Rowley has repeatedly threatened to arrest both citizens of the United Kingdom and of the United States for online comments, and has singled out Elon Musk, the owner of the social media platform X;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas five armed police officers detained Irish comedian Graham Linehan upon his arrival at Heathrow Airport from Arizona in connection with posts he had made on X;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Ed Davey, leader of the Liberal Democratic Party, has called for the arrest of Elon Musk and regards him as a criminal in connection with comments Musk made on his own platform;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Isabel Vaughan-Spruce, director of March for Life UK, was arrested twice within five months for silently praying outside an abortion clinic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Adam Smith-Connor, a British Army veteran, was convicted and forced to pay a fine for silently praying outside an abortion clinic; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas British authorities arrest more than 12,000 individuals in the United Kingdom each year for speech-related offenses, averaging roughly 30 individuals per day: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HB570D3B60C034CA0BC94F92C67628409"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H715ECC41F74A4802904E155A5980A351"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H897DD0081A994EF0B36CD2F444F02F92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses disapproval of Prime Minister Keir Starmer and the Labour Party for violating the rights to freedom of speech and expression of the citizens of the United Kingdom;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1FCC55FB6314C83AAA3315634B06EEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>condemns statements and actions by officials of the United Kingdom that seek to extradite American citizens for exercising the right to freedom of speech guaranteed under the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6280991635F4D8E935C25614AB12F74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges the Trump Administration to employ all necessary resources, including tariffs, sanctions, revocation of visas, and other measures, to hold accountable officials of the United Kingdom who act as though they are above the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD39D79EF8E448283731142C751979C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>urges the Trump Administration to refuse recognition of any laws or orders of the United Kingdom that infringe upon the rights to freedom of speech and expression;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D3E0D164EA14A5890D6D6A9A6F52C59"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reaffirms that, in commemoration of the 250th anniversary of the United States of America, our Founding Fathers and patriots fought against a tyrannical government that levied unjust taxes, violated fundamental rights, and restricted the rights to freedom of speech and expression; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBD1B6F822AC42719119AE006B552E10"><enum>(6)</enum><text>reaffirms that the constitutionally protected rights of American citizens take precedence over any actions by officials of the United Kingdom aimed at undermining such rights.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

