<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E925C78B6374CA8A70A6D9C6BC174AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6145 IH: Experts Protect Effective Rules, Transparency, and Stability Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6145</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001131">Mr. Casar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000602">Ms. Lee of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require disclosure of conflicts of interest with respect to rulemaking, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HA782AC189E2849AA8DAFF9BD9BBEE51E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6998EF60CD684B48A6B79A73AC4CDFE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Experts Protect Effective Rules, Transparency, and Stability Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EXPERTS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H3C113193CEB34B26A29C82CD4A2AD20A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H583D76686708488D96A67D014E398FF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress is dependent on providing discretion to executive officials and agencies (including independent agencies) to implement its statutes. Congress provides appropriate oversight of the use of this discretion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2BB50238DDC40F19015114570397C7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulatory legislation is often phrased in broad terms, with an intelligible principle, to empower agencies to address issues, such as those presented by technological, scientific, or social developments that were not precisely foreseen when the legislation was enacted, and to draw upon the agency's specialized knowledge, experience, and responsibility for implementing the statute.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF294436B2AA441DD87E0AE66EF787667"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such broad authorizing language is often necessary to empower the administering agency to take effective action when new or unforeseen issues arise, provided that the rule does not exceed clear limits in statute nor implement it in an impermissible manner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H677175C8AE524821A63960237091CF74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A rule that an agency has adopted to implement a broadly worded regulatory statute should generally not be held to be invalid on the basis that Congress has not addressed the agency’s proposed course of action in specific terms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H622D3B9A13944A2ABF9974D40B5681C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A rule that an agency has adopted to implement a regulatory statute should generally not be held to be invalid on the basis that the agency has not previously adopted a similar rule or scheme of regulation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EFE54EAD59545F79B13DF36F01E1FF9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expectation that a rule will have broad economic, political, or social significance, should not, standing alone, negate application of the principle stated in paragraph (1), (2), or (3).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H2158C8EC68074B66BD14C01FF1807168" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H4898CA97A1E244A9AE17562E5EDCFC3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>agency economic analyses of regulatory actions commonly underestimate the benefits of regulatory actions that protect public health and safety and overestimate the costs of regulatory action to industry;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC42BD1C0EF5249BF846E202DB7E6A4F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agency regulatory actions often fail to adequately consider the distributional effects and social equity impact of regulatory action; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1EE3731F8CA40AEB1A867D5A9EB0514"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an agency shall prioritize the statutory direction of Congress when taking regulatory action. </text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE7A277AFE9A043EFA3F206E1F2E81A78"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosure of conflicts of interest</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H69F55F7A0E9F4762927BFAF5D2FDFEAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H89ACD711551447AFB3E96B567D1FCF10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>After notice required</quote> and inserting the following: </text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HBACF53885B404AA8A5CAFB81C6698FFB" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HCA45753C2C8340F1BBE2CE3A59490680"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After notice required </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7ECA08BDF0DE4AE9ABAB177DA9236398"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the first sentence of paragraph (1), as so designated, by inserting <quote>, subject to subsections (f) and (h),</quote> after <quote>the agency shall</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07C91156F8384B41956153B6E20CAAC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="HC5BEAFC2EAF44A30AF2E4C3D64E2DD21" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HA827638E54E64E088886CC7942F6DA81"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any submission under paragraph (1) by an interested person that includes a scientific, economic, or technical study or research (or a citation thereto) that the interested person funded directly or indirectly, or the nonpublic results of any scientific, economic, or technical study or research that the interested person funded directly or indirectly, the interested person shall disclose to the agency the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H66B3DBE0E97F43858B685FBF57FB7E21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The amount of any funds that were received by the person who conducted the study or research.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48A36D4DF6E049C5B11A34C9FDC4A85E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The entity that provided the funds referred to in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H31991A28338647F79FCA651553037911"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any entity that was allowed to review or revise the study or research, and the extent of that review or revision.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5C9EF485A274EE6980E32ED94EFEB67"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any financial relationship between the person who conducted the study or research, and any person that would be affected by the proposed rule. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BC89AA623F645AB8631BA98DD1065FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1BF23BEAF35746E2A34F6F7810FC9EB2" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H024D1E5DDBE74806ADE019CCFEDFEA87"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any submission by an interested person under subsection (c) or any other submission by an interested person relating to a proposed rule or final rule that includes a scientific, economic, or technical study or research by the interested person not published in a publicly available peer-reviewed publication, or any result of a scientific, economic, or technical study or research by the interested person not published in a publicly available peer-reviewed publication, the interested person, in making that submission, shall disclose to the agency—</text> <paragraph id="H51B0297512BC4C648374468BD6800E8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the source of any funding for the study or research, as applicable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59F6399833B8428B98A487B1BC2E2318"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any entity that sponsored the study or research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD10D97C4EB1F4E0CB67C79F653EF1BC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which the findings of the study or research were reviewed by a person that may be affected by the rulemaking to which the submission relates;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42888E2E60004A2B89E0BA347D2332F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the identity of any person identified under paragraph (3); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97A4802E267B4B6084D23387C3930617"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the nature of any financial relationship, including a consulting agreement, the support of any expert witness, and the funding of research, between any person that conducted the study or research and any interested person with respect to the rulemaking to which the submission relates.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HECB2FE85CF4C4D10B4BE7481BD2D9BCC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increasing disclosures relating to studies and research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 4 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block id="H5C362E436D834D7C837B007FC768C5A4" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HC70730348DEC4CAC9E2D84BAAA3AB92A"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a study or research that is submitted by an interested person to an agency under subsection (c), the agency shall ensure that the study or research is available to the public (including on the Internet website of the agency and on the public docket of the agency for the rulemaking) unless disclosure is exempted or excluded under section 552. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F407741C7BC42FF9D5E5FA8F5C6000D"><enum>(h)</enum> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3BEC215BF351496E90F70A5B139E7D61"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a study or research submitted by an interested person to an agency under subsection (c) presents a conflict described in paragraph (2), the agency shall disclose the conflict to the public on the internet website of the agency and on the public docket of the agency, and by publication in the Federal Register, unless disclosure is exempted or excluded under section 552.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6ED4C8D9C4B44E869D97BF7C98992D09" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A conflict described in this subsection means a study or research for which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1A043FF931F94C939862FEA91B511C54"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 10 percent of the funding for the study or research is from an entity subject to the jurisdiction of the agency with respect to that rulemaking; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C0267C2C96C4FA199A4D549E24EF327"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity subject to the jurisdiction of the agency with respect to that rulemaking that is regulated by the agency conducts, reviews, or revises the study or research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD679651186BA4C8E89AC99BFCA08BDBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of a violation of the requirement to make a disclosure—</text> <paragraph id="H822F62B821DC44A58B8372FD7D6326CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under subsection (c)(2) or subsection (f) with respect to a submission; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H944B5B45FAC24511A482E4892F06334A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>under subsection (h) with respect to a conflict related to a submission referred to under subsection (g), </text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">the agency may exclude from consideration or otherwise disregard the submission, and the agency has no obligation to respond to the submission, except that the submission may be remade with required disclosures during the opportunity for participation referred to in subsection (c)(1). Nothing in this subsection may be construed to affect the level of deference (in accordance with applicable law) accorded to agency action by a court reviewing such action.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H6D0B3207F2C447BBB379C02F372D2FF7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Disclosure of inter-governmental rule change</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to any material provided to the Office with regard to a regulatory action for purposes of centralized review of regulatory actions, the agency shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD986306D4907463FBC517BB96149E1A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than the date on which the agency publishes a general notice of proposed rulemaking required under section 553(b) of title 5, United States Code, with respect to the action, place in the rulemaking docket—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D469181DFCC4734A08A556A1602E37E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the substance of any change between the text of any draft regulatory action that the agency provided to the Office and the text published in the general notice with respect to the action; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE83F6E6341B1462E8EE34296428F9696"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a statement regarding whether any change described in subparagraph (A) was made as a result of communication with—</text> <clause id="HDC08357A95264C1AA6AC03D71B2D2974"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Office;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2E072D1E85994D4996A161281FC19F3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another agency; or</text></clause> <clause id="HAC7C262D10D745ECB92A07FBC94BCBC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal official; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9C5179005424C2FBCD9B57F1B6D68E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than the date on which the agency publishes the regulatory action in the Federal Register, place in the rulemaking docket—</text> <subparagraph id="HAD78BF15EE9248048A1C7E15071852C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the substance of any changes between the text of the regulatory action that the agency provided to the Office and the text of the regulatory action that the agency published in the Federal Register; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3D2DE95FAF9D4606A38B78EE88760A95"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement regarding whether any change described in subparagraph (A) was made as a result of communication with—</text> <clause id="H1052E141028B470981780AA790DBBC61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Office;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBDB901BAEFB8474EB851E43006FA3749"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another agency; or</text></clause> <clause id="H48F82453B35C4A4389EF14309E597B45"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other Federal official.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC30AB612F1864F0BA4B926FBDF755AF7"><enum>7.</enum><header>Justification of withdrawn rules</header> 
<subsection id="H8DE5BA7F136C4CA0B13537FF3607737C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an agency withdraws a regulatory action after providing the action to the Office under section 6(a)(3) of the Executive Order 12866 (or, if the agency does not provide the regulatory action to the Office under that section, after publishing the general notice of proposed rulemaking with respect to the action under section 553(b) of title 5, United States Code), the agency shall publish in the Federal Register, on the public docket of the agency, and on the internet website of the agency a statement regarding the decision by the agency to withdraw the action.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2627C488FF8B4E9085CEB770D515910B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A statement required under subsection (a) with respect to a decision by an agency to withdraw a regulatory action shall include, at a minimum—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4EE87DDCB5884965AB1A5A67A8F32D68" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of the reasons that the agency withdrew the action; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H26EDB77D39C7453295C9B705F7FC1AB7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an explanation regarding whether the decision by the agency to withdraw the action was based, in whole or in part, on a request by, or input from— </text> 
<subparagraph id="HAAC1C90385CD45FEB4E6D54AEEDF21AD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H30C8D7926F034A8AB9E5FF45413A28BD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>another agency; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0925CBDDE3814966A56310CE8B03E058" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other Federal official.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HBA63E8EC8ECD462881430B145E9FDEC9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Negotiated rulemaking</header> <subsection id="HD121A730454D4625ADCF33E9D51976FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H99164D494CC74C75B42834858CA68DAB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 561, in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>between agencies and Federal, State, local, or tribal governments. This subchapter shall apply only to informal negotiations between Federal, State, local, or tribal governments</quote> after <quote>informal rule making process</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF161A991E88C412FB7A42EBF6A0F6C02"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 563—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H957D8AB209E0420C8B9D1072131A7D05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HF58D91997EC249E2990BCB9E01BC75CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>Federal, State, local, or tribal government</quote> after <quote>identifiable</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7BBFC02F6A7D4A2F92CA2C5A1ECDAFEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>persons who</quote> and inserting <quote>representatives of Federal, State, local, and tribal governments that</quote>; and </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5528E196A583462ABC6E217A82CED726"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<clause id="HF10495B85995458CB1F86A44B61301F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subclause id="H8A53E106C00A4C03A4DBE7A1E079B9A6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<item id="HB9073C06668D4296A40406AF8C05B108"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>persons who</quote> and inserting <quote>Federal, State, local, or tribal governments that</quote>; and</text></item> <item id="H3E6496DCB6DA457FB2F5DBD6B8CAED16"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, including residents of rural areas</quote>; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H98AB4727E9F84ACF8F60FD955ED07233"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <item id="H6AE817A23FEA474BA68E62E1D6EABBA7"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>with such persons</quote> and inserting <quote>with representatives of those governments</quote>; and</text></item> 
<item id="HF997B946D7224701B92DA116296E2112"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to such persons</quote> and inserting <quote>to those governments</quote>; and</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF366AE29D0D64035903807D609893F19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the second sentence—</text> 
<subclause id="H1E21A32D023A46EDB9E335558B48AF71"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>persons who</quote> and inserting <quote>representatives of Federal, State, local, or tribal governments that</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H847093F7552D4F9C9C271F8D0F2CC651"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, including residents of rural areas</quote>;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FF4F9DDA2174153A46F4E85D6CC6F23"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 564—</text> <subparagraph id="HF130D925082F49A6BFBA5AF1190DCF2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote>; applications for membership on committees</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3342267E644046D19F41CC3D956F74BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HE254A2EAFE144282805C72370CD843F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>the person or persons</quote> and inserting <quote>the representatives of Federal, State, local, and tribal governments</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6D8B7E06179F48A1AB8157666E142ADF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause> <clause id="HC33831108C8348299B4D197305F6A0DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8D526D91EFC9421D9CEAF4B12A69F9ED"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (8);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50AC336AE10548D9A3D0AE24864AFCA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54EB1F760BF142199800AE1AE10E9F7B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB7B91A7ED3A4326B14E50A2ADCB38F8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in subsection (b), as so redesignated—</text> 
<clause id="H85E9B754AB6E4F7384DF055CCB77721B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and applications</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H11691EA54D0D413585A50613518E72A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and applications</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB61357B939CD4AC8A1A7CF9774253594"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 565(a)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB6605C2CCD764A4992F20DC4C5475780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>and applications</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFBE163FDAAAE4FC0B10C4E36DA7B5E56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HD858A6A2C1D34E34ABE62D60CE48899A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and applications</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H61DF74F8A59B447F9F3E1BADF17FB182"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>publications,</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>publications.</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4682696D0A054B55920638EDC9BFAB79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 569(a), in the first sentence—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDA56BF695B644A47A2835BF86ACD5330"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and encourage agency use of</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFD5CCCAB6CC40C7971CA8EAB7F7E863"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>between Federal, State, local, and tribal governments</quote> after <quote>negotiated rule making</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC4B73793F5684AB1B7D141B5E02A2774"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H3C75A9F8269D4126A21C59FF14FC8CE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Balanced Budget Act of 1997</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1856(b)(1) of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-26">42 U.S.C. 1395w–26</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, using a negotiated rule making process under subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9029ABEB8CDC4727804B9A356BE9CCB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elementary and secondary education act of 1965</header><text>The Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB475090200AD493BA06E419D4F08D2A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 1601 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6571">20 U.S.C. 6571</external-xref>)—</text> <clause id="HD23E49D46A454F009D07D9F0F93F61D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>subsections (b) through (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (b)</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE8CC605BB76B43889AC8D9231DEB752D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) and (c); and</text></clause> <clause id="H4281BBB763D7426F83434F7F806D4815"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) and (e) as subsections (b) and (c), respectively;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76C9E0DBF0C5484785AADF0DBBC33362"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by repealing section 1602 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6572">20 U.S.C. 6572</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD99536E1081E4C529E5F776504934D06"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 8204(c)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7824">20 U.S.C. 7824(c)(1)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>using a negotiated rulemaking process to develop regulations for implementation no later than the 2017–2018 academic year, shall define</quote> and inserting <quote>shall, for implementation no later than the 2017–2018 academic year, define</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4574112EE7A40128F265042344479E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health insurance portability and accountability act of 1996</header><text>Section 216(b) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b note) is amended to read as follows: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD59E2C4997D9491F9FF6D1F1259E7C06" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H963D5B1685234A0689BB3EA84BEA7A63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking for risk-Sharing exception</header> <paragraph id="HA5963F5505714EAE8D1915860D6FF6BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish standards relating to the exception for risk-sharing arrangements to the anti-kickback penalties described in section 1128B(b)(3)(F) of the Social Security Act, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60E25BE6D54B4068B703D58CB4FAA828"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors to consider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing standards relating to the exception for risk-sharing arrangements to the anti-kickback penalties under paragraph (1), the Secretary—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B5B089A1C9F43649FCCC4D55D8EC231"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall consult with the Attorney General and representatives of the hospital, physician, other health practitioner, and health plan communities, and other interested parties; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7AF5A58170DD421991287576F5680C0A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall take into account—</text> <clause id="H4F79BA4AF73A46EEBDDB2077DFBE2B57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the level of risk appropriate to the size and type of arrangement;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H478F72CBFC4E473992F41F118DA376E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the frequency of assessment and distribution of incentives;</text></clause> <clause id="H63F2F27C85404BA7817B93A81BB3830A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the level of capital contribution; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5E9E44B714514DA79CF5DD501C7933D0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the extent to which the risk-sharing arrangement provides incentives to control the cost and quality of health care services. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF01634D1A574F51834581D1DAD8648A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Higher education act of 1965</header><text>The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H32CB696B1E1544B0BFCD6FC6EB0E05D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 207—</text> <clause id="H954A3EAE4B6E41E4973D32AB7FEFD195"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subsection (c); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7363432ED68C42E991CA29CDC25437FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (c);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0BABCACD59AE466BACB0C5A75B3C6A50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 422(g)(1)—</text> 
<clause id="H06B320F3A11C471193BA745C413F51AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause> <clause id="H6BE5A19E97C34A96A883FC3604234E44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H067DB04E379A49DF9A0475A4650EA641"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (D);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA28DC88AC6DC40E9AD8DDC42F4639314"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in section 487A(b)(3)(B), by striking <quote>as determined in the negotiated rulemaking process under section 492</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E5C75DD3CA0449F964B462E95E7947F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in section 491(l)(4)(A), by striking <quote>, not later than two years after the completion of the negotiated rulemaking process required under section 492 resulting from the amendments to this Act made by the Higher Education Opportunity Act,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2D227FA88C543FFBF836935AC1E46AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in section 492—</text> 
<clause id="H70630D1D01334118871D79FEBE24BA7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Negotiated</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC7F6F497B8D44AA2AD16DC7F5F4C43F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HE5F1CA82522045B6AA63EF39DC1101B7" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HFAA60B10CEF84CD4B86585979BC70D6F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issuance of regulations</header><text>After obtaining the advice and recommendations described in subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall issue final regulations within the 360-day period described in section 437(e) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1232">20 U.S.C. 1232(e)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87D2BBE4B7BE4BB4B7E28CDD1A3C40B9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Housing Act of 1949</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 515(r)(3) of the Housing Act of 1949 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1485">42 U.S.C. 1485(r)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>in accordance with</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>under the rulemaking authority contained in section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</quote>.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA736DBC534F044BC93AB6FFFDCFA3EF6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Magnuson-stevens fishery conservation and management act</header><text>Section 305(g) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1855">16 U.S.C. 1855(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HC210AD6625A645EF9E93B9E05E7C7E65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF754020D4E64111927150A4943A3AB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H06915503410343B4B1602F967558590D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(A)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H655A374E6DBF40CC9AC5743A1578E055"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as paragraph (2) and adjusting the margins accordingly; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A4A4E6E42014BA99A4889B68240598E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), as so redesignated, by striking the second sentence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34A9C3903FA742009CB10E0FF1CE4437"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Mandatory price reporting act of 2010</header><text>Section 2(b) of the Mandatory Price Reporting Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/239">Public Law 111–239</external-xref>; 124 Stat. 2501) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H6353E3B79B67453EA1A07130B963D040"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Wholesale pork cuts</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows through <quote>chapter 3</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Wholesale pork cuts</header-in-text>.—Chapter 3</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19880CE255F24305ADA53E1F3556EF9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2), (3), and (4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5ECEFE0D4935418185A99E43C5C4BE88"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Patient protection and affordable care act</header><text>Section 5602 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD41BD5FDB88848E8A1091E7D197BB42A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Negotiated</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA57B4F8833B46ABBCF473F5E2D97989"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsections (b) through (h);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H528B7BDF21264906AE87A35BBDA1FE07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="H545726AB4492418C9557A114CF4FD65D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as subsection (b) and adjusting the margins accordingly; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6DA200D413804ACC95E39AEB4EDEC72D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Establishment</header-in-text>.—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>The Secretary of Health and Human Services</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Establishment</header-in-text>.—The Secretary of Health and Human Services</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H7FC4644C41B74336865BD3020EA8D75A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>, through a negotiated rulemaking process under subchapter 3 of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H51F27F4C11EA4CF091ACDBE82CABC14C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9161A4285AD4D039C1C60A87FF6FB96"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subsection (b), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>paragraph (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98936F148A0E4FA4980AEBD3B5721C80"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Price-anderson amendments act of 1988</header><text>Section 19 of the Price-Anderson Amendments Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2210">42 U.S.C. 2210</external-xref> note) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H5328192C53784F95A975B6AF1579E709"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBC9690A34344463889FBD0FD471C3367"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause id="HC287F15805574D92B3FD371AA45D793A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Purpose</header-in-text>.—The Nuclear</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Rulemaking Proceeding.—</header-in-text>The Nuclear</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0B97D8FD42AA49E6881462F963E7F510"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as subsection (b) and adjusting the margins accordingly.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7A0BDD26DA849029E57A2703EE7A635"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Social security act</header><text>Title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE0F0A7923C6341159979433EE970E436"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 1834(l)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(l)(1)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>through a negotiated rulemaking process described in title 5, United States Code,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61726C34E56C462A89F2B0478BA6F259"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 1856(a) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-26">42 U.S.C. 1395w–26(a)</external-xref>);</text> 
<clause id="H5079B250D48B4CD68CAA75DE36529AB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) through (9);</text></clause> <clause id="H615F3EEF52C440F1AED04FAFDA167D11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> 
<subclause id="H2EBB8B3B5E4F420681E05A43F302CECA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Establishment.—</header-in-text></quote> and all that follows through <quote>The Secretary shall establish</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Establishment.—</header-in-text>The Secretary shall establish</quote>;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC2181519E8BA47B68CF4DB2BC62806C4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and using a negotiated rulemaking process under subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H31322C42FBF948B18E618AC6F4BADB99"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC480D3FDBE2E43C0BC76711908571684"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), as so redesignated—</text> 
<subclause id="H7962A400329D4EC39171985F8B5B4711"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3C5157865CE84987AB87D482CCB89DF4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating clauses (i), (ii), and (iii) as subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), respectively, and adjusting the margins accordingly.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E23B6467E1541889EF6BFD2CFE129F9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Title 5</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 564 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H6857DE4C57FF48D7B30B5A2B9AAD8DC1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">564. Publication of notice.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD560A2A786FA4EEEBF72031110DD60F3"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Title 49</header><text>Section 31136(g)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3F873F9D964C408A8FFFAC9DE76CA39F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>issue</quote> and inserting <quote>shall issue</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60F24741B9A24D4483F9EA8B2675B20D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6632AFA912FD4716AC925B944CA7DC75"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6CAA8A2E35C4D3388BF8D55B35E5909"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Toxic substances control act</header><text>Section 8(a) of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2607">15 U.S.C. 2607(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6435735B7F9F4DEDAB4F6082E1BD4895"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (6); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56B9D67083124C61B46132AD603DA2DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (6).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED9B5EDFFF114DC68BF37795C1C48C05"><enum>(13)</enum><header>United states housing act of 1937</header><text>Section 9 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437g">42 U.S.C. 1437g</external-xref>) is amended by repealing subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1259BF56B0144FF8A8861CE47B96F1C6" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Streamlining OIRA review</header> <subsection id="H9695BB0954274B9593A29138FE5BE0B7" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), if the Office commences a review of a significant regulatory action, the Office shall complete such review not more than 60 days after the date on which the Office receives the significant regulatory action.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5079955E678B4DF092B3F3B187E24C92" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Office may extend the 60-day period described in subsection (a) by a single 30-day period if the Office provides the agency with, and makes publicly available, a written justification for the extension.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5C54044662584DE59FC7DDFA61091518" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication of regulatory action</header><text>If the Office waives review of a significant regulatory action of an agency without a request for further consideration or does not notify the agency in writing of the results of the review within the time frame described in subsection (a) or (b), the agency may publish the significant regulatory action in the Federal Register.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7E32B001832D4B91AAE3573B4D79A7E3"><enum>10.</enum><header>Penalizing public companies that submit false information to agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, as amended by sections 4 and 5 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H271BE4B2C5614B0895C878EDC47410AC" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H660C5B838DC349A7A54FCC09ABB14BAF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(j)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD45363BEBF1D45F0A12599BDD043088E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity required to file an annual report under section 13 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</external-xref>) that makes a submission under subsection (c) knowing the same—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H53B75ED1ECA64CB38D71C3A943B05EC3" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to include any materially false, fictitious, or fraudulent statement or representation; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D1B3D8586F64B358B3B7B5C5B2CD2C8" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to omit any material fact resulting in any statement or representation being false or misleading,</text></subparagraph></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be subject a civil penalty of not less than $250,000 for a first violation.</continuation-text> 
<paragraph id="H5FED8AE7CBC440DFB53648421E686D11" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any entity that has a subsequent violation of paragraph (1) shall be subject to a civil penalty of not less than $1,000,000 for each subsequent violation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB630759EC56B48B6A01975A9EAB54121" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any submission in violation of this subsection may be excluded from the record and from consideration by the agency or otherwise disregarded, and such submission (or any amendment to such submission) may not be resubmitted thereafter. An exclusion or other disregard of a submission pursuant to this subsection shall not affect the level of deference (in accordance with applicable law) accorded to agency action by a court reviewing such action.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F848F2087F84EF28045F0CD0BE9C6A1"><enum>(k)</enum><text>Any entity required to file an annual report pursuant to section 13 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</external-xref>), shall include in a submission under subsection (c)(2) of this section the annual report filed in the year previous to such submission and the quarterly report filed most recently prior to such submission. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HBF2190A8EF784F88BB167EFBB9E93DC4"><enum>11.</enum><header>Establishment of the office of the public advocate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H104DC2D77EA24C4B8D795FB80D2AD4AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HF067968FB0A14F5780C9891A1977373E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H22BFD302874E4174B7C1A492430219B2"><enum>505.</enum><header>Office of the Public Advocate</header> <subsection id="HCC1407F9273F43698B9AAFF458BEC189"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Office of Management and Budget an office to be known as the <quote>Office of the Public Advocate</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17576DCCA3714F9695D1291726925C44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National Public Advocate</header><text>The Office of the Public Advocate shall be under the supervision of an official to be known as the <quote>National Public Advocate</quote>, who shall—</text> <paragraph id="H0BDD5A5629FD443EB1295AF9B444FE46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37B7FC937B8740A8977AD7365258EF0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report to the President;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D6B5C0F8F7F459EB972387BD5AF90E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be entitled to compensation at the same rate as the highest rate of basic pay established for the Senior Executive Service under section 5382;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78EF62E7CD0B4A9A846A3048BFF39735"><enum>(4)</enum><text>have a background in customer service, consumer protection, or administrative law; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE539B6FC8AA2464382B8001CE16E59D7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>have experience working with the public in cases involving rules (as defined in section 551).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H038B8467372345B9A88529B885AA892D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Office of the Public Advocate shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HB80D14B7DA074EE4B89C9B2D3F37F5F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assisting agencies in soliciting public participation in the rulemaking process;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6509E767F404048948E786EC23E8BBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assisting individuals in participating in the rulemaking process;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0D457EE037F449948684B29A4709190F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">working with agencies, Congress, and the public to identify problems and improve public participation in the rulemaking process;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE92476D566B44C3D8A9F79E7EA3883A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conducting and publishing research on social equity impacts of the rulemaking process;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A26B136F2724FBE94EC8ED231A55A41"><enum>(5)</enum><text>developing and coordinating social equity definitions across the executive branch;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H20E036D3158C4144A4C01FF0596DEDEB"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when requested by the agency or by the public through comments submitted through the process described in section 553 of title 5, United States Code, performing, not later than 30 days after the receipt of such a request, a social equity assessment (as such term is defined in the Stop Corporate Capture Act) for a proposed rule; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AD377BB0FD44BCDA9CC04BE58DF61E8"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitating means by which individuals and populations that have not historically participated in the rulemaking process may be better included in the rulemaking process, including by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H261930399DA44A4C94267493E11B1CDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommending and implementing new outreach plans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCECFCAD4ED2D44B08071E93AAC32E369"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">partnering with State, local, and Tribal governments, and with community-based organizations to propagate information about rules changes; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9F368405C1A64DFA83B29F2CD14B7701"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensuring information about agency rulemaking and changes to rules are written in clear, accessible language that is accessible in multiple languages.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF9EF87012A394C97A4D71A66A29D05AD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the National Public Advocate is appointed under this subsection or 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, whichever is later, the National Public Advocate shall make rules to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDD6412609E3E4A80A5F1F980534D75EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the table of sections for such chapter, by inserting after the item relating to section 504 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H8FA6BD2ACB19424E8DD5E19C909757A4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">505. Office of the Public Advocate.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HAE046F5DEA474369A144C2F5085BA322"><enum>12.</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 706 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEECB222A72E2434288733EBABC3C9353"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence of the matter preceding paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6D4DD2EABE2647D2957F288A297A043E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>agency action.</quote> and inserting <quote>agency action. If a statute that an agency administers is silent or ambiguous as to the proper construction of a particular term or provision or set of terms or provisions, and an agency has followed the applicable procedures in subchapter II of chapter 5, has otherwise lawfully adjudicated a matter, or has followed the corresponding procedural provisions of the relevant statute, as applicable, a reviewing court shall defer to the agency’s reasonable or permissible interpretation of that statute, regardless of the significance of the related agency action or a possible future agency action.</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H75C2BE3B0F884582A587005928283B8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>To the extent necessary</quote> and inserting:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4E2E93452B394084BA11F926F05ACB46" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H7D160D586D8344A5A231E2781C3A9384"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent necessary</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H186D19A37A554173B7816441EAC86EFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H431C7A0A5C764C3295A2077EC6249C1B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HE789E8A18A754EBEB76ED033ACDC0B80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Unreasonable delay</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(1), unreasonable delay shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB1941DFB195543E78840A0BDE816A0DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>when an agency has not issued a notice of proposed rulemaking before the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of the legislation mandating the rulemaking, where no deadline for the rulemaking was specified in the enacted law;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7818CD64B0B44F109926E4EACBAE4A37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when an agency has not issued a final version of a proposed rule before the date that is 1 year after the date on which the proposed rule was published in the Federal Register; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52AFC51257C34B4FA88B952FC60DA3D4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>when an agency has not implemented a final rule before the date that is 1 year after the implementation date published in the Federal Register or, if no implementation date was provided, before the date that is 1 year after the date on which the final rule was published in the Federal Register; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51A9A09269154F6FAF7F80C82F3511B2" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>when an agency has not issued or implemented a final rule, upon a showing of good cause therefor.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H0C6C9D7B9C904F7BA24EEEAD86286AE4"><enum>13.</enum><header>Right of review</header> 
<subsection id="HD747284EA25943548250C6D0568CDCEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HA6E616D13D824F149B68245DD4181855" style="USC"> <section id="H572378D3C3A54D49A1309D9953431227"><enum>707.</enum><header>Statute of limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided by law, an action under this chapter for review of an agency action shall be commenced not later than 6 years after the date of the final agency action.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF52E62B896454FF39238EFAB149A4031"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 2401(a) of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>or section 707 of title 5</quote> after <quote>title 41</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2D1C906ABB944E5EA8988F2B777E8D2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H8F1D4C485540482BA12F088494324A99" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">707. Statute of limitation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H64BCDA8545D846D19AA39FE454D29A0C"><enum>14.</enum><header>Expanding public awareness of rulemakings</header> 
<subsection id="HB4620838CB85413696BE122280ABAE86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 4, 5, and 10 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HD673895857E24F259BECD3A5B9450B96" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H717D5030E7684B1794F3FABD38F1B723"><enum>(l)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H09CC3C392DAA46B8B69523922F6D9E06"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The head of each agency shall take such actions as may be necessary to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9E92715F1775436BA38FCEE3B885705D" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expand public awareness of the initiation of each rulemaking proceeding;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1941AFF26FBB4EA0B6EE8166AD50BA52" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand public awareness of the publication of each proposed rule; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE759FB697FFF419F805AF51E440C5814" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>expand public awareness when a rule is published; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H864BD822C4C24F6589396A76A0287270" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>establish a participation log, including all rulemaking participants, with respect to each rulemaking. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H800EDCA5740644D3A8045877AE472B40" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two business days after the date on which an agency publishes a notice of proposed rulemaking or a final rule under this section, the agency shall notify interested persons of the publication, including by using contact information that interested persons have provided to the agency and by publishing such notice on the agency's website and any social media accounts.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H9FD807EE402049C2A53493660B1B6DEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall take effect beginning on the date that is 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H082E8F14391547BF8FAD690B8CFA1D7C"><enum>15.</enum><header>Public petitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 553(e) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB0CEEE997D53413682BE6C09A916380B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before <quote>Each agency</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B480B7854CF41B78337285A421E3652"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H864AF75A2F4C4CA4BE3C463166E56E48" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HB4B9806EB04341028A917D61FD64170D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which an agency receives more than 100,000 signatures on a single petition under paragraph (1), the agency shall provide a written response that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H061220D4D2E5410DA3B996C73BF74692"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explanation of whether the agency has engaged or is engaging in the requested issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7767E0CE8EDF4020B86036C97569D19E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the agency has not engaged in the requested issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule, a written explanation for not engaging in the requested issuance, amendment, or repeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD673C62D20D48288B18D79ECBC440CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this paragraph, the head of each agency shall establish and publish procedures for the processing of a petition under paragraph (1), including—</text> <subparagraph id="H68CBEE9EA2344210B7F126D38C4F9B48"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using the agency website, the Federal Register, and other Federal websites to educate the public about how to file a petition under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBF15AA9833F4497AB7ED8285E6BD0D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>creating an accessible docket on the internet website of the agency, or on any existing Government-wide internet website, of any petition filed under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB873CCF99B24707ACA3AAD12BC35734"><enum>(4)</enum><text>No agency action under paragraph (3) shall be subject to review under chapter 7.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H1B9943510CD44C00A1D8E4D4FF1BCC6A"><enum>16.</enum><header>Amendment to congressional review act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 801(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H63BDAB1FF15B487288BBB8B52803F46A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>(1)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74F90F4CFB284372A467269804AB24F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD4DA89A3684D47F38C3053FBC9778267"><enum>17.</enum><header>Reinstatement of disapproved rules</header> <subsection id="H4CF574B095384912B41361484F4DB9B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5ED8D7C99E534CC4BA75EBF4ECF6C86C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered rule</term> means a rule for which a joint resolution of disapproval was enacted under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, before the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3E8612D2C00410EBDD6341A12738FAF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Federal agency</term> has the meaning given the term <term>agency</term> in section 551(1) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCD6E1E7481D545978E66384E1073BD51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fast-Track reinstatement</header><text>A Federal agency may reinstate a covered rule by publishing the covered rule in the Federal Register during the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0DBA112BEE5144319F33CA924CAB3D67"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reinstatement after 1-Year period</header><text>After the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, a Federal agency may reinstate a covered rule using the rulemaking procedures described in section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCFE563290532488DACB1D5E5484FDC9A"><enum>18.</enum><header>Cost-benefit analysis</header> 
<subsection id="H2C75E82600FC4B4388367ADBE07D0A3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement of regulatory impact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an agency is performing a cost-benefit or regulatory impact analysis in the course of issuing a rule, the agency shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAB70782AC3374CEE90A38F292EBF404F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take into account the benefits of the rule to the public, including the nonquantifiable benefits of the rule; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6497611A5784963854D420532FAD1C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except for good cause shown, prioritize adoption of a rule that provides benefits to the public, including nonquantifiable benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0D3D23BCEB464FABB727C30BB3FAB669"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement of distributional effects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency shall agency shall take into account distributional effects and the social equity impact of a rule when issuing such rule.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44D9A05683CE4C198DDC041DDAE577C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Scope of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 706 of title 5, United States Code, as amended by section 12, is amended in subsection (a), as so designated, by inserting after <quote>prejudicial error.</quote> the following: <quote>When acting under paragraph (2)(A), the court shall not require an agency to demonstrate that the challenged action meets a cost-benefit analysis standard except where explicitly required by law.</quote>. </text></subsection></section> <section id="H0FC032C9842B46DF824C7C020815C5FE" commented="no"><enum>19.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6BDF6FF614C04BF0999DE0B0158ED403"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency; rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>agency</term> and <term>rule</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H162EF3E655FE4C2CA60B7011F8721B04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interested person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>interested person</term> includes individuals, partnerships, corporations, associations, or public or private organizations of any character other than an agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D92FB2D08DA401B99D8EA44DB4F8D73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB49ED365E242430F94EDFB02D13738D6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regulatory action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>regulatory action</term> means any substantive action by an agency that promulgates or is expected to lead to the promulgation of a final rule or regulation, including notices of inquiry, advance notices of proposed rulemaking, and notices of proposed rulemaking.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F0EC39F172D4CC596072F55B32DCC23" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Significant regulatory action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>significant regulatory action</term> means any regulatory action that is likely to result in a rule that may—</text> <subparagraph id="H29E57C0A96D945BD95CC1E517031B248" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have an annual effect on the economy of $100,000,000 or more or adversely affect in a material way the economy, a sector of the economy, productivity, competition, jobs, the environment, public health or safety, or State, local, or tribal governments or communities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A52E0A30B394A509C7EF675B7B5E7D7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>create a serious inconsistency or otherwise interfere with an action taken or planned by another agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84B0EB89DA104E1BA2E15072E07BA5E0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>materially alter the budgetary impact of entitlements, grants, user fees, or loan programs or the rights and obligations of recipients thereof; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B7BED54056249A1BF669C98DA0E5B80" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>raise novel legal or policy issues arising out of legal mandates, the President’s priorities, or the general principles of regulation customarily practiced by the executive branch.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA8E4FA4476C48BA8B02863881A78508" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Social equity impact</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social equity impact</term> means any impact of a proposed rule, whether intended or unintended, that might reasonably be expected to disproportionately affect a population of interested persons that is part of a protected class or set of protected classes, based on the rules’s plain language, stated intention, and based on credible statistical projections and data on the impacts of similar rules, laws, and policies. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H237587847B144439A571BB59AB064FEC" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Social equity assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social equity assessment</term> means a written and publicly available report that shall specifically consider any social equity impact, positive or negative, that the proposed policy might have on a population of interested persons who share a common characteristic that renders them part of a protected class, where that population was previously subjected to discriminatory or exclusionary practices by the agency promulgating the rule or where credible demographic evidence demonstrates significant disparities experienced by different populations within a protected class.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

