<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5A55857BB7C44A7280B7410D32402CCB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9131 IH: Protecting Kids from Creeps Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit surrogacy agencies from facilitating surrogacy contracts with sex offenders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD7CC966BC9E94E6AA3DFF9C714EEFA66" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE47B33083EF24A56AA0521B172321B39" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Kids from Creeps Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H743829F367054BA29D57B431DF91343B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/110">Chapter 110</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H48EA0E53D0ED4CED90C219F9E3E88658" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H53C4EB9DF5714A35825664AC4ABC7907"><enum>2260B.</enum><header>Prohibition on sex offenders obtaining a child through surrogacy</header> 
<subsection id="H30FB9F7551564079846D215B2CA63E98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Surrogacy agency</header><text>Whoever, being a surrogacy agency, knowingly or recklessly facilitates a surrogacy agreement in which a party to that agreement is a sex offender shall be—</text> <paragraph id="H9A5C14F392A24D2FB3A525D7E82C7C4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of an agency acting recklessly, fined under this title and imprisoned not less than 10 years; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H811DE65FDE0A4BD3A770E9E6A5C29D13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an agency acting knowingly, fined under this title and imprisoned not less than 20 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEAD9633EB92D4C5B87B3ADF95829DE89"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employees</header><text>Whoever, being an employee of a surrogacy agency, knowingly facilitates a surrogacy agreement in which a party to that agreement is a sex offender shall be fined under this title and imprisoned not less than 20 years.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C65B91531CD4DA29B676CFA8B44A49B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sex offender</header><text>Whoever, being a sex offender, knowingly enters into a surrogacy agreement shall be fined under this title and imprisoned not less than 20 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD14C1120CC1E4E66AF3815DAE99D3600"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Status as a 501(c)(3) organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A surrogacy agency that is convicted of an offense under this section shall be ineligible for status as an exempt organization under section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1984.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBB37ACF82DBB403F96F52BB0A18A949A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal funding prohibition</header><text>A surrogacy agency that is convicted of an offense under this section shall be ineligible to receive a Federal grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H84C19F161DA048ABB5264D45DBF92F5B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect of unlawful surrogacy agreement</header><text>A surrogacy agreement entered into in violation of this section shall be void and unenforceable.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14E40C4D42B84922BC1899CD109479D9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H9454CD36AC674155BFCD225C04EE994D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>employee of a surrogacy agency</quote> means any individual employed by a surrogacy agency who is not an officer of such agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCD479CEEBABC42A8A9D73DFC536A4CAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>sex offender</quote> means an individual who is, or at any time was, required to register under section 113 of the Adam Walsh Child Protection and Safety Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20913">34 U.S.C. 20913</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF18B50BC27D4AEF8608D07C2B40ADE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>surrogacy agency</quote>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5DB657C2062D4D2085B3AE0092CB7B0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any entity in the United States that facilitates, arranges, procures, or otherwise assists in the formation or execution of a surrogacy agreement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A91314E45FD4008B6162B3A826E0992"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any officer of such agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F15C77BF42B4231BD73994A00980AE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>surrogacy agreement</quote> means an agreement, contract, or arrangement, without regard to whether it is oral or written or is direct or brokered, between 1 or more prospective parents and a surrogate parent, under which the surrogate parent agrees to become pregnant and give birth to a child, and to relinquish all parental rights and responsibilities to the prospective parent or parents.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10E7A1C7A4FA4B53BD466AA9E878F14D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>surrogate parent</quote> means a person who agrees to become pregnant and give birth to a child, and to relinquish all parental rights and responsibilities to another person under the terms of a surrogacy agreement.</text></paragraph> </subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HEC9B0D7D85BF4688B7C8614E4EEF88B6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Civil enforcement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General may bring a civil action in the appropriate United States district court against any person who engages in conduct constituting an offense under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code, for a civil penalty that is equal to the amount of compensation which the person received or offered for the prohibited conduct, whichever amount is greater.</text></section> <section id="H2452DAA656B844B3A0F9AC4C02D98711"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effect of unlawful surrogacy agreement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Legal custody of a child born pursuant to a surrogacy agreement that is void and unenforceable under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code, shall be decided based on a determination of the best interests of the child under the law of the State where the surrogate parent resides, with no effect given to the surrogacy agreement or any other purported agreement, contract, or understanding concerning the custody of the child.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

