<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD8B76C12D1B247AFA0ECFCD7E1D8A91A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7870 IH: ICE Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7870</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260309">March 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require immigration enforcement reforms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F3E9A8AB6434F5BB853CB5D9B0ABD49" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF5AFC21A7E864EF2A8DC2DD3E2C8BE13" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ICE Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H12A1A5A611C84F009C07A2711A6A9274" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Immigration enforcement reforms</header> <subsection id="HA645B1AEF35043B6A6284101FECB604A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training standards</header> <paragraph id="HBEF153548D2F4C95BB09CFBBC958E571"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate describing the standards, policies, and practices governing the training of immigration officers (as such term is defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE8CD249BF8E40E68813D3AAB3FF4AB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require each immigration officer to complete training not less than once a year, including web based, classroom, and tactical instruction, on updated policies on use of force and applicable legal developments, and training designed to—</text> <subparagraph id="HD361D58339B546218163D00B63065F6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote sound judgment and responsible decision-making in the application of both nonlethal and lethal force; </text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC73BAC64F98148DAB88C934B53364768"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emphasize and practice de-escalation strategies to mitigate risk to officers and the public;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB66F9C556F074ADC909DE6F995AF5C57"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that the immigration officer is educated on rights protected under the First Amendment, including those of members of the press, demonstrators, and individuals engaged in lawful assembly, and performs duties in accordance with such protections; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB7B8329F55046DC8F6919B7D29FDE00"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure searches and seizures are conducted consistent with the Fourth Amendment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1054641FB33547BCB8ECBA9C04A5D75C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Body worn and dashboard cameras</header> <paragraph id="H8D413862438C45F8B1E23EBECCBE488E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Secretary shall require the use of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2A663EE2699943CABC0957065844940B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>body-worn cameras by all immigration officers; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC924CF2495E64BC29297E52D60311976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dashboard cameras for all vehicles being used in Federal immigration enforcement operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DB2E94111C3468493B2B80159046E71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Right to review footage</header><text>An immigration officer has the right to review footage captured by body-worn cameras and dashboard cameras.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1FE2161660D644198F6B68B6F1F0EEB5" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>ID for all officers unless undercover</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text> 
<paragraph id="HA34FF7E12B844FC2AADCBF66B5207FCA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require each immigration officer to wear a uniform or identification clearly displaying the immigration officer or the name of the agency in which the officer is employed, unless—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E8DC00286FB41A8989256D9FFFD278F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there is a public safety or national security threat;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3B47871FD3F43B69092D6C3F6C209EE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not wearing identification is necessary to carry out the operation safely; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E46F4D9559148A8A7E60673030F77F7" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the personnel receives prior written approval from a supervisory officer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F91B08EF1054ACFA79F9AF13FC4B1E4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An immigration officer may not wear a uniform that bears any identifier as <quote>police</quote>, unless the uniform clearly displays the name of the agency in which the officer is employed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB41E796D4CB4F2DAB73D30CCEB5DC53"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sensitive Locations</header><text>Section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3CA536A6C16745D798FCE9F35EB40F7B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H77B2B2CF44F04CA7A35950BDC0AB1E3A"><enum>(i)</enum> 
<paragraph id="HB173B10C8C3341788F58A8527423BCC5" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an officer or an agent of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or U.S. Customs and Border Protection may not perform an immigration enforcement action in a protected area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H778A781769604087BF40025E1C18D3F3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This subsection shall not apply—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC3F9060324834CD99C5847D34A6C8C85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under exigent circumstances, including an immigration enforcement action that involves a national security threat, the pursuit of an individual who poses an imminent public safety threat, or the pursuit of an individual entering or attempting to enter the United States in the presence of the officer or agent;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEBF5407D99D410182BCA99DD30C305C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under circumstances that involves the imminent risk of death, violence, or physical harm to a person or the imminent risk that evidence material to a criminal case will be destroyed; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC622C9B29FCA49348B7544D2D968C562"><enum>(C)</enum><text>where a safe alternative location does not exist outside of the protected area. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9866E5F15F754284B1E431872E7B6EB7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>protected area</quote> means any school, any hospital, medical facility, mental health facility, any place of worship or religious study (including permanent or temporary locations), and any polling place or voting site.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H828364F04CFA486084ABA94CDF286A85"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Minimize risk</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require each immigration officer to make all reasonable efforts to de-escalate tensions prior to using force.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HA263E9ED62AE4E618C591FA543F1053A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Impose strict prohibition on the arrest and deportation of American citizens</header> <paragraph id="HFE9ED20C9547431A861D2065581B949A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require each immigration officer to verify citizenship status of an individual prior to arrest.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAF949EFB73E4D05B893DAE6E01527BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on deportation</header><text>A national of the United States may not be deported from the United States. </text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HD7C0C737C2794BC5A2DDCFD7F4D9A4D1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Notification of local law enforcement</header> <paragraph id="HD034B7FFFDF74AB9A10D9CEF57A57B80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify local law enforcement agencies of impending Federal immigration enforcement operations in their jurisdiction at least one day before such operation occurs. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C07135F1A864FBB9BFB758D9FFC7BB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall make every effort to coordinate the operations Federal immigration officers with State and local law enforcement. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

