<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H039DC60E969A4C2D94306FFCF48DADB2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6196 IH: Locally Led Development and Humanitarian Response Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6196</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize and encourage the United States to pursue a model of locally led development and humanitarian response and expand engagement with local actors and increase its local partner base.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9207F3AD43DE47D2A3BEC119D5C2B5AB" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEC1B61D091624FBFB2C464053BDB995D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Locally Led Development and Humanitarian Response Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H213DA7D25D9848D59D89DA1A1E121BEB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to encourage the United States to pursue a model of locally led development and humanitarian response and expand engagement and partnership with local actors.</text></section><section id="HBDC57F330D7A492AA7EEF58040D5B2EE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HAAE98CFA179B41A880866EC9BEAD8E7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>locally led development and humanitarian response is linked to more efficient and sustainable development and humanitarian outcomes, and is vital to building long-term self-reliance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFB65DA8677E4BC3AD88D778886B8F39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>over multiple Administrations, the United States Government has sought to achieve greater development outcomes through stronger local partnerships, including through <quote>Country Ownership</quote>, <quote>The Journey to Self-Reliance</quote>, and <quote>Locally Led Development</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB860B1C63B4E4B0D9D7AC2BA963C8D65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the relevant foreign assistance agency should increase the proportion of direct funding to local entities, including by increasing the amount of development and humanitarian assistance to such entities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F294D26B2D4BF3AD771CE8337F4F0F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the relevant foreign assistance agency should ensure its programming enables local communities to exercise leadership over priorities, project design, implementation, and measuring and evaluating results of such programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF4481F39A294810B2B0585F049CD763"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the relevant foreign assistance agency should ensure most awards, requests for proposals, and requests for applications outline expectations for implementers to elevate local leadership and hold implementers to account for elevating local leadership;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13BCC5F6D8AA4DC6B3842D49D4FDC4A3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>working with local partners requires more time, staffing, and flexibility of resources than traditional partners, including extended availability of funds and additional staff resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5049AC8B889F4F15AA0ABE371915E306"><enum>(7)</enum><text>increased flexibility is critical to respond to local priorities and leverage local capacities, including with respect to staffing, availability of funds, program design, and acquisition and assistance processes, among other areas.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H81534441AF404CA896B19B124ADC8FDD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Working with local partners</header><subsection id="H420670EEF4884A7AB687D0A6A1967012"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent feasible and appropriate, the head of the relevant foreign assistance agency should localize the development and humanitarian assistance partner base by considering—</text><paragraph id="HE83B09A8EC774AC49923696B887E461E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting and funding existing effective local projects and initiatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC59AECD2CF3B4A078B369DD982F16177"><enum>(2)</enum><text>simplifying and increasing access to United States foreign assistance resources for local partners in humanitarian and development sectors, including local partners who have relations, agency, or power structures in place that have produced, or can produce, strong trust, accountability, and legitimacy in the communities or networks such partners work in;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF430998369CF463389A15C4E89F4135C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>setting realistic goals and timelines for sunsetting assistance and adhering to existing agreement totals and timelines to incentivize self-reliance and encourage exit plans with appropriate notice;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5FF8FDE2D53483CB3229E3683260494"><enum>(4)</enum><text>exploring offering matching grants and in-kind contributions to ensure that United States Government investments in local partners are helping generate new resources of their own from other donors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD36AABA6AAB9440B8438326C4A6C4E70"><enum>(5)</enum><text>exploring government-to-government partnerships with adequate guardrails and oversight, in consultation with local civil society, with select countries where feasible and practical to enhance foreign governments’ ability to deliver good governance, service delivery, and public goods that benefit local communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC82DAD0DC0641D0B7B6E447FF01A56C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>exploring other types of funding modalities and types of partnerships with local and national actors, including support for pooled funding mechanisms and unsolicited projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD6C7BAA13B14896BC1BB4F21FDD0FE9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>diversifying award types to streamline performance requirements and working with the Office of Management and Budget to address threshold constraints that pose a barrier to effectively supporting local partners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A81C72F533F46838FFDA7F2F40621B5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>ensuring staff of the relevant foreign assistance agency is able and encouraged to conduct regular consultation with local partners in local languages of the host countries relating to policies and programs, including making available solicitations for acquisitions and assistance and accepting submissions in local languages, video format, or verbal presentations, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H0AF55A2752F84671B889F328B170DEC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>investing in translation services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73C4EB9995C144B49F552D9023AC0465"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hosting workshop-based engagements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H630E461F82B249A6B3B5164C6AE3EBEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advertising solicitations in local trade publications, local media including newspapers and radio, local community centers, and local online forums;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD28E91B7289D47BB8493B06ED354211F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>allowing and promoting multi-year, flexible, tiered and milestone-based funding for new programs and to bring successful programs to scale;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82AF9E47A9C74B30B96450C14A164A7B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>utilizing <quote>other transaction authority</quote> through innovation incentive awards for local and national actors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5024F22FECAC474AA7046B0613C2354F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>supporting consistent and unimpeded access to full cost recovery for local partners implementing United States foreign assistance activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF95F849CDD954D93808A22378A34B75B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>undertaking outreach campaigns and engaging with local actors, formally and informally, to raise awareness about opportunities, as well as how to apply for and manage awards in compliance with applicable Federal regulations and the relevant foreign assistance agency policies, and ensuring such engagement is accessible to all entities, including unregistered and informal organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B5A03581BA14CEB83FAF8010755B780"><enum>(13)</enum><text>strengthening oversight of capacity strengthening components of awards to ensure United States and international awardees are making good-faith efforts to strengthen local organizations’ capacities, including independent and external evaluations to evaluate the mentorship process and regular feedback loops;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A816FB089B24669B7C62FE3C7FE72E6"><enum>(14)</enum><text>ensuring there are sufficient acquisition and assistance personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6E2B6BBFA29439DBB89008460B95740"><enum>(15)</enum><text>soliciting feedback on and updating, as necessary, performance evaluation criteria to create greater workforce incentives for the relevant foreign assistance agency personnel to champion locally led development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62DA953A885A46B4A2957573F4586F20"><enum>(16)</enum><text>addressing internal delays and recipient organization issues that result in the required extension of provisional Negotiated Indirect Cost Rates (NICRAs);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92598EA6E904FA6BFFD447BF52E64A8"><enum>(17)</enum><text>conducting seminars and providing documentation in local languages on NICRA, the de minimis indirect cost rate, and other options for indirect cost recovery relevant to the award type; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A2925D32B3A47608D90308368B7B780"><enum>(18)</enum><text>ensuring that acquisition and assistance personnel communicate to awardees who do not submit for a NICRA that they are eligible for the de minimis indirect cost rate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H526579F803CB4A11BB03A84F58E0A483"><enum>5.</enum><header>Institutionalization of actions described in section 4</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of the relevant foreign assistance agency shall initiate policy actions, including rulemaking if necessary, to institutionalize the actions described in section 4 to the extent appropriate and feasible within all relevant foreign assistance agency internal rules and regulations, including the Foreign Affairs Manual, the Foreign Affairs Handbook, and the Department of State Acquisition Regulation, as well as other relevant strategies and policies.</text></section><section id="H7B4AC3FF297443899FC8E261E84FE759"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to accept applications, proposals, and contracting agreements in local languages and local language support</header><subsection id="H25397FD73CFD41DB939E18F2708D28D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the relevant foreign assistance agency is authorized to accept applications or proposals in languages other than English if such acceptance eases the burden of a local actor working with such agency and such agency is able to effectively evaluate such applications or proposals.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAD0F93D883A5453880E92D600F48C09A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local language support</header><paragraph id="HA7EA458E59084133A0AAA5CC15DFE847"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of the relevant foreign assistance agency shall conduct an assessment of options to enable such agency to utilize local languages to support local partners with award solicitations, proposals and applications, evaluations, management, close out, and other types of partnerships, including advising local partners on applicable United States regulations and the relevant foreign assistance agency policies and local country rules and regulations common in such activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AECB8767FEF4EB9A69C8C79498A0BB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of the relevant foreign assistance agency shall submit to Congress a report on the assessment described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD79F8BACBBFE45339E3EF151069FC8A2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Modifications relating to the code of Federal regulations and other requirements</header><subsection id="HE8E18DAE570E4E4F94DC05D4CEBC3C0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increase in the de minimis indirect cost</header><text>The head of the relevant foreign assistance agency is authorized to—</text><paragraph id="H12E6CBF3D6D3445F99B21688F6057111"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase the de minimis indirect cost rate provided for in section 200.414 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulations, by 5 percentage points for local partners receiving assistance awards from the agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64A3B50CB76B4E8488A2628C675893C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a de minimis indirect cost rate at the same rate provided for in paragraph (1) for acquisitions awarded under title 48 of the Code of Federal Regulations to local partners, and to increase this threshold further should subsequent Office of Management and Budget regulations recommend doing so.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92ED6F8D61AE420AABC5257008FB24DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption for local entities</header><text>The head of the relevant foreign assistance agency is authorized to exempt local partners, as needed, from the reporting requirements of the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6106">31 U.S.C. 6106</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/282">Public Law 109–282</external-xref>) to allow for a 180-day delay in obtaining a unique entity identifier and registration in the System for Award Management. This delay shall be no later than 30 days prior to the end of the award’s period of performance.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD44341D49F2944999E76F14E3BF8EA49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local competition authority</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the head of the relevant foreign assistance agency (or their designees) may award contracts and other acquisition instruments in which competition is limited to local entities if doing so would result in cost savings, strengthen local capacity, or enable the agency to deliver programs or activities more sustainably or quickly than if competition were not so limited. Such authority may not be used to make acquisition awards in excess of $25,000,000 and shall not exceed more than 10 percent of the amounts appropriated to the relevant foreign assistance agency each fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4D6784B56F234302A6451285FCC4CBB0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of national or international generally accepted accounting principles</header><text>The head of the relevant foreign assistance agency, in consultation with the Administrator of the General Services Administration, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, is authorized to allow foreign entities to use national or international generally accepted accounting principles instead of United States Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP) for contracts or grants awarded under the <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/4/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations or chapter 7 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBECC6EF7909D4EBCBD4552A47E133F43"><enum>8.</enum><header>Review of locally-led development in public international organizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of the relevant foreign assistance agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a review of public international organizations’ support for locally-led development, to include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H2FE7BF763951476BA434F3C06D9F74E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of how such organizations’ approaches and financing structures support locally-led development and humanitarian response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2983C1A7F84045C7ABE77BAEB72DB3C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An action plan for how the United States will use its position in such organizations to encourage greater focus on locally-led approaches.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2B57DACE5DF046B6A8F45B4AB5FD92D3"><enum>9.</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the end of the first fiscal year following the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the head of the relevant foreign assistance agency shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and publish on the agency’s website a report on the agency’s progress to advance locally led development and humanitarian response, to include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="HB7D59169E34748F4A0DFB7949A70F527"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The amount of funding implemented directly and indirectly by local partners, including to local and national nonprofit organizations, local and national governments, and local and national private sector entities, in the previous fiscal year, including all development and humanitarian assistance programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77E267EE84674565BB3EFC0CD5A8B2A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of how the agency is enabling more local leadership of foreign assistance programs, including recipients of direct funding, subrecipients and subcontractors to an international implementing partner, participants in an agency program, or members of a community affected by such programming.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H013DBBB1ABD14015A03615D326CEAA78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of how the relevant foreign assistance agency is using new authorities granted in sections 6 and 7 and an assessment of the impact of these authorities on such agency’s ability to work with local partners and communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0993E8CD3B8C4BA4AC9D583A9AFC8AFE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of how many organizations with a Negotiated Indirect Cost Rate (NICRA) cognizant to the relevant foreign assistance agency are utilizing provisional NICRAs for over 48 months without a final NICRA and steps that such agency can take to reduce the extension of provisional NICRAs beyond 12 months.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H776189285CC74D6B9AF12F4407C55312"><enum>10.</enum><header>Report on contracting officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, the head of the relevant foreign assistance agency shall provide a report to the appropriate congressional committees on the recruitment and retention of contracting officers and grant officers at such agency and recommendations to improve contracting/agreement officer recruitment and retention.</text></section><section id="HB6C25EE058384343883B6710CAC8DF10"><enum>11.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE01D446DE6A342B6B7377E027403CEE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9AB2A189E1EE43D9BD8683EC33CAB861"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE64FDDAB127B428783ABAE77A63C66AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8206410A593048E9BDE239ACC3AC9486"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local partner</header><text>The term <term>local partner</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HFA342875E9A44C1B94202D65BABE8E30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is a citizen or lawfully admitted permanent resident of and have his or her principal place of business in the country or region receiving United States foreign assistance with which the individual is or may become involved;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92174717550F403C8FEAC0B9B7B62784"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a sole proprietorship that is owned by such an individual that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96F035091CF64D67903105A871C3728D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity that—</text><clause id="HF764BA6633F842B1A1CCC416360AA609"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is incorporated or legally organized under the laws of, and have its principal place of business in, the country served by the program with which the entity is involved or in a country within the same region as the program with which the entity is involved;</text></clause><clause id="HBC6026AD9355441FAED9CE0C888FAA54"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determines its own autonomous leadership and governance structures, sets its own strategic direction, priorities, and programmatic focus, and makes independent financial decisions separately from an international organization;</text></clause><clause id="HCE03289995D94568A8DA0E4663AE1EB3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if it has a Board of Directors, has 51 percent or more board directors who are citizens or lawfully permanent residents of such country or a country within the same region; and</text></clause><clause id="HE7797BA1EAF04B06A9E91851025A9677"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>if it is a corporation, is 75 percent beneficially owned at the time of application by individuals who are citizens or lawfully admitted permanent residents of that same country.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC590BCD068BD4114AA8AFF502A8602F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Relevant foreign assistance agency</header><text>The term <term>relevant foreign assistance agency</term> means the department or agency designated as primarily responsible for implementing the United States foreign assistance under part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

