<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B65F122F271469B85E9A08C4E3EFAC6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7317 IH: Golden Thirteen Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7317</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260202">February 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award posthumously a Congressional Gold Medal to the Golden Thirteen, in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H88BC8BD310654C3DADBB2ABEA53CA45F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD5E062A1B8AE4809AA0CD1C44229ADE6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Golden Thirteen Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEAECB6C50EE840B19245FFDB6C7345BF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H907DDDFD87EC4BC8B3A9229374495DCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In January 1944, there were no Black officers in the United States Navy. That month, 16 Black enlisted men were assembled at the Recruit Training Center in Great Lakes, Illinois, for officer training.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14104ECC7BA44772BF37E8A548119A15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These men were expected to complete officer training in 8 weeks, even though officer training was normally 16 weeks.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H448C84C1633A4542B1BB006AEE25A16C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These men supported each other, including by placing blankets over their windows and studying as a group by flashlight at night. Each man brought to the group his own expertise to help the others.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE3F7F2F159140B5A0AA0D26790B689B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>When their officer training was completed, all 16 men passed their exams, leading some to claim that they had cheated. The men were forced to retake certain exams, and the group scored even higher.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H118EFD3F6F1B4A7F99D78BB25C9134D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The average grade for these men on the exams was a 3.89 out of a 4.00, the highest average of any class in Navy history at that time.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71EC1A961B4C48F89861D74709B86A72"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Even though all 16 men passed their exams, on February 24, 1944, the Navy commissioned only 12 of them, and a 13th was made a chief warrant officer. Because the Navy had assumed a 25-percent attrition rate, only 12 officer commissions were anticipated. As the class had a 100-percent passage rate, the other three men were returned to the enlisted ranks, with no reason given.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9D5ABD22C7841A1A86F2C28597C37CC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>During their careers, these men oversaw all-Black units or the training of Black recruits. One would go on to make his career in the Navy after World War II, and the rest would return to civilian life.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H258C1DFE1F9341EDA4007D1F0EBD66C4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In the 1970s, Captain Edward Secrest, a former instructor, gave the group the name <quote>Golden Thirteen</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0557544CAF19406689E2C6BA562B438A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 1982, these men were formally recognized with a first-ever reunion at sea aboard the USS KIDD–993.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1A5DC46E1824F4B9ED94839A731D19D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The members of the Golden Thirteen were Jesse Walter Arbor; Phillip G. Barnes; Samuel Edward Barnes; Dalton Louis Baugh, Sr.; George Clinton Cooper; Reginald Ernest Goodwin; James Edward Hair; Charles Byrd Lear; Graham Edward Martin; Dennis Denmark Nelson; John Walter Reagan; Frank Ellis Sublett, Jr.; and William Sylvester White. The three men who passed their exams, but not made officers, were Augustus Alves; J.B. Pinkney; and Lewis <quote>Mummy</quote> Williams.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H94DF8AD75FBD41C998941C2FA1209DAB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header> 
<subsection id="H8207F489915F4CB19A500BF9B547DB7A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the posthumous presentation, on behalf of the Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design in commemoration to the Golden Thirteen, in recognition of their contributions to the Nation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB816AE4D27784986AE5445CC1E2B5ED5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC15E058170F54663B2DC05A0C2CD53AA" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Smithsonian institution</header> 
<paragraph id="HC344D963BCC347BCA5C1B2538F6F1EAF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Smithsonian Institution, where it shall be available for display as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5EC6A4A496147FD8F8F6FF18F898F98" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Smithsonian Institution should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with the Golden Thirteen. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H72D69AD0E1404076B2323910A2DCB045"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section> <section id="H5C0B6E6053934D4BAB06F826536F5B4F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header> <subsection id="H38EF0239FB4E43C2ABD05D87668DC553"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1E46EA89C41428FB5A78BE542A753DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD3E1C833DD4D42AE94DC31EBA0AFA690"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header> <subsection id="H673E8B7623CE47B5ACB219D41330AF75"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A99CAEA68C5423B87521C09F4788F9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>The amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

