<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HADA84DC731B241BE8318A794F6709AFA">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7112 IH: Veterans’ Bill of Rights Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7112</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out efforts to inform veterans of their rights with regards to the receipt of health care, benefits, and services furnished under provisions of law administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H8D76E5CA1F434BDAB1527BFB9CCDEAAF">
<section id="H5961488561184027AF9F77A71636D0C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans’ Bill of Rights Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAB7A89A9DD3B421E9BCDF44F08ECF51C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HC1B665AF0ADD4057A66C66C9F1943648"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States has a solemn obligation, articulated by President Abraham Lincoln in 1865, <quote>to care for him who shall have borne the battle, and for his widow, and his orphan</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93EDBD396115460D9F7B8B0B9765EB2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Veterans transitioning to civilian life from service in the Armed Forces deserve timely access to health care, benefits, and information, as well as respect, dignity, and transparency in all interactions with the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86E8F65EB539470E9DB6205112434E73"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>The responsibilities of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs require that veterans’ rights be clearly codified to ensure accountability and consistent nationwide administration of benefits and services.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="H88C2B396559948C9A12FB93B5C161DAB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Veterans’ Bill of Rights</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDE51F2EEA6E4920B387360CDB52E407"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall carry out efforts to inform veterans of their rights with regards to the receipt of health care, benefits, and services furnished under provisions of law administered by the Secretary.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97FE49F0B63D47578781EAB55AC35679"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall ensure that veterans are aware of their rights with respect to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H0AEC4EB83CF344518868BBEE77990414"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access to VA or VA-authorized providers</header><text>Veterans have the right to receive health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs or, when eligible under Federal law, from community providers authorized by the Department.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H756B8D7C33AB47D8AA2B9C0CF705FA08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Respect and dignity</header><text>The right to be treated with courtesy, respect, and dignity in all interactions with personnel of the Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7D3754C6E5447F5A3EED621696F7521"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Informed consent</header><text>The right to receive clear, complete information about treatment options and to provide informed consent for care furnished under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE64DC7380817478E9300FF3EECE267BA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Awareness of benefits</header><text>The right to receive comprehensive, understandable information about benefits, programs, and services for which the veteran may be eligible or entitled under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A0D1676AC91499A86AF327239F7C53F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Access to benefits</header><text>The right to apply for benefits furnished under provisions of law administered by the Secretary at any time and to receive clear explanations from the Department regarding eligibility determinations concerning such benefits.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF622454F279C43DC8B72018BB44B268B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Health care without retaliation</header><text>The right to seek care or raise concerns without fear of stigma, retaliation, or adverse action from the Department.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06448A1CA7F2431D8C59A4EFFC0AE295"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text>The right to the protection of personal information and medical records consistent with provisions of Federal law relating to privacy, protection of personal information, and medical records.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7651255642EC498A8C82DBE18D00730E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Right to grievance redress</header><text>The right to file complaints concerning services furnished by the Department and to receive timely, thorough investigation and resolution of those complaints.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H208C9997AE114799AB0A54D0F29299AD"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Transparent communication</header><text>The right to clear written notification from the Department regarding the status of claims, benefits, and appeals filed with the Department.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAE3CB6733AF94FCA8B161043038D388E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Appeal and fair hearing</header><text>The right to appeal adverse decisions of the Secretary and to receive fair hearings from the Department within a reasonable time.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6ECF58CA97F04368AF4855A45358560D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H11033AA0A4974553BBC880D9A2244677"><enum>(1)</enum><text>integrate the rights described in subsection (b) into all Department of Veterans Affairs policies, directives, patient-facing materials, and employee training programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H926268CB365F4E568EEC272B0345E011"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure every employee of the Department receives annual training on such rights;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDDD61FB1ED3D442CA91AE19D1DA636F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prominently display such rights at all Department facilities and the website of the Department;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8C522FEBF2945A59A70E84954C4B2DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Labor, include a dedicated instruction module on the rights described in subsection (b) as part of the curriculum for the Transition Assistance Program (TAP) under section 1144 of title 10, United States Code;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF3F4B09E66EA461C8AA4D24F5E662020"><enum>(5)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, ensure that the rights described in subsection (b) are accessible through a prominent, dedicated feature within the official mobile application of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the eBenefits portal (or any successor personal benefits portal);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8343C589A6642F8A1F7BABFEF709409"><enum>(6)</enum><text>require each Department medical facility to designate a patient advocate or ombudsman to conduct an annual internal audit to assess facility compliance with the rights described in subsection (b), including a review of veteran satisfaction surveys and the timeliness of grievance resolutions; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA59BF273E32540F6A37C710C49BF55A6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure that any written or electronic acknowledgment of a claim for benefits or an application for health care services includes a summary statement of the rights described in subsection (b), emphasizing the veteran’s right to transparent communication and grievance redress.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBF2B9EFFA36540AB8D543835EDBAE83A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of this section shall not be construed—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H648269A4C2D643EBA38AA4751AA43268"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to create a cause of action for damages or judicially enforceable rights beyond those already established under Federal law; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D120397E265464BBC806A70E5E4A287" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to alter statutory eligibility requirements for care or benefits furnished under laws administered by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

