<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H672367E5D7A142F4BF1A898FB8926EA0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8335 IH: Prioritizing Resources and Opportunities for Talent, Employment, Compliance, and Terms Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8335</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260416">April 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform the H–1B nonimmigrant visa program, with exceptions for certain vital professions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H497C81B78365466C8BB38287FA14A507" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H330666E7CF8A4B5484502D96BBD81CD0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prioritizing Resources and Opportunities for Talent, Employment, Compliance, and Terms Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROTECT Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H97237BEDA8DF495BA9AEA4FB63A07CDD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provisions relating to H–1B nonimmigrant petitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(n) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text> <paragraph id="H148002730D0946EB95A0F0B486439500"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Wage requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H031BCFD871D144D487E5BF22FA514068" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HE7FB3219383940DDA5B8AF025DE2A8A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The employer has offered, and will continue to offer for the duration of the authorized period of employment, an annual wage to the H–1B nonimmigrant that is not less than the greatest of the following:</text> <clause id="H30EA433BF3224CFC95E16FAACD79271C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The annual wage paid by the employer to a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident who performed the same or substantially similar duties during the 2-year period immediately preceding the filing of the application. </text></clause> 
<clause id="HE6F71CA149C7464591F483F2BC8244FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$100,000, as adjusted annually for inflation beginning on the first July 1 following the date of enactment of this Act, by increasing such amount by the cumulative percentage change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers (CPI–U) since the date of enactment.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31BE7F3C60EE42FE8CE90718A623A58B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Third-party worksite limitations; compensation-based prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">By adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFC5BE8F72CD646859AA6E99D6E7D4E16" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HC06F712325234152BD597B2A63DBFAD1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Limitation on visa validity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An H–1B visa issued pursuant to an application filed under paragraph (1) shall be valid for a period not to exceed 1 year if any portion of the work performed by the H–1B nonimmigrant will take place at a third-party worksite.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC0A21621907406A8CD18F17ACAF5602"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Conditions for third-party placement</header><text>No H–1B visa may be issued, and no H–1B status may be granted, if any portion of the work will be performed at a third-party worksite unless the work assignment—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H55D3C97260A749298C1DC0CE68B8D791"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is clearly defined and not speculative; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H037D60890A594DCFACA7AD4974DBAE3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is expected to continue for the full duration of employment requested in the petition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9EE4A5827764330A20B584FEE92D011"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Petition prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In adjudicating H–1B petitions during a fiscal year, the Secretary shall prioritize approval of petitions offering higher levels of compensation over petitions offering lower levels of compensation, without regard to the order in which such petitions were filed.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H6503569647F148ABBDD37CD244E512B2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Health care personnel exemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 286 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (w) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H427E1FFC1F5B4CB89E3E4488C0B28264" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H584F6CCA0FFF4BE09213813A887C778F"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Exemption for health care personnel</header> 
<paragraph id="HC3BDC17DB29D473DAE6BA7016A1905EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any fee or surcharge imposed on a petitioner or beneficiary in connection with the filing of a new H–1B visa petition (including any fee or surcharge established by presidential proclamation, regulation, or guidance on or after September 19, 2025) shall not apply to a petition filed on behalf of a health care worker described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8078AE2BC064931ACF7D0FFA4CCF751"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Eligibility</header> <text>To be eligible for an exception under paragraph (1), the petitioner shall submit, in such form and manner as the Secretary of Homeland Security may require, evidence that—</text>
                        <subparagraph id="HB47F38E6BA924D569FCBB43B78E79D3F">
                            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the petitioner has made a good faith effort to recruit and hire a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident for the position for which the H–1B worker is sought; and</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                        <subparagraph id="HE8C8D96EFA5F41DABB38C0C0EA013101">
                            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the petitioner was unable to fill such position with a qualified United States citizen or lawful permanent resident after such recruitment efforts.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
                    </paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA1AEB7378B004F56BED9E71151C74F47"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Standards and procedures for submission of documentation</header><text>The Secretary shall by rule establish standards and procedures for petitioners to submit documentation demonstrating compliance with the requirements set forth in paragraph (2), including evidence of job postings, outreach to domestic workers, and other recruitment activities as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAF9D3338CC14641A44F8CE8DED96AD2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>health care worker</quote> means an individual who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD431E371A6BA4DA2A34511239EF4383F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is seeking classification as a nonimmigrant H–1B worker; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81158DB4A9AC4CA9AE7139EDF3F7BAE4"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>is being petitioned for employment as a physician, registered nurse, licensed therapist, pharmacist, clinical laboratory professional, advanced practice provider, or other direct patient care professional in a health care facility or system, as defined under 42 U.S.C. section 300s–3 of the Public Health Service Act.</text>
                        </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2F8636CCC2B421EBA36496E468E05C4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish additional exemptions or to define categories through guidance consistent with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HD69DDC7D8E1E49F8B5D422B474B53A83"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date of enactment and shall apply to any H–1B visa petition filed on or after such date.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

