<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7238ADA6E7D4321B231EC27D50E9729" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9595 IH: Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto Medal of Honor Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9595</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260706">July 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the President to posthumously award the Medal of Honor to
                                    Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto for acts of valor as a
                                    member of the Army during the Vietnam War.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H732012795EA944EB94EAE61AA0388141" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCC9B3929AD2D48AFBC1462821DA31EF3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto Medal of Honor Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H05EA562C62134621BC329B2F9D9D1C8B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2408A0F7C3E345CAB86EAAB86803F35E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto of the United States Army, born in Vega Baja, Puerto Rico, served the United States with extraordinary distinction, unwavering courage, and unparalleled dedication throughout his military career from 1959 to 1970.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFDFD657471E44D8B935A5D29E390127"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto distinguished himself as the first Puerto Rican graduate of the Army Air Assault School and went on to serve five consecutive voluntary tours of duty in the Republic of Vietnam, reflecting exceptional courage, sacrifice, and devotion to the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BDAB41363A6453184F16B702CC55F3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Throughout his five combat tours, Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto participated in more than 200 combat and aerial missions, demonstrating extraordinary courage and resilience under fire while protecting his fellow soldiers and carrying out missions with distinction as a member of the 101st Airborne Division and the 82nd Airborne Division.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H074808E7256A42A4AAB6A426317D7F4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto earned 38 military decorations in recognition of his extraordinary valor, service, and sacrifice during the Vietnam War, including two Silver Stars, five Bronze Star Medals with <quote>V</quote> Device for valor, five Purple Hearts awarded for wounds sustained in combat, and seven Air Medals.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8532C6B7207340BC9ED2FA34483F2282"><enum>(5)</enum><text>On May 1, 1968, during Operation Carentan II near Huế, Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto’s platoon was subjected to a fierce, multi-wave assault by an overwhelming North Vietnamese Army force. Sergeant First Class Otero Barreto single-handedly neutralized a fortified enemy machine gun emplacement and its three-man crew, then led his squad in clearing three additional enemy bunkers, saving the lives of his fellow soldiers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3EA208D5BDAC49A3910535DECBA44F27"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto passed away on October 14, 2024, at the age of 87, leaving behind an enduring legacy of service that extended far beyond the battlefield, including decades of work as a veterans’ counselor helping fellow veterans overcome post-traumatic stress and substance abuse.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B4836B0E41145948F64E14D74A1169B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The extraordinary heroism, gallantry, and selflessness demonstrated by Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto merit the highest honor that the United States can bestow upon a member of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB0BA489E48FE49729A129B5B7355574E">
                                    <enum>3.</enum>
                                    <header>Authorization for posthumous award of Medal of Honor to
                                                Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto for acts of
                                                valor as a member of the Army during the Vietnam
                                                War</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding the time limitations specified in section 7274 of title 10, United States Code, or any other time limitation with respect to the awarding of certain medals to persons who served in the Armed Forces, the President is authorized to posthumously award the Medal of Honor, under section 7271 of such title, to Sergeant First Class Jorge Otero Barreto for acts of valor as a member of the Army during the Vietnam War.</text>
                        </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

