<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDEFC5446AE964C6BA2EF4DCD6216DFA9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6987 IH: Public Charge Clarification Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6987</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108">January 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001102">Mr. Harris of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000603">Mr. Gill of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to clarify the definition of <quote>public charge</quote> and <quote>likely at any time to become a public charge,</quote> to establish requirements for affidavits of support and public charge bonds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFD942F48955B468DB7C5DB4817949BB6" style="OLC"><section id="HCD348B41A4DC48C396DFACD66CA35FD6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Charge Clarification Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE58520788E34409F954E2C75552E7752"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H56F7BE508BE24D7DAB993D10360335E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 212(a)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(4)</external-xref>) establishes that an alien who, in the opinion of the consular officer or the Attorney General, is likely at any time to become a public charge is inadmissible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD342000816874239BFD1383A940B5356"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress has laid out specific factors to be considered in determining whether an alien is likely to become a public charge, including the alien’s age, health, family status, assets, resources, financial status, education, and skills, as well as any affidavit of support under section 213A.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CA71A8DFAFC4A2296A7EA701C8653D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These statutory factors have not been faithfully applied in the intended totality of the circumstances analysis by executive agencies, leading to inconsistent and overly permissive interpretations that undermine congressional intent to ensure self-sufficiency among immigrants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFDD364726F348458EFD18E42078C9F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The proposed rule entitled <quote>Inadmissibility on Public Charge Grounds,</quote> published by the Department of Homeland Security in the Federal Register on October 10, 2018 (83 FR 51114), provided a clear framework for identifying public benefits that render an alien a public charge, including both monetizable and non-monetizable benefits.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCCCDD767AC04CF896CE04E015EAC691"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To protect American taxpayers and promote immigrant self-sufficiency, it is necessary to codify and expand upon this framework, ensuring that all current and future government benefits are considered in public charge determinations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H53D9F24FDA2644EB9C203B8B3647AEFA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition of public charge</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(a)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H9E345F64C45B46FEBE26478D239152D6" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HD7C23FABE1744D90BE468A9E62F7A690"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public charge</header><subparagraph id="H1F0C6A41FE8740FF8C0A58EA82131F79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any alien who, in the opinion of the consular officer at the time of application for a visa, or in the opinion of the Attorney General at the time of application for admission or adjustment of status, is likely at any time to become a public charge is inadmissible.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB203421313CF43A2B0703D6EA7533CC9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text><clause id="H81BD9AC40B8B4765A348ADF8D9596A80"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <quote>public charge</quote> means an alien who receives one or more public benefits (as defined in subparagraph (C)) for more than 12 months in the aggregate within any 36-month period (such that, for instance, receipt of two benefits in one month counts as two months).</text></clause><clause id="H02BA509C6DD949F7A55B6D904FCDE208"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An alien is <quote>likely at any time to become a public charge</quote> if the alien is likely to receive one or more public benefits (as defined in subparagraph (C)) for more than 12 months in the aggregate within any 36-month period after the date of admission or adjustment of status.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29754A07A0E9420E888ED278E2F95562"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public benefits defined</header><text>The term <quote>public benefits</quote> means any Federal, State, local, or tribal cash assistance for income maintenance, supplemental nutrition assistance, housing assistance, non-emergency medical assistance, or other similar benefits, including all monetizable and non-monetizable benefits as defined in the proposed rule entitled <quote>Inadmissibility on Public Charge Grounds,</quote> published in the Federal Register on October 10, 2018 (83 FR 51114). This definition shall include—</text><clause id="HD7B1BF1E75A4469889B65CE691B99D9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Supplemental Security Income (SSI) under title XVI of the Social Security Act;</text></clause><clause id="H2E5B2D4CE9FD4012BE11E657682327F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act;</text></clause><clause id="HE0956B9A918B43B09ED132C47EF98485"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any Federal, State, local, or tribal cash benefit program for income maintenance;</text></clause><clause id="H62FE5EC306D34DE281633E7944B08339"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008;</text></clause><clause id="H81F58605DFCF4732921E96F4D0760D54"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Section 8 Housing Choice Voucher Program under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937;</text></clause><clause id="HEAC703FF220B4C9FABB7A691E1793824"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Section 8 Project-Based Rental Assistance (including Moderate Rehabilitation) under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937;</text></clause><clause id="H128D4D452F614C948C8D9FE2BB73C314"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Public housing under section 9 of the United States Housing Act of 1937;</text></clause><clause id="H7B22B9823E334D9BB60C4C2BC3AFD502"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Medicaid under title XIX of the Social Security Act (except for emergency medical assistance, benefits provided to individuals under 21 years of age, or benefits provided to pregnant women);</text></clause><clause id="HA94D6475390D4960A087CF2B406380B5"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Premium and cost-sharing subsidies under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to refundable credit for coverage under a qualified health plan) or section 1402 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (relating to reduced cost sharing); and</text></clause><clause id="H1147ED000C3F43C99352928036B66280"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Any other Federal, State, local, or tribal program providing monetizable or non-monetizable benefits, including programs created after the date of enactment of the Public Charge Clarification Act of 2025.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CE3DE783468407EB0B2D7CDC554AA3B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Publication of list of benefits</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the Public Charge Clarification Act of 2025, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, shall publish in the Federal Register a comprehensive list of all public benefits (as defined in subparagraph (C)) that may render an alien a public charge or likely to become a public charge. The Secretary shall update such list as necessary to include any new programs or benefits created after publication and shall publish notice of such updates in the Federal Register.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D77685ECA440D5BAE3594F8E1BF856"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Factors to be considered</header><text>In determining whether an alien is inadmissible under this paragraph, the consular officer or the Attorney General shall consider, in the totality of the circumstances, the alien’s—</text><clause id="H45F5D0C125E7404F83389CC781F7AF4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>age;</text></clause><clause id="H006188486B6341229309934F4187188F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>health;</text></clause><clause id="H4C057D2CDA994AC4B9A17FFC5727D060"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>family status;</text></clause><clause id="HAC63561AF65B46328F43035953C9B5BD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assets, resources, and financial status;</text></clause><clause id="HF236C0E7EF42434FBACBF33F5CB7445E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>education and skills;</text></clause><clause id="H5B4F205FC4BC48FD8D91FC70D1922D0E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>prospective immigration status and expected period of admission; and</text></clause><clause id="H1E11C81FA875488083049706DD05DD39"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any affidavit of support under section 213A.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">No single factor shall be dispositive, and the determination shall be based on a holistic assessment of the alien’s likelihood of becoming a public charge.</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H123157F2CBBD439F9D16F37A025218E6"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to—</text><clause id="H68B1972970124BCB8DB45E11529CCA6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>refugees admitted under section 207;</text></clause><clause id="H0CF494A9A3A04FBAA3EA0A0B57A9E06E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>asylees granted asylum under section 208; or</text></clause><clause id="H7FD9E42C79484196A678FF21D530CDEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>aliens serving in the Armed Forces of the United States or the dependents of such aliens.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B6BF58D7B440DF8681E098EF22226C"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text>No waiver of inadmissibility under this paragraph shall be granted to any alien not exempted under subparagraph (F), unless specifically authorized by an Act of Congress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39C41525A73B4275A8EB164716249FC8"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Affidavits of support</header><clause id="H5D00EDBCFA1A4D80A1CE12C97BF33B86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An affidavit of support under section 213A may be considered as one factor in the totality of the circumstances under subparagraph (E), but shall not be sufficient, standing alone, to overcome a finding that an alien is likely to become a public charge.</text></clause><clause id="HC7B3B5E94F854F51B8FEC4E4EDF331C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any affidavit of support submitted under section 213A shall be accompanied by documentary evidence demonstrating the sponsor’s ability to financially support the alien and all members of the sponsor’s household, including proof of income, assets, and resources sufficient to maintain the household at an annual income equal to at least 125 percent of the Federal poverty line.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDF1E685735C46A1BC7DB6D8FA16945B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Public charge bonds</header><clause id="HD075420FCB5B4295AB6B50FE0A74F543"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The consular officer or the Attorney General shall require the posting of a public charge bond as a condition of admission or adjustment of status if the alien is determined to be likely to become a public charge but other factors warrant conditional approval.</text></clause><clause id="H82DE90E708184DB88FF4D9B2BA949540"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Such bond shall be in an amount of not less than $10,000, payable to the United States, and shall be forfeited if the alien becomes a public charge within 10 years of admission or adjustment of status.</text></clause><clause id="H17EB695B68CD4957AE9D4D52F0B31C0B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish regulations for the administration, forfeiture, and cancellation of such bonds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H032FED964E6047078C5C04987F75137B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subsection id="H4908902293A946BD83E0A2D8F9100F1D"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Section 213A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1183a">8 U.S.C. 1183a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HAE7DCE8E4C6442DA90108DC3897E25F1" style="OLC"><subsection id="HBA3B678F8A16499D985AD7F33D85A250"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirements for public charge determinations</header><text>Affidavits of support under this section shall comply with the requirements of section 212(a)(4)(H).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF480F8063EF44A269E81ECB6ADD0DB07"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any reference in Federal law or regulation to <quote>public charge</quote> or <quote>likely to become a public charge</quote> shall be construed in accordance with the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5410D0568432469087AC7899FF1EE42C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply to all applications for visas, admission, or adjustment of status pending on or filed after such effective date.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

