<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H79E7B549FD8E4A0C8DE1B4E713F76862" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7489 IH: Georgetown VA Community-Based Outpatient Clinic Authorization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7489</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the construction of a community-based outpatient clinic in Georgetown, Texas, as a major medical facility project of the Department of Veterans Affairs for fiscal year 2027, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCC27E856F76F4BA79031256FF3E63D3B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H38A65A486F074F8597FE3758B2059265" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Georgetown VA Community-Based Outpatient Clinic Authorization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H2FA1E8A68C6C4AEEB52A586BC1A7C247"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of community-based outpatient clinic in Georgetown, Texas, as a major medical facility project of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> 
<subsection id="HC1022E6CC8A04508905A937EED91A235"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may carry out a major medical facility project in fiscal year 2027 in Georgetown, Texas, that consists of the construction of a new community-based outpatient clinic in an amount not to exceed $96,448,066.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F44EE5BF82040F3A7C04AD1E6F58ED0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for fiscal year 2027 or the year in which funds are appropriated for the Construction, Major Projects account, $96,448,066 for the project authorized in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

