<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM26007-VHJ-M4-NDG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3589 IS: Respond, Innovate, Succeed, and Empower Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3589</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide students with disabilities and their families with access to critical information needed to select the right college and succeed once enrolled.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Respond, Innovate, Succeed, and Empower Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RISE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idF11F21E1976444E6969D881BE1362031"><enum>2.</enum><header>Perfecting amendment to the definition of disability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103(6) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003(6)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 3(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3</quote>.</text></section><section id="id9E008E69E5294F8C8FA237FA074D493F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Supporting students with disabilities to succeed once enrolled in college</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54F7B33F1FBC4E43B5EC189D43B77F8C"><paragraph id="idC004B9DA795B4445ADE9C8918E634C62"><enum>(30)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idE7BFE7E6B6B1499B8A59AE79BC6AC800"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The institution will carry out the following:</text><clause indent="up1" id="id760D828368F14BD99791CB441FD97D29"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Adopt policies that make any of the following documentation submitted by an individual sufficient to establish that such individual is an individual with a disability:</text><subclause id="idDBC47CEF17D64CFC9ED1E3A007898BB0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Documentation that the individual has had an individualized education program (referred to in this paragraph as an <quote>IEP</quote>) in accordance with section 614(d) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, if the IEP for the student was utilized in high school.</text></subclause><subclause id="id75E64DA792C442B5942EBF9FE6F25DFB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Documentation describing services or accommodations provided to the individual pursuant to section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>) (referred to in this paragraph as a <quote>Section 504 plan</quote>), if the Section 504 plan for the student was utilized in high school.</text></subclause><subclause id="id847DF615A524470AAE219F357A60820C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A plan or record of service for the individual from a private high school, a local educational agency, a State educational agency, or an institution of higher education provided in accordance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="idEE6E06D19C0945B2AF85F5E2FDA5E1BA"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>A record or evaluation from a relevant licensed professional finding that the individual has a disability.</text></subclause><subclause id="idD4539C8F81B642B2AB3961B86D4B03FB"><enum>(V)</enum><text>A plan or record of disability from another institution of higher education.</text></subclause><subclause id="idDD46E6E55D2145299A0F86283730DA0C"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Documentation of a disability due to service in the uniformed services, as defined in section 484C(a).</text></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" id="id31C627A5666649C0AEE9AE7CE0E7D9B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Adopt policies that are transparent and explicit regarding information about the process by which the institution determines eligibility for accommodations.</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="id614E2DD457364C8A98AACC04C485974A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Disseminate such information to students, parents, and faculty in an accessible format, including during any student orientation and making such information readily available on a public website of the institution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="id66034964110E423B9DC1C5A9301D8849"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to preclude an institution from establishing less burdensome criteria than that described in subparagraph (A) to establish an individual as an individual with a disability and therefore eligible for accommodations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="idA0C599C69AD14EC99707A9F03A35A80E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of funds for the national center for information and technical support for postsecondary students with disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 777(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140q">20 U.S.C. 1140q(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="id56574949641E4BA3B3ABB42ED6F050A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>From amounts appropriated under section 778,</quote> and inserting <quote>From amounts appropriated under paragraph (5),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE9148CD55AF54D8CA0B34C2F85977A5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6F55E972DD6846318E7DA27D959332A2"><paragraph id="id9FA037063BF548CCACE329C3249F6E29"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection a total of $10,000,000 for fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="id72510D62FFEA4C7784A7E8ED9956D89E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Inclusion of information on students with disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7EBEF8B39D6E4714BD20CF42741E660F"><paragraph id="idB2EC12F4FB3541A28380CE0791DF6FBB"><enum>(31)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idd33ec31eb38d4679841d90c530818a1d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The institution will submit, for inclusion in the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System (IPEDS) or any other Federal postsecondary institution data collection effort, key data related to undergraduate students enrolled in the institution who are formally registered as students with disabilities with the institution’s office of disability services (which, for purposes of this paragraph, includes an equivalent office), including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8261cf4982d44e4481b2d110e5920f6a" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of students registered with the institution's office of disability services;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="ida99aa0d159bc458d81884b77cebafdb8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of students accessing or receiving accommodations, as voluntarily reported to the institution’s office of disability services;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id9796b0b6d9c94cba8dffbf51291c28e1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of undergraduate students enrolled in the institution who are registered with the institution's office of disability services; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id75af23f18899486fb530c725e66f8bfa"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of undergraduate certificates or degrees awarded to students registered with the institution's office of disability services.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id62e97d8d32034d028f09a5890e39ecf6" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), an institution shall not be required to submit information under this paragraph if the number of such students would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id76B283FD92B74F30B09A591CE0470461"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to affect the meaning of the terms <term>reasonable accommodation</term> or <term>record of impairment</term> under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) or the rights or remedies provided under such Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

