<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26507-VGY-H4-H11"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>109 S4206 IS: Know Your American Customer Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4206</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 31, United States Code, to require certain financial institutions to verify the citizenship and legal status of individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Know Your American Customer Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id8c6f2ef2e86f48bca74a678bd69624ba"><enum>2.</enum><header>Verification of citizenship and legal status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5318 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf092104559524508b964f3f31a6b6967"><subsection id="id37d8b173d4214a338db794d1540297f2"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Verification of citizenship and legal status</header><paragraph id="id555bb32a8037475fbcda3eb624e4fbda"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="idbd2c293a951d4ca4a2cb70e0a5f7fd71"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means any natural person who—</text><clause id="idb7ea2e7bffcd4be28013c568e31b624b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>seeks to open an account at a covered institution;</text></clause><clause id="id416fef33a78a4dca98461bacfc7832da"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idafc051020f2741338598bf77d17a9657"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who holds an account at a covered institution that was opened on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this subsection; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0aebe095a32a4c3aae7daf48dbd1bd09" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose eligibility for such account was established through documentation of authorization to temporarily reside in the United States in compliance with paragraph (2)(C); or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="iddca26e325eff4a81808a1ea0c901b3a1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is identified as the individual exercising substantial control over a legal entity, as described in section 5336, that seeks to open an account at a covered institution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id410f511769ae4feea25f3d108e011267"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered institution</header><text>The term <term>covered institution</term> means—</text><clause id="id17b163f7a30e4103a402f493bd9cbb02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an insured depository institution; and</text></clause><clause id="id16ad2a2ed06c42969b41d35882c904b4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an insured credit union.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2de61fc9adf9420d80536297abcb64ef"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Distributions or transfers</header><text>The term <term>distributions or transfers</term> means any payment, refund, deposit, or other funds that would otherwise be directed to an account that has been frozen or closed under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54cc7d0026ac4fefb5029c0fe0b41c9d"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Insured credit union</header><text>The term <term>insured credit union</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0be83bf8a08b475a8479e9af7a9f4a13"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Insured depository institution</header><text>The term <term>insured depository institution</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8407a735c7b247549b60dbf36f95faa3"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Lawful presence; lawfully present in the united states</header><text>The terms <term>lawful presence</term> and <term>lawfully present in the United States</term>, with respect to an individual, mean that the individual is—</text><clause id="idae6625266ea14a779ee0549ce4eaa7f8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a citizen or national of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="ida7a868002f97492dab21380a007ec185"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an alien—</text><subclause id="id3e105b931df94f109026aea9c33ae7a1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who has been inspected and admitted or paroled into the United States under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide811ce7863724449a535480cdf70d790"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whose period of authorized stay has not expired.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b89001ef9484b008b6b21fa12221bb1"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Period of authorized stay</header><text>The term <term>period of authorized stay</term> means the period during which an alien is authorized by the Secretary of Homeland Security to be present in the United States, as evidenced by a document issued by the Department of Homeland Security, including an Arrival/Departure Record (Form I–94) (or an equivalent document).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id145ca3e9ea594742a8cf14d26bc81f8c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility to open and maintain an account</header><subparagraph id="id38432431512247509241b44836c3db91"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), a covered institution may not open or maintain an account for any covered individual who is not lawfully present in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf2fd3696b3284edd8e56573108869d2f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Verification requirement</header><clause id="id90761db197874dac8ab1ea488b0052a9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>New accounts</header><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5288caa01039444fa1fa88f1ab955093"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), beginning on and after the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this subjection, a covered individual shall present 1 of the following, which may be an original or certified copy, to open an account at a covered institution:</text><item id="idf356851b286748a1ba439d6b5e6ec762"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>A driver’s license or identification card issued by a State that is compliant with section 202 of the REAL ID Act of 2005 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/13">Public Law 109–13</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30301">49 U.S.C. 30301</external-xref> note).</text></item><item id="idf14a048dca8d4c0a937c296fe3e9031c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>A United States passport or passport card.</text></item><item id="id6547d85ed0424b329fd32810dd47d0b1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>A birth certificate issued by the vital records office of a State, territory, or the District of Columbia.</text></item><item id="idb448ec41ebbe4eeb8b33115b1c0cf986"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>A Certificate of Naturalization (Form N–550, Form N–570, or Form N–578).</text></item><item id="id659b11ae579d41e694e4a844ac3fb3b4"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>A Certificate of Citizenship (Form N–560 or Form N–561).</text></item><item id="idce8d4c81641340b68ae34209f06ac0ac"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>A Consular Report of Birth Abroad (Form FS–240) or Certification of Report of Birth (Form DS–1350).</text></item><item id="id7e9e29edff5b4be38f6b0b8ca8a5cca4"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>A Permanent Resident Card (Form I–551).</text></item><item id="id53a59eeb0d9f43e68d8977f8fca341a0"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>A valid, unexpired foreign passport with a valid Arrival/Departure Record (Form I–94) or nonimmigrant visa demonstrating lawful admission and lawful presence.</text></item><item id="idc858d813e62b4f7594b5fadb8ef8f443"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A Social Security Administration proof-of-earnings card or statement, presented with a valid driver’s license or identification card issued by a State regardless of whether such license or card was issued in accordance with section 202 of the REAL ID Act of 2005 (division B of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/13">Public Law 109–13</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30301">49 U.S.C. 30301</external-xref> note).</text></item><item id="id2614c1b94e3e44b9997f6b22ae1db774"><enum>(jj)</enum><text>A valid identification card issued by the Department of Defense to a member of the uniformed services or to a dependent of such a member.</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74b0aec3f1294641baa703733a214905"><enum>(kk)</enum><text>Any other document determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security, by regulation, to be sufficient evidence of United States citizenship or lawful presence.</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f35abf358884797b801a671abe10f50"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authorized users</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who does not maintain an account at the covered institution and who is added as a joint holder or authorized signer on an account at such institution after the date described in subclause (I) shall be subject to the verification requirements of that subclause.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3337e79c364a48a29d9158a198b30be9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to an individual who maintains an account, before the date described in that clause, at the same covered institution the individual seeks to open an account.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idac26ed3b4dc944abbe24ce6e8c964b07"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Individuals with limited period of authorized stay</header><clause id="id7706f717927740d5a29d79976cf35c63"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Documentation of authorized stay</header><text>Any covered individual whose period of authorized stay in the United States is temporary, as of the date on which the individual opens an account at a covered institution, shall provide the covered institution with a certification, on a form prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury, that—</text><subclause id="ide6af58de788b4a25917ed2d4db9ccbe1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identifies the expiration date of such authorized stay;</text></subclause><subclause id="id97be8eeaeb634cb5ba45cfb5a2cbecdf"><enum>(II)</enum><text>describes the basis for such stay; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ida016613b3aed42fa883fb515ab9c1047"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is modeled after the certification requirements applicable to nonresident aliens under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/3">chapter 3</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id859f852cf86a4d0caf4d07329f0d3e26"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Grace period and account closure</header><subclause id="id920f95af2de34b9ebd54860bfef2f527"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (III), beginning on the last day of the period of authorized stay of a covered individual described in clause (i)(I), the covered individual shall retain full access to the account for a period of 30 days, after which, if the covered individual has not provided updated documentation of lawful presence, the covered institution shall restrict transactions involving the account of the covered individual for a period of 60 days in accordance with subclause (II).</text></subclause><subclause id="id232f1c47a3a540ad86a6929897e55551"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Transaction limitations</header><text>During the 60-day period described in subclause (I), the covered institution shall—</text><item id="id255184dd6a2346da810278b835cc5fc0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>permit incoming deposits, direct deposits, and other credits to the account; and</text></item><item id="id26193f5944b944cfa285235fd7ab5425"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>prohibit all withdrawals, outgoing transfers, debit or credit card transactions, and wire transfers.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="idec1abe46f3aa414ab678fe2bbcdc8fc1"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Full access</header><text>If the covered individual provides updated documentation of lawful presence during the 30-day or 60-day period described in subclause (I) in accordance with clause (i), the covered institution shall restore full access to the account of the covered individual.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id655642176da740fab61e2ab2d5bd06e7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Account closure</header><text>If the covered individual does not provide updated documentation of lawful presence before the end of the 60-day restricted period described in clause (ii)(I), the covered institution shall close the account in accordance with regulations promulgated under paragraph (4).</text></clause><clause id="idea02dcab24ef47eb84284604de4be91b"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Accounts opened by legal entities</header><text>The requirements of this paragraph shall not apply to accounts opened by legal entities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd1501212ad8547ca915ff4af1b293074"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Frozen or closed account procedures</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6925560d3bda401bb7c5ca9519b9c53a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2)(C), a covered institution shall freeze or close the account of any covered individual who is not lawfully present in the United States or who is otherwise determined to be ineligible under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7467409179964ed7bebbd2e8ce36e1d8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any applicable provision of law (including regulations) regarding the closure of an account shall apply to an account frozen under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id979b6acee48a4f8c8c009a3d5ba39c01"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalty</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6a3cb7e780a466ea2e3dca2c17a0c56"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), any covered institution that violates this subsection shall be subject to a civil penalty.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id66fa3d9a48ea40c09fb0147c7f9df199"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Safe harbors</header><text>No covered institution may be subject a civil penalty for a violation of this subsection if the covered institution—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a8d76a955cd400d840db5b59cc5690e"><enum>(i)</enum><text>makes a good-faith effort to comply with this subsection, and the regulations promulgated under this subsection;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80fd8dacfb3f41c6939565fd8ae50527"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accepts any document listed in subparagraph (B)(i)(I) and relies on such document, including in any good-faith closure or freezing of an account under paragraph (3); or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39c4eca9ffff41c38180e445a9a544d3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>accepts a driver’s license or identification card issued by a State that requires proof of lawful presence or United States citizenship as a condition for issuance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf255a0d16554eae8dc1379e0483ed35"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ead4be28fed46f199d1b122fce5adc8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, shall enforce the provisions of this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac24e88eea874847b239aaa510b1e7d7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Insured credit unions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to insured credit unions, the Secretary of the Treasury shall coordinate enforcement with the National Credit Union Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida961ca8e565043b5aaf5fa65f5693d00"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9bdeee8afbe4877a57311c5ebc4cfd3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interim guidance</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb5688c21303f474a8303e9855f3fb3da"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue interim guidance carrying out this subsection.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idae7cb1ac13cf4bcdbde814c37b0d6d22"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Force and effect</header><text>The interim guidance issued under this subparagraph shall have the force and effect of a rule promulgated under section 553 of title 5 until superseded by final regulations under subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id71cf664c850b4dd191723667891d33c6"><enum>(iii)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Inapplicability</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44 shall not apply to any collection of information required under the interim guidance issued under this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7890125df10740be8012dfe857892efd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of the Treasury shall promulgate final regulations carrying out this subsection, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idacb07a9b394c4bdc9ec29ca6114d94a9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the procedures and timing for freezing and closing accounts;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfdf663f13f854a09b30b1da0e4fcf565"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the notice requirements applicable to account holders;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idce821b26524046698c898dcf17e50e02"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the handling of distributions or transfers directed to frozen or closed accounts, including procedures for redirecting incoming payments; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id40c12e250e494f81a88fe804bcee8cbb"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the disbursement or transfer of remaining balances to another financial institution or foreign financial institution designated by the individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida9728aa26aab4826938ab164d792d886"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall apply to, restrict, or impose any additional verification requirements on—</text><subparagraph id="id2de51e66e5064551ab9c2b81bc894672"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accounts held by nonresident aliens (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">section 7701(b)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) who are not physically present in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5962bd0198d4c27a20c91332abb3894"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accounts maintained by foreign persons, foreign corporations, foreign governments, or other foreign entities not resident or physically present in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbcdbf1a61377453e994154518fb0385a"><enum>(C)</enum><text>deposits or accounts at branches or agencies of foreign banks in the United States, to the extent attributable to non-resident or foreign sources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb3f8f904f7264c2da131dd9cf16fc02b"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other foreign capital inflows, correspondent accounts, or international banking liabilities to foreign residents, as reported under the Treasury International Capital system or similar frameworks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida66b3cfc9e144366b9a121311701c258"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Effect on State law</header><text>The provisions of this section shall supersede any provisions of the law of any State relating to the verification of the lawful residency of covered individuals by financial institutions chartered, licensed, or operating in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id9e4f9e4fae9f419a822a5492e333cdba"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on criminal penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5322 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8989687fed1c498886b2bf959f0426a6"><subsection id="id0c19a0bc899b415489e1272fbfba259e"><enum>(f)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idc7179a5c56274388ac4ea4d771be2d24"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6552f3934f54979935381da7784239e" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>active account</term>—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e71ae53b4144391bc00f2fa979fcd50"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an account with which an individual may conduct transactions; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55dd1336c7284b4085bb3cd8fec81097"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include an account that has been restricted or frozen under section 5318(r); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idda9a39c3916c4854b783524893d9f212"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>covered institution</term>, <term>lawfully present</term>, and <term>period of authorized stay</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 5318(r).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id634582e4f0dc4b3fa20065b4a504521c" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idb75e0c12ed6648e0a5b9625ff7e510b5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), Any individual who is not lawfully present in the United States, or whose removal has been ordered under chapter 4 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1221">8 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>), and who opens or maintains an active account at a covered institution, shall be fined not more than $1,000,000, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both. This paragraph does not apply to any individual whose period of authorized stay expired within the preceding 90 days, or who has filed an application for asylum under section 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>) that has not been finally adjudicated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id105d71adc6404d0c959ffb0314e9ff64"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any individual—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4c7c7bcdc17a4a019de3ca7bd25e0a6b"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose period of authorized stay expired within the preceding 90 days; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3ad3de6ba2964a71a129f53f125987df"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has filed an application for asylum under section 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>) that has not been finally adjudicated.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e9b9b447830470181a69d164b085285" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any individual who is not lawfully present in the United States, or whose removal has been ordered under chapter 4 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1221">8 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>), and who opens or maintains an account at a covered institution through a legal entity, or who directs another person to do so on the behalf of the individual, shall be fined not more than $1,000,000, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb128311504d84c359743ddbf16fa381a" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), no person shall be subject to criminal penalties under this section solely for a violation of section 5318(r).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idb53625e8e6744c6abea080c271024287"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit criminal liability for any criminal violation of Federal law arising independently of a violation of section 5318(r).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

