<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GAI25A12-FN0-SP-FFS"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3531 IS: To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a tax credit for qualified combined heat and power system property, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3531</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a tax credit for qualified combined heat and power system property, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H788B339842074FF4B76CB490FD89FC2F"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6EAE437EE02B4CF98B5889E7E723222E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Tax credit for qualified combined heat and power system property</header><subsection id="HCEB54F67EDD1473196DA41730E4E454C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of credit</header><paragraph id="H86D181C313EF423792FA7FE5FBC66C5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 48E the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4ECD94659579400B847CF6A94A73C3BB"><section id="H703038694E9B43A8BAD0C61ED3AE94BE"><enum>48F.</enum><header>Credit for qualified combined heat and power system property</header><subsection id="H91DAD2FABE3C4AD3AAC9BDAC74CB1CCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Credit for qualified combined heat and power system property</header><paragraph id="HF7414CDD0AF143F897BB14F97748D5C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 46, except as provided in subsection (c)(1)(B), the credit for qualified combined heat and power system property for any taxable year is an amount equal to 10 percent of the basis of each qualified combined heat and power system property placed in service during such taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA07FBE72BB7E4E12B7FC3ECF7CDB6017"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with rehabilitation credit</header><text>The percentage specified in paragraph (1) shall not apply to that portion of the basis of any property which is attributable to qualified rehabilitation expenditures (as defined in section 47(c)(2)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE246F7A6F65642E7864027CA6319ED22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified combined heat and power system property</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified combined heat and power system property</term> means any property—</text><subparagraph id="HCD83890C63EF48968E514EB2635BDAC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which is combined heat and power system property,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA175644185A4FA58BA87D4970CCBDF8"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB6FF0D1BE9884D52959F2316288E8744"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the construction, reconstruction, or erection of which is completed by the taxpayer, or</text></clause><clause id="H632A7D41C9E94D4BB742BEA76D445D92" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is acquired by the taxpayer if the original use of such property commences with the taxpayer,</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA319DEA25C284C5A95DB2F06BE4B2DD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to which depreciation (or amortization in lieu of depreciation) is allowable, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ED346FB0DAB4A67A69049DB76C1A795"><enum>(D)</enum><text>which meets the performance and quality standards (if any) which—</text><clause id="H2F91C9FEB69B4FB0A956EAC4F3A4C836"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have been prescribed by the Secretary by regulations (after consultation with the Secretary of Energy), and</text></clause><clause id="H841D7C701632489AAB3C3E26FBC17B9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are in effect at the time of the acquisition of the property.</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Such term shall not include any property which is part of a facility the production from which is allowed as a credit under section 45 for the taxable year or any prior taxable year.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H786B7521561242AC959EAEAE1D54DC83"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule for property financed by tax-exempt bonds</header><text>Rules similar to the rule under section 45(b)(3) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6BC10462F87E4768AFD20DCE947AF49F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Domestic content bonus credit amount</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1C135217AE324B9AA33E8A5DF3FC8D8F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any energy project which satisfies the requirement under subparagraph (B), for purposes of applying paragraph (1) with respect to qualified combined heat and power system property that is part of such project, the percentage specified in paragraph (1) shall be increased by 10 percentage points.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H988389C990D84C3C894D6D03CCD1DFCA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of section 45(b)(9)(B) shall apply.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F33A329931743E7A31ADACE6FC5D0EF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Increase in credit rate for energy communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any energy project that is placed in service within an energy community (as defined in section 45(b)(11)(B), as applied by substituting <quote>energy project</quote> for <quote>qualified facility</quote> each place it appears), for purposes of applying paragraph (1) with respect to qualified combined heat and power system property which is part of such project, the percentage specified in paragraph (1) shall be increased by 10 percentage points.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17B64DA73BBF40CB9C163E030E82FB79"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection, including regulations or other guidance which provides for requirements for recordkeeping or information reporting for purposes of administering the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B87EE7854084011967EEE5E31F8071C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain progress expenditure rules made applicable</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rules similar to the rules of subsections (c)(4) and (d) of section 46 (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) shall apply for purposes of subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9A31F410B6FC4BB99DC6C9F9F5CC566F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HAD7D98E9A3B040CDBDE43454E4D354C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Combined heat and power system property</header><subparagraph id="HA245EF5F794249DCBDA2CF1B1E008127"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Combined heat and power system property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>combined heat and power system property</term> means property comprising a system—</text><clause id="HC9C30F79B2E74756A595A173AFD58159"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which uses the same energy source for the simultaneous or sequential generation of electrical power, mechanical shaft power, or both, in combination with the generation of steam or other forms of useful thermal energy (including heating and cooling applications),</text></clause><clause id="H2DCAB0680B2A48ACA75D8364E4AB8F06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which produces—</text><subclause id="HEFDACFE3E73C4DDF8F3AB7D01AB284E1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 20 percent of its total useful energy in the form of thermal energy which is not used to produce electrical or mechanical power (or combination thereof), and</text></subclause><subclause id="H22A7BB6B92A749209EFF94955200261B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 20 percent of its total useful energy in the form of electrical or mechanical power (or combination thereof),</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7FE8C20083204BAEAEFB804EA1EBE7A3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the energy efficiency percentage of which exceeds 60 percent, and</text></clause><clause id="H86FC8A45233A4C1EAE454FB12DD269E3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the construction of which begins on or after January 1, 2025.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H552F52BF21CB478080CB1291D868509F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><clause commented="no" id="H0B436875496442C493C0F0077E0B5DED"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of combined heat and power system property with an electrical capacity in excess of the applicable capacity placed in service during the taxable year, the credit under subsection (a)(1) (determined without regard to this paragraph) for such year shall be equal to the amount which bears the same ratio to such credit as the applicable capacity bears to the capacity of such property.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H966C3F23337E486E8481B70F0C2811C8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable capacity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>applicable capacity</term> means 25 megawatts or a mechanical energy capacity of more than 33,500 horsepower, or an equivalent combination of electrical and mechanical energy capacities.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD29B03767690421CB0D150E7310BE5A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Maximum capacity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>combined heat and power system property</term> shall not include any property comprising a system if such system has a capacity in excess of 50 megawatts or a mechanical energy capacity in excess of 67,000 horsepower, or an equivalent combination of electrical and mechanical energy capacities.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H97A81F2C00D8496BB829EDF6F102261C"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Clarification regarding capacity determinations</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, the determination of the electrical or mechanical energy capacity of any system shall be based on the normal operating rates of such system.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBBEFE6970D5499D9A73F1420822D94F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special rules</header><clause id="HEC54F19E1FBD42D58B7D7AC666645932"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Energy efficiency percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the energy efficiency percentage of a system is the fraction—</text><subclause id="H3E1C86274B7F4798B2842B581E1AFBAC"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the numerator of which is the total useful electrical, thermal, and mechanical power produced by the system at normal operating rates, and expected to be consumed in its normal application, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC6E9CF8E851C4E1DA41E5C1DD63B2AB8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the denominator of which is the lower heating value of the fuel sources for the system.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3BFC33A4F752487DBC8B4DFF8E22497F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determinations made on Btu basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The energy efficiency percentage and the percentages under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be determined on a Btu basis.</text></clause><clause id="H8A2DBC1BA66A404DB2F2B552BA3AC14B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Input and output property not included</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>combined heat and power system property</term> does not include property used to transport the energy source to the facility or to distribute energy produced by the facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF4942A441644CB8AAF23B7C5F6B25AB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Systems using biomass</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a system is designed to use biomass (within the meaning of paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 45(c) without regard to the last sentence of paragraph (3)(A)) for at least 90 percent of the energy source—</text><clause id="H0FF0ABC321974BAA9040447E5240BBAD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (A)(iii) shall not apply, but</text></clause><clause id="H7756962447CB40A4B442327BEDA82BC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of credit determined under subsection (a) with respect to such system shall not exceed the amount which bears the same ratio to such amount of credit (determined without regard to this subparagraph) as the energy efficiency percentage of such system bears to 60 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H794D8AAAC3294D0D889DCCCFAE4D75AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>energy project</term> means a project consisting of one or more qualified combined heat and power system properties that are part of a single project.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD96FBAFABFEF4B478367E0FBEA182D7F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart E of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 48E the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC481B6876AC04C6DB5B32A0B4DD553CE"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">48F. Credit for qualified combined heat and power system property.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3EDEA6946FF6432CA6AF7006C53B1049"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with energy credit</header><text>Section 48(c)(3)(B) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H591497C89B0447C5875E6B7003C67A50"><clause commented="no" id="H6FEEB6E82F944D738623537FBB5E4C88"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Clarification regarding capacity determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, the determination of the electrical or mechanical energy capacity of any system shall be based on the normal operating rates of such system.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3D002B42767A49C2B9F404CF643FA107"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H98028EC2939E4F57A4DE7A5E1ECDC00A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 38(c)(4)(B)(x) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or the credit for qualified combined heat and power system property determined under section 48F</quote> after <quote>section 48</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB3C327F81D14659BE8F122B652F6F8B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 45L(f) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>47 or 48(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>47, 48(a), or 48F(a)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H849536C68E3C4C30B4BABC8AB3DCCE0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 46 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (7) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E72E47DA6CC4228B1DB592BBB967899"><paragraph id="H3942D968170A4C17A346068B8406B1C4"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the credit for qualified combined heat and power system property.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE09735671B240B6BF29D52BEA7C055E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Section 48C(f) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>48F,</quote> after <quote>48E,</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H151992458D7C4A129378026BFB7108D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 50(a)(2)(E) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>or 48E(e)</quote> and inserting <quote>48E(e), or 48F(b)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C3E71DE90754156B4D6A32AC9203000"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 59A(b)(3)(C) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or the credit for qualified combined heat and power system property determined under section 48F</quote> after <quote>section 48</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD0BA3A5248534BB183E3133499B9DEBA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H89EE4A23444445F298B3AAF1D3DB2B68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the amendments made by this section shall apply to property the construction of which begins after December 31, 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE445A755096C4FBC9489395BD36700E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with energy credit</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C7F6E2491574A7F91BB4A07554BCDB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (b) shall apply to property—</text><clause commented="no" id="H430EF17E1D7042F6BBF1B67DFEEBC0DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the construction of which begins before January 1, 2025, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H06122AA73506474280102B2F363D59B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which is placed in service during taxable years beginning after December 31, 2024.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H177C010B7A314F1B8113B9481AFE5F1B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No inference</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (b) shall not be construed to create any inference with respect to the proper application of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/48">section 48(c)(3)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to taxable years beginning before January 1, 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

