<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9A9804DFB3F945BF9C04A28EA0A8C34C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7941 IH: Pay TSA Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7941</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure the passenger security fee paid by airline passengers is used exclusively for aviation security, establish a Transportation Security Trust Fund to support the operations and personnel of the Transportation Security Administration, and ensure continuity of aviation security operations during a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5E5A76322D844DFFA24F3590D0889051" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H51DF46A7A00C42B495D925A6850828FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pay TSA Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H02D7A39B8C664FF8A8AE8BC42F4BF2D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transportation security funding</header> 
<subsection id="HCD2E1A3E704C478888156CBCA27D5943"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of diversion of passenger security fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44940 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H32B32E24B3F74F9E95BD2DC24A54C420" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (f); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9174AF5A03464E7385F355E38B2B2924"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (i).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF7D8329A20BF45AA9B708C7345E37E31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transportation Security Trust Fund</header> <paragraph id="H4687EE42FD964554A5C9A5747221A441" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department of Homeland Security a fund to be known as the <quote>Transportation Security Trust Fund</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4C331227B4F4967927EAE357FB5E6FA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts collected from fees imposed under section 44940 of title 49, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>9/11 Security Fee</quote>), shall be deposited into the Fund and available without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F6086F431C24BD5A1B6CC98928E6F07" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts in the Fund shall be available to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration for activities to strengthen aviation security, including relating to the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5303645512594DAE8D96DADFD496DE9C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Salaries, benefits, training, and workforce support for Administration personnel.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1A564EC06D942B0BB8A40D9DC4453A7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Passenger and baggage screening operations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37D1A9BD0FF04605AC5CFED8582E778A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Aviation security checkpoint and screening technology.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09F6C6F22AF74D9EB70B2A4D17759E47" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Airport security infrastructure and equipment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEED683074C934938805CF3DEA97F4B13" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Research, development, and deployment of advanced aviation security systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6C9659BEAA14B31884D19A43F813748" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restriction on diversion of funds</header><text>Amounts deposited in the Fund—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H123E27520DBF46F4AE2469A3484307F3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be used only for the aviation security purposes specified in paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D02852AB8184922BCFBA264A89E2D34" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not be transferred to the general fund of the Treasury or used for deficit reduction or other non-aviation security purposes.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H22DDF500C77844B298044501026311CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of funds during a lapse in appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="H8CEB6360E7124CF08CB59D55BA136A2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8433A14D78E64F8BA4E7A84CF1B448C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If during any period during any fiscal year the discretionary appropriations Act providing funding for the Transportation Security Administration, or continuing appropriations for the Transportation Security Administration, are not enacted into law, amounts in the Fund shall be available without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration for the continuation of programs, projects, and activities necessary to maintain aviation security operations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H122B0FDD9A11443F89E18885313D8DC5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aviation Security Capital Fund</header><text>Notwithstanding section 44923(h) of title 49, United States Code, during any period described in subparagraph (A), amounts available in the Aviation Security Capital Fund established under such section 44923(h) shall be available to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration to carry out the activities described in such subparagraph, subject to the priorities described in this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6D9A2D53510F469F92A44CC01CB8D141"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority for TSA personnel</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE26C10E0A76D4959A36E201418714224"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall prioritize the use of funds made available pursuant to paragraph (1) for the following:</text> <clause id="HD1D136F159214571B95DBE9505D5676E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Salaries, benefits, and overtime compensation of Transportation Security Officers and other personnel necessary to conduct passenger and baggage screening and aviation security operations.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H63B8D25E2BE84874B2C954B427B30100"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Staffing levels required to maintain the safe and efficient operation of aviation security screening checkpoints and related security functions.</text></clause> <clause id="H72D6F94C45D4412991D7736585469381"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Other operational expenses directly supporting frontline aviation security personnel.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H43126340428F446F92C47D8261ECA0EB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Amounts made available under this paragraph shall first be applied to carry out subparagraph (A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0A3F815AA234E908D84658F666C317A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secondary uses for security infrastructure and technology</header><text>After the funding requirements described in paragraph (2) have been satisfied, remaining amounts made available pursuant to paragraph (1) may be used for the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD6DA3728702F436385621A7AAA7216F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The procurement, deployment, and sustainment of aviation security checkpoint technology.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9D8C866F08545ECBEAA679C685CB6F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Baggage screening equipment and related aviation security infrastructure.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89666E26949B40D692328406A35AB8D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Maintenance and modernization of airport security systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64B53D85FE9143808F2EBCD237174F84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Grants to airports for aviation security technology improvements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6504A8C3DBCC4C15990A5A50AD0C929D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rate for operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available under this subsection shall be provided at a rate for operations not greater than the rate for operations provided for the Transportation Security Administration programs, projects, and activities described in this subsection during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C5633ED00F341AA9C5AAB64E0E781B3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Duration of authority</header><text>The authority provided under this subsection shall remain in effect for the period beginning on the first day of a lapse in appropriations and ending on the date on which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H58B4761398F54BC59CD22D643909E6FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable regular appropriation Act providing funding for the Transportation Security Administration is enacted into law; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0209FF2E3894795B33F69200514D4A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continuing appropriations for the Transportation Security Administration are enacted into law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B1D75950C59470FA515B5A6480E0EE9" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>Funds made available under this subsection shall be subject to the terms, conditions, and limitations applicable to the Transportation Security Administration programs, projects, and activities on the date immediately preceding the date on which the applicable lapse of appropriations occurs for the immediately preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H96F09B3289F34926A67BDF76C677485B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Aviation security technology and infrastructure account</header> <paragraph id="HFD39CE974D974D9DAC754D68B522A6A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Fund an account to be known as the <quote>Aviation Security Technology and Infrastructure Account</quote> (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Account</quote>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA54366978364DFDBF68588A8C70352C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Account is to support the modernization, procurement, deployment, and sustainment of aviation security technology and infrastructure necessary to enhance the safety and efficiency of passenger and baggage screening operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB10A1197B32B4EC39CBD43C3AC8F4242" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts in the Account shall be available until expended to the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration for aviation security technology and infrastructure investments only after the funding requirements necessary to support Transportation Security Administration personnel and operational aviation security activities have been satisfied, including the compensation and staffing requirements described in subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8F621C005D34B2180BF1F6DC9A7FEC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header><text>Amounts made available under this subsection may be used for the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H4956DD063980469E86F72DD8D53A44A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Procurement, deployment, and sustainment of aviation security checkpoint technology.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00621436400949BDB1EA7AAB20C12FD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Computed tomography screening systems and related screening equipment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CAAE991748B4AE7A5C37504321B2B5F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Credential authentication technology and related passenger screening systems.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H16CA4D0569034B7CBFCEC3817161628D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Airport security screening infrastructure and associated equipment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71A56D0D396745DFBB92509974102726"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Exit lane and perimeter security technology.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDDFA635BBFB344479FF45664E7C9E23C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Grants to airports for aviation security technology deployment and modernization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

