<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD16E305B5A547AC9A92170FC073568A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8561 IH: Commission on Americans Living Abroad Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8561</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a commission to study how Federal laws and policies affect United States citizens living in foreign countries.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H191B2B1F4D684B2A873B543BA8AEA2A7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5C48F01EC3BE4C7793E4709021CF4529" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commission on Americans Living Abroad Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC15BD195972C493CA3FF9DCFD7878B95"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is established in the executive branch a commission to be known as the <quote>Commission on Americans Living Abroad</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></section> 
<section id="H6911776B363B45448ABCBD63374A88F5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Membership</header> 
<subsection id="HE73821A616A649659EC7CEC91A474095"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Number and appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall be composed of 10 members appointed by the President, of whom—</text> <paragraph id="HF5BB841D1F814EAA9D722593B930F10E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>two members shall be appointed from among individuals recommended by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56790240AC904E40A7673D3A1DD7892A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">two members shall be appointed from among individuals recommended by the minority leader of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H70B5C3A1ABE74A0CB9F050FCB7DC0836"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">two members shall be appointed from among individuals recommended by the majority leader of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD502F12F90344F88D7EBF78F1ED0C34"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">two members shall be appointed from among individuals recommended by the minority leader of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE4980F43D9C44126BCAA00AB99C09EDA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header> <paragraph id="HE67A9E9485374AE3BD4D62CD638C731A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limit on officers or employees of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 6 members of the Commission may be officers or employees of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07F6C16978CB4ACD97293274D5BFEBFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Political party affiliation</header><text>Not more than 6 members of the Commission may be of the same political party or appointed by recommendation of individuals belonging to the same party.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H202E72496DD14FFC9C7AC8330E557A6F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expertise</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H4C2EE43165E84A8EA4A2ACAC09842BB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Officers or employees of the United States</header><text>Members of the Commission who are officers or employees of the United States shall be appointed from among individuals whose employment is directly related to the matters to be studied by the Commission under section 4(a)(2).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H688467DEAE274C4E81BE581425EEC39D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other members</header><text>Members of the Commission who are not officers or employees of the United States shall be appointed from among individuals who—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H42387B87392E42B790D671D198199E1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have lived in a foreign country for not fewer than 5 years;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H30FD7708A8D949DC8524538D1D931140"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are members of organizations that represent United States citizens living in foreign countries; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HAEC2A16C3A7147AFAB9D1927CB755A8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>have other experience that is relevant to the matters to be studied by the Commission under section 4(a)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H02FA8659882943EDBB66FE2F5368F0AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period of appointment; vacancies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members shall be appointed for the life of the Commission. Any vacancy in the Commission shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made. Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8C354798EE1544D493E0A02DA5BD63CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The President shall select a Chairperson for the Commission from among its members.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H34E4A713C2C84F3DAB1771A10C9C6AFF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date on which all members of the Commission have been appointed, the Commission shall hold its first meeting. The Commission shall subsequently meet at the call of the Chairperson.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC4CBE065DD964865910F2B3F1151FF59"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H39647A6D91CB437A843CA2ACB22D89F3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties</header> 
<subsection id="H66D7B69C5EEB4488A24E77C031044246"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall conduct a study on the following matters:</text> <paragraph id="H5BB9F491F6CB485AB45FCF2FDFEA4C35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The manner and extent to which Federal laws and policies affect United States citizens living in foreign countries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2542F02E289C4E30A82244465669006A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The costs and burdens of such Federal laws and policies on such overseas citizens.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H197BA2BE57554CA48469FD04D618E3F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The lack of access to Federal benefits and health care through the Department of Veterans Affairs for veterans living abroad compared to those veterans residing on United States soil.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6430248197834E4DBE4FC00A42435575"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal financial reporting requirements for a United States citizen living in a foreign country, including the requirements under section 5314 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6715375100D433CB6EA914AECB842DF" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal policies and requirements that affect the ability of a United States citizen living in a foreign country to access foreign and domestic financial institutions, including requirements under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/4">chapter 4</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (commonly known as the <quote>Foreign Account Tax Compliance Act</quote>) and requirements affecting financial institutions imposed by the Uniting and Strengthening America by Providing Appropriate Tools Required to Intercept and Obstruct Terrorism Act of 2001 (USA Patriot Act) (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/56">Public Law 107–56</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC694A0C0DE9E45DB891240CA51EE057B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Federal requirements for a spouse, child, or another family member of a United States citizen living in a foreign country who is not a United States citizen to become a United States citizen.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE66B355815EA46ACA7842E61EFA7122D"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The ability of a United States citizen living in a foreign country to vote in Federal, State, and local elections in the United States, and the process for such a citizen to vote in such elections.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41C9D2A797CF47FEB69AAE2662818C13"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The processes by which a United States citizen living in a foreign country interacts with Federal programs such as Social Security and Medicare.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA26C989EA1C54D75B5746B84660C30BA"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Which Federal departments or agencies have jurisdiction over each Federal program that serves United States citizens who live in foreign countries and possible methods to improve the collaboration of and coordination between such Federal agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB375313DDFFE41C792B9A9F2C2F50F74" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The impact of tax filing and information reporting requirements on the ability of a United States citizen living in a foreign country to save for retirement and use financial products available in their country of residence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D7946A217BA4E02886752E0991EDD9A" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The impact of taxation and other Federal policies on the ability of a United States citizen living in a foreign country to send and receive remittances.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A36D82993EC46BCBF233DB55831B1BE"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The impact of Federal policy on the ability of United States citizens living abroad to establish and conduct a small to medium size business and own it outright for the benefit of themselves, their family and their future.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6E0CB29958074AEE8F719A7DFB1D1971"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation with outside organizations</header><text>In conducting the study under subsection (a), the Commission shall consult with organizations that represent United States citizens living in foreign countries.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H97687CB27056410C887D813593C3D9F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H38E26556078E48708DE9526A1EEB542A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to the President and the Congress, and transmit to the head of any Federal department or agency identified in subsection (a)(9), a report that contains a detailed statement of the findings and conclusions of the Commission, together with any recommendations for—</text> <subparagraph id="H23A3425546404EE6ABBAA8D32C8E5EEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing tax and compliance costs and burdens for United States citizens who live overseas;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H076A22E36A0E460FAA521BBCEBD52E9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing access to Federal services by such citizens; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB40D936F0E3D4F53B77A7549B80DA07B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any appropriate legislative and administrative actions to achieve the goals described under subparagraph (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EAB21CAA3AA4599B4FE7D62EE192EA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date on which the Commission submits the report under paragraph (1), the Commission shall submit to the President and the Congress, and transmit to the head of any Federal department or agency identified in subsection (a)(9), an update that describes any administrative actions taken by the head of any Federal department or agency pursuant to the recommendations in such report.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="HF6914D23B5E041C89978B2797DA52EC6"><enum>5.</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header> <subsection commented="no" id="HC6F873AC895B43DCACC8A39B745C0A76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings and sessions</header><text>The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out this Act, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, and receive evidence as the Commission considers appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H7C454E07B7204D608BB6A7D9B9D451B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Powers of Members and Agents</header><text>Any member or agent of the Commission may, if authorized by the Commission, take any action which the Commission is authorized to take by this section.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H249B6D4662484F90BBA46C980D438545"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Obtaining official data</header><text>Subject to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">section 6103</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out this Act. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H16E02E0D11744A8B9B704E00EA6E1E6B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mails</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the United States.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H799E521336E8495D9A7901C603304856"><enum>6.</enum><header>Commission personnel matters</header> <subsection id="H71E07813440442ECB29101CA09F73969"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text>Each member of the Commission who is not an officer or employee of the United States shall be compensated at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which such member is engaged in the performance of the duties of the Commission. All members of the Commission who are officers or employees of the United States shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for their services as officers or employees of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB435F7671D2D4FF59C1B9B8E9BCB7FFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8810A234991A41C2924255C9115136F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Staff</header> <paragraph id="H2E6B20F640044693BAE52E131D3C31C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may, without regard to the civil service laws and regulations, appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to perform its duties. The employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H12456737BBB64A539681606B96FBB793"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2621B2175CE5404C826FCA0CBE1D2BDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>Any United States employee may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF59F658A4C164D1B85AB1E11BC66D9E3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</header><text>The Chairperson of the Commission may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals that do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H9BCE0DCE83594EEE9E95A59B63168E2F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Federal agency response</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Commission submits the report required by section 4(c)(1), the head of any Federal department or agency that is affected by a recommendation in such report shall submit to the President, the Congress, and the Commission a response to such recommendation, including any plans to take administrative action pursuant to such recommendation.</text></section> 
<section id="HA7CAA155893F485E9FF97BB8C2E6F8F3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall terminate on the date of the submission of the update required by section 4(c)(2).</text></section> <section id="H44250897F4AB450981CAD5A8652FC676"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commission $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028 to carry out this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

