<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN25667-K5L-SL-HV1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3549 IS: PBM Fiduciary Accountability, Integrity, and Reform (FAIR) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3549</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to ensure that pharmacy benefit managers are considered fiduciaries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC30E288CED5A41EC8D5C85EA469CB61D"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF8AC6BB884E64C4AB319ABB6BD032E69"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PBM Fiduciary Accountability, Integrity, and Reform (FAIR) Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PBM FAIR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77557e5f24c6401bbce8b1178c5f50fb" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing fiduciary duties of pharmacy benefit managers</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74FCB8006E874BD3968A9579DD03676A"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Deeming pharmacy benefit managers as ERISA fiduciaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(21) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1002">29 U.S.C. 1002(21)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9B5D75586FE477E8FB400D5818854AC"><subparagraph id="H793B136A1D734CD3A84518D0296755AD" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person or entity shall be deemed to be a fiduciary with respect to a group health plan for the purposes of this Act if the person or entity—</text><clause id="H45DDB1A975944A548D9F3BF202493946"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maintains for the group health plan, the plan sponsor or plan administrator of such plan, or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage a prescription drug provider network or prescription drug formulary through the purchase of prescription drugs from a drug manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, rebate aggregator, group purchasing organization, or any associated third party; or</text></clause><clause id="H3B879ACF42DA431398A60A481E2EBCE4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engages in, on behalf of, or in connection with, the group health plan, the plan sponsor or plan administrator of such plan, or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage—</text><subclause id="HFD18B0774BAE4B998C341009E3D0E205"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the negotiation or aggregation of rebates, fees, discounts, or other price concessions for prescription drugs;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA66571D87C7F4759A00363331A93E0A4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the processing and payment of claims for prescription drugs; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H0B453D9FB5104A74A3D9151E52F63D00"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the performance of utilization review and management for prescription drugs on behalf of a group health plan.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2471D159B58D4FABA19D577D7322A097"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required compensation disclosures from pharmacy benefit managers and third party administrators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(bb)) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8AC5C8B27BAF4283B4CE45BFC99339F0"><subitem id="HA80DB465510A4F1C8904ED7B1208C732" indent="up3"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pharmacy benefit management services provided to a covered plan, for which the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive indirect compensation or direct compensation described in item (dd), including the establishment and maintenance of a prescription drug provider network or prescription drug formulary or through the purchase of prescription drugs from a drug manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, rebate aggregator, group purchasing organization, or any associated third party for the covered plan.</text></subitem><subitem id="H0C2ED5594E8748BD93A4766CA3838A7A" indent="up3"><enum>(DD)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Third party administrative services provided to a covered plan, for which the covered service provider, an affiliate, or a subcontractor reasonably expects to receive indirect compensation or direct compensation described in item (dd), including establishing and maintaining a network of medical providers, adjudicating or processing health claims, maintaining records, and negotiating reimbursement rates for the covered plan.</text></subitem><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA947FBB07BA8414189DC1747C30C0896"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification of responsible plan fiduciary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(ee) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(ii)(I)(ee)) is amended by inserting at the end the following: <quote>A covered service provider may not be the responsible plan fiduciary for purposes of the disclosures required under clause (iii). Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, in the case of a pharmacy benefit manager who sponsors a covered plan for the employees of the pharmacy benefit manager, the pharmacy benefit manager may be considered the responsible plan fiduciary for such plan.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H106E6EC34B214AD0990154F0272624E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on indemnification for breaches by a section 3(21)(C) fiduciary</header><text>Section 410(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1110">29 U.S.C. 1110(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H47C8AF2B816F43599826FB7700E4B9FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except</quote> and inserting <quote>(1) Except</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H97A95C86DE71419697EF682C1C236043"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA75190578694348AA6F8EF834D9D70C"><paragraph commented="no" id="H946860A145DE464382BAC7AFD13A3E2B" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as provided in subsection (b)(2), no person or entity deemed to be a fiduciary under section 3(21)(C) may be indemnified, directly or indirectly, or otherwise relieved from liability for any responsibility, obligation, or duty of such person or entity under this part.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H33E071BD463F431AB977176FEE4BD44E" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any provision of contract in violation of paragraph (2) shall be void as against public policy.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25BD425B87E74BCB8CB97E58BEBCA048"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 408(b)(2)(B)(i) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1108">29 U.S.C. 1108(b)(2)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>this clause</quote> and inserting <quote>this subparagraph</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9487D1B6414846249390C877F6963E90"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to plan years beginning with the first plan year that begins at least 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

