<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA97B0A6F180547C99F6C6761BCAB0DDB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9261 IH: Comprehensive Paid Leave for Federal Employees Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9261</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide paid family and medical leave to Federal employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF0AC3A2F19CD49F0A0BE40996334EB1F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE8DE8E4A3238485E95458A1BA8F25017" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Comprehensive Paid Leave for Federal Employees Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H04CD8DC2386C4DB7B07AADA7C610474A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Paid family and medical leave for Federal employees covered by title 5</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/63">Chapter 63</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCD487BB72283428D9B7C3C4DB4A3EF46" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 6381, by amending paragraph (1)(B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H7A1B2F2E4E4A431690DF5FBF1A0BF1D2" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H3248891C36B9476B887EA7250AD2702F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has completed at least 12 months of service—</text> 
<clause id="H25197606BF33425C9E0917AFDF486967" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as an employee (as defined in section 2105) of the Government of the United States, including service with the United States Postal Service, the Postal Regulatory Commission, and a nonappropriated fund instrumentality as described in section 2105(c); or</text></clause> <clause id="HFBACD31A52064A6F848CF043AA5940B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which qualifies as military service (as defined in section 8401(31));</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC190532E5E784799B1C12CCE157C7C35" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 6382—</text> <subparagraph id="H876618C812A9406AB75FE911FD8508DE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> 
<clause id="H571FCDDBDA13411BA46F0E786B81640F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subclause id="HFD2D65422ECC4AD7B00D1A125B32529C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>12 administrative workweeks of leave</quote> and inserting <quote>12 administrative work weeks of leave plus any additional period of leave used under subsection (d)(2)(B)(ii)</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD3FD7FA5E25A423A9D6ACD5C31CBA19F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and in order to care for such son or daughter</quote> before the period; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBF0B10BBB01F47689F74049229F69B87"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>by adding after subparagraph (E) the following:</text>
              <quoted-block id="H8D6A026CCE204193B35D80AF3E1669FE" style="OLC">
                <subparagraph id="H6361BA886B944B99AD4EE2333CA971C9" indent="up1">
                  <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>In order to meet the needs of the employee, or a family member of the employee, who is a victim of dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, sex trafficking, or stalking to—</text>
                  <clause id="HAE167B05FEF349A99A88EE5D9B62F5C3">
                    <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>seek medical attention or treatment for physical or psychological injuries related to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, or trafficking;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H2C8E2286636C44AB9E6AE02FF21F35B5">
                    <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>seek mental health or counseling services for injuries and trauma related to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, or trafficking;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H5931B17D849A4D8DA0311FA8AC0F79AB">
                    <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>seek services from a victim services organization, including, but not limited to, a domestic violence program, a sexual assault victim service provider, a stalking victim service provider;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H28C3C1A29A2844B3AA6FC7822349AF18">
                    <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>seek civil or criminal legal services to prepare for and participate in legal proceedings related to domestic violence, sexual assault, dating violence stalking, or trafficking;</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="HD6640E9CA5D6464D8A942DAC4684B479">
                    <enum>(v)</enum>
 <text>secure safe housing, including searching for new housing, relocating, and installing additional safety measures; </text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H69B7B51C18DC452BBECACCC5510BE307">
                    <enum>(vi)</enum>
 <text>in a case in which a family member of the employee has been a victim of dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, sex trafficking, or stalking, to assist the family member in any of the activities described in clauses (i) through (v);</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="HCECEC237CE32438096C8C25D8E41E044">
                    <enum>(vii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enroll a family member in a new school or care arrangement; or</text>
                  </clause>
                  <clause id="H045B7319B6FC4A8CBF541A71EE502E5A">
                    <enum>(viii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take other steps necessary to protect or restore their physical, mental, emotional, spiritual, and economic well-being or the well-being of a family member recovering from a qualifying act of violence. </text>
                  </clause>
                </subparagraph>
                <after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block>
              </quoted-block>
            </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H0567029DC9B040A5A193A3D0DCEF7100" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HA5F2B200DC374A7C9197B0B1E9A90D51" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HF0E7F78F94AD40A1AB85B7F2F59869C5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3A2803A2A164433F9FCD39D004552147"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The entitlement to leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) shall commence at time of birth or placement of a son or daughter and shall expire at the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date of such birth or placement.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB858356830C8489F91615772C7C34D4C" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the entitlement to leave under subparagraph (B) in connection with adoption may commence prior to the placement of the son or daughter to be adopted for activities necessary to allow the adoption to proceed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DF981178FB647C9BCE977BA1B4A41BA" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee may use leave under paragraph (1)(A) in the event that the employee experiences any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="HBDAD26A9863345E880C3789768BE6FAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A pregnancy loss.</text></clause> <clause id="H39E83A3A2C82421DB8C1E949E2F08C92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An unsuccessful round of intrauterine insemination or of an assisted reproductive technology procedure.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H378C230823544933937FBC915FA4AB57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A failed adoption match or an adoption that is not finalized because it is contested by another party.</text></clause> <clause id="HFC2A338ADD314D4AB8CCC75484E02F37"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A failed surrogacy arrangement.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H76FD6568B0C7442F8B4F099682D33A0B"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A diagnosis or event that impacts pregnancy or fertility.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFA3076AAA7644A8804DF0810EFEF825" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee may use leave under paragraph (1)(A) in the event that the absence is necessary to care for a spouse or domestic partner who experiences a circumstance described in subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC9142914F214EA2BCAA57369B369984" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum> 
<clause id="H8A147E5C97D14D0892DB928832AD7FB9" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that an employee gives birth to a child under a surrogacy arrangement, the employee may use leave under paragraph (1)(A) during such recovery period.</text></clause> <clause id="H06E4077AA123458CBB0734BB35170444" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For an employee who gives birth to a child under a surrogacy arrangement, the child shall be considered to be the child of the employee for purposes of determining entitlement to leave under this subchapter notwithstanding the definition in section 6381(6).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D534516880141A5A1AEF5F172D39468" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event that a child dies during the birth-giving parent’s post-birth recovery period, the employee may use leave under paragraph (1)(A) during such recovery period. In the case of the employee who is not the birth-giving parent, such leave is available only to the extent the employee is providing care to the birth-giving parent. In these circumstances, an employee may not use leave under paragraphs (1)(C) or (1)(D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H9FE7346D1AFD454DAEB33593E5E2ACF6" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text> 
<subclause id="H2CD1FB18B4194D79B02718C86B825D07"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Subject to subsection (d)(2), during</quote> and inserting <quote>During</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H24EF092DE5074CB4A002CE756CC626C8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(or 26 administrative workweeks of leave plus any additional period of leave used under subsection (d)(2)(B)(ii))</quote> after <quote>26 administrative workweeks of leave</quote>;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE5ED990D3824ED69263138F8631F615"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subsection (c) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HF6408227D2EF40B391E891BF8B27C4D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HA7DBD1327F1549BD9D6CA547FBB6E165"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leave granted under subsection (a)(1) shall be paid leave, as provided in subsection (d)(2), except that paid leave may not be provided for leave granted under subparagraphs (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) if an employee does not enter into the required work obligation agreement described in subsection (d)(2)(F). Leave granted under subsection (a)(3) shall be leave without pay unless annual or sick leave is substituted as provided in subsection (d)(1).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C8D598CC66E4BF8B8DC3A5D1A846AEF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <clause id="H1FB211C5CD1F4E12B6DE955637362C49"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking the first sentence; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF7E942757F2B48F28B12EA0D99C2352D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subclause id="H4C770C947420415E98D2478898E7B3BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A) through (E)</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD1923EEB79B64D5EAC2EF1B49210E530"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>parental</quote> in each instance;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H689CA6FEC86F49E281525F69DA66437C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i) of subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>any such subparagraph</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCCAC1D38417742E1ACD12492CE8D244E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B)(i), by striking <quote>in connection with the birth or placement involved</quote> and inserting <quote>during any 12-month period (as referenced in subsection (a)(1)) for leave granted under subsection (a)(1), except that the total paid leave granted for leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) in connection with a given birth or placement event may not exceed 12 administrative workweeks</quote>;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8AF680AD95B14B7D899309F4620DB17B"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending subparagraph (B)(ii) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H581671A71A514BFE90B3C7C58F57B98B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HA483F9B150224954972E4FB98B69FD15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in addition to the 12 administrative workweeks under clause (i), any annual or sick leave accrued or accumulated by such employee, if used during a 12-month period (as referenced in subsection (a)(1)) for leave granted under subsection (a)(1).</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause> <subclause id="H43ED93314CC845EABFDB3A93128CB81D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (E), (F), and (G) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7FD188CE73FA428D979A5356F3E87E8F" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H5CFF35D7B9EE47D9BE10024949F8AF01" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to modify the service requirement in section 6381(1)(B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0A59950373A4E01A558E9C03FBAEB4F"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, an employee may not receive paid leave for leave under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (a)(1) unless the employee agrees (in writing), before the commencement of such leave, to either work for the applicable employing agency for a period of time equal to the total amount of paid leave granted to the employee under subparagraph (B)(i) or provide any reimbursement required under subparagraph (G). The qualifying period of work shall exclude any period of leave or other time off, except for leave covering periods of service in the uniformed services creditable under section 4316 of title 38.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFDB3312F58F4424A88BF2C24DA3EACA6"><enum>(G)</enum> 
<clause id="H7D542A1132A749438E68B52BCA59F798" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an employee fails to complete the work obligation required under subparagraph (F), the employing agency may recover, from such employee, an amount equal to the amount of Government contributions paid by the agency under section 8906 on behalf of the employee for maintaining such employee’s health coverage under chapter 89 during the period of such leave after offsetting that period of leave by periods of work performed in partial compliance with subparagraph (F).</text></clause> <clause id="H06925076B39545FBA326E72EA9964443" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the agency shall not apply the work obligation requirement in clause (i) in any instance where the employee fails to complete the work obligation required under subparagraph (F) because of the employee’s death or because of the continuation, recurrence, or onset of a serious health condition (including mental health) affecting the employee or the employee’s spouse, parent, son, or daughter.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCDF114F573374C2EA7CD0DCD7AB465D1" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the employing agency may require that an employee who claims to be unable to complete the service required under subparagraph (F) because of a serious health condition described under clause (ii) provide certification supporting such claim by a health care provider. The employee shall provide such certification to the agency head in a timely manner.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5749843DF9CD4A0FBC424C54F24EC1AE" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subparagraph (B)(i), with respect to any employee (as defined in section 6381(1)(B)(i)) who received paid family leave under a provision of law similar to this section and becomes subject to this section, the limitations in subparagraph (B)(i) shall be applied as if the paid leave granted under that similar provision of law were granted under this section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA58624A2C8A8496B8F73C733CADB8B2D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H77A0ED152EAB4F4D86CDDB4AD4228E92" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE2536445CA19417C8E8B76B4BA915C57"><enum>(f)</enum> <paragraph id="H0EBC185E86164D6D9465E138223442B1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of leave under subsection (a)(1)(F), and subject to paragraph (2), an employing agency may require that a request for leave under such subsection be supported by a certification issued at such time and in such manner as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may by regulation prescribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H215296BCD4794DB480BC4B6B7ECD2A46" indent="up1">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an employee requesting leave under such subsection who has not yet received a certification as described under paragraph (1), such agency shall accept a sworn statement in a form prescribed by the Director that such employee has requested such certification.</text>
                            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52500A3B521C48EF823B9D19FEA8F2FB" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(F), the following definitions shall apply:</text> <subparagraph id="H20C0E057E79F4E8E8B1D5DED7AA7B7B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>dating violence</quote>, <quote>sex trafficking</quote>, <quote>sexual assault</quote>, and <quote>stalking</quote> have the meaning given those terms in section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(a)</external-xref>).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB2A1EAACA9A41748FBC57801B892D9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>domestic violence</quote> has the meaning given the term in such section 40002(a), except that the reference in such section to the term <quote>jurisdiction receiving grant funding</quote> shall be deemed to mean the jurisdiction in which the victim lives or the jurisdiction in which the employer involved is located.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H500941F439C9423AA3D214EEA7311066"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <quote>family member</quote> means, with respect to an employee—</text> 
<clause id="HA774D698CBCF4EA183FD4CC7508FDE90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a spouse (including a domestic partner in a civil union or other registered domestic partnership recognized by a State) or a parent of such spouse;</text></clause> <clause id="H1A538316AA0C4DA6945ADA13A2E2C0E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a child (regardless of age) or a child’s spouse;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9189DAB7298B47DDA00CDE827CD7BB43"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a parent or a parent’s spouse;</text></clause> <clause id="H46E473E5ACA249EE8BE2634511A881F9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a sibling or a sibling’s spouse;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF9666F93DDA54B13AA9F5EAC452B0066"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a grandparent, a grandchild, or a spouse of a grandparent or grandchild; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7E8EF72F048A4D5DA30D6427C19BF18C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>any other individual who is related by blood or affinity and whose association with the employee is equivalent of a family relationship.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD32E027ED7CE4B639CC9F9A113106DBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <quote>qualifying act of violence</quote> means an act, conduct, or pattern of conduct that could constitute any of the following:</text> <clause id="H6609E77CBAD4414D98692954B3340E86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>dating violence;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9AC8B14E137843CA8AEED54D692F4B98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>domestic violence;</text></clause> <clause id="H802809CCC85844698CC0509681D05ED8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>family violence;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC718289E050A4FFFAFCDB9C4706BE11D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>sexual assault;</text></clause> <clause id="HA30B97DA69264D6991C861207C867D97"><enum>(v)</enum><text>sex trafficking;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEE28F9BD7D7441C199520FC196A4B5DA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>stalking;</text></clause> <clause id="H421A27A30A9F4C3DA6E5A1E37828CCDD"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other forms of gender based violence or harassment; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE4340CA5211E4F598A0EE0B0AFF0DD09"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an act, conduct, or pattern of conduct—</text> <subclause id="H3F80318A59FD4E6F98C93B1CF53720D4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in which an individual causes or threatens to cause bodily injury or death to another individual;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5F8FFD484B4840F89A6B080F9849EE4C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in which an individual exhibits, draws, brandishes, or uses a firearm, or other dangerous weapon, with respect to another individual; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9EA612386B4E4B3399A14EC1F0B183BC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in which an individual uses, or makes a reasonably perceived or actual threat to use, force against another individual to cause bodily injury or death.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF86A7F4B55BC4A4CA2805A9DA131BD4A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The term <quote>victim services organization</quote> means a nonprofit, nongovernmental organization that provides assistance to victims of a qualifying act of violence or advocates for such victims, including a rape crisis center, an organization carrying out a qualifying act of violence prevention or treatment program, an organization operating a shelter or providing counseling services, or a legal services organization or other organization providing assistance through the legal process.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HACE0C221BF6240F4953730BA4A76462C" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional employees under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1312">2 U.S.C. 1312</external-xref>), is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H78C124A42E8A4B76BFA7CF3C0E06F64D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H632187BA794F4B68B42C7DF35E0A9A0B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>paragraph (1)—</text> 
<clause id="H7ED4938536744F9CA312CEA32F6BBFEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the second sentence—</text> <subclause id="HE5CC6ED93DD04FA9B530D22CC7ABF8CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (a)(1)(A) or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>under any of subsections (a)(1)(A) through (E)</quote>; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5C4793636C32492F87728B599404D76B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>apply.</quote> and inserting <quote>apply, and in the case of leave that includes leave for such an event, the period of leave to which a covered employee is entitled under section 102(a)(1) of such Act shall be 12 administrative workweeks of leave plus any additional period of leave used under subsection (d)(2)(B) of this section.</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H79FE71D2C4A24D0684C2ADE7B7DDCA6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the third sentence and inserting the following: <quote>For purposes of applying section 102(a)(4) of such Act, in the case of leave that includes leave under any of subparagraphs (A) through (E) of section 102(a)(1) of such Act, a covered employee is entitled, under paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 102(a) of such Act, to a combined total of 26 workweeks of leave plus any additional period of leave used under subsection (d)(2)(B) of this section.</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B2F20A81131438EA6A9E060F270FC10" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBDFBADF2B08F49FF9EF990F0F2C6F287" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H1CE67DFECB944C528C1AC32DF79CC71C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except for leave described under section 102(a)(3) of such Act, the term <term>eligible employee</term> as used in that Act means a covered employee.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF1A3D22ADCB4CD5BE883300ED630E98" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <subparagraph id="H62E447571EDA4FF3BD933DE854386253" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">parental leave</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">family and medical leave</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F18B2A3A7EF48478C134FB9D8278F35" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>any of subparagraphs (A) through (F)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E8FE54A62AF451786E7138E1439C9E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>parental</quote> in each instance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H617470CAB66341A2B871E3D9EEFE47EF" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>birth or placement involved</quote> and inserting <quote>event giving rise to such leave</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C3A675DB97649E3A7867BCFE3C7B773"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD851790844BF419BB62C76EDC0EB2385" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H927D2C8C76AA4325A240A9BE11F4D030"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special rule for leave relating to dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, sex trafficking, or stalking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leave provided under section 6382(a)(1)(F) of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to covered employees in the same manner if such leave were provided under 102(a)(1) of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, subject to the requirements of this section and section 6382(f) of such title 5.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HA45C0E7EC1D04F59813C0F9D03148D2D" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO, Library of Congress, Postal Service, and Postal Regulatory Commission employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612</external-xref>), is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H650A8CB3193145CF8902C67FB324BF39" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 101(2)(E)—</text> <subparagraph id="H31CB6C0F3F9A47AE809C0CAB069FB6C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">USPS, and Postal Regulatory Commission</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">GAO</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9AB7A2D391F549C582583F26CAF924A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the United States Postal Service, or the Postal Regulatory Commission</quote> after <quote>Government Accountability Office</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CE06ECDFE7543EBA0CFF512C61629AE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 102(a)(1)(A) or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 102(a)(1)(A) through (E)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE14C442C59F4B1EAD0342FBA7F87C9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 102—</text> <subparagraph id="H4DFCC934FC15420392EF7218063227F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HB3CFB458DE6C441996138108F71AA3F2" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H2C15F062262C4C82921431487F56EC68"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rules on period of leave</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an employee of the Government Accountability Office, the Library of Congress, the United States Postal Service, or the Postal Regulatory Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="HFCCC794E3BDF46CF844E04597C4EBBE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of leave that includes leave under subparagraph (A) through (E) of paragraph (1), the employee shall be entitled to 12 administrative workweeks of leave plus any additional period of leave used under subsection (d)(3)(B)(ii) of this section or section 202(d)(2)(B) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1312">2 U.S.C. 1312(d)(2)(B)</external-xref>), as the case may be; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B1C38534CEE490B8D3428373135B671"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the purposes of paragraph (4), the employee is entitled, under paragraphs (1) and (3), to a combined total of 26 workweeks of leave plus, if applicable, any additional period of leave used under subsection (d)(3)(B)(ii) of this section or section 202(d)(2)(B) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1312">2 U.S.C. 1312(d)(2)(B)</external-xref>), as the case may be.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA0ABEC056A9B41C8A19E1F811AC91063"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(3)—</text> 
<clause id="H23F20EA6C35F4A56AAFB927F5C76D646"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">USPS, and Postal Regulatory Commission</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">GAO</header-in-text></quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H2CF7C0DD87F448E18BE270DFC46FD8AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Government Accountability Office</quote> in each instance and inserting <quote>the Government Accountability Office, the United States Postal Service, or the Postal Regulatory Commission</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H608CD0731ABD4F109AA6FC132C7C2B0E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>parental</quote> in each instance and inserting <quote>family and medical</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H3992677191B0491FB3DCE0FD6F23C017"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (E)</quote>;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H96730584DAB94C108BEA160F7E255514"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B)(i), by striking <quote>birth or placement involved</quote> and inserting <quote>event giving rise to such leave</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HED223B6C89A549FEB82E35A1E6EFC34B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7B02CAE6BB10450391FC2055188F05EA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HD353257605AC4B8B9E5D4A440B16E875"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Special rule for leave relating to dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, sex trafficking, or stalking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leave provided under section 6382(a)(1)(F) of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to employees under this paragraph in the same manner if such leave were provided under 102(a)(1), subject to the requirements of this subsection and section 6382(f) of such title 5.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HA9F616AB06C94E7B84016A986539CA58"><enum>5.</enum><header>Employees of the Executive Office of the President</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 412 of title 3, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3B945F54F12441209EA82D591499E4B4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0876D882E27B455A8D45131CC9058BD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H3DD3EC0241474676ACB8F5F538EE712B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H4CB2A7CD59894F92B629DA6DACD6604B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>eligible employee</quote> as used in the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 means a covered employee who is employed in any employing office, excluding any individual employed on a temporary or intermittent basis.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7B266B586FCE4BC491E0658BE467CB1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H41AE7E5B4BE447288E56B8FBFA18B00C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="H69DCDAD6755B4631932F873CA204CA3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subparagraph (A) or (B)</quote> in each instance and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (A) through (E)</quote>; and</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF5B77A8E138242BC9CAA7C0363C22B31"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HACBA0F60872D4AB18898F65C45E6199A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for substitution for leave without pay under subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 6382(a)(1) of such title</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2E3FE66B2EEE43DCBB65CAB3C3E6F276"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding after the period at the end the following: <quote>Leave provided under section 6382(a)(1)(F) of such title 5 shall apply to covered employees in the same manner if such leave were provided under 102(a)(1) of such Act, subject to the requirements of this subsection and section 6382(f) of such title 5.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </section> <section id="H5A5D43A863904FEA89163D06739CA326"><enum>6.</enum><header>FAA and TSA employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 40122(g)(5) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H196299D07FB74C698DF7703497B3B168"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="USC">parental</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C4DF6116E5F4F4B89C901206009F1B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>parental</quote> in each instance.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H310CCB475A594D128C241F4B32F8E237"><enum>7.</enum><header>Title 38 employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall modify the family and medical leave program provided by operation of section 7425(c) of title 38, United States Code, to conform with this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> <section id="H52BDF48FFE2547EEA99D482D9FF65E96"><enum>8.</enum><header>District of Columbia courts and District of Columbia public defender service</header> <subsection id="HCEB5137A618B478CB259C4B24D95CF7C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>District of Columbia courts</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 11–1726, District of Columbia Official Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H91131B87158D46C9B2B0E13430D87265" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HC2677368013641A296C21945F63C6241"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2601">29 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to non-judicial employees of the District of Columbia courts, the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration shall, notwithstanding any provision of such Act, establish a paid family and medical leave program for the leave described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of section 102(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</external-xref>), and such program shall include paid leave described under section 6382(a)(1)(F) of title 5, United States Code. In developing the terms and conditions for this program, the Joint Committee may be guided by the terms and conditions applicable to the provision of paid family and medical leave for employees of the Federal Government under chapter 63 of such title 5 and any corresponding regulations.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HEB90D9BDE944493F9C8F4DEDC5EE2EA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>District of Columbia public defender service</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 305 of the District of Columbia Court Reform and Criminal Procedure Act of 1970 (sec. 21605, D.C. Official Code) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAD37CC92A3DD4B1C9F7FA17084AC3861" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HAC29CB005FE747C280F049590E1F998C"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2601">29 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to employees of the Service, the Director shall, notwithstanding any provision of such Act, establish a paid leave program for the leave described in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of section 102(a)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2612">29 U.S.C. 2612(a)(1)</external-xref>), and such program shall include paid leave described under section 6382(a)(1)(F) of title 5, United States Code. In developing the terms and conditions for this program, the Director may be guided by the terms and conditions applicable to the provision of paid family and medical leave for employees of the Federal Government under chapter 63 of such title 5 and any corresponding regulations.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HBE354D883CC34C888417131B24600527"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall begin to apply on the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

