<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25A46-9L4-KN-V86"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3051 IS: Partnership for Advancing Regional Training and Narcotics Enforcement Response Strategies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3051</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251023">October 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was
                read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on
                    Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To build the capacity of the Armed Forces of Mexico to counter the threat
 posed by transnational criminal organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Partnership for Advancing Regional Training and Narcotics Enforcement Response Strategies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PARTNERS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ida8ad4cc167e44ed4940506907e312a86"><enum>2.</enum><header>Building the capacity of the Armed Forces of Mexico to counter the threat posed
 by transnational criminal organizations</header><subsection id="id5901fcc3023e422f99a078b4c9e13ef5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States Government to counter the threat posed by transnational criminal organizations, including through military capacity building and security cooperation with the Government of Mexico.</text></subsection><subsection id="id18a36024e3ab4bd5b33a8fa7f305040f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State and with the agreement of the Government of Mexico, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan for a pilot program under which the Armed Forces of Mexico and the United States Armed Forces will train jointly in the United States on tactics, techniques, and procedures for countering the threat posed by transnational criminal organizations, including through—</text><paragraph id="id6d5848f5ec1249048b7a6e9c7c5e7702"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operations involving the use of rotary-wing aircraft; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6762cc0925a34e61865f6aa0f9d81b64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in consultation with the appropriate civilian government agencies specializing in countering transnational criminal organizations—</text><subparagraph id="iddb7700085e3446ea84b26cc714bc1e5e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>joint network analysis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id180ae15c5dec406697d6e7de582d56b3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>counter threat financing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63ea900a28b54a6fb6808a7475e5dd27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>counter illicit trafficking (including narcotics, weapons, and human trafficking, and illicit trafficking in natural resources); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf50a863810d940e3b676d7700df75c61"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assessments of key nodes of activity of transnational criminal organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7cf730d0f3c6401c8934a0198efc01d4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date on which the plan required by subsection (b) is submitted under such subsection, the Secretary of Defense shall begin implementing the pilot program described in the plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="id96c84992b36c405b93d7b4be442fbc9a"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id19525f90b678470092f00134a1e0ad0e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id837467c817934fb78e11ab31e473d5de"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


