<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB53C27FBFBF2497C83FD0F42D6CA1DDD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8688 IH: Forest Health and Wildfire Risk Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8688</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001100">Mr. Hurd of Colorado</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify the categorical exclusion proposed in the National Environmental Policy Act Implementing Procedures for the Bureau of Land Management related to tree density modification published on April 6, 2026.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H450AD48142D14D6DAC079D5CC7D3C9DA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCD47E0C215424B02BEAC62B907C326F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Forest Health and Wildfire Risk Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC19AA09CB3384EF6A8279192EDFFF3B9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of categorical exclusion</header> <subsection id="H6C7DDC1A4F3847F8A02D338F63AC231B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tree density modification activities described in subsection (b) are a category of actions hereby designated as being categorically excluded from the preparation of an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under section 102 of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332</external-xref>).</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HC0E87E954E4145D0B6BA2CEE5563F4CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tree density modification activities designated for categorical exclusion</header> 
<paragraph id="HC36428279B754C8FB640419530A94636"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tree density modification activities designated under this section for categorical exclusion are covered actions carried out within a treatment area of less than 5,000 acres.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H88C0F418FBDC49D4AB9051FA9C0554EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The categorical exclusion provided for under subsection (a) does not apply to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H571E86E178B34057B33E177340204988"><enum>(A)</enum><text>silvicultural methods that are intended to regenerate whole stands, such as even-aged regeneration harvest, clearcutting, or variable retention harvest; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEFD0B78508F346BEBF21BC8349379799"><enum>(B)</enum><text>vegetation management intended to convert forest or woodlands to non-forest vegetation cover.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H77D81F4D1C794DCDB9CA28722C241EBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on actions</header><text>In addition to the covered actions under paragraph (1), tree density modification activities to which the categorical exclusion under this section applies—</text> <subparagraph id="H5120DCE942024E3EA8F1754EFA6C9528"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may include construction of up to 5 miles of new permanent road to facilitate covered actions, provided that all segments conform to applicable land use planning decisions with route-specific designations disclosed where travel management planning has been completed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H592C0254888B46B6B137A4B765AAA6AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include maintenance and renovation of existing roads as needed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CFFB10AF8D54C0596C4CD77283782CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may include construction of temporary roads not to exceed a ratio of 2.5 miles per 1,000 acres of treatment area as needed, provided that the temporary roads—</text> 
<clause id="H89046409D5A646898CE35624132075ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are not part of the permanent transportation system of the Bureau;</text></clause> <clause id="H39889875773F4F7EA1F069044E9D7CCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are designed to standards appropriate for their intended use (safety, erosion control, sedimentation prevention, and resource protection);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFE4396C1BDAD4CE9AAD30AC4E9616BC0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are not needed for long-term resource management; and</text></clause> <clause id="H43642BACE5C848CA98F3173562562722"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are decommissioned and stabilized after use to minimize erosion and protect water quality; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3CB1634EDEB6499CB3CBDBCBB4626E54"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require the disclosure of design features, in documentation of finding that an action is excluded pursuant to the use of this categorical exclusion, that address the following resource considerations consistent with applicable land use plan decisions, or, where no plan requirements apply, specify how the following resource considerations are addressed:</text> <clause id="H21393AE9BFCC452E90C544461CE32869"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Snag and downed wood—amount to be created or retained.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF0161A2DEDBC4B438287CA5BD0381D41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Erosion control—specifications or measures (e.g., water bars, dispersed slash).</text></clause> <clause id="H77E4FDA84B2246E4BF6BA93FB0C60E4E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Soil compaction—criteria for avoidance, minimization, or remediation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H57F7A5AE5F3A4F42A377895271401ECF">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>Logging systems—types and scope of constraints (e.g., seasonal, location, extent, etc.).</text>
                        </clause> 
<clause id="HEF3135A57D1246FD93D9235BDFCC33DE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Seasonal operations—purpose and extent of operating restrictions.</text></clause> <clause id="HE581E0B194C64347B97333480F71FF7F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Invasive species—measures to prevent or limit spread.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1CD03F2A17DA4D8DBE3C1089EA36B66B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Riparian areas—buffer widths and/or operating restrictions.</text></clause> <clause id="H6638F8DB575B4A998433460A2720E31F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Prescribed fire—operating constraints for underburning or pile burning.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4079BE2E1A4E410AAE10764745DADEE4"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Temporary roads—decommissioning standards.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H34430EF6134F47BDA7E4CAD77875950B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H52DEFF6CC7AD4D08A8442E5A9827FF5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text>The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEE9E806CA3B4D91B1E1575AC2C0DED5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered actions</header><text>The term <term>covered actions</term> means one or more of the following actions:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD74E8502702E46729A518FCDCDC5F360"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Cutting, yarding, and the use of landings and skid trails to facilitate the removal of commercial and non-commercial trees.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD29901B42DC047F0BB1D48AA17DE77B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Chipping, grinding, or removal of residual slash.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE63702123304D0BA3C847E6010D8A1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Group selection silvicultural treatment to promote regeneration of shade intolerant species and early successional habitat in an uneven-aged context not to exceed 2-acre individual patches and 10 percent of the treatment area (group selection openings will retain overstory legacy elements consistent with the applicable land use plan (for example, large fire resilient trees, snags)).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B1C68EB10394BE4B9695AF9AA32B1D9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Pile burning or underburning of fuels created by covered actions described in clauses (i) through (iii) and fuels within or in close proximity to those actions’ treatment boundaries whether created by those actions or not.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53CA4AD5FDC34DDF94A90BD8B65FAAB6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Seeding or planting necessary to accelerate native species re-establishment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20C9967665FC4A548BB7AAC60D99EB48"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Group selection</header><text>The term <term>group selection</term> means an uneven-aged harvest method where groups of trees are removed to promote spatial heterogeneity, regeneration of desired tree species, or the establishment of new cohorts.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H240CFBD3D9C94841A688D970F870D1D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Permanent road</header><text>The term <term>permanent road</term> means a road constructed or reconstructed and managed as part of the permanent transportation system of the Bureau.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6607D455FA7401D9E069F8F0A93B2CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Temporary road</header><text>The term <term>temporary road</term> means a road authorized by contract, permit, lease, written authorization, or emergency operation, not added to the permanent transportation system of the Bureau, and decommissioned after use.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

