<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL25B26-DL5-3C-M42"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 514 ATS: Designating November 2025 as “American Diabetes Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 514</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 2025 as <quote>American Diabetes Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention—</text><paragraph id="id2cca72ca6ad243de8487c448700f5ce8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an estimated 38,400,000 individuals in the United States have diabetes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id17f9eb86ed654595b1f32ef3142f4dd2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimated 97,600,000 individuals in the United States who are 18 years of age or older have prediabetes;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas diabetes is a serious chronic condition that affects individuals of every age, race, ethnicity, and income level;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reports that—</text><paragraph id="ided28e627b8fd4c4dac35c55481770c9b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hispanic, Black, Asian, American Indian, and Alaska Native adults in the United States are disproportionately affected by diabetes and develop the disease at much higher rates than the general population of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idae33a61d85cd487fa6d4582a0ecf1b61"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimated 23 percent of individuals with diabetes in the United States have not yet been diagnosed with the disease;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the United States, an estimated 11.6 percent of the population, including 29.2 percent of individuals who are 65 years of age or older, have diabetes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, of the approximately 15,800,000 veterans in the United States, nearly 1 in 4 receiving care in the Department of Veterans Affairs system receive treatment for diabetes, representing more than double the rate found in the general population;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the risk of developing type 2 diabetes at some point in life is 40 percent for adults in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the American Diabetes Association—</text><paragraph id="idf9b8058d99f1406dafd641d48a54b83c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in 2022, the estimated direct and indirect medical costs in the United States for cases of diagnosed diabetes was $412,900,000,000; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc128555ca8d442b980a78aec471cf06b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as insulin prices remain high for some patients, 1 in 4 individuals using insulin report reducing use due to insulin cost;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the American Diabetes Association reports that, in 2022, care for individuals with diagnosed diabetes accounted for 1 in 4 health care dollars in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas medical costs are estimated to be 2.6 times higher for individuals in the United States with diabetes than those without diabetes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, as of November 2025, a cure for diabetes does not exist;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are successful means to reduce the incidence, and delay the onset, of type 2 diabetes;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, with proper management and treatment, individuals with diabetes live healthy and productive lives; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas individuals in the United States celebrate American Diabetes Month in November: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idb5a3fece042546cd94b40a491fb60142"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates November 2025 as <quote>American Diabetes Month</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b564b76a0ea46fd9d84bd508c4dc545"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the goals and ideals of American Diabetes Month, including—</text><subparagraph id="ida48747cbd7c2496f903057d89e8aed2a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encouraging individuals in the United States to fight diabetes through public awareness of prevention and treatment options;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6fb5b4c7893464db67afb8bc8be4455"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhancing diabetes education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id86b61572046941aa9cec66f2a2bd7db1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recognizing the importance of awareness and early detection, including awareness of symptoms and risk factors such as—</text><clause id="id6b758cef49744a3cab25d5c9ef18d368"><enum>(i)</enum><text>being—</text><subclause id="id0269456b426d44b5bf750d26aa43d69d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>older than 45 years of age; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id63762e1d9f1b4683ab380254d1474d2a"><enum>(II)</enum><text>overweight; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="iddc66b4a0b4e64eedac6832d2aa23da29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>having—</text><subclause id="idf0e369e1bff642f39dce2926472c0185"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a particular racial and ethnic background;</text></subclause><subclause id="id19b86c3cafc641dc8c0fb214ce88764e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a low level of physical activity;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7091b5a1d9474ead970b6044d624dcfb"><enum>(III)</enum><text>high blood pressure;</text></subclause><subclause id="id59295b8e64d5400cab2f8d318d846971"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a family history of diabetes; or</text></subclause><subclause id="ide0c7fc6469d5428e9a99ea009ff25760"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a history of diabetes during pregnancy;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id40d0b8ae157b4d8c9c512968916cffbe"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supporting a decrease in the prevalence of type 1, type 2, and gestational diabetes in the United States through research, treatment, and prevention; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id164c8b212a934237bbb8ece9fb94273e"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recognizing the importance of addressing barriers to health care that—</text><clause id="id3b594317601b4b969506a693d62393a3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>leave many communities at a heightened risk for diabetes; and</text></clause><clause id="iddd7f574cee204ff599b9f03fa1d317a4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>limit access to health care resources that are needed to effectively prevent the onset, and to manage the condition, of diabetes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

