<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6755464B4E3F4A078D7C9AD59B9D2EE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7644 IH: Millennium Challenge Corporation Strategic Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7644</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260223">February 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 to modify the authorities of the Millennium Challenge Corporation relating to strategic competitors of the United States and critical minerals.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCA6D13D8423B4335975624D7DBFE1E67" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H42AD19EF4E344EBA8565AD0047E2602F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Millennium Challenge Corporation Strategic Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEC93B58F99A643BFB042A23C17A5A091"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H69770491C66F444DBDEFB9C9465292B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Millennium Challenge Corporation is an independent United States Government agency that delivers results-driven foreign assistance, using a transparent, data-driven model rooted in good governance, economic freedom, and investment in people to advance America’s economic and strategic interests.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8656F69F67E24ADF904A2110F9D0F7B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Strategic competitors of the United States, including the People’s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, and the Islamic Republic of Iran, increasingly deploy state-directed finance, infrastructure development, and resource investments to gain long-term political and economic leverage in developing countries.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEAF4317D97364C9AAE55FBA56F28CC14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The global supply of critical minerals is increasingly concentrated, opaque, and vulnerable to coercion by strategic competitors of the United States, creating risks to United States national security, energy security, and advanced manufacturing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E1BBDA6B95D4FD1B536D2A739E225AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Millennium Challenge Corporation’s tools, including grant-based financing, policy reform conditionality, and high governance standards, are well-suited to addressing constraints in critical mineral supply chains, such as infrastructure gaps, regulatory weaknesses, and workforce development limitations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1DED872826EB491B9F858F587BC33C74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Earlier and more systematic engagement by the Millennium Challenge Corporation with the United States private sector can improve project design, crowd in private capital, and strengthen economic ties between partner countries and the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6BC5BB839EA4490916AB950E4FB968A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The modernization of the Millennium Challenge Corporation should strengthen, not dilute, its core development mission and independence.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HE1BAC7FCE1354C46B98482BC5C2BA75B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HBCD407F6DB8F4CAB8DB18430A60FD92F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategic competition considerations should inform but not replace the Millennium Challenge Corporation’s existing eligibility standards;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H44E05F16CB064200AFBC66424B57781C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reforms should increase transparency, accountability, and value to United States taxpayers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H829F5FFC965A49599A593F7E95854BD3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Millennium Challenge Corporation should be modernized as a strategic asset in an era of global competition.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H36687E07FBF54FECBE8A182094443131"><enum>4.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 602 of the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7701">22 U.S.C. 7701</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HFDB5F22364964DD89663CD4082ABFEDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H17654F017D9949BFB4BEA49C10D74330"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H413877D8F1D14BE2A36B7BD849CFDB44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3225DB9E9CED4DF2BB6FA19E8CC6CBC6" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="HF31777B6885440118ABBC5E9FB0FA413"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to advance United States economic security and strategic competitiveness by supporting eligible country reforms and investments that strengthen critical mineral supply chains, strategic infrastructure, and market-based economic integration, while also supporting poverty reduction and sustainable economic growth.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H5AAB18CA09484A20B3B97292F9F356D9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Critical Minerals Task Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 604 of the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7703">22 U.S.C. 7703</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4208768824C647609A6DAB8D22857B1C" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="H365046D447D94E10B5107E3F9C388712"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Critical Minerals Task Force</header>
<paragraph id="H7AB9216DA30442E998D43581FBD4FA6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Directors shall establish in the Corporation a Critical Minerals Task Force (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A954CA7805A47CDB6CCD6349317ED7D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6ED75F9301D1497B9FE7F5AE99B0F9FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess global and regional critical mineral supply chain vulnerabilities to United States economic and national security;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H940476A4C4284B7D83213962C2D7ABF7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify candidate countries in which Corporation engagement could enhance transparent, diversified, and sustainable mineral supply chains;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD4405D41983546DDBF494BEBEFF61136"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluate infrastructure, regulatory, environmental, labor, and governance constraints affecting mineral development and downstream processing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8655C8769AA14CF492F43364C9C976C0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommend priority policy reforms and investment areas appropriate for Corporation assistance; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2DBCACAFC8CA4500A18D0F2CF78BAC18"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinate, as appropriate, with relevant United States Government agencies, multilateral institutions, and private sector stakeholders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A80EC2E13E3456B8AB6760303DB3241"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to authorize the Corporation to engage in extractive activities or to subsidize mineral production.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H881A9A431BA64E12B8A91966BF3DC777"><enum>6.</enum><header>Great Power Competition Factsheet</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 607 of the Millennium Challenge Corporation Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7706">22 U.S.C. 7706</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H23EFFF8699804F589A3E49E9CEAF21CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H4B9DED23EABB4C2B8CEF772B7BB9D446"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Great Power Competition Factsheet</header> <paragraph id="HF0C4DA72AF044974A4A897D1310DA612"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining eligible countries under this section, the Board shall assess strategic exposure and resilience of candidate countries to the People’s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, the Islamic Republic of Iran, and other strategic competitors of the United States using the factors described in paragraph (2). The assessment carried out under this paragraph may be referred to as the <quote>Great Power Competition Factsheet</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>GPC Factsheet</quote>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D1D3280C8E44FDDAEF3128823A8F9EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The GPC Factsheet shall include, where data are available—</text> <subparagraph id="HDA770C750C6C428BB5B7EDCFDD0CCA9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trade volumes, export dependencies, and import reliance involving the People’s Republic of China, the Russian Federation, the Islamic Republic of Iran, and other strategic competitors of the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H274CC29E181847B19299573A9E6F9F79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>foreign direct investment, sovereign lending, and state-owned enterprise activity from such countries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H57C4F6BCF1F34C6082E5C04A3A8828BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>foreign assistance, concessional finance, and debt exposure linked to such countries;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDBFE03F2A8754563B2848E4E2643B9F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ownership, control, financing, or operation of strategic infrastructure, including ports, rail, power generation, transmission, digital networks, and data systems such countries;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28A4D42FB8EE4D49BAA7443224E61E0B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>critical mineral endowments, processing capacity, export controls, and governance frameworks; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEF5A1E19AD3A4D9F9DE65B755807E6A9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>alignment with international transparency, labor, environmental, and anti-corruption standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H243F5E01603D489EAA078B56D9552762"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The GPC Factsheet shall inform Board deliberations but shall not replace other eligibility criteria under other provisions of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H546A824FB079496FAEE0BB5CD4DC117D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Millennium Challenge Compact</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 609 of the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7708">22 U.S.C. 7708</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF1E7D993487F47DCBE8BFF8DA6F26382"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (j) to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFA5B4EA4DEDA43A19C83B47151F2763B" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="HDA67FD4336F4474290DFF3D5D1D00F1B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Duration of Compact</header>
<paragraph id="H66902CF9620D4C46A11F3B9B9867FCA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The implementation of a Compact shall not exceed 5 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78DA2132B68F4E36A2FEF329DCA7EFB5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other matters</header><text>The Corporation shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H05534B9FD39E4EADB3808348B55FE233"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obligate the entire funding for a Compact upon the execution of the Compact; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D0A10B7749C4039BDAD6B2151E531C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consult with the appropriate congressional committees at the commencement of the implementation period of a Compact.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H804B0F8437104820B7C6EF18E21A10CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H15ECE179AF604699A4927753C2A512BC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H01D1109F514342AE9BE7368BA355CDAB"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Early private sector engagement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing a Compact under this section or under other programs developed under section 616, the Corporation shall, to the extent practicable, engage United States private sector entities, investors, and technical experts during the early stages of project identification and design. Such engagement shall seek to—</text>
<paragraph id="HC28E93DBB385403DB292B284B9F6AD0B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the feasibility and effectiveness of Compact projects;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31030AFE748E477E9158E9F7625EE4AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>mobilize private capital to supplement assistance provided under this title; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3D919797DD344DABB1E8395A40F9421D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhance the long-term sustainability and impact of assistance provided under this title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H430772A81997477DA08F4C47BE4C7F92"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Timely completion of constraint analysis and due diligence</header> <paragraph id="H8E9E2F1A373F47F9B950395C1D5195F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Corporation shall use best efforts to commence implementation of the program by ensuring that all required constraint analyses, feasibility studies, environmental assessments, economic analyses, and other forms of due diligence necessary for project commencement are conducted in an expeditious and efficient manner, consistent with the Corporation’s policies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H16505E590A734822A04D0F44E325A1BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safeguards</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to authorize the circumvention of any requirements for a Compact described in subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56442725DBF4409CBA2BC0562E26C336"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Board oversight</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on which a Compact or an agreement under section 616 is entered into and ending on the date on which the Compact or agreement has commenced implementation, the Corporation shall periodically provide a written update to the Board and consult with the appropriate congressional committees to describe—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6CAB5FC2C480459E93946D77273E7E5E">
                                <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of the program, including the anticipated date of implementation the program will commence;</text>
                            </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9006CAF989004BA3A8C40143DFF6F817"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issues that may negatively impact the anticipated date implementation will commence and steps taken to resolve such issues; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F137F3455F9425886673E6DC5E766FF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any measures adopted with the intent to mitigate the issues identified in subparagraph (B) for future Compacts or agreements under section 616.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="H641DEE0978CF4D13B03CB58229A65633"><enum>8.</enum><header>Congressional and public notification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 610(a) of the Millennium Challenge Corporation Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7709">22 U.S.C. 7709(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H8B20B7935EE142D68BF49E32AD96A21F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (5); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71943D77FEC243A69009F9F39207BE9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE4B750F4E1EF429FA8C17858CB0D7BE0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H060D0580C2DF469DBF865BF4C9DD2A6D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Complementary framework</header> <subparagraph id="H8ED120F711AE41B580AC73524313E4E8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text>In addition to a report describing the economic rate of return of the Compact as required under paragraph (3)(A), the Corporation shall develop and include in the report a complementary framework to assess benefits accruing to the United States under the Compact.</text>
                        </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1E54DD755C3A4A6CA268FE8243983BA4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>Such complementary framework may include—</text> <clause id="HA38ACE0CD06744618605ED484BFAEE95"><enum>(i)</enum><text>diversification and resilience of critical supply chains and inputs to United States productive activities;</text></clause>
<clause id="HAD63AAE2CC3C4CFFA3B228F32BD98BB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increased participation of United States companies and investors;</text></clause> <clause id="H7C35E76699124E67A577635B88006B60"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>actions to reduce recipient country exposure to strategic competitors;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9D19290E8B8D4B76A56ABED79A0B5BE8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>export of goods and services from the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFE2BDD18B25B4D9A80B680DFFB9C8055"><enum>(v)</enum><text>strengthened diplomatic and economic partnerships.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

