<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE5A47304E0C546C0A4F727E675E99B71" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1194 IH: Recognizing April 2026 as “Distracted Driving Awareness Month” and promoting efforts to help prevent tragic and preventable crashes, deaths, and injuries caused by distracted driving.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1194</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing April 2026 as <quote>Distracted Driving Awareness Month</quote> and promoting efforts to help prevent tragic and preventable crashes, deaths, and injuries caused by distracted driving.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas distracted driving, including visual, manual, and cognitive distraction, remains one of the leading causes of preventable crashes on United States roadways;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to national safety data, over 3,000 people are killed each year, and over 300,000 more are injured, in crashes involving distracted drivers;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas distracted driving has increased in recent years due to the growing use of mobile devices and in-vehicle technologies, contributing significantly to roadway fatalities and serious injuries;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States Congress has supported efforts to reduce distracted driving through investments in roadway safety, public education, and technology that helps drivers stay focused and reduce distraction before crashes occur;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas when a person reads a text while driving, their eyes are off the road for an average of 5 seconds, the same distance as traveling the length of an entire football field at 55 miles per hour;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas more work must be done to stop the preventable and tragic consequences of distracted driving to make roads safer for drivers, passengers, pedestrians, cyclists, and all who share the road;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas research shows that texting while driving increases crash risk by up to 23 times and that hands-free technologies do not eliminate cognitive distraction;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many States have enacted hands-free or antitexting laws, and continued adoption and enforcement of such laws can help reduce distracted driving and save lives;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Transportation and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration work to educate the public each April through the national <quote>Put the Phone Away or Pay</quote> and <quote>U Drive. U Text. U Pay.</quote> campaigns;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas State and local law enforcement play a vital role in reducing distracted driving crashes, injuries, and fatalities; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas State and local law enforcement agencies partner with the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration each April to conduct high-visibility enforcement and public outreach to combat distracted driving: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA3F8466B763C40AF9D1DD80136E49633"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H57D5731D91A8478C881F97BB09AAEC9D"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4000A65C79774155873CF990D94C7368"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expresses support for the recognition of <quote>Distracted Driving Awareness Month</quote> to raise awareness about the dangers of distracted driving;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE63769F935AE4FA4ADDC0F67F95F7B75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supports the efforts of the Department of Transportation, State departments of transportation, State and local governments, and State and local law enforcement to prevent and stop distracted driving, thereby saving lives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32C460D2D6A44FE9A620758F8BFF3A58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urges people across the United States to take preventive steps against distracted driving, such as putting phones away while driving, enabling <quote>Do Not Disturb</quote> features, and staying focused on the road at all times.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

