<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-FLO26082-2MR-FG-1D3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3725 IS: To require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to determine the feasibility of constructing a project to supply municipal, rural, and industrial water to expand the capacity and reach of the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System, Inc. (doing business as “Lewis &amp; Clark Regional Water System”), in the States of Iowa, Minnesota, and South Dakota.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3725</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S303">Mr. Thune</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study to determine the feasibility of constructing a project to supply municipal, rural, and industrial water to expand the capacity and reach of the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System, Inc. (doing business as <quote>Lewis &amp; Clark Regional Water System</quote>), in the States of Iowa, Minnesota, and South Dakota.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lewis &amp; Clark Regional Water System Expansion Feasibility Study Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id367484c898284d94beed3dff55c3b25f"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id762a00eac981453d812763a2c9172039"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Federal project entity</header><text>The term <quote>non-Federal project entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="ida4c6e070bfc2448d9a2947f170bf4753"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Lewis and Clark Rural Water System, Inc. (doing business as <quote>Lewis &amp; Clark Regional Water System</quote>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id941ae51be5104f57bf9d5d1ee56e03c6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any nonprofit successor entity to the corporation described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id95a21c0919cc4535a468bd256895b1c4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposed rural water supply project</header><text>The term <quote>proposed rural water supply project</quote> means the proposed project to supply municipal, rural, and industrial water to expand the capacity and reach of the Lewis &amp; Clark Regional Water System in the States of Iowa, Minnesota, and South Dakota.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id79dc0fb29df145f2a677ffbca83e6136" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idb07749ca7a934b93af5fc531ecb67180"><enum>3.</enum><header>Lewis &amp; Clark Regional Water System expansion feasibility study</header><subsection id="id335172d55dca47f592e14e75c9e85d4e" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd0d0c0ce816d4fe49264c30ad096e0ed"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the non-Federal project entity, shall carry out a study to determine the feasibility of the proposed rural water supply project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea0fc6a49aca4c33a0b76d9af6c7cd7b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Feasibility report</header><text>After completion of the feasibility study for the proposed rural water supply project under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="idf89dc5ead0474935b00f591f5c8ac235"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a feasibility report that includes a recommendation of the Secretary on—</text><clause id="idcd7e5ac75e2249b7948d813da6dbb298"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the proposed rural water supply project should be authorized for construction; and</text></clause><clause id="id1f910f0ddcaa4aae80383e12994bf790"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the appropriate non-Federal share of construction costs, which shall be—</text><subclause id="id0a86a1b8b8ce40aa87a09e312a55618a"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at least 25 percent of the total construction costs; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id6244504b35004ea3a1235a5f927a9afc"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determined based on an analysis of the financial capability-to-pay the allocated construction and operations, maintenance, and replacement costs of the recommended plan;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4723b74400bd44fb9fccca54408370a4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit the report under subparagraph (A) to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72ab1584463b40d7839969ef8989b978"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make the report under subparagraph (A) publicly available, along with associated feasibility study documents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5d85513313b4ff995559b8d019a96ef"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation and cooperation</header><text>In addition to the non-Federal project entity, the Secretary shall consult and cooperate with appropriate Federal, State, Tribal, regional, and local authorities during the conduct of the feasibility study and development of the feasibility report under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc910be6e473640a992e99c4831fbff8e"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Cost-Sharing agreement for feasibility study costs</header> <text>The Secretary shall enter into a cost-sharing agreement (or an appropriate financial assistance agreement, as determined by the Secretary) with the non-Federal project entity to conduct a study under subsection (a) that complies with the reclamation feasibility standards.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1b04ceb969784929af984528f84ddf10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal share of feasibility study costs</header><text>The Federal share of the total costs of carrying out the feasibility study under subsection (a) shall not exceed 50 percent.</text></subsection><subsection id="id929070e543a2446b86ff3bd6003c03e5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $10,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="id05c52daad732490f80673d172ba72c06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>The authority provided by this section expires on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

