<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV26776-9MF-3F-GT8" key="G"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>94 SJ 185 PCS: To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran that have not been authorized by Congress. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 415</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 185</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc> Committee discharged and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran that have not been authorized by Congress. </official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="id007afcf404494e1391fd4f7cdc788ba3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="idaaf1c48b840c4974be1e0a51e2a71a4a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8, clause 11 of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4a4ef00fb77844b29d127b621cd4cf55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President has a constitutional responsibility to take actions to defend the United States and its territories, possessions, citizens, servicemembers, and diplomats from attack.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1501a56fdb9c4cd8b535a30c1c37e24a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war upon Iran or any person or organization within Iran, nor enacted a specific statutory authorization for the use of military force within or against Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id27d340184f734eae9a8201687467ef96"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The use of military force within or against Iran (including the enforcement of a naval blockade) constitutes the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities within the meaning of section 4(a) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1543">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id115c859bf0494b2a9d803781a6be76d0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) provides that any joint resolution or bill requiring the removal of United States Armed Forces from imminent engagement in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures under section 601(b) of the International Security and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="id89033dbcead24cdba486836536aaa636"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8dd8da9346d8420cb2949adb57048ea4"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>), and in accordance with section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>), Congress hereby directs the President to remove the United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Iran, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or a specific authorization for use of military force.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2512b6f6cbe540f6a4c79e6fb4e13e35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this resolution may be construed to prevent the United States from—</text><paragraph id="id049148d87cad4a6780f7864913a90641"><enum>(1)</enum><text>defending against an attack on the United States or its personnel or facilities in other nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04c0a878374842efab91a63edbe1b429"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collecting, analyzing, or sharing intelligence with partner countries who have been attacked by Iran since February 28, 2026, and other nations and international organizations as appropriate, related to threats from Iran or its proxies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb78645b260414b4ba2e6cc61af4c2f78"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assisting partner countries who have been attacked by Iran since February 28, 2026, and other nations—</text><subparagraph id="id98599cf134da473c82a6fbe945ac4a2f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in intercepting retaliatory attacks by Iran or its proxies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63bb9801448144cd87b044b570a4f2d6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by providing defensive materiel support for such defensive measures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></resolution-body><endorsement><action-date>May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc> Committee discharged and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></resolution> 

