<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H478463C1F5F64D08A7555656A0E0E12C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9413 IH: Military Family Limb Loss Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9413</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to carry out the Military Family Limb Loss and Limb Difference Support Program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H211D4B336D06409782D660BAFF6ACBF4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDA4484E131F94FA3878383FBFE0E7C84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Family Limb Loss Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBEB17B33E941496E987D34E5DF480410" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Military Family Limb Loss and Limb Difference Support Program</header> <subsection id="HFE0C7259E26F4735B67E792B487B5F36"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Beginning in fiscal year 2028, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a program, to be known as the <quote>Military Family Limb Loss and Limb Difference Support Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>), to augment the holistic rehabilitative care for covered beneficiaries with limb loss or limb dysfunction through peer mentoring, education, and community outreach.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H517DD857C7B846428557EA563209BF9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Program shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HF84CBD8B4D474EC981F9FD95BB4A2F0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>peer mentorship and family support services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H154C3C461DA340B4BDA271BFE6124E6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>education related to limb loss care and services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H519EC7336C8349348EB75063BBAA845A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>community reintegration supports;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86E7EC3EFC27459F81341B9BBE5045F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordination of nonclinical resources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7AAB929311E141ED98CB039E7BE2895F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>outreach and awareness activities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA88CDF2579E840E19914279C46B3B56E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>such other activities as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H07DF2011ED2C4BA2A70A90D7BE71BC1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may enter into a cooperative agreement or contract with one or more organizations that have demonstrated experience in carrying out the activities described in subsection (b) in virtual or in-person settings to support individuals with limb loss or limb difference, including individuals belonging to pediatric, military, or veteran populations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC183B53C4BA0429FA322ABA1A28775F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a plan for implementing the Program that—</text> <paragraph id="H85D23130DA204B3B9E0A9CC0C94A8953"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the process for selecting and entering into cooperative agreements or contracts with organizations under subsection (c);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64341DF5DF634F949AA199E4C22EA6B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>estimates the costs and staffing needs of implementing the Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H908462E3486E4F77A74BBBE66337724A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assesses the extent to which existing resources and programs of the Department of Defense can support the Program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAFC72BFB90C460AB60D5CCA71A30063"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes performance metrics the Secretary will use to evaluate the effectiveness of the Program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF493812734D442F9D3AB000ABB671E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>requires integration of the Program with research efforts of the military health system to improve health care quality, access and outcomes for members of the Armed Forces and their families.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8B3312BB1694660B059174BB9225EA7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which the Program is implemented, and annually for three years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report that includes, for the year preceding submission of the report—</text> <paragraph id="H3B79F2633D8E47B29D5004AEB590BC0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and demographic characteristics of covered beneficiaries served by the Program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C809F233E1245359D40DBE1879CD0F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of services provided and partnerships established under the Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA24BBBF7F7046198809985760346A3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of gaps in services or geographic coverage of the Program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBD90A0678AAB4F389C950F2DED696D95"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or administrative action to improve support for military families affected by limb loss or limb difference.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE9112E3C9BBD46B9B2F1AE7B7F7E3E2F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered beneficiary defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered beneficiary</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE58A2D22A9694D0CA351C494C7A59455"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual who has experienced limb loss or limb difference; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB3E884A2D954A4E9B3595A6C639D516"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H93C9EA0F5B954AF4B04444CCFFFFA995"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a dependent of a member or retired member of the Armed Forces; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6FB5B95CE84D42F19DB24DCB47ADD653"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise eligible for health care under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

