<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-PAT26498-89J-9F-7YV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4951 IS: Opening Programs to Organic Farms Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4951</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to submit to Congress a report on barriers to participation in Department of Agriculture programs faced by certified organic farms and farms that may be interested in transitioning to organic production, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Opening Programs to Organic Farms Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf811b6de43f24cca94f9e3f487297949"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on barriers to participation in Department of Agriculture programs faced by certified organic farms and farms interested in transitioning to organic production</header><subsection id="idd4e55defc7834ae49fa5df06c30aff14"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef9f9e519a694886a9eb0d9106a3c725"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida81383394a054496933eb474e0e18c60"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6bed0fdfe264ff9805e65af3b476672"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id949aada7d30346a08a7d51e58cc64f8c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certified organic farm</header><text>The term <term>certified organic farm</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2103 of the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6502">7 U.S.C. 6502</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84e3fd1474b7498bb81ddf0004578ed6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23cb67c42a2d4017b4abe599f195636f"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb7e901d5dcf84d48ad6bc8d7b4c76032"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, and make publicly available on the website of the Department, a report on barriers to participation in Department programs faced by certified organic farms and farms that may be interested in transitioning to organic production.</text></subsection><subsection id="id8b2be5f4163b4d8d9c95cf8bec412d88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (b) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="id9de155208d584149b93824eae9146ece"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program review</header><text>An assessment of barriers to participation in Department programs faced by certified organic farms and farms that may be interested in transitioning to organic production, including barriers in programs relating to conservation, credit, disaster assistance, risk management, export promotion, market development, technical assistance, rural development, data collection, procurement, and organic certification cost-share.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id64a13bb7a09745c0b052f7693d3311a5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participation data</header><text>To the extent practicable, data on application rates, approval rates, denial rates, funding levels, geographic distribution, farm size, production type, and reasons for denial or nonparticipation by certified organic farms and farms that may be interested in transitioning to organic production.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfe9d4e7819f94b5b9ba6a57f64139ad7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specific barriers</header><text>An assessment of barriers relating to program eligibility, payment rates, ranking criteria, application forms, recordkeeping requirements, crop insurance price elections, disaster assistance valuation, conservation practice standards, certification documentation, supply-chain infrastructure, organic literacy among Department staff, and the availability of organic-specific data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63f336beb8744eed88f9d49ea6a20dfc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Staff training and technical assistance</header><text>An assessment of the need for organic-specific training, guidance, and technical assistance for Department field staff, including staff of the Farm Service Agency, the Natural Resources Conservation Service, the Risk Management Agency, Rural Development, the Foreign Agricultural Service, and other relevant agencies and offices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id918700c6bfb54be0b208b5c9c64330db"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administrative actions</header><text>A description of administrative actions that the Secretary intends to take to remove barriers identified in the report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4906cfcd1c124a788120b44e4e605c4f"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Statutory recommendations</header><text>Any recommendations for statutory changes needed to remove barriers identified in the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc8f753c1ea7e4d62831e13126c0a4f7b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual updates</header><text>For each of the first 3 years following submission of the report required under subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, and make publicly available on the website of the Department, an annual update to that report that describes—</text><paragraph id="id64fb780f862948f49a3a6eff9764bd7b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any progress made to remove barriers identified in that report;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5daedb4f7ab4ead913b562993f36ca4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any administrative actions completed or underway;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d45f854a7024f33a6134efa3a2b7a47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any remaining barriers to participation in Department programs faced by certified organic farms and farms that may be interested in transitioning to organic production; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbd8181eeb96e45f08b6b3c0370b7f5d7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any additional recommendations for statutory changes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

