<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H901DD962940449999169CDE1F61D915D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9558 IH: 21st Century Federal Writers’ Project Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260630">June 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program in the National Endowment for the Arts to document the American experience.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0CEE00DAB4B34F4CAA8368DD6B927712" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7398DF6BBF3942CD9F46AB6547D0563E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Federal Writers’ Project Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H55AEEF69E72D496BA4373C9758A47669"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCF0AD2A5B38E482DAC441E71E3F1A90D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The observance and commemoration of the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States are of major significance to the national heritage.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB3A79BD91994965AF156DBFFFC28664"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States should inspire patriotism and national unity.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB33EC466D974A53BC9145BF8B2461A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Documenting the full breadth of the American experience, including the history, culture, customs, folklore, and daily life of communities across all States and regions, will foster mutual understanding and national unity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B826DC52C3B49BA9C3E9ACBEF054848"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Nearly a century ago, the Federal Writers’ Project employed up to 7,700 people to document the American experience, producing—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA55137A781594DDA8D10239E901EF915"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the American Guide Series, which included 48 States, 40 cities, 18 regions and territories, and countless counties; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5CD6C7D9DC2143858149F0D549AB1577"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 1,000 books and pamphlets covering local and regional histories, folklore collections, humor, and nature studies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H532FAFDD074147B8B9A3D84226666C8E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The commemoration of the 250th anniversary of the United States merits a new portrait of American life, capturing the history, culture, agriculture, industry, infrastructure, and communities that define this Nation, produced by a 21st-Century Federal Writers’ Project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8B2AA1BFC12460E9414D70171BF04D0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The National Endowment for the Arts is the appropriate Federal agency to administer a program supporting literary and documentary arts that capture the full diversity and vitality of the American experience, consistent with its mission under the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/951">20 U.S.C. 951 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C88A52AB80748F7982C139B6BE19BD7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>American feature writers, photographers, and documentary artists possess skills uniquely suited to preserving a living record of American life for future generations.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H4D487414932A48F19729A98089B92EEE"><enum>3.</enum><header>21st Century Federal Writers’ Project Grant Program</header> <subsection id="H0FF3E358D05F4B03A91D062C07E99CD2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chair of the National Endowment for the Arts (in this section referred to as the <quote>Chair</quote>), with the advice of the National Council of the Arts, shall establish a competitive grant program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to provide grants to eligible entities described in subsection (d) to document in writing and images the history, culture, customs, folklore, and lived experience of the American people.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDFAF7CDD19974FF3B3EF9DE050C6AF41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory panel</header> 
<paragraph id="HC0C5F3B6513A4E8B8B275DCA9485DE09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chairperson shall appoint an advisory panel comprising 5 members to assist in developing guidelines for the Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H64EE8C34A8F144FD919CE519B4B266D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The advisory panel shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07EB1B163A36413DB29C97546E8AA642"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member representing the literary arts, documentary audiovisual, or print journalism communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD5CD01E51544BFCA88D45089C320AFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Librarian of Congress, or the Librarian’s designee;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCBD50C614EDF4C93B6346D333C67780E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a member representing a State arts agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0AB69FA6B0E48509EB43CE64FA9AAD3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a member representing communities underserved by existing arts and literary programs, including rural and Tribal communities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B2887A2CEED40EEB6CB0BFFCF4F8BF5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a member with expertise in—</text> <clause id="H32807C7D132A46BCAAC93FFE90A74FFF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the original Federal Writers’ Project;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9A355046C87645B39560B272874340D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>involved with ongoing efforts to reproduce it; and</text></clause> <clause id="H629BD7797DA345D7910B1A1C50DF0DBF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with Federal experience with administering nationwide programs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HABCA670702E9402CA67E77187221C460"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the advisory panel is established, the panel shall submit to the Chairperson a report with recommended guidelines for the Program, including criteria for evaluating applications and ensuring that projects collectively cover the geographic and cultural breadth of the American experience.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24FFCA181263459DB46E0F6C37D432FF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The advisory panel shall terminate not later than 90 days after the submission of the report under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB416915FEAD146A79ACC85D2289E294F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant administration</header> 
<paragraph id="H92ECFF9CE18E495DB493E37A07370C41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant parameters</header><text>The Chairperson shall determine—</text> <subparagraph id="H2FEEEE81290B43FE834B1F8BC50F99A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the parameters and scope of the Program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFD6C43648C9946C0B67572C9D5098A42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount and duration of grant awards, except that no individual grant awarded for a fiscal year shall exceed an amount equal to 10 percent of the amounts appropriated under subsection (l) for such fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6E8548979824946B22FBAD2FDBC477E"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Limitation</header> <text>Notwithstanding section 5(e) of the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/954">20 U.S.C. 954(e)</external-xref>), the matching requirement shall not apply to grants made under this section.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BF32025B5804D3FA4B455856C987825"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Editorial and curatorial role</header><text>In administering the Program, the Chairperson shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0364C96532BB4BFD8BC54EF709B76391"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish, prior to the first solicitation of grant applications, an editorial framework for the Program that—</text> 
<clause id="H3C01625AD9C74F3588D0765BA8B67E41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identifies the thematic and subject-matter scope of the Program as a whole;</text></clause> <clause id="HB4174B02032F4B4E857711E21E497EE7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establishes standards for factual accuracy, editorial consistency, fair and balanced geographic and demographic coverage, and attribution of individual works; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9941B776E682412C80EBB5A3EF82CD29"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identifies the intended forms of publication and distribution for works produced under the Program, which includes not only books, but periodicals, digital media, audio recordings, documentary film, and other formats;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D461218897E4AE2B51377197A4F8FAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with a qualified organization to serve as the editor-in-chief and executive editor for the Program. Such organization shall be responsible for—</text> 
<clause id="HA199A2974CE349D7AADDB45627A29865"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing editorial guidance to grant recipients consistent with the editorial framework established under subparagraph (A);</text></clause> <clause id="HC97C064E9BB64B4FA48CFBE53F474E53"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reviewing and approving works prior to public release to ensure compliance with Program standards; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H80C94B91AB14423C9F85CD7439CF4EAE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reporting to the Chairperson on the progress and geographic and thematic coverage of the Program;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D308076513B4821B4FC970409BE8A24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinate with grant recipients to ensure that the subject matter of individual projects collectively covers the full range of topics and regions contemplated by the Program, avoiding duplication and gaps in geographic or thematic coverage;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC89CF7F66C634E97952F9386AD70AF0D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitate the production and publication of works developed under the Program, including by entering into agreements with publishers, distributors, or other entities to make such works available to the public in print and digital formats; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9EAE512DD5304CE28DB59E644B976885"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ensure that the Program as a whole replicates, to the greatest extent practicable, the scope, editorial standards, and public-facing mission of the original Federal Writers’ Project of the 1930s and 1940s.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D1DC471BA32489F9C76F135D43F610B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall—</text> <paragraph id="H810E59C1E51B4273A9713AD8683F7A56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit an application to the Chair at such time, in such form, and in such manner as the Chair may require; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF9CF3C353FE4869BDDE80F3A2B50F15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be one of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3529A067F27F474FA8AB51A33933C153"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A nonprofit, tax-exempt organization with experience in literary arts, documentary arts, journalism, oral history, or the collection and dissemination of cultural or educational content.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8D9E06353564E41AA05C025A1392884">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>The fiscally sponsored projects of organizations under subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F60053229264C63817AFB263CC97476"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>A State arts agency established pursuant to section 5(g) of the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/954">20 U.S.C. 954(g)</external-xref>), or a regional arts organization designated by the National Endowment for the Arts.</text>
          </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5FB6E4490FF3482EA14FFE523C9B169E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A State or territorial commission established by State legislation or executive order for the purpose of commemorating the 250th anniversary of the founding of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3C1B48BC71C44FE79392781E90DBF804"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use grant funds to engage individuals to produce written, photographic, audio, or other documentary works capturing the history, culture, customs, folklore, and lived experience of the American people, and may use grant funds for related administrative, training, and editorial activities directly supporting such work.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HECD51086799F4C5E90BD435C9D3C45B6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preference for certain individuals</header><text>In selecting individuals to receive funds, a eligible entity shall give preference to individuals with education or experience in—</text> <paragraph id="H4BD4C0E7AC984C5ABF38779289B5CA35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>literary arts, journalism, documentary arts, or oral history; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD45E1D0D8AE74EFC868E767F90C2D712"><enum>(2)</enum><text>occupations described in the Standard Occupational Classification for categories 25–0000 (Education, Training, and Library Occupations) and 27–0000 (Arts, Design, Entertainment, Sports, and Media Occupations).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3F64975EA8934A34BA5AA0211368BFA6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Geographic and thematic scope</header><text>In selecting the recipients and evaluating applications under this section for a grant, the Chair shall ensure that the projects funded under the Program, taken as a whole, collectively document communities and subjects from all regions of the United States, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEA537FE24F8D45CB925B34AEA1BD9FDF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>urban, suburban, and rural communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H447A5D9E43D94FE7874112C0FD199B1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Tribal communities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H318D76301BC7405C877D48CBB566E887"><enum>(3)</enum><text>each of the major geographic regions of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3F98CB800D34B2FA49301578E55A1A4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the full range of subjects that defined the original Federal Writers’ Project, including history, culture, customs, and folklore.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H69D3F462441A4806BDBE58A9571FDEF4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Repository, archive, and publication</header> 
<paragraph id="HA588540CFFEB488B8FF03DC4D9F7D38F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repository</header><text>The Chairperson shall establish a publicly accessible repository of works developed through the Program. Grant recipients shall submit completed works to the repository and each such work shall include attribution to the individual writer, photographer, or artist who created it.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E908F18618E431ABD32EACEDF0501BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Archive</header><text>The Chairperson shall transmit works received under paragraph (1) to the Librarian of Congress not later than 90 days after their receipt. The Librarian of Congress shall establish an archive program within the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress to collect and make publicly available, in both digital and print formats, the written and visual drafts and finished works produced under the Program, with attribution given to each work’s Creator.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBC3C77E8F094A43852A30D8CAACDBA9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Chairperson shall facilitate the publication and public distribution of written works produced under the Program. In carrying out this paragraph, the Chairperson may—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0D6C25F044C4C83964B64D51A68BE02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enter into agreements with commercial, nonprofit, or government publishers for the publication of books, anthologies, periodicals, or other print or digital works derived from the Program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78566493D4294FB08BF8085FE441A3FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use revenues derived from any such publication agreements, to the extent permitted by law, to support the ongoing activities of the Program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4C1249D10C047A2A6895BC7FD3E39A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that any published works include attribution to individual creators and to the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HECDF5D6EBCC343D7BA3E70DE3F287FA7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HE80D77ADA36E4D86BB7D52C426C11921"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant recipient reporting</header><text>The Chair shall develop reporting guidelines for grant recipients under this section to include, at a minimum, information regarding—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E49E8BC56184A388EFB78DFA9091843"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount of funds received and expended;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEA6734A0FFF9461FAD60EC13D7B8F98E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of individuals engaged and works completed under the grant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9AE7EBF5610F486C9CBA7A1716898B3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the geographic location and subject matter of works completed under the grant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC433D8F4DFD8483EB3C2E7CDC68CDC66"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of public requests to access or review completed works, where available;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF646AD0DE0D649DDAFE5D446FAA50632"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of copies of published works distributed or sold, where applicable, including through any agreements entered into under subsection (h)(3);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3B1B3D9453643A8A64C995E82B2707D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other data as the Chairperson considers important to assess Program efficacy; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1EA3276A476A437F92B91FFB09FFED42"><enum>(G)</enum><text>such other data as the Chairperson considers important to assess Program efficacy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02C16B47B88E45208B148B8E470B50C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting to Congress</header><text>Not less than once each year while the program under this section is in operation, the Chair shall submit a report to the Committees on Appropriations and Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Appropriations and Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate summarizing—</text> <subparagraph id="H03AE20ABA3294BF28719D5B5DEE2FAD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the data collected under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC0171A48394C462B8361F9ABEFC41E89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the geographic and thematic distribution of projects funded under the Program; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B06F98EC4C544C593FDAC1A29FFBF81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Chairperson’s assessment of Program efficacy and recommendations for improvement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0661B82B0E474EC29C4B698E80F9EF0E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair may reserve not more than 20 percent of the funds made available to carry out the Program for administrative costs of the National Endowment for the Arts.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2138EB565D7F4E48BB0AA0A9660F5545"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Coordination with other Federal agencies</header><text>The Chairperson may enter into interagency agreements with other Federal agencies to fund the Program and support the purposes, consistent with section 5(o) of the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/954">20 U.S.C. 954(o)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

