<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E4319F3C1924FFDB059960CBB602BDA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9399 IH: Juvenile Firearms Safety Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9399</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for criminal penalties for a person who provides fire arms to juveniles if such firearms are thereafter used for the commission of a criminal offense.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD9ED79549CDF4C3A8BCF115A95626E36" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6A95EDAE8092412C8E635D2CEE101E93" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Juvenile Firearms Safety Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HDDBAD239119B44B7940901734C57CBB5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unlawful acts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 922 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H467296B7525545A9A0DE4B059B86B0E3" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H08C1084A7B9F47128E906085FE03EF15"><enum>(aa)</enum> 
<paragraph id="HF7EB29A202704E4CB72DE7AF01147219" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It shall be unlawful for a person who is 18 years of age or older to—</text> <subparagraph id="H57E9BF8FD2254E85AEAEB0EAE6272F3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly provide a firearm, other than a handgun, to a juvenile (as such term is defined in subsection (x)(5)), knowing or having reasonable cause to believe that the juvenile intends to use such firearm for self-harm or in the commission of a crime; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H31412046E6FB45FE960D5650C549C29A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>knowingly store or keep any firearm that has moved in, or that has otherwise affected, interstate or foreign commerce on the premises of a residence, vehicle, or facility under the control of the person if—</text> <clause id="H74A94C5B4C114C0CA9247E1AE797A0C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the person knows, or reasonably should know, that a juvenile is likely to gain unauthorized access to the firearm; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6F2AAA5FB7D48A29B954B0B68DB1549"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a juvenile obtains the firearm and uses the firearm in the commission of a crime or causes injury or death to such juvenile, or any other individual.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF588C8252E3471987D2B357E97666E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the purposes of paragraph (1) a fact finder may consider other relevant factors, including if the person—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE0191EC6ED984A84921971DF5EF28584"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has received outreach about concerns about the juvenile’s mental health from the juvenile, the juvenile’s parent or guardian, other parents, school administration, law enforcement, medical professionals, or other adults;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBAEA4C3B87264F7EBBC26E251B1CF219"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has knowledge of prior acts of violence against others by the juvenile; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H787ADB9572E04723AC7D68AD003C61E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has knowledge of suicidality on the part of the juvenile, including previous acts of self harm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89A54C9A10D346D8865C4E62F91A57CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Paragraph (1)(B) does not apply to a person if the person—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF8191CFC26CC4B0FBA159E90B13DEFC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>keeps the firearm—</text> <clause id="H9E66DA13B5994F02B7640580A53B83BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>secure using a secure gun storage or safety device; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE81122443BA4BC48FA852C0F2011B1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a location which a reasonable person would believe to be secure; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA876142A299848D082CB3EF24239C1E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carries the firearm on his or her person or within such close proximity thereto that the person can readily retrieve and use the firearm as if the person carried the firearm on his or her person.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prevent a juvenile from engaging in lawful activities involving the use of a firearm, with the permission of the parent or guardian of the juvenile. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect any existing law related to consequences of a minor providing a firearm to another minor or to affect any existing law related to an adult’s responsibility for a crime committed by a third party minor who did not access the adult’s weapon directly.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HEDBBF9F750AB4C2C838C5D6720A07CBA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Penalties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 924(a) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H72C252146FBD4113BE17418F8823AA5A" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H62EEF3B1A17347FAA022764FCB23FDA2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Whoever knowingly violates subsection (aa) of section 922—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB4DDFE2C0E8E4D05AB89913241129041"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H794D6B63C6EF40FB883C5835B32ECBAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the firearm is used in the commission of a crime, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 2 years, or both;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC1FFCC369E624AA580D608E631B85B21"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the juvenile obtains the firearm pursuant to a violation of (aa)(1)(B), and the juvenile causes injury or death to such juvenile, or any other individual, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 5 years, or both; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BDE95A291264E2283C1BD50921C6B29"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if a person provides the juvenile with the firearm in violation of (aa)(1)(A), and the juvenile causes injury or death to such juvenile, or any other individual, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

