<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H7E5B8026F02D43DFB5CC50ED336FBCCF" resolution-type="house-resolution">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1218 IH: Recognizing the importance of the special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom and welcoming the visit of King Charles III to the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
<session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1218</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance of the special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom and welcoming the visit of King Charles III to the United States.</official-title>
</form>
<preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom remains a cornerstone of peace, security, and prosperity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks the 250th anniversary of the United States declaring independence from the United Kingdom;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States and the United Kingdom established diplomatic relations on June 1, 1785, during the meeting between future President John Adams and King George III;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, over the last 250 years, the partnership between the United States and the United Kingdom has grown to a special relationship based on mutual commitment to our shared democratic values and shared commitment to security and prosperity;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States and United Kingdom Armed Forces have served side by side in defense of our democracies and to bring peace in the world during World War I, World War II, and the Korean war;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United Kingdom provided military support to the United States in Iraq and Afghanistan following the attacks on September 11, 2001;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States and United Kingdom have continued to promote our mutual defense priorities through commitments to multilateral security arrangements based on shared responsibility and cooperation;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United Kingdom is a strong trading partner of the United States with bilateral trade exceeding $340,000,000,000 in 2024; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in April 2026, King Charles III will visit the United States at the invitation of the President and address a joint session of Congress: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble> <resolution-body id="H9D780E9D1CB64355B08C8664AC7D40D6"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H4CC0B713C8674FD79EEDDF0071E2055E"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="HD7C5671F82F54FE9A7D4A2A336EDE592"><enum>(1)</enum><text>welcomes King Charles III to the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D34E51F32CB4D2E831AEBF2FE66EB51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaffirms the strong and enduring special relationship between the United States and the United Kingdom, built on a shared history, common values, and a commitment to democracy and human rights;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9BAFAEE55AF74B8083599B20DA008F21"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports continued efforts to strengthen our shared defense through commitments to multilateral security arrangements grounded in shared responsibility and cooperation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31E090F9246444D6A206C3CDA287A028"><enum>(4)</enum><text>calls for continued cooperation between the Governments of the United States and the United Kingdom in promoting our shared democratic values, rule of law, and respect for internationally recognized human rights; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1B9A4680B53A4312A9C176E72F747365"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commits to strengthening and deepening diplomatic, economic, security, and people-to-people ties between the United States and the United Kingdom.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body> </resolution> 

