<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H75C99AC987E24C2285DB2788B8AEA7BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8730 IH: Connected Vehicle Security Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8730</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of connected vehicles and related software and hardware associated with foreign adversaries.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H7B956BF55E434F4281377C4919FD8E51" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H647171BD73D9446E8BBA889F53ABD77E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Connected Vehicle Security Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1779CCD3E942483FAF93F50D59D6C997"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8C946EB2E7AD47BEAB5529FB3E3A54DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States automotive industry is critical to the national economy, supporting millions of jobs, supply chains, and advanced manufacturing. The introduction of vehicles and components controlled by foreign adversaries threatens United States economic security, industrial competitiveness, and technological leadership.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCEA2A96CFC2247C786D55BBC7AF48F59"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China has rapidly expanded its automotive manufacturing capacity and is increasingly targeting export markets. Despite having the largest market in the world, the People's Republic of China exports nearly 8,000,000 vehicles annually, approximately twice the volume exported by any other country, demonstrating the scale at which vehicles and components controlled by a foreign adversary may enter global markets, including the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC884E9F926FF4EE3A1C9BCA5D5F9D93C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Connected vehicles incorporate advanced information and communications technologies that collect, process, and transmit vast amounts of sensitive data, including geolocation, operational, and personal information, and are capable of being remotely accessed and controlled.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7015C5D529C84FBE8452B6BC5403A0C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In Executive Order 13873 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to securing the information and communications technology and services supply chain), the President declared a national emergency with respect to the threat posed by foreign adversaries creating and exploiting vulnerabilities in information and communications technology and services.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87D213A38B9E462B9794D5AF98C5201A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The access, control, or influence of vehicle connectivity systems or automated driving systems by foreign adversaries creates substantial economic and national security risks to the United States, including risks of surveillance, espionage, cyber intrusion, and disruption of critical infrastructure. Such risks fall within the scope of the national emergency described in Executive Order 13873 and pose an unacceptable threat to the security and resilience of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0B92EBB99F5F4F38A992D70B53CB7C2E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HBEAD915FB6C34DFCA42C37E4728AA6C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Automated driving system</header><text>The term <term>automated driving system</term> means hardware and software that, collectively, are capable of performing the entire dynamic driving task for a connected vehicle on a sustained basis, regardless of whether it is limited to a specific operational design domain.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB754021892D04B399D0E1BFAEB7E09C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Connected vehicle</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39FAFE391AD848CD940E1DD505041C38"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by subparagraph (B), the term <term>connected vehicle</term> means a vehicle driven or drawn by mechanical power and manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways, that—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2957636FAC8440F2B0E0A99AE7076165"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrates onboard networked hardware with automotive software systems to communicate via dedicated short-range communication, cellular telecommunications connectivity, satellite communication, or other wireless spectrum connectivity with any other network or device; or</text></clause> <clause id="H20092B5008A74FAD9ACB3EEA26CCD3F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is designed, manufactured, or originally equipped to communicate via such methods, regardless of whether such capability is enabled, disabled, or removed at the time of importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction of the vehicle into interstate commerce in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B18CEC01A4741E68D1B141FAA92FAC5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>connected vehicle</term> does not include a vehicle operated only on a rail line.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91988C58BE3B4F4DA4F55527A864C96F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Connected vehicle hardware</header><text>The term <term>connected vehicle hardware</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H253FF9D5B070475CB7ED1366F35E8C7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a vehicle connectivity system; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7939204109F4961BA610D015ED2F3F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>vehicle connectivity system hardware.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2B0E81F888D453396AAB555E116C1AF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Country of origin</header><text>The term <term>country of origin</term>, with respect to an item, means the country—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85DC6CECFDC24A5AA56DD616AE96A26E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which the item is manufactured; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CAE85415B0143448DC92E340A59C48E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the government of which owns or controls, or has jurisdiction or direction over—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CAE512276F546FD9FF29DAF0F9AC0AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the entity manufacturing the item; or</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2837C33B9CF64612867BD5D2928B9F26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the entity supplying the item.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E0CA79444374B05872BE258BA1F1358"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered country</header><text>The term <term>covered country</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB13F496CF26C415283EFC5922CED2064"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Democratic People's Republic of North Korea;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE19881E15DF14F658E64F8DB926FBAD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the People's Republic of China;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19B6024EFAFC414BB7D84F91574FAF1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Russian Federation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F069ECB4D294C25A9AF4963B7B4E877"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC7B2B87805A460087F65405819D99AE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered software</header><text>The term <term>covered software</term>—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C39A4761BD0468F8CE43C8DAE7879EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the software-based components installed in or on a connected vehicle, or designed to be installed in or on a connected vehicle, including application, middleware, and system software, executed by the primary processing unit or units of an item that directly enables the function of a vehicle connectivity system or automated driving system at the vehicle level; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1E700ACF6BE04F54BF559F1B29C3F769"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any machine-learning model or other artificial intelligence component that directly enables decisionmaking or control of an automated driving system at the vehicle level.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H886D75B1DB434703B2352D4BA9A092A8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Electric vehicle</header><text>The term <term>electric vehicle</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the Electric and Hybrid Vehicle Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2502">15 U.S.C. 2502</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0F53EB6C46684B6FB9EDD79A7BBAA35F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Importation</header><text>The term <term>importation</term> has the meaning given the term <term>import</term> in section 1001 of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/951">21 U.S.C. 951</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17FB5912A0854DC2B8AB46DD77F1FBA9" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Resale</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87141493F9274F08B9CC125C66146EF1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>resale</term>, with respect to an item, means the transfer of ownership of the item by an individual or entity that acquired the item for the purpose of transfer in the ordinary course of business, and not for the use of or consumption by the individual or entity.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF6B5ADED2F0D4121B3455D8D93414C64" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>resale</term> does not include the transfer of a connected vehicle that was previously titled or registered to, and used by, a consumer or end-user or was acquired for bona fide use, lease, or operation by the individual or entity transferred the vehicle.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7689526DB40435988D6C8CFEFAB19DA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Safety equipment</header><text>The term <term>safety equipment</term>, with respect to a vehicle, means air bags, air bag inflators, and seatbelt systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EBFA6197FE6473596BAA1D3C59D40AF"><enum>(11)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC9DBF663C56C45A99A1A2F67563400AB" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Transaction</header><text>The term <term>transaction</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63D1A83AC48344B7AD55E7A7D7F4C037"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any acquisition, importation, transfer, installation, dealing in, or use of any item subject to a prohibition under section 4(a), including ongoing activities, such as managed services, data transmission, software updates, repairs, or the platforming or data hosting of applications for consumer download; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAEFCF5607E91469F84AD18E07A5CC503"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7EB3CD1236FE47408103BFE19128EB9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other transaction, the structure of which is designed or intended to evade or circumvent this Act; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D2ACFE8B2BE4D45B53A6C5D8EC2D416"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a class of transactions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF66E513270E4ABE8EA3A6CF5194FF81"><enum>(13)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Vehicle connectivity system</header><text>The term <term>vehicle connectivity system</term> means a vehicle connectivity system hardware or covered software item installed in or on a connected vehicle, or designed to be installed in or on a connected vehicle, that directly enables the function of transmission, receipt, conversion, or processing of radio frequency communications at a frequency over 450 megahertz.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12CB131E80024BC4BD0C8AA65C8C9DA3"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Vehicle connectivity system hardware</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>vehicle connectivity system hardware</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9A85880393CD432F89BE04C5CB346E10"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means software-enabled or programmable components that—</text> <clause id="H3E5F1F2217E14C968865DC47779935D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are installed in or on a connected vehicle or designed to be installed in or on a connected vehicle;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0384C32E131C42C9BFE546DD0DC06C80"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are directly connected to a vehicle connectivity system; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC70BCDC7FB6A4C409C45820EF8DFFD82"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>directly enable the function of a vehicle connectivity system or are part of an item that directly enables the function of a vehicle connectivity system; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8D8DC763E2C477E8305ECC9CA3BE72A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H097AC0AB214A4D2D809098CCAB9707D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">microcontrollers, microcomputers or modules, systems on a chip, networking or telematics units, cellular modem/modules, Wi-Fi microcontrollers or modules, Bluetooth microcontrollers or modules, satellite communication systems, other wireless communication microcontrollers or modules, external antennas, digital signal processors, and field-programmable gate arrays;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCFB6F9BF702F4EF38E0A41FE6F562FB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>electronic systems integrated into a battery that directly enable or control the monitoring, management, security, or external communication of battery performance or operation, including any transmitter or interface component that performs such functions; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3D490C80DB2444BF8B028CD54DBD9D71"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>safety equipment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5390B03BC25749D08E806BC9B140CEDA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on connected vehicles and other transactions that threaten economic or national security</header> 
<subsection id="H1115047365FB4E0FA548061280B2F03B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header> 
<paragraph id="HD8389D3D4A47440DA4C0FA960454EE2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Connected vehicles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after January 1, 2027, the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of a connected vehicle is prohibited if—</text> <subparagraph id="HAC858284FF6041B5AAC4941CCC33E373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the country of origin of the connected vehicle is a covered country or the connected vehicle is designed within a covered country, without regard to whether—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7F05DD8E5C044ACA34762BE9537CE0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the time of importation, sale, resale, or introduction, the vehicle is equipped with any covered software or connected vehicle hardware subject to a prohibition under paragraph (2) or (3); or</text></clause> <clause id="HDF43302A51F74D8FADAF0E503ABF613E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any such covered software or connected vehicle hardware—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFF86DFD6069411290F4C47D5BE00317"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is removed from the vehicle before importation, sale, resale, or introduction; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06E991B0ABC147768BA58D3689E78F49"><enum>(II)</enum><text>will be installed after importation, sale, resale, or introduction; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE6FDA671E0743139F3A2621218BAF8A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the manufacturer of the connected vehicle is a joint venture, subsidiary, or other entity in which more than 15 percent of the equity interest, voting interest, board representation, or other indicia of control, whether directly or indirectly, is owned or controlled by an entity, or combination of entities, organized under the laws of, or with its principal place of business in, a covered country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05B6AC3849184CCAB0CB9F46F98FFE6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered software</header><text>On and after January 1, 2027, the integration of covered software into a connected vehicle that is imported, manufactured, sold, resold, or introduced into interstate commerce into the United States is prohibited if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC22F840CC7E849459D7F651749AFA71F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the country of origin of the covered software is a covered country; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3739500EC560491FB2F0F2192BAA4406"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the developer of the software—</text> 
<clause id="HCE7514B83D6E4D6A9B75EE1C2A522A6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of, or has its principal place of business in, a covered country; or</text></clause> <clause id="H4388383E5CD24B13B2CE2C6DFDE408ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a joint venture, subsidiary, or other entity in which more than 25 percent of the equity interest, voting interest, board representation, or other indicia of control, whether directly or indirectly, is owned or controlled by an entity, or combination of entities, described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA75670EEC1F4AD3BDB6540FED03B00A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Connected vehicle hardware</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28A03AC420EC4C0EA870B5139ACE0F84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On and after January 1, 2030, the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of any connected vehicle hardware is prohibited if—</text> <clause id="HB76089591249495C896D10FE8DA458F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the country of origin of the hardware is a covered country; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0EF2C18A85714CA9A94C3BD4B6D7ADEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the manufacturer of the hardware—</text> <subclause id="H13BC157E0B1E48758CF10C1EE3D12AC4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of, or has its principal place of business in, a covered country; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H05D33C9AF3824FE582CAF8A5A16C03CD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is a joint venture, subsidiary, or other entity in which more than 25 percent of the equity interest, voting interest, board representation, or other indicia of control, whether directly or indirectly, is owned or controlled by an entity, or combination of entities, described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H27953C0CCC2341E28EA7353855FC8204"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Repair and warranty</header><text>The prohibition under subparagraph (A) shall not apply to connected vehicle hardware that is imported, manufactured, sold, resold, or introduced into interstate commerce in the United States for the purpose of repair or under warranty for a connected vehicle with a model year before model year 2030.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9558774C3CA9432D8D84837D4439570A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional items</header><text>Subject to an applicable ruling or advisory opinion issued under subsection (d), a prohibition under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) applies with respect to a connected vehicle, covered software, or connected vehicle hardware, as the case may be, that is renamed, rebranded, restructured, or altered to circumvent the prohibition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC54BC0A8FD574FF7B9F9D886E5046693"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibitions under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) shall not apply to the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of a connected vehicle, covered software, or connected vehicle hardware, as the case may be, for the sole purpose of testing and evaluation by an entity that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37B3F4CB920847138D0DAE9F66B81174"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of a State in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20703EC5DE444801B85728F19D8E8191"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not have its principal place of business in a covered country; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC739A692703346B4BE51FBBD5880CB44" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not 25 percent or more, whether directly or indirectly, owned or controlled by an entity, or combination of entities, organized under the laws of, or with its principal place of business in, a covered country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H81B7B6FF36FC4B57BE490F0DD0ADF108"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Related transactions</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D409576AD194ED6BA3A2F078938608E"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe regulations, pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to prohibit any specific transaction relating to connected vehicles, including the importation, sale, distribution, integration, or use of a connected vehicle, covered software, connected vehicle hardware, or any other item subject to a prohibition under subsection (a), that the Secretary determines poses an undue or unacceptable threat to the economic or national security of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68AE204254044DF29D3BA9CF8C727BF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>If the Secretary prohibits a transaction under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall deliver, by certified United States mail, to the parties to the transaction a notice of the prohibition that includes an identification, by name, of the specific item that the Secretary determines poses an undue or unacceptable threat to the economic or national security of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDF7EB26E9CDE451BBD7FEEE71041DB56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorizations</header> <paragraph id="H0D970325E134422390A6C47AA516FCE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Issuance</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF7CD374446804F328F4F189FA665F58F"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Energy, may issue a general or specific authorization for the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of an item that would otherwise be subject to the prohibitions under subsection (a) if—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EC3EF4D9C2E4D369DA7EA512248A24D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines, based on clear and convincing evidence and a written risk assessment, that the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction of the item does not pose, and is not reasonably likely to pose—</text> <subclause id="H2B0020C5A75046D9A80784AEE84E1406"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an undue risk of data exfiltration from, or remote manipulation or operation of, a connected vehicle;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8197579E13CB4E8884CF1BCAF63C8519"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a risk to critical infrastructure or the integrity of the industrial base of the United States; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1337E58E64814652B9F0A501F549619D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other risk to the national security of the United States;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H425D907E7F3A465B97DE8FDD8E28DC3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than 60 days before the authorization takes effect, the Secretary submits to Congress a detailed written notification, including the determination under clause (i) and underlying analysis, including the written risk assessment; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9259D5B889C449CFBCB3C754FEA4B6A3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>during the 60-day period described in clause (ii), there is not enacted into law a joint resolution of disapproval with respect to the authorization of the item.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCB41038D18364A39A1C06E99ABDBD2A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Continued validity and modification and revocation of authorizations</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE81296C40A44727B5AEDFCE253982E8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Continued validity of existing authorizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided by clauses (ii) and (iii), any general or specific authorization issued under subparagraph (A) or subpart D of part 791 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, before January 1, 2030, shall remain in effect until January 1, 2032, unless modified, suspended, or revoked under clause (ii).</text></clause> <clause id="H3FCF7CB0209646C59D256443700DA90B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Modification or revocation of general or specific authorizations</header><text>The Secretary may, at any time, modify, suspend, or revoke a general or specific authorization described in clause (i) if the Secretary—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA6F96CA4FCDF464688CB2261D544F5B9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines that the authorization no longer satisfies the requirements of subparagraph (A)(i); and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF80D83741184B48AE9173970CE8DDA8"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides the public with an opportunity to comment before modifying, suspending, or revoking the authorization.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H375988CFA72F4E179811CE171EDF3750"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of list of authorized items</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H311B765B5C6A4CFBB46CCB3015CCB444"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall publish, pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code, and maintain a list of the items the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of which is authorized under paragraph (1). The initial such list shall be published not later than January 1, 2027.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAB0A22066FC441C8985F46023C49A52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header> <clause id="H7AB4CCAEFAC446BC8711C96666A6534A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent possible, the Secretary shall include, in the list required by subparagraph (A), the manufacturer and product name for each item on the list.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCFD33A0954EF47E4B19B9638EF13F3C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other identifying characteristics</header><text>When it is not possible to include, in the list required by subparagraph (A), the manufacturer and product name for an item, the Secretary shall provide technical criteria sufficient to enable the automotive industry and importers to determine without undue difficulty whether the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of an item is authorized under paragraph (1). In carrying out this clause, the Secretary shall protect intellectual property to the extent practicable.</text></clause> <clause id="HC17104F070164B83AB34F56943ADFBEF"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Risk assessment</header><text>To the extent possible, the Secretary shall include, in the list required by subparagraph (A), a detailed explanation about why each item on the list does not pose an undue risk described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF928997C81B74D58B40A959B8EEC6A44"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requests for authorization</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall establish a procedure pursuant to which an importer, manufacturer, supplier, or seller or reseller may seek the authorization under paragraph (1) of the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of an item described in subsection (a) that would otherwise be subject to the prohibitions under that subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H21A92E2E305A413F9A06DA098DDC08E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulings and advisory opinions</header> <paragraph id="HD4CEDCB6989A46658C96E6378A287AAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2027, the Secretary shall establish a procedure pursuant to which an importer, manufacturer, or seller or reseller may seek a binding ruling or advisory opinion with respect to whether—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H19CB7E3A37C5488CB22822FB22E66242"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the importation, manufacture, sale, resale, or introduction into interstate commerce in the United States of an item is or is not prohibited under this section; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53435C403AA342C7B8631755DEDA6F77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a connected vehicle, covered software, or connected vehicle hardware has been renamed, rebranded, restructured, or altered to circumvent the prohibitions under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAF9E5529CFA4145AA8A031EE74ECD4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall issue a ruling or advisory opinion under paragraph (1) with respect to an item not later than 45 days after receiving an application supported by a reasonably clear description of the item.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73E505B2E4524AC2ACFADB6CE8504BF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publication</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB58BA6C09414B8A929723F2A38E36C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H432EA5CF9F9F4895A1FFA9F7D07D64FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish a list of the items for which the Secretary has issued rulings and advisory opinions under paragraph (1); and</text></clause> <clause id="H0E55E5E3B4654575908F27127F9FA6AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>update that list not less frequently than annually.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H371048D8A44043A6B92C0C73B363FBB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on publication of identifying information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not publish the name of, or other information that might reasonably identify, the party that requested the ruling or advisory opinion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF40C21050F104AB3AEE0D567A64B0E53"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Continued validity of existing rulings and opinions</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (5), a ruling or advisory opinion issued under this subsection or subpart D of part 791 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, before January 1, 2027, shall remain in effect.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H006B8F5A0B904E55A935E570995609E5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Modification or revocation</header><text>The Secretary may modify, suspend, or revoke any binding ruling or advisory opinion issued under paragraph (1) or subpart D of part 791 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, with respect to an item at any time if the Secretary determines that the circumstances that led to the ruling or opinion have changed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H45AB6714768D49229660A251CC49DB18"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Declaration of conformity</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process under which a person that imports, manufactures, sells, resells, or introduces into interstate commerce in the United States a connected vehicle or connected vehicle hardware is required to submit a declaration, to be known as a <quote>declaration of conformity</quote>, to the Secretary before importing, manufacturing, selling, reselling, or introducing the vehicle or hardware that certifies that the vehicle or hardware is not subject to a prohibition under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H85A18D9EE9114BE4A459C88058385486"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header> 
<paragraph id="H1812F0FD36B94A248DDBE2BBD9DBE312"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall assess a civil penalty for each transaction that is a violation of a prohibition under subsection (a) in an amount that is not less than the greater of—</text> <subparagraph id="HDEC84AA8E9264FFCB3015D270A3E7BCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$1,500,000; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25BF3CB45A804A8482745FED3F39FE26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>five times the value of the transaction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63E63E1FEAAE400EAB13BDCF848236CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuing violations</header><text>In the case of a violation that occurs on more than one day, each day on which the violation continues shall be treated as a separate violation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H33EB26D5C8CE401EAA711A17CB4B4BB2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Classified information</header><text>The Secretary may rely on classified information in carrying out this section, which may be submitted to a reviewing court ex parte and in camera.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF1C18ABB0D374253B0AAA11134FDDCB6" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Petitions for review</header><text>The filing in a court of a petition for review shall not stay the effectiveness of any action under this section unless ordered by the court.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H31ED81428C754C1CAB24A866B0453085"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use of existing advisory bodies; interagency coordination</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC289DED8021B4BB5BDBD57CB7B841A71"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Use of existing advisory bodies</header> 
<paragraph id="HADB16095947242B4A80A90CA1817C033"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary may consult, as appropriate, with existing advisory committees of the Department of Transportation and other relevant Federal agencies, including the Advisory Committee on Automation in Transportation, on matters relating to connected vehicles and associated national security risks.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CD0F347B08F4178B829C725F39057C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of consultation</header><text>Consultation under paragraph (1) may include consideration of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H314A671467A74154BB43E036009F99EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>risks relating to data security, cybersecurity, and supply chain integrity associated with connected vehicles;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H429B1BB2B4DC4BAE80594C1BC1BF09B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effectiveness of authorities and regulations issued under this Act;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEA602DF81F54891924498331ED0FBE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>emerging technologies and threat vectors relevant to connected vehicle ecosystems; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB5513610EAC429D8217911383D1A763"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations made to the Secretary with respect to regulatory, enforcement, and policy measures to mitigate risks described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9AD5F431D3D746519886444B2439C53F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary may consult and coordinate, as appropriate, with the Federal Communications Commission and other relevant Federal agencies to ensure alignment with respect to the scope, timeline, and implementation of any prohibitions or restrictions issued under this Act, including to avoid duplicative, inconsistent, or conflicting regulatory requirements.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H7A4CA06FC28C4A3C8DBEE2A006A8D228"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report—</text> 
<paragraph id="H53B8B16742AA4C47903F92F05882F11C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describing activities carried out to enforce the prohibitions under section 4, including enforcement actions taken and resources utilized;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5288010534934C0FA1EF132DBD1E36F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing a detailed accounting of items covered by such prohibitions during the 1-year period preceding submission of the report;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FF1A484F959481E90AC75F52D5B244F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>explaining any exclusions, exemptions, or determinations made by the Secretary, including the rationale and criteria applied;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC38C79F8D63945ADA6C763273F41B202"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assessing the effectiveness of such prohibitions in decreasing the threats to the economic and national security of the United States posed by connected vehicles;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4D087E1E8624A338FC7D7351089F438"><enum>(5)</enum><text>including metrics on enforcement, compliance rates, violations identified, penalties assessed, and any identified gaps or challenges; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF8D6D8771394495950C86CACF0A2F49"><enum>(6)</enum><text>making recommendations with respect to further decreasing such threats.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H49256B571CBC41949B84D5A2553CF6A9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability; regulatory continuity</header> 
<subsection id="HE43A07F06E124B47903E9EA4641770C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be invalid, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the remaining provisions to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9CD93769864E4596AD00F44C47C62175" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restoration of prior regulations</header><text>If a court of competent jurisdiction enters a final judgment holding invalid or unenforceable a provision of this Act and supersedes regulations prescribed to carry out section 4, the Secretary may, notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, reissue or reinstate, in whole or in part, any similar regulations that were in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H416BA9C0E3F04C29B42427F6A2DCACC2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Interaction with regulations</header> 
<subsection id="H9B851A3A14014617B8ED42F296E6ED83"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit, limit, or otherwise affect the authority of the Secretary of Commerce to implement or administer subpart D of part 791 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, as added by the final rule of the Bureau of Industry and Security entitled <quote>Securing the Information and Communications Technology and Services Supply Chain: Connected Vehicles</quote> (90 Fed. Reg. 5360).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H13FFB3D7DAE54AAEAC2B9CEDAE0BE85F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Delayed implementation for software and hardware not covered by regulations</header><text>In the case of covered software and connected vehicle hardware that is subject to a prohibition under paragraph (2) or (3) of section 4(a) and is not subject to subpart D of part 791 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall implement the prohibition under section 4(a) after January 1, 2030, and before January 1, 2032.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAD62F2C808634ACDB593255D90A0D5DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Treatment of prior exclusions</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A9FA3D3993D474E870CA35BA522E8B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), any exclusion or exception to a prohibition under subpart D of part 791 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall remain valid and shall apply to the prohibitions under section 4(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DE8ED2F898D459C9E4E2746872C802B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2030, the Secretary shall conduct a rulemaking, pursuant to section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to determine whether exclusions or exceptions described in paragraph (1) should be continued, modified, or terminated for the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


