<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2BF3A86108254F3B9010474B3369FD58" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9492 IH: Cybersecurity Logging Enforcement and Accountability Reporting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9492</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to produce a report that identifies gaps in resources, guidance, and policies to satisfy all event logging requirements for cybersecurity incidents at the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2E89D2761FAB49E9BE1157E68985C1B5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H89B92AA39687412BA9B55A4270072A74" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cybersecurity Logging Enforcement and Accountability Reporting Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> 
<section id="H558877848123401795E7ACE6E0E49F7B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on gaps in resources, guidance, and policies on event logging of cybersecurity incidents at the Department of Homeland Security</header> 
<subsection id="HCA708D33F76846D4BC986F2A4EE3514B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H58DCA4B3C1914EA9842BFE0277F2C19E" commented="no">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
          <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Department’s efforts to satisfy all requirements under Executive Order 14028, the Office of Management and Budget Memorandum (OMB) M–26–14, and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) Special Publication 800–53 for event logging of cybersecurity incidents.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A3248EDE8EF4EC4A06D1EB74CAB33A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H628FD0B749F94EABBD6CC9A73E13EEEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the Department of Homeland Security’s current implementation status of the requirements for event logging of cybersecurity incidents.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H228E1FD36CEB430394466899EC51D600"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An identification of any gaps in guidance that prevent the Department from satisfying such requirements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1C88B12839143A0B2F1B17603D5CBEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An identification of any policies that prevent the Department from satisfying such requirements.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF51BC2EA98384CF2907244EFBC884727"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An identification of any gaps in resources that prevent the Department from satisfying such requirements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H081C497C39AA459B81B1AFF44DB98A02"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recommendations for policies, guidance, or resources, as the case may be, that would support the Department in satisfying such requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD349D5E2C57F40E8A7DF758E1A8D41B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, and shall include an unclassified executive summary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE481FF520284FD09E1238C386357782"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The unclassified executive summary of the report required under paragraph (1) shall be published on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF971291B11B4C6BA2926E6DC001851C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the submission of the report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the findings, conclusions, and recommendations contained in such report.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0CED8169EF7C45F198245183E7A0F483"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H69C861BFB3684D49A0094EBF78C2628D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H384AD025050A41998B1C99CF3F0899D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

