<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7353E0207302490AAA33FB51CBF6A1CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6146 IH: Supporting Tours Across Years Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6146</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on options to reduce the frequency of permanent changes of station of members of the Armed Forces and the sea-shore rotations of such members, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0E2DCDC4C5E2483281DE8DABB0F07E56" style="OLC"><section id="HA29233B06B6541D5BAF4D85B9B8065F6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Tours Across Years Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STAY Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6AC15D4783784E1F9171339EC2C8C9DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on reducing frequency of permanent changes of station and naval vessel to onshore rotations</header><subsection id="H9D3B4138B9D44E76882ECAE892002E56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2026, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on options to reduce the frequency of permanent changes of station of members of the Armed Forces and the rotations of such members between assignments to naval vessels and onshore assignments (commonly referred to as <quote>sea-shore rotations</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE07D8345861453B875A1BC5606A4A93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HD2D64F214F7C4BC4B7C424485E54AFE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the costs associated with the permanent changes of station and rotations specified in subsection (a), disaggregated by military department and occupational specialty, over the five fiscal years preceding the date of the report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H024CF0D5E7904541928D9D5866647F09"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the potential cost savings of the Department of Defense to be realized through a reduction in the frequency of such permanent changes of station and rotations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8A74B5B2EB84CE4A3C0FD75D0730F18"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the effects of a reduction in such frequency on retention of members of the Armed Forces, employment for the spouses of such members, and education of the children of such members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H628070C29F7F451689FD7A7339DDED5D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of billets, duty stations, and communities with respect to which extended tour lengths or rotation adjustments would be operationally feasible while sustaining mission readiness and career progression requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2057968E5F9944739CB1EDF2450E0DBF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recommendations for any legislative or policy changes necessary to conduct a pilot program for, or otherwise implement, extensions to tour lengths or rotation adjustments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7AA4E62977B54BE9ACEE92A6571D59E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

