<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A1D1B55A53941F0B83715B6353B5E5C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5932 IH: Claims Legitimacy and Evaluation Accountability Nationwide for VA Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5932</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance employee accountability, prevent fraud, strengthen whistleblower protections, and modernize disability rating processes in the Department of Veterans Affairs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9732F624B7614307B78F0F6FF1DB51D8" style="OLC"><section id="H63D57B28782045D9B4FFDE6614B926BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Claims Legitimacy and Evaluation Accountability Nationwide for VA Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAN VA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0390C8F35BB946AD818F690BA41D1A0C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited procedures for employee accountability actions</header><subsection id="H8A356E6A4C6A4DE2B50466776BE32CE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Modification of disciplinary procedures for department of veterans affairs employees</header><text>Section 714 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H01F67FABFF9543B680E8D62B1531B751"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HAA93149AB5764CFD9AC61BE70B9C6960"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>by substantial evidence</quote> after <quote>the Secretary determines</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84DDDDB2D9D0421AAB6B4563AE2448A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3EB1752D539B488AA33769FCFA582E7E"><paragraph id="H337C681D3C98413997603BFD899AE504" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H61337D0ED1B644E58709D402D11C4F97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>When making an initial decision under this subsection with respect to determining whether a covered individual should be removed, demoted, or suspended, the deciding employee of the Department shall exclusively apply the following factors:</text><clause id="HE7C20731EDE649AEB8B555D1E1AC1219" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The nature and seriousness of the offense, and its relation to the covered individual’s duties, position, and responsibilities, including whether the offense was intentional or technical or inadvertent, or was committed maliciously or for gain, or was frequently repeated.</text></clause><clause id="H9DD12EB274B14630A756E5444B4B1F90" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The covered individual’s job level and type of employment, including supervisory or fiduciary role, and prominence of the position.</text></clause><clause id="H227357DB59C244B29E8D3BB8FB3DBAB9" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The covered individual’s past disciplinary record.</text></clause><clause id="H167799EB78D64326A3A9AD38F1FFC811" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The covered individual’s past work record, including length of service, performance on the job, ability to get along with fellow workers, and dependability.</text></clause><clause id="H483DE83A6BCD4F3391BB1F8EDF19525D" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Mitigating circumstances surrounding the offense such as unusual job tensions, personality problems, mental impairment, harassment, or bad faith, malice, or provocation on the part of others involved in the matter.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AD3861E204E4152A3DA57402CE0FF27" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall review the initial decision and uphold such decision if it is supported by substantial evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE83E791843044FB6A4650239F132B40E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HAD7CFB629A854D35A19A737C0C9F4677"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1)(D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F5EF54401F74369B91AD82D9C17B3F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, and the Secretary may carry out such a removal, demotion, or suspension without first placing a covered individual on a performance improvement plan</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB3F7858573F44C2A33943B1290A558F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="H7136DA1EF29446CAA75148AEE82CC51D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HA0B55B5D1F7C4860823F0D907C8F5DBB" style="USC"><subparagraph id="H667D07C41D724BDEB7DCB46611C64359" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, the administrative judge may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84C70F2A8DF84C1E9354C01AE99A22E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idEB57EE8162B64AABB1D1D31620D9E62E"><subparagraph id="H5468630223664D738724D576115A5FD4" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, the Merit Systems Protection Board may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD5D54E9E32F4BB4863E0D982DF1B9AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id680B3F2F0C664865BD8881546B86E941"><subparagraph id="H9E6F60482309472D8149E9F4B01C7B02" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Except to the extent that an appeal under this subsection presents a constitutional issue, such Court may not review a challenge to the penalty imposed against the covered individual or mitigate such penalty.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CAC30EEDA4E4C2DA81C84BCB667E1A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (10); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF6F785EE52F4AED9B8714C75253ED4F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (j).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H555FCEFA282F4C65AC1852D229FA1A23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing of disciplinary actions</header><text>Section 714 of title 38, United States Code, is further amended by inserting after subsection (a) (as amended by subsection (a) of this section) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H661FFE3497B6400FA0F21443E11C887B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H480CF9F17FCE4388808DFDC17A8DF4C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><paragraph id="H5D5028B81E4F4874A2295B2E07F99E19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The aggregate period for notice, response, and final decision by the Secretary of an action under this section may not exceed 15 business days.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55ECB2AB048049EEAEE6D44AE1676DC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The period for the response of a covered individual to a notice under subsection (a)(2)(A) shall be 7 business days.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AECD7521EE34F39930AAF3459170842"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The final decision by the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(B) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H36A59D6B68474146AD987D546A703BFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be issued not later than 15 business days after notice is provided under subsection (a)(2)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7826EB4D0663482C8B2B3FB5EB1973DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be in writing and shall include the specific reasons for the decision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HBFA4533847CA43928E0DAAFC1A1D3284"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhanced penalties for VA employee fraud and misconduct; whistleblower protections and incentives</header><subsection id="HE141FF9A890640A2B7E7A655E1D50EF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enhanced penalties for fraud and misconduct</header><paragraph id="H0B7697A39A8546C4BE38816ED6339865"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public money, property, or records</header><text>Section 641 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>If the offense under this section is committed by an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs, acting in an official capacity or using access to veterans’ records or benefits systems, the term of imprisonment shall be not more than 15 years, and any fine imposed shall be not more than $500,000. The court shall order mandatory restitution to the Department of Veterans Affairs or the United States Treasury for any loss sustained.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21D2A0B4BC16437C90A45FB23E1C665A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>False statements</header><text>Section 1001 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>If the offense involves the falsification or concealment of material facts related to a claim for veterans’ benefits or the performance of duties by a Department of Veterans Affairs employee, the term of imprisonment shall be not more than 10 years, and any fine imposed shall be not more than $250,000.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H582F66EE90E24B9F827CA00320C57B6A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Bribery of public officials and witnesses</header><text>Section 201 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>If the public official is employed by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and the bribe or gratuity relates to the processing or awarding of veterans’ benefits or contracts, the maximum fine shall be twice the amount of the bribe or thing of value received, and the term of imprisonment shall be not more than 20 years.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE948486F0F6248868D4C5624E7F11EF5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>False statements or fraud to obtain Federal employees’ compensation</header><text>Section 1920 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>If a person convicted under this section is an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the fraudulent conduct relates to veterans’ disability, compensation, or employment benefits, such person shall be fined not more than $250,000, imprisoned not more than 10 years, and shall forfeit any Federal pension or annuity benefits pursuant to section 8312 of title 5.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC38B3DAE27F458E9D7D92DE32E3C510"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Forfeiture of Federal pension and annuity benefits</header><text>Section 8312 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H124B9DB0509F45D1B8F4CCCADB9FB2E9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA5818D4143254BCA90864E8F55D16121"><enum>(e)</enum><text>An individual convicted of an offense under section 641, 1001, 201, or 1920 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by the Claims Legitimacy and Evaluation Accountability Nationwide for VA Act, if such individual is an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the offense relates to their duties, shall forfeit any entitlement to annuity or retired pay under this chapter or chapter 84 of this title.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CBE1C7B777947AF97B3B8649B8F4278"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Whistleblower protections and incentives</header><paragraph id="H3D32A4C9DFD74FFC9ABF33770B39A6CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Expedited retaliation investigations</header><text>Section 2303 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HB0DB3097007143AFA7BCBF48ED8CB9B9" style="USC"><subsection id="H3747D703500F40CD9EB45A0AE9F7BB2F"><enum>(e)</enum><text>In the case of a retaliation claim involving an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Office of Accountability and Whistleblower Protection shall complete investigations within 60 days of filing. The Office shall provide written justification to Congress for any delay beyond 60 days and shall ensure interim protections against reassignment or adverse personnel actions while claims are pending.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DC278E7F6874070A932D968E533AB40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transparency and oversight of settlements</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall report annually to the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives on the number of whistleblower retaliation claims filed, investigated, and settled; the total settlement amounts; and whether settlement obligations were fulfilled. The Secretary shall publish an anonymized summary of this report on the Department’s website.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6C9744FF4D54DF9802AC775DFD98E40"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incentive awards for valid disclosures</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs is authorized to provide monetary awards up to $10,000 for substantiated internal disclosures that prevent or uncover significant fraud, waste, or abuse valued over $100,000. Such awards shall be funded from recovered amounts when practicable and shall not be considered compensation for pension or benefit purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAEFFBA8D2C64E6F898EA78894F44027"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Independent review and reporting</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall review the implementation of the provisions of this subsection within 2 years of the date of enactment of this Act and submit a report to Congress on the timeliness of investigations, settlement compliance, and effectiveness of incentive provisions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H065937E18A4542B9ACB9239B629D6079"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review of the VA disability rating schedule</header><subsection id="HDC7451CF1C2A4CA59AAABB2EFA7B5606"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comprehensive review</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a comprehensive review of the Department of Veterans Affairs schedule for rating disabilities to—</text><paragraph id="HE077AC7DCA9E4BA8825CA4F7DFD9A9B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify vulnerabilities to fraudulent, exaggerated, or duplicative claims;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF432CC69EC5046689F082E23F085BC23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess whether existing rating criteria accurately reflect current medical standards and functional impairment measures; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0554FE592AFA429685FA98DDB84524D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommend updates to ensure consistency, integrity, and fairness in disability determinations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8C27F3731D447CFA53A997E836D15DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Integration of artificial intelligence and data analytics tools</header><paragraph id="H3D8368043EFB4DEE857D5DD3092FDD7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Comptroller General of the United States, develop and implement a program utilizing data analytics and artificial intelligence systems to proactively identify irregularities or high-risk indicators within disability claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33C1497908EC4596A8F5193EA79C8655"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such systems shall be modeled, to the extent practicable, after the Waste, Fraud, and Abuse Identification and Reporting system utilized by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H007992EE705C4380BA91BD0BD32AF057"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All findings generated through automated or algorithmic processes shall be subject to human review and validation before any administrative or disciplinary action may be taken.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EF05989895A42D19A50320FAA4AA66C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the use of such systems respects all due process protections and privacy safeguards afforded to claimants under Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EA1D762BCD3499DB9AC0BB238A304FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination and oversight</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Office of Inspector General and the Government Accountability Office to—</text><paragraph id="H90F8206ABE8A4A288AAE0ECD0EA2291A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of the tools described in subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H956495514E25445F8D16D0D9C3FD6ECB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify risks of over-flagging or under-detection of improper claims; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6726D83291FB4674A4493098412D2F73"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommend best practices to ensure balanced oversight and prevention of misuse.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEEB73647C634FAAAB70011522A7A3B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later that 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs and Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report detailing—</text><paragraph id="HE7425554B9144D918C4AEBE7885C7F73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the review conducted under subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FC726579F9D45D9AABF9C248BD7628B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>vulnerabilities identified and corrective measures proposed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD08955859CB40BAACBED6282A575120"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the status of data analytics and artificial intelligence integration under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2DF5E4D42E40F0B51719329BFA2A12"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for further modernization of the disability rating process.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4DDC492DAD584EE9BE144B9BF119F477"><enum>5.</enum><header>Mandatory ethics and fraud prevention training</header><subsection id="HA59160D93DA64402BFC352FA0AFEBD41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for annual training</header><text>Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/77">chapter 77</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H194A135DCC054235A072B5672F1CD991" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H5450435A7DEB41C28E0D2C54182BA9F6"><enum>7735.</enum><header>Mandatory ethics and fraud prevention training</header><subsection id="HE0B1C7B8033D400EB85FBC8BDF1E2A05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall require all employees of the Department to complete annual training on ethics, fraud prevention, and compliance with applicable laws and regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0DE55A0D4784DE5B4E08FA878946743"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department shall oversee compliance with the training requirement under subsection (a) and submit an annual report to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives on training completion rates and any identified deficiencies.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H240FA3996F234790B63FD418AB4A6EB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/77">chapter 77</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7734">section 7734</external-xref> the following new item: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H4C11D501F42841DFA711AE3E1BE1479E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">7735. Mandatory ethics and fraud prevention training.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H980CC2B99FB54EEDB69E4FF8B95C3DC8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Review of the VA disability rating schedule</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FF0484EBEA74513A858C32F6D2CBF0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Comprehensive review</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall conduct a comprehensive review of the Department of Veterans Affairs Schedule for Rating Disabilities to—</text><paragraph id="HE565B4099DA847E38A68935832CAFED4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify vulnerabilities to fraudulent, exaggerated, or duplicative claims; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE565B4099DA847E38A68935832CAFED1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess whether existing rating criteria accurately reflect current medical standards and functional impairment measures; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE565B4099DA847E38A68935832CAFED0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommend updates to ensure consistency, integrity, and fairness in disability determinations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7BDDD5BC43140FDA135925BB4149A83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Integration of artificial intelligence and data analytics tools</header><paragraph id="H6BD77CE23108454CAC65008F3760797C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Comptroller General of the United States, develop and implement a program utilizing data analytics and artificial intelligence systems to proactively identify irregularities or high-risk indicators within disability claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99101022F7B447AA8C11A1FA07A123A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such systems shall be modeled, to the extent practicable, after the Waste, Fraud, and Abuse Identification and Reporting system utilized by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99101022F7B447AA8C11A1FA07A123A8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All findings generated through automated or algorithmic processes shall be subject to human review and validation before any administrative or disciplinary action may be taken.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99101022F7B447AA8C11A1FA07A123A7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the use of such systems respects all due process protections and privacy safeguards afforded to claimants under Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF9010AF302D4C43A9D3D5F05C8B3223"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination and oversight</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Office of Inspector General and the Government Accountability Office to—</text><paragraph id="H93EFD9886F4944CFA371EF9289F73D4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of the tools described in subsection (b); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93EFD9886F4944CFA371EF9289F73D4F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify risks of over-flagging or under-detection of improper claims; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93EFD9886F4944CFA371EF9289F73D4G"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommend best practices to ensure balanced oversight and prevention of misuse.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BB488D91320408CA983DE661C6104D4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs and Oversight and Accountability of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report detailing—</text><paragraph id="H5FD5BF3C8BB34C77B1599EA36D0CC9B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the review conducted under subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD5BF3C8BB34C77B1599EA36D0CC9B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>vulnerabilities identified and corrective measures proposed; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD5BF3C8BB34C77B1599EA36D0CC9B2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the status of data analytics and artificial intelligence integration under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD5BF3C8BB34C77B1599EA36D0CC9B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for further modernization of the disability rating process.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

