<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE589D3DDE1AF40CB98200636AFA14508" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9011 IH: Vacancy to Value Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9011</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260522">May 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Administrator of the General Services Administration, in coordination with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, to establish a pilot program and a grant program administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development to facilitate the sale or transfer of underutilized Federal property to eligible entities for economic redevelopment, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H87AC76654BC64A04AB67F99CD096E55F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H988AEA32DBAE406CA9BB9F0DEF3AD540" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vacancy to Value Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H83CDD95BA87B498287292108666C6262" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for redevelopment of underutilized Federal property</header> <subsection id="H6EA5BCCEC92D456BB4925E176013FE52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the General Services Administration shall establish and implement a pilot program to facilitate the sale or transfer of underutilized Federal properties to entities and individuals for an eligible purpose described in subsection (b) on a pilot basis.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3B3C44936C2046908F9AA12A93D0B589"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible purpose for a property sold or transferred under this section shall only be for redevelopment or economic development purposes that benefit the surrounding community, including affordable housing, job creation, economic growth, and community facilities such as clinics, childcare centers, and schools.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H68564CB995F84834B4E40CBCF79FC794"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amount of sale</header><text>A sale or transfer under this section may be for an amount that is less than fair market value of the property being sold or transferred.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8A731CA9FEE3419890C65CEFCBDE1F03"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Development requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity acquiring property under this section shall submit a redevelopment plan including the specified use under subsection (b) and begin redevelopment not later than 5 years after acquisition.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2059E432761C414E97871E43293BE33D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Recapture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an entity fails to meet the requirements under subsection (d), the Administrator may require the return of the property or impose other appropriate remedies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H78484CB46398441782A464EDDCA4F67A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program under this section, the Administrator shall give priority consideration to community-based nonprofit organizations and public entities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H47F6A7B1F7AC47DEABF0FA0E6A62285A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The pilot program established under subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4033D44E1D494561B4DE7612338360B5"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definition of underutilized Federal property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>underutilized Federal property</quote> means any real property owned or controlled by the Federal Government that—</text> <paragraph id="H2CB280B6D6DC40B1B6EF1D01A63BCF0C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is not fully occupied or utilized for the purposes of the Federal agency with jurisdiction over the property; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F7568FCE30C4A86BE01DDFCCDCF3CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has been determined by the Administrator to be excess to the needs of the Federal Government, including property that is vacant, obsolete, or economically inefficient to maintain.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H15FE80C5AE4E4706914B6D6087E081D5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study and report</header> <subsection id="H0EE6434BA2904483933ED45358E82B30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the General Services Administration shall conduct a study on the outcomes of the program under section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H053F1C8060664DF89BF11C793B322744"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the termination of the pilot program under section 2(g), the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the program containing the results of the study under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H5E448E9FB00C42DE936C2F08E4BB5FD6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal redevelopment grant program</header> <subsection id="H4E17AEBAD43B4E15B53006F73F546311"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish a Federal Redevelopment Grant Program to provide competitive grants to eligible entities acquiring property under section 2 for redevelopment and community revitalization purposes.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7469BD0535AF45E28DB46B76425B8E10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>Entities eligible to receive grants under this section shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HDD63CAFED7C542E4A2B7CBA6E500961D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>units of State or local government;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38BC7792EF424BBC8C871D26CA4D2483"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Tribal governments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C6163D43BCB4A88A1BCCE4E54E017AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>public housing agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0747DA71341044CD8639B78598C637D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>community land trusts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA69AF7EFB7A54175A99533C60CBD1B17"><enum>(5)</enum><text>community development corporations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4CDF6CF9213E455DB43737EC175A0C56"><enum>(6)</enum><text>nonprofit organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17FEBAD97780428D957ECA56604782C3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>partnerships between public entities and nonprofit organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H93EF3A48A799436DAB3DC7195D2F4446"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>Grant funds awarded under this section may be used for—</text> <paragraph id="H1510226E2CD54F6CB5962125F3972B29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>predevelopment and planning activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE2EDEA0347B401FA8340F430FA1ADC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>environmental remediation and site preparation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H502D6A90E74A4C8A8EFFDD1A668B2CBA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>demolition, rehabilitation, or construction costs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D269132B5C145ADB4F2A0B045B0B6EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>infrastructure improvements;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC987E99E43D84B67AD1275D2B9D8AFBF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>development of affordable housing;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE259AE9D523487AAE5C47F617A61406"><enum>(6)</enum><text>development of community facilities, including health clinics, childcare centers, schools, workforce development centers, and community centers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2ADBD68E62134E2C90772DFA2BD6A54E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>other activities determined appropriate by the Administrator to carry out the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5E6A2787BA04A41AF2957F8FE731A7F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize projects that—</text> <paragraph id="HC1326088B1074F938D53D3223E4AEA9A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create or preserve permanently affordable housing;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7210424466B14B4CB8819F6A6417A866">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>benefit low-income or historically underserved communities; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAF016AE1F074C2C99CAFD77241E1C9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are proposed by community-based nonprofit organizations or public entities;</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9125D807E24450396CD60291F354EF8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community benefit requirement</header><text>As a condition of receiving grant funds under this section, an eligible entity shall demonstrate that the proposed redevelopment project will provide a substantial public benefit to the surrounding community.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFBC08D95CC634652B7B55D1A5B392D1B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Recipients of grants under this section shall submit annual reports to the Secretary describing the use of funds, redevelopment progress, community impact, and compliance with the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA492526833C746C9965E0E113E3EADC1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

