<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL26119-7FT-0K-D1N"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3875 IS: Responsible Firearms Marketing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3875</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Federal Trade Commission to conduct a study and submit to Congress a report on unfair or deceptive acts or practices that may be prevalent in the advertising or marketing of firearms and to issue regulations to prohibit unfair or deceptive acts or practices related to the advertising or marketing of firearms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Responsible Firearms Marketing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd80c9bae1a1f42b4af478f6cb844ba9d"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices related to the advertising or marketing of firearms</header><subsection id="id6f8a4bded35e44558cb345fd7e6d77fd"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and report by the Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph id="id07e0cdb4292645df9f41d891e3a84802"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><subparagraph id="ida993ed5a63fc4131b365595db3be89b1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall conduct a study, using the Commission’s authority under section 6(b) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/46">15 U.S.C. 46(b)</external-xref>), regarding the advertising or marketing of firearms. Such study shall identify potentially unfair or deceptive acts or practices that may be prevalent in such advertising or marketing, as well as any other information determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2aedabeaae71401eb97337af43b1e566"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In conducting the study under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall consider—</text><clause id="id3722994a04e94d6897f73c781738c6b5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advertising or marketing materials that may—</text><subclause id="id8728efc0120b4ea7b85d29e8eb13dda1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be designed to appeal to individuals who are younger than 18 years of age; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id53660d75da234e06a8b1adb9cc36399c"><enum>(II)</enum><text>imply or encourage illegal use of the advertised or marketed product; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id892f70f3e7894d8e97462ad63c90d008"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advertising or marketing of semiautomatic assault weapons.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3dc87a7ec34459ab57b0a9700e72d61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1), together with such recommendations for legislation or administrative action as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98ce6666663347c1be204672f3363628"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exemption from Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code, shall not apply to the collection of information under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7af134dfd548411296c851f1ee85c301"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="idb31740338de94c79a5603ae738c2f542"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after submitting the report required by subsection (a)(2), the Commission shall promulgate regulations under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to prohibit any manufacturer, dealer, or importer of firearms from engaging in any unfair or deceptive act or practice related to the advertising or marketing of firearms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5289f61be3ec4a96992c85b640749917"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In promulgating regulations under paragraph (1), the Commission shall address—</text><subparagraph id="id7b85ce1bc26341e6bdb1cd714d5a1ea9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>unfair or deceptive advertising or marketing that—</text><clause id="id62571d8457d04b8c84fc8732239f51c3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may be designed to appeal to individuals who are younger than 18 years of age;</text></clause><clause id="id54a6e9a954e648ef8b098b2985b44695"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may imply or encourage illegal use of the advertised or marketed product; or</text></clause><clause id="id79d6b42c4ecf4e84a0013908d807358a"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>relates to the sale of semiautomatic assault weapons; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id21822441fa0c4abb8053053b7d3f4da9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other unfair or deceptive acts or practices related to the advertising or marketing of firearms by manufacturers, dealers, or importers of firearms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfc33ded6e15c464eabe1dd42d518a246"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="idd065d7811a934bb3b7ad09df977090ff"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of a regulation promulgated under subsection (b) shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf5ba191bff9b48d3ae081b06d952e12c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph id="idf9f3565c7473463aac991bb387e5d62d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce the regulations promulgated under subsection (b) in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id337a834f703f4d66b91bdb9ae8ed3c46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates a regulation promulgated under subsection (b) shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddb731173e1a14151956d28c518b10f81"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id404bfa1091bb4f8fb7924ba3e6866d33"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idecd3511319684a2cb024c5690079b7d2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8009ec36b2b74e45ac64ffe938fba611"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Firearm; importer; manufacturer; dealer</header><text>The terms <term>firearm</term>, <term>importer</term>, <term>manufacturer</term>, and <term>dealer</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

