<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HC98C0C9725D7499A9F6B7D7CA87140ED">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7832 IH: America’s Living Library Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7832</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To establish the America’s Living Library Project, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HEC1191B9F1D648CCAC2494C08DB40162">
<section section-type="section-one" id="HD0063A2FD2E74BE6947047344ECB1BCA"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>America’s Living Library Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7A0EE9FAF3DE4B5D870FE83F9F7A84D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>America’s living library project</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F9C61D875BC4E0C8FD37894E8F32F39"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H37EC63EE367C49B7AB54EA918F4A3852"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Control</header><text>The term <term>control</term> means having the ability, directly or indirectly, to determine (without regard to whether exercised through 1 or more corporate structures) the manner in which an entity conducts activities, through any means, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H7650D308DA6F4C9E9E3E1310089F16B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ownership interest;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1928AD2AD3FD4BC59220B89818443D42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>authority to commit the real or financial assets of the entity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D50A9F9E1BF429EB0908DF282FEA55D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>position as a director, officer, or partner of the entity; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB5AC5D9B6806402F9DF5593879BD2AE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>contractual arrangement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA858AE102E24E79AB0B6592FE7B6343"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2BDE3781B92403DA48FAD2FAAA95BF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>foreign entity of concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 40207 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18741">42 U.S.C. 18741</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H2103DBE321D0479E9AB6D84FFBDF598D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-priority species</header><text>The term <term>high-priority species</term> has the meaning given the term by the Secretary, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution, based on factors such as the conservation status, economic, cultural, or ecological value, biomedical or public health relevance, and rarity of the species.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H57E1654110A44E1CAD0A20BABB5267E3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5130">25 U.S.C. 5130</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F3AD7E507644FE884DF08FE8B4DBF81"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>office</term> means the office established or designated under subsection (e)(1).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEE98373D2A214F4A85C4BB51AF480A5B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the America’s Living Library Project established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6575BE016BE4947934EF1826ABF315F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior (acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H92CCDAF74789409D95C182262E3CC624"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a pilot program, to be known as the <quote>America’s Living Library Project</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H361D0C8FB8DC4B588DF696DE66D48E8D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the program is to facilitate the collection of new genomic data from species that are found in units of the National Park System.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1D962DC62052460D80ADABBF8D3C78B0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header>
<paragraph id="H29F03453C49F45AF98355A5E49254441"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall coordinate—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D6024B5110C408EBE9CE7FCE9C58800"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the collection, cataloging, and whole-genome sequencing of samples from animals, plants, fungi, and microbes found on selected units of the National Park System, subject to—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF201D896F6DC499BBBD0E93646364579"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicable permitting and consultation requirements under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39DA674B89964D0EA9FD71F2F5D5438D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicable permitting requirements under section 42 of title 18, United States Code; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H37089E4114214346893585A3B9EAE167"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicable requirements under the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3371">16 U.S.C. 3371 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9BC83D30B89473D9D307C314DB5F16F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of a publicly available genomic database for resulting genomic data collected under the program, including long-read sequence data, genome assemblies, annotations, and associated metadata, except that the database shall withhold from public release any personally identifiable information and any sensitive collection locality information, including precise collection site locations or coordinates, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary to protect personnel, specimens, and resources;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1ACF81A39B8E435281E76EFFEFEAE051"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, the integration of the Integrated Taxonomic Information System and any other systems, such as the PLANTS Database of the Department of Agriculture and the World Register of Marine Species, to provide scientific name concepts for organisms to accompany the genomic database; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DCFFC74D4F141888520E68E13770EBC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the long-term storage of samples collected under the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEB827E49662240E3A3631ECD2533A43C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Partner agencies</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall coordinate with the Director of the National Park Service, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the Smithsonian Museum of Natural History, the Director of the National Center for Biotechnology Information of the National Institutes of Health, and any other appropriate Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H68B0DE478A934A08939348984302C318"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Establishment of program office</header> <paragraph id="H18ACCD187A1945B895EBA26744E67357"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a new, or designate an existing, office within the United States Geological Survey to administer the program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8A9A21FD41A142D99661E1F4C2D4BAE1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Secretary shall hire staff to carry out the program in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EE6090C983943E88DEE3A0BD0E215AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The office shall have the authority—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HD3A43E1841624EB1B6C1DB0DCE2D76AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out the program in accordance with this Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H337971309DFF4929BDBCB4BC25662B07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to such terms as the Secretary may determine appropriate, to enter into and implement any contract, lease, cooperative agreement, or other transaction that is necessary to carry out the program with—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B97914F24C64BDF9F6B828943D9017F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Federal agency, including the Department of Agriculture and the Department of Defense; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H96980124F9D94D8BBA0F80E3DBDD1520"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any public or private person or entity;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H3D00E80CE9D9423AB5028FEB5DB4A4BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to develop mechanisms to receive in-kind contributions from biotechnology companies, subject to requirements that the mechanisms developed shall—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B2619CD6AF142CD8E4552652EFE0EF3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limit in-kind contributions to the provision of resources to carry out the program, such as materials, instrumentation, or technological capabilities (such as deoxyribonucleic acid sequencing); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H87CDEDC0059D4FF68832D96D3CA58100"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include vetting for, and prevention of, conflicts of interest; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H1C457DA280E94D77A3CA1457D4F66B84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to use, subject to the consent of the applicable Federal agency, the services, personnel, and facilities of any other Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H88B92143474342EEBC1C769165498DCA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Selection of units of the National Park System</header>
<paragraph id="HCBFAD0FFD7744153A70BFB7CA90BAFC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial selection</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, based on the criteria described in paragraph (2), the Secretary shall select 5 units of the National Park System at which to carry out the program initially.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9F13B8761B04C9883FCEB47167314CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the National Park Service, shall select units of the National Park System under this subsection based on objective criteria that take into account—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9B12E539E6914A57A9BB9CB7DAAFF7FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the biological landscape of the unit of the National Park System;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E4C91C971EE4D7B9A9F81DA00643436"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the feasibility of implementation at, and operational readiness of, the unit of the National Park System;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1FBED62DCFB048CBAFB76449F368BB6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the quality of the education and public engagement opportunities at the unit of the National Park System;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DB0261DE3884887A85FFD98D65D9AB2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the research value and alignment of the unit of the National Park System with program priorities, including, where appropriate, genomic sequencing and associated metadata needs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H59DC69EA414F4190ABCBB5A212A69555"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the geographic and ecological diversity across the National Park System; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19A94E3331404702A9C9D00792833A3C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other criteria established by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H42B405BA1C52485FADE4FDAD92EF1094"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional units of the National Park System</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall select, in accordance with the criteria under paragraph (2), an additional 20 units of the National Park System at which to carry out the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAF786796C4845D89E6D258BF9788AD1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice of selections</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date on which a unit of the National Park System is selected under this subsection, the Secretary shall make publicly available on a Department website a notice that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7170295334724A5798CB3A2EEA96DE96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lists any units of the National Park System selected as part of that selection process; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFDE5E27D3D14568A6A2E2B99A96212D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides, for each unit of the National Park System selected as part of that selection process, a brief statement of reasons describing how the selection satisfies the criteria described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H09FFC975240B433BB38016A14A12BA58"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Program requirements</header>
<paragraph id="H1F3D7C18A00E426FBA778CAB89F5B1D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data standards</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA0418AA7EB7481096371B85C757E45A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>leverage existing and emerging data standards to ensure—</text>
<clause id="HA40FE9F6539547B0A77BF8729FF97B64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high-quality data are obtained under the program; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD61147C7DB554DD19D75246525941D06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>program data are considered usable and interoperable, with appropriate metadata to be included;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9F174CD44B5B44E2B5C7ADF6A844B6F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that data outputs under the program—</text> <clause id="H200D0134B1C5422D80292B2A8421F0DA"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFB2FC336F252469597F9F0E1CE989DBE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>meet applicable Federal data standards for biological data; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HA07445D1A9EB4169B4B0F6B65685B57E" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if there are no applicable Federal data standards described in subclause (I), meet data standards for the program established by the Secretary, in consultation with relevant Federal agencies, based on findability, accessibility, interoperability, and reusability data principles and using industry best practices;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6123D35AA5214AF297A84B343337AC31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as appropriate, comply with Department policies relating to species listed as endangered or threatened under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HED2B873A97EA4387AA9B6FCDCD86F4C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are updated to comply with any applicable United States Geological Survey standards for biological data; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA6B16949CC14468B3417E8E2E254073"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that appropriate cybersecurity and access safeguards are implemented to protect the data generated or stored under the program, including by ensuring that data outputs under the program are updated as necessary to meet applicable Federal cybersecurity standards for genomic data, including controls consistent with the National Institute of Standards and Technology special publications 800–53 (relating to Security and Privacy Controls for Information Systems and Organizations) and 800–111 (relating to Guide to Storage Encryption Technologies for End User Devices) or any successor framework.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4FAF7F484B3F4B08AC06A4485E0ACCA6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Long-term storage</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution with respect to storage capabilities for the management and long-term storage of samples collected under the program, subject to the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3592832E0FAD46419814A5648B3DFEE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Ownership of any samples collected under the program shall not be transferred, but samples may be housed with the Smithsonian Institution, the Department of Agriculture, or another qualified repository pursuant to a written repository agreement, which shall provide that access to samples collected under the program shall be managed by the respective institutional collection managers, with—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57DE3D9FB3284B1A8DEA1DE0EB5ACCE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the natural history collections to be managed by the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03AFCAF0412244F6B1A70A5F114D0B95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the germplasm repository to be managed by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC5C343C05E364266BC0146A2DE27A7C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Before any samples are collected under the program, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution, shall—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAF742CB2FEE45F893235CF4D6814700"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the species to be sampled to identify which species need to be collected for long-term storage;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93D7333BF6C6446ABC5598CCDB01674E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">from among the species identified under clause (i), identify which species should be considered to be high-priority species;</text></clause> <clause id="HC9691DA0129B4033A93660FCF7DC2395"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensure that all samples proposed for collection and long-term storage under the program are evaluated in accordance with appropriate standards identified by the Secretary to minimize the risk of collecting or storing disease vectors, pathogens, or other harmful biological agents; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC014EBC529814C788D70EFF1FC06CF0E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>require that any microbial or pathogen material identified through an evaluation under clause (iii) as requiring enhanced biosafety or biosecurity measures shall be—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H136BC8DEB723438F8DFE65C8D76ED7A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accessioned and stored separately from other program samples in a distinct, access-controlled collection; and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H784EA2B1C44C4A12B029EBBEFEAD6545"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">handled and stored only in facilities with containment and operational controls appropriate to the identified risk, consistent with applicable Federal biosafety and biosecurity requirements.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8DE1589E821D4207BFDF8E425D6D6674"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any samples identified for long-term storage under subparagraph (B)(i) shall be—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5BB9DA313CD4A07A33ACD7635A22E92"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collected and stored under the program; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0C5F4AEC21E46778B62DF9E5C7F5F8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserved in the natural history collections to be managed by the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution for the purposes of later research and long-term preservation.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAF5EB3E8313641FD8F1BE775B8375DC5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any high-priority species identified under subparagraph (B)(ii) shall be collected for storage in each of—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E5D4413E65B43BF88512B85E3586EBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the natural history collections to be managed by the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2ED57EE2785741289AA1DE5EDF6DD82D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the germplasm repository to be managed by the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4E5C97137B846DBBFF438A969A5DDBF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any physical samples collected under the program shall not be transferred, exported, or loaned outside the United States.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCC251B80CAF84BF0B92D90085587287F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Any physical storage, curation, and laboratory processing of samples collected under the program shall occur within facilities located in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5524920935364968A5F76251EB7CDCE0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sampling and collection procedures</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFED84AFD5549486D9E64BBE99D80138F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish sampling and collection procedures and policies consistent with applicable Department rules and standards, including permitting and consultation requirements under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.</external-xref>), section 42 of title 18, United States Code, the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3371">16 U.S.C. 3371 et seq.</external-xref>), and the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H597A43BAB0DD48EB800C1B9342E3A4A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop sampling plans that leverage existing research and monitoring programs within the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8CF0FDD5F2604D69AB9362C787638D15"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sequencing and data processing</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7A05F9ED66324B18A0503FF1E8A9CC8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>partner with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution, and the heads of other applicable Federal agencies to sequence genomic information from samples collected under the program;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9668CC71B0C54B658041378249954679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop and use standardized sequencing protocols to ensure consistency and comparability of data; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86E80C841A714900B572EE407D28F051"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incorporate automated data processing and quality checks to ensure the reliability of the data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1F1CCC5433474727A9CBEB5090ECE195"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Tribal consultation</header><text>In implementing the program, the Secretary shall engage in consultation with Indian Tribes in accordance with section 306108 of title 54, United States Code, Department policies on Tribal consultation, and other applicable law.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF6C37BE160C8448A9C0338E4BF7D917D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an implementation plan for the program that provides the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HCC14DCAB71A14C27836653A02DAB5899"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the expansion of genomic sequencing under the program to additional units of the National Park System under subsection (f)(3), including the consideration of partnerships with companies, contractors, and third parties to assist the office in carrying out the expansion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA165EA51D8C44C27ADD18E027E51D236"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An outline of methods in which the program could be expanded to include other federally managed land and Federal programs and facilities that manage biological resources, including land and programs or facilities managed by the Bureau of Land Management, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Forest Service, including units of the National Wildlife Refuge System and units of the National Fish Hatchery System.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H09B7DF1861D042D9B593F71E3DECA0E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A plan to facilitate, prior to public release, expedited access pathways or other non-public services (including bulk export application programming interfaces and any computer resources supported by the program within the United States) for the development, training, or evaluation of artificial intelligence models, to be limited to entities organized under the laws of the United States that are not owned or controlled, directly or indirectly, by any foreign entity of concern.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H298684C048FA4377967A4BF032D00C3D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD68C699898A94299B89C11E1F07B9AEF"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Preliminary report</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HED036A8012664E8CB4EEB443FA1159F4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a methodological review and report of preliminary findings of the program.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H885871542A3F40E6866625881A4CEA02"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The review and report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include a plan for the sustainable and long-term funding of the program with recommendations relating to—</text> <clause id="HC8EFA0FA5CC34903A9FCE38B3864DB92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a graduated subscription model developed in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Director of the National Institutes of Health for the database established under subsection (d)(1), the cost of which shall be based on the size and usage of the accessing organization; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H0A6FB074B11B472198DFB5E0B5B5A77C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>potential partnerships with institutions of higher education, philanthropic organizations, and nongovernmental organizations, such as the National Park Foundation, to secure grants and additional funding for the program in accordance with applicable policies of the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A963E5826874E6CACE6C5F21197BF43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date on which the program is terminated under subsection (l), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a methodological review and report that describes the final findings with respect to the program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEEFB6FC0C1DB42D6AB9FADAD5B64ABCE"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Program funding</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H9285ACD20B2E48438544AC00B20CD99E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the Secretary for program oversight and management of the conduct of genome sequencing in selected units of the National Park System—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B3ED3FD5295412C9C963D58D3AA3050"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$16,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71068AEFF13B4B0AAAEFF796148433A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$36,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3062C842A064C04B80B445CB8A15A31"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$54,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2030 and 2031;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC57715E008A243459E9E2A2426BD37FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the National Museum of Natural History of the Smithsonian Institution for sample storage—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H90C8207107874BD1981FC92E24561AAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H961E67A182834330A12957A0CA22CC14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$7,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4E10E1334B848B9BEBE90983BA4B673"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2030 and 2031;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2917061412BC40A6AC5B6447924B6D7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the National Center for Agricultural Utilization Research of the Department of Agriculture for sample storage—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDDC04F3C7FB14836BA541D6B592BCD9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4833BDAF72141D6992F302A187E8B3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$6,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69ECD2C468DF48FCBBEA1E99FC4D2D77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2030 and 2031;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65D61BAFBAA545AC8247EF0DC324DB12"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to the National Animal Germplasm Program of the Department of Agriculture for sample storage—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC014D02A208D441AB79F8755EA844696"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EAB5787431245B28CD6FD87326F71F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$2,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0CABAEE2CAA146FCA1CE7D113543CC88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2030 and 2031; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8EAE84CBB0540EAA8AF8E5C6ADBC0E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to the National Center for Biotechnology Information of the National Institutes of Health for program data storage—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB8B709D6CB84ED6ABC3326646F6C729"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 and 2028;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2B484AE2291443A38F514539E0849AA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$10,000,000 for fiscal year 2029; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94C255425B444717BD778995D575338E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2030 and 2031.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82049A16DE1D412A928046744C72B3C0"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to carry out the program terminates on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

