<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG26801-VPH-FP-3PH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>109 S4439 IS: Built To Last Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4439</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to identify a consistent, Federal set of best available forward-looking meteorological information and to require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to convene an effort to make such set available, with advice and technical assistance, to standards-developing organizations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HB5E4CBB257064611A27FCDEFC89A92FB"><section section-type="section-one" id="id57CDD03E001D4D9BAD84B6AB786C9EEC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Built To Last Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H0CC1709F34AE4128A0272AF38AC7484F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identification and dissemination of consistent, Federal set of best available forward-looking meteorological information</header><subsection id="HB79F470DED43424AAE57C18910A831AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="id15F9B7D88107410EAA4A4F3C0CB2A10A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idF119B4AB1DA641A8B4EA93AF1AB2A3C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5BE447B2DF54BC882C962364A4091A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Extreme weather</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>extreme weather</term> includes observed or anticipated severe and unseasonable atmospheric conditions, including drought, heavy precipitation, hurricanes, tornadoes and other windstorms (including derechos), extreme heat, extreme cold, flooding, sustained temperatures or precipitation that deviate substantially from historical averages, and any other weather event that the Under Secretary determines qualifies as extreme weather.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0A4705B0E484EFB9957F0BBB41423B2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other environmental trends</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>other environmental trends</term> means wildfires, coastal flooding, inland flooding, land subsidence, rising sea levels, and any other challenges relating to changes in environmental systems over time that the Under Secretary determines qualify as environmental challenges other than extreme weather.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83C7B577FA3A4571A384150F3386FA08"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mitigation Framework Leadership Group</header><text>The term <term>Mitigation Framework Leadership Group</term> means the Mitigation Framework Leadership Group established pursuant to the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/295">Public Law 109–295</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/701">6 U.S.C. 701</external-xref> note), or successor group.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idE071DA233A024F06A9B59C8BA0D0E4BC"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States Global Change Research Program</header><text>The term <term>United States Global Change Research Program</term> means the United States Global Change Research Program established under section 103 of the Global Change Research Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2933">15 U.S.C. 2933</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idA791CEAC82E2477D905BA610BF5EBD4B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Long-term</header><text>The term <term>long-term</term> shall have such meaning as the Director, in consultation with the Under Secretary, considers appropriate for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3075E4A1C24048B2904732A7070F649C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification of consistent, Federal set of best available meteorological information</header><paragraph id="id3DB23555F00444A0BB940767A9AAC855"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall identify and support research that enables, a consistent, Federal set of forward-looking long-term meteorological information that—</text><subparagraph id="id82C7E04B32654C3195AF0D6EA8930DF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>models future extreme weather events, other environmental trends, projections, and up-to-date observations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB18D00DF3A754A06AD73D5943756C164"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is suitable for use under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB4F67F02A2554A258B81D66FEF47AA11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mesoscale meteorological information</header><text>When the Under Secretary determines appropriate or upon request of the Director, the Under Secretary shall provide the Director with mesoscale meteorological information that is suitable for use under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9F21F742D154C3DB3A1F8B13366A5AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Advice, technical assistance, and dissemination</header><paragraph id="idA547AC642B064AD7BF87577BF588C573"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall, in consultation with the Under Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="id390E3F0CD7E24264B580F893C3B19156"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make available to the public information identified under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07D96072212E497382759AE0212EA7FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify Federal and non-Federal efforts to develop and adopt standards, building codes, and voluntary certifications; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7BEB33879DA47D1B89CB91A703AC662"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using the best available, consistent, Federal set of forward-looking long-term meteorological information identified under subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H281712E9BA15434393A95AE86451667D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advise and provide technical assistance to organizations that develop standards, model building codes, or voluntary certifications in order for such organizations to appropriately incorporate forward-looking long-term meteorological information into such standards, building codes, and voluntary certifications; and</text></clause><clause id="H9ABAE1D8BA5C4E1E9C14D721CB716578"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>take appropriate steps to make information identified under subsection (b) available to the entities described in clause (i) developing such standards, model building codes, and voluntary certifications.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id00DD8B80748F42BDBE458AF7B52C5CA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Director shall carry out paragraph (1) through each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="idF61D9378EF534399805356C9525F94FE"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>The Fire Research Center, established under section 16 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to establish the National Bureau of Standards</quote>, approved March 3, 1901 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278f">15 U.S.C. 278f</external-xref>).</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFADB766CDC8747CD882B65CE60B2CEC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The National Windstorm Impact Reduction Program, established under section 204 of the National Windstorm Impact Reduction Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15703">42 U.S.C. 15703</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70309155C1894AE58D176C991D268013"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other statutory authorities as the Director considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68A25FA37B734D8BBD186F890F47F1C4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Working group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to identify and support research that enable information as required under subsection (b), the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in coordination with the United States Global Change Research Program and the Mitigation Framework Leadership Group, shall designate a working group consisting of representatives from such Federal agencies as the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy considers appropriate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

