<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-joint" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-DAV26H48-VD6-X7-LMN"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>94 SJ 200 IS: To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran that have not been authorized by Congress.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIA</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. J. RES. 200</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260713">July 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following joint resolution; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>JOINT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against the Islamic Republic of Iran that have not been authorized by Congress.</official-title></form><resolution-body><section id="id33ea72744e254a32bfe39a64fcbe0053" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="idc35c8fa54cad4f039d4bfc872a897cca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Congress has the sole power to declare war under article I, section 8, clause 11 of the United States Constitution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id88be8b02cdd74cd38b07eb940a974141"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The President has a constitutional responsibility to take actions to defend the United States, its territories, its possessions, citizens, servicemembers, and diplomats from attack.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9dbca50f24554d2690fb3367a971dfaa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress has not declared war upon Iran or any person or organization within Iran, nor enacted a specific statutory authorization for the use of military force within or against Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida33e1f18c18543b5811b653ef6bf7330"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On February 28, 2026, President Donald J. Trump declared the start of <quote>major combat operations in Iran</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4edab8b4f0864bce9f54311d85fbf250"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The President did not terminate the use of United States Armed Forces following 60 days as required under section 5(b) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1544">50 U.S.C. 1544(b)</external-xref>), withdraw forces from the region, or seek the 30-day extension to accomplish a safe withdrawal provided for by that statute.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id43f07d2888894dada15d6131cb11bec1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>On June 17, 2026, President Donald J. Trump signed a memorandum of understanding with the Islamic Republic of Iran as a framework to negotiate a final termination of the war between the two countries. Since then, the United States and Iran have continued to exchange fire, including Iranian strikes against ships transiting the Strait of Hormuz, Iranian strikes against United States military installations within partner nations in the region, and multiple waves of United States strikes against hundreds of Iranian targets since July 7, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8f838a2c1b34f2aba69368d11d8e773"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On June 3, 2026, the House of Representatives passed on a bipartisan basis House Concurrent Resolution 86, 119th Congress, directing the President, pursuant to section 5(c) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1544">50 U.S.C. 1544(c)</external-xref>), to remove United States Armed Forces from hostilities with Iran, which the Senate passed on a bipartisan basis on June 23, 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d1b97128b9049cdb769e9eb8872629b"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The use of military force within or against Iran since February 28, 2026, and continuing to the date of introduction of this resolution constitutes the introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities within the meaning of section 4(a) of the War Powers Resolution (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1543">50 U.S.C. 1543(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7293b545b13e460cada0b4ab2263be7c"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>) provides that any joint resolution or bill requiring the removal of United States Armed Forces from imminent engagement in hostilities without a declaration of war or specific statutory authorization shall be considered in accordance with the expedited procedures under section 601(b) of the International Security and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="idd167c934ae674374a115dab0563b0a6e"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Iran</header><subsection id="id68bffd0a805a4b3e89ae0eb53f02c9b4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Pursuant to section 1013 of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1546a">50 U.S.C. 1546a</external-xref>), and in accordance with section 601(b) of the International Security Assistance and Arms Export Control Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/329">Public Law 94–329</external-xref>), Congress hereby directs the President to remove the United States Armed Forces from hostilities within or against Iran, unless explicitly authorized by a declaration of war or a specific authorization for use of military force.</text></subsection><subsection id="id82fb4d460cc847e6a154a36c05697497"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prevent the United States from—</text><paragraph id="idbf0e0b01bf3646ff89aabb1e8e77b3ed"><enum>(1)</enum><text>defending against an attack on the United States or its personnel or facilities in other nations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a050419404b44f0b33f6362c5efd55b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collecting, analyzing, or sharing intelligence, including with partner countries and international organizations as appropriate, related to threats from Iran or its proxies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id262af32867944cc3a0a7ffd7cb91290a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assisting partner countries who have been attacked by Iran since February 28, 2026, and other nations—</text><subparagraph id="id0ab315cba26245cbadd24efb1a6e6076"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in taking defensive measures to protect their territory from retaliatory attacks by Iran or its proxies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id76c74a4aee364e0d8ad8c750ef655980"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by providing defensive materiel support for such defensive measures; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8d0ec2336008474087c72b5113ec4cdd"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing assistance for the security, departure, and evacuation to United States citizens affected by the hostilities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

