<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26136-TK5-GC-LLT"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3664 IS: Correctional Facility Disaster Preparedness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3664</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Bureau of Prisons to submit to Congress an annual summary report of disaster damage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HF34D96F980604A29A407E8E1C1981BE6"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF939905F055D464BB672F362687BA6F8"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Correctional Facility Disaster Preparedness Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H28B9A5487E8D48CF86A63735AC58E02C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>major disaster</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H024DE7BB4F7C4A099A6E242CD73742EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17E23891C73C404F8D3C5CE7B5621C86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any natural disaster or extreme weather or public health emergency event that—</text><subparagraph id="H2383EA312DFB4D7FB74A1B098F419D7C"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3e292e75983b4a15969cb8a1ac821e3a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">causes physical damage to a Bureau of Prisons facility or contract prison; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3949dba7a3f646acb42b1246c8515b3d" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disrupts services described in paragraph (2), (4), (5), or (6) of section 3(a); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EE13F0F58174AD8A71CA2FD9C7A974C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Bureau of Prisons determines is a major disaster.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HB0B004F3E4DD4DA6A5E0C84A328347EA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Bureau of prisons annual summary report of disaster damage</header><subsection id="HC380882AB308477594CE0E00D9524176"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Government Accountability Office, and the Inspector General of the Department of Justice an annual summary report of disaster damage on the scope of physical damage from a major disaster by each Bureau of Prisons facility and its contract prisons impacted or struck by a major disaster that explains the effects of the damage on inmates and staff, including—</text><paragraph id="HB6EE945C18E644EAB640A6DB0F57936F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data on injury and loss of life of inmates and staff;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H770C02A7F3F64847AF561EDA74988521"><enum>(2)</enum><text>access to health and medical care, food, special dietary needs, drinkable water, personal protective equipment, and personal hygiene products;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2920856F77DB4D09832DA96E7F10B99E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>guidance used to adjudicate early release or home confinement requests, data on early release or home confinement approvals, denials, and justification for denials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61107136F77B4FE89FAD65482C124E25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an explanation as to whether using home confinement or early release was considered;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF66B674FD2AF4234892A633E2D5584AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>access to cost-free and uninterrupted visitation with legal counsel and visitors with justifications for facility decisions that resulted in suspended or altered visitations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F0C214DB6544557A7FCD8ABE303AE8C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>access to appropriate accommodations for inmates with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A21A95527904B998337B50761D75C39"><enum>(7)</enum><text>access to educational and work programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCE3220F6D3745F2BAF4A1336681BADE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>inmate grievances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BA4BAF0F8D44302A290161C5CCDEDE4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>assessment of the cost of the damage to the facility and estimates for repairs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31DCF60D24B942F1B0BF956D103068D0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the impact on staffing, equipment, and financial resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEB4DE2FD1404CB2B589CDBBEE690BAE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>other factors relating to the ability of the Bureau of Prisons and any existing contract prison to uphold the health, safety, and civil rights of the correctional population.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D37C8C51BB0413596A492AE9CA9C57B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Corrective action plan</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include agency corrective actions that the Bureau of Prisons will take to improve and modernize emergency preparedness plans, as they relate to natural disasters, extreme weather, and public health emergencies and a timeline to implement the corrective action plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE30CFD2D01764305AB86F8103E9B4F7D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include specific legislative recommendations to Congress for improving emergency preparedness plans within the Bureau of Prisons.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4DE17E2D30084788AD048291F32791C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall appoint an official of the Bureau of Prisons responsible for carrying out the corrective action plan.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA4C6B5D3A4BF4D3687619EE7C800414C"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Institute of Corrections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4351 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3F094AD8E6C34D0EAFC1C7FDE7D4000C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H9820F81AF46843BA9C86644D7F5185CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>ten</quote> and inserting <quote>14</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F325755114B4C1D8C326DE216938C94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB05454C33BB48DABF45412D1BCF0FFB"><paragraph id="HEAB4DC42A7094BD58F61DFF41BD578ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>One shall have served a sentence in either a Federal or State correctional facility or have a professional background advocating on the behalf of formerly incarcerated or incarcerated individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D0C9DE19A134DAFB3C4E9E79B783485"><enum>(4)</enum><text>One shall have a background as an emergency response coordinator that has created an emergency management accreditation program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9220A02D8BF4BA68FEE7D78A3F47FA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>One shall have an educational and professional background in public health working with communicable diseases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2783C6AA629241EE90D6540E0C9239C3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>One shall represent the labor union that represents Bureau of Prisons employees.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB887EA412D044DB1AFD8C42A3A42BB2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD426397633564D5687DCF10CF602904C"><subsection id="H0D05CA932EF745D3B8C0054F25BF02F0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Field hearing</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the National Institute of Corrections shall conduct at least one public field hearing on how correctional facilities can incorporate in their emergency preparedness plans and recovery efforts—</text><paragraph id="HC1EC85888DA84A749B6B30DC884BAD5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>inmate access to medical care, food, drinkable water, personal protective equipment, and personal hygiene products;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H480D8CE0824749AF82E29FE2805C6FD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consideration by staff of using home confinement or early release;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7726B8499F394C739ADE64F6531002F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inmate access to cost-free and uninterrupted visitation with legal counsel and visitors with clear standards for when facilities may suspend or alter visitations; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42BDF30DCA9F47B7B83AFC9A37FA80DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>inmate access to appropriate accommodations for inmates with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE70B51F8E6F4E23A98148B18AC6FA06"><enum>(5)</enum><text>use of Federal funding to restore disaster-damaged correctional facilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7B5D8EF390B41AEBBBFA14EDB22349E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>incorporation by staff of risk management best practices, such as those made available under the relevant agencies of the Federal Emergency Management Administration, Department of Health and Human Services, and the Government Accountability Office to enhance emergency preparedness plans.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

