<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN25A74-5V1-60-809">
    <metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3056 IS: Combatting the Persecution of Religious Groups in China Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
        <distribution-code>II</distribution-code>
        <congress>119th CONGRESS</congress>
        <session>1st Session</session>
        <legis-num>S. 3056</legis-num>
        <current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber>
        <action>
            <action-date date="20251027">October 27, 2025</action-date>
            <action-desc><sponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs.
                    Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>,
                    <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice
                and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign
                    Relations</committee-name></action-desc>
        </action>
        <legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
        <official-title>To state the policy of the United States with respect to religious freedom
            in the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title>
    </form>
    <legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause">
        <section section-type="section-one" id="S1">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combatting the Persecution of Religious Groups in China Act</short-title></quote>.</text>
        </section>
        <section id="id7e10459fee254fd0b2e4a0b7b074af5a">
            <enum>2.</enum>
            <header>Statement of policy</header>
            <subsection id="id16a81dff2c1d42f59569838a95cc9e3d">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Holding officials of the People’s Republic of China responsible for
                    religious freedom abuses</header>
 <text>It is the policy of the United States to consider that any official of the Government of the People’s Republic of China who is responsible for or has directly carried out abuses of religious freedom, including those involving arbitrary detention, forced sterilization, torture, forced labor, and serious restrictions on freedom of religion or belief, expression, and movement against religious minorities, including Protestant Christians, Catholics, Buddhists, Muslims, and Falun Gong practitioners, in the People’s Republic of China may have committed a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights for purposes of imposing sanctions with respect to such official under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="id2ac4cbe95e9c4969a354d51ec745ea15">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Department of State programming To promote religious freedom in the People’s
                    Republic of China</header>
 <text>It is the policy of the United States—</text> <paragraph id="id194b8d75ba3c47d085a01982242914c9"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>that the relevant bureaus of the Department of State, including the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs, should support efforts to promote international religious freedom in the People’s Republic of China; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="id4c305c1587ba4e68bdffd9e3df4c7808">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>for programs of the Department of State to promote religious freedom in the People’s Republic of China and monitor transnational repression of religious minority groups engaged in by the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
        </section>
        <section id="ida65389deb6d24a32945dea0633b2275d">
            <enum>3.</enum>
            <header>Sense of Congress regarding promotion of religious freedom in the People’s
                Republic of China</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States should promote religious freedom in the People’s Republic of China by—</text>
            <paragraph id="id61e4896fd6994c2586b622c66d12c3e1">
                <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>designating the People’s Republic of China as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under section 402(b)(1)(A)(ii) of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6442">22 U.S.C. 6442(b)(1)(A)(ii)</external-xref>) as long as the Government of the People’s Republic of China continues to engage in particularly severe violations of religious freedom (as defined in section 3 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6402">22 U.S.C. 6402</external-xref>));</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id2d20ca2aba4543d391c32e348aa94ba4">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>strengthening diplomacy relating to religious freedom on behalf of Christians and other religious minorities facing restrictions in the People’s Republic of China, including through the widespread engagement of international partners to combat abuses of religious freedom committed by the Government of the People’s Republic of China;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="ida3d3b5251f5a49af87c265f1a32b28de">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>raising the cases of religious and political prisoners at the highest levels with officials of the People’s Republic of China;</text>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph id="id77818fa651bc4c4c99d212f6ceae4409">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>calling on the Government of the People’s Republic of China to unconditionally release all unjustly detained religious and political prisoners and ensure that detainees who have not yet been released are treated humanely with—</text>
                <subparagraph id="id27ccc0e223714b2a9fea420ce59a462a">
                    <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>access to family, the legal counsel of their choice, independent medical care, and international monitoring mechanisms; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
                <subparagraph id="id2768939bf1a246fca91af45fcbe7421e">
                    <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the ability to practice their faith while in detention; and</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="ide076c95473f64e8c99f4786a967febf5"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>encouraging the global faith community to speak in solidarity with oppressed religious groups in the People’s Republic of China.</text>
            </paragraph>
        </section>
    </legis-body>
</bill>

