<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB74022260934D739724A68B61256A18" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8942 IH: GME Transparency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8942</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require hospitals receiving payment for direct graduate medical education costs under the Medicare program to report information with respect to the citizenship status of residents in an approved medical residency training program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H112F2ED071B445CA8C786DD5FE898470" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H399C9485F01A4B84B26FF7A671A8B31C" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>GME Transparency Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3B4CC9DBB70748E6B8F8B6C00861BC62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring hospitals receiving payment for direct graduate medical education costs under Medicare to report on citizenship status of residents</header> <subsection id="H11F68D76B33240AE83991268FD87402B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(h) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD203AE492E644ED58A6C2F64D80B5857"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(A), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such term does not include any residency or other postgraduate medical training program of a hospital that does not submit to the Secretary the information required under paragraph (11)(A) in accordance with such paragraph.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE29DC211733641FEBA209BF11D03AAFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7F12CA21FD974F5AA83E00A3D1B8D4BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HF458D7DD216245B49982C1C00231DD78"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Requirement to submit certain citizenship information with respect to residents; CMS report</header> 
<subparagraph id="H84320AD7DEB4448AB9DFF28BB2171D75"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year (beginning with the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this paragraph), a hospital receiving payment under this subsection for direct graduate medical education costs shall submit to the Secretary such deidentified information with respect to residents enrolled in an approved medical residency training program of the hospital as the Secretary determines necessary for purposes of the report required under <internal-xref idref="HC8DA0B152284464CA63DD1D2CA216CDF" legis-path="(11)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8DA0B152284464CA63DD1D2CA216CDF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the end of each fiscal year (beginning with the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this paragraph), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes, with respect to all approved medical residency training programs for which information was received pursuant to <internal-xref idref="H84320AD7DEB4448AB9DFF28BB2171D75" legis-path="(11)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> for such fiscal year, information regarding the number (and percentage) of residents enrolled in all such programs (disaggregated by State) who are—</text> 
<clause id="H218ABE424A704E4F93BA956415389183"><enum>(i)</enum><text>citizens of the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H7FD6FE92BF894BB2AD94EFB731ABD5EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>lawfully admitted for permanent residence in the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6563AFEDC90B445686CBB36E63109FE3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aliens with status under section 101(a)(15)(J)(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act;</text></clause> <clause id="H94FFE2EB55D0406DB43741E3AA1621A9" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aliens with nonimmigrant status under section 101(a)(15)(H)(i)(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2476F689566140538D1E65950006509F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>otherwise lawfully present in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08187F2AFDF4469791A6A96A08DC4BDE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Standardized reporting form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make available to each subsection (d) hospital with a residency or other postgraduate medical training program described in the first sentence of paragraph (5)(A) a standardized form for purposes of reporting the information required under <internal-xref idref="H84320AD7DEB4448AB9DFF28BB2171D75" legis-path="(11)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

