<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H652BDD3E14984E9C8E937159A7CE900C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6922 IH: Texas Dreamer Work Authorization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6922</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251223">December 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To grant the Secretary of Homeland Security express statutory authority to issue Employment Authorization Documents to individuals granted deferred action under the DACA policy, thereby superseding any judicial interpretation or injunction that restricts such authorization.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6385C99FEEE14FCB9C1312C83A823540" style="OLC"><section id="H17AFC789E75945E398BD1B5974A31328" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Texas Dreamer Work Authorization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H694D6E49A6654B6EBB74094B3E9FD27E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header><subsection id="H23B5894CC28047A5A461F5881D2AFC4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H67FC32A6E9054B7EB0A02DFE1C7837FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (hereinafter in this section referred to as <quote>DACA</quote>) policy has allowed hundreds of thousands of individuals brought to the United States as children to contribute significantly to the economy, national security, and communities across the nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50737AF6BB4D481C9A0DE84748A03D9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The granting of employment authorization to DACA recipients is critical to their ability to provide for their families, pay taxes, and utilize their education and skills, benefitting the entire country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H957793AE410B4A5DBEE5A212358D61DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recent judicial decisions have created uncertainty and an unequal application of the DACA policy, particularly by blocking the granting of work authorization for new applicants residing in certain jurisdictions, including the State of Texas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H051788DB5DCE420CB674D9E76FA1B927"><enum>(4)</enum><text>It is the express intent of Congress to ensure uniform and continued access to employment authorization for all eligible DACA applicants nationwide, including first-time applicants, by providing clear statutory authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DA5349CAF9945EC8C6953CFEC70DB6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this Act is to grant the Secretary of Homeland Security express statutory authority to issue Employment Authorization Documents (EADs) to individuals granted deferred action under the DACA policy, thereby superseding any judicial interpretation or injunction that restricts such authorization.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9CB92A514F80473A8BDA399E992B6071"><enum>3.</enum><header>Employment authorization for daca recipients</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 274A of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF65BC79C55D54F3BB2F0733BE9123955" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H106BBC7D8F9D4AFCA774FB5BACC2C621"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Employment authorization for DACA recipients</header><paragraph id="HCCD7C5E10AC84F27BEE2376103451823"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including any judicial order to the contrary, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall authorize for employment any alien who is granted deferred action under DACA, or any successor policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4225EC11FF3A43D0A8971120917F978E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New applicants</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that each applicant for DACA who has not previously submitted such an application and who meets all other established DACA eligibility criteria (including any applicant residing in a jurisdiction previously subject to employment authorization restrictions) is eligible for and is issued authorization for employment concurrently with the grant of deferred action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ACA5433E4CF4C37883AF88A79137B91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>DACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>DACA</quote> means the policy set forth in the memorandum of the Department of Homeland Security entitled <quote>Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion with Respect to Individuals Who Came to the United States as Children</quote> issued on June 15, 2012.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HA95757FA28D043C69B0065721A57A924"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

