<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROM25715-CMS-9K-6HW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3211 IS: Recognizing the Role of Direct Support Professionals Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3211</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251119">November 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S288">Ms. Murkowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Office of Management and Budget to consider revising the Standard Occupational Classification system to establish a separate code for direct support professionals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="section-one" id="id25b4985b7a1048928f5051d31396c027" changed="not-changed"><enum>1.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recognizing the Role of Direct Support Professionals Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id94e2805a31dd4313b2f0752b8d4352b4" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08a559bc0f1e4ac4b7f3a9a645dbecc6" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Direct support professionals play a critical role in the care provided to individuals with intellectual and developmental disabilities by providing a wide range of supportive services on a day-to-day basis to promote independence, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id564787c4b5f64c1bb6766b63c8a7439e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhancing independence and community inclusion of these individuals, including through travel and recreation, visiting friends and family, shopping, or socializing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72ce279a72894783b48ea295fe100373" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coaching and supporting individuals in communicating needs, achieving self-expression, pursuing personal goals, living independently, and participating actively in employment or voluntary roles in the community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2da294bc0e584baeb7987a7c33aca8eb" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing assistance with activities of independent daily living (such as feeding, bathing, toileting, and ambulation) and with tasks such as meal preparation, shopping, light housekeeping, laundry, and home management; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id569dc412378546738ca09249aa5fab5b" changed="not-changed"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting individuals at home, work, school, or any other community setting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd2d3a9508e44422aae16aee6da23efe0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Through the support of direct support professionals, individuals are able to lead self-directed lives within their own communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5cefe69b7cbf48a58ac5d9e07df41608" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providers of home- and community-based services are experiencing difficulty hiring and retaining direct support professionals, with a national turnover rate of 39 percent, as identified in a 2023 study by the National Core Indicators.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef18a642f3804b729a7d3d2f3a76e106" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">High turnover rates can lead to instability for individuals receiving services, and this may result in individuals not receiving enough personalized care to help them reach their goals for independent living.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd863b0b2e101424a9a6661d16d474cce" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A discrete occupational category for direct support professionals will help States and the Federal Government—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6733461d5f634d7db072f9a102ab631c" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">better interpret the shortage in the labor market of direct support professionals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id316932b18a9749739c0c0aa0acf2ba78" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect data on the high turnover rate of direct support professionals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e2dccce4f0b40c195521a90a4a002e0" changed="not-changed"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Standard Occupational Classification system is designed and maintained solely for statistical purposes, and is used by Federal statistical agencies to classify workers and jobs into occupational categories for the purpose of collecting, calculating, analyzing, or disseminating data.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ab18e50a88947dabb4007fb3d8b4b53" changed="not-changed"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Occupations in the Standard Occupational Classification system are classified based on work performed and, in some cases, on the skills, education, or training needed to perform the work.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idecce4073e29b4ea39ac60dfd97cb200e" changed="not-changed"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing a discrete occupational category for direct support professionals will—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida511afa67f454364b29d97f1f235ddc3" changed="not-changed"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">correct an inaccurate representation in the Standard Occupational Classification system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id44659a27260a42d09288084cdf119e22" changed="not-changed"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognize these professionals for the critical and often overlooked work that they perform for the disabled community, which work is different than the work of a home health aide or a personal care aide; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id934ba0fc2b0241cab06b4c3651d3b2c1" changed="not-changed"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">better align the Standard Occupational Classification system with related classification systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idbf1db02dd61c4c8b8034e6973040e318" changed="not-changed"><enum>3.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Revision of standard occupational classification system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall, as part of the first revision of the Standard Occupational Classification system occurring after the date of enactment of this Act, consider revising the Standard Occupational Classification system to establish a separate code for direct support professionals as a healthcare support occupation.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idd6b67a61f9e742bb915166241f4a99bc" changed="not-changed"><enum>4.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If, after carrying out section 3, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget decides not to establish a separate code for direct support professionals in the Standard Occupational Classification system, the Director shall, by not later than 30 days after the first revision of the Standard Occupational Classification system occurring after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives explaining the Office of Management and Budget’s decision.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="idcb746da42e7e462292fbdf7abe6aad1c" changed="not-changed"><enum>5.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">No new funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

