<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8508693C6C8E4CE28BECC2EFF81B999C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6527 IH: Justice for the Living Victims of Lockerbie Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6527</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide compensation for United States victims of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C26B9282EA54FCF9F54869885BD426C" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H13A3D2DCD4DE47C38EDB439428E03356"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice for the Living Victims of Lockerbie Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H447D7D9CAFCA42B38EE4F532F0521B22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>compensable living victim of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism</term> means an individual who—</text><paragraph id="H5223655C1CCA4DCD9D97FBD44B40D517"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a United States person;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74947FD1C839490E99824ED17821E8FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was 45 years of age or older on December 3, 1991;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD83F41CA770447CC8E8A27004B94F9E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>was employed by Pan American World Airways, Inc., on December 3, 1991;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8827F84291843599C6ACA86AD6DA372"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>was a named claimant in Abbott et al. v. Socialist People’s Libyan Arab Jamahiriya (case number 1:94–cv–02444–SS) in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H671450EC5AAC40C9B73F2C63EAE00228"><enum>(5)</enum><text>was alive on August 14, 2008.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFA61ECE87A6E4B1AAB49424FD2E66A21"><enum>3.</enum><header>Living Victims of Lockerbie Claims Trust Fund</header><subsection id="H6F2C6F8D06B544EEADBE51FDA823D1FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish, in the Treasury of the United States, a trust fund, to be known as the <quote>Living Victims of Lockerbie Claims Trust Fund</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>) for the payment of claims submitted by compensable living victims of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism under section 4.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA6C3B63C22BF447E8007D6ACA1A8240B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Once the Fund is established pursuant to subsection (a), there shall be appropriated to the Fund, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, $42,066,338, to remain available until expended, which shall be made available to provide compensation to compensable living victims of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5AE4F480057B47A180752C8A544C36C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compensation for living victims of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism</header><subsection id="HB03C33B0215E4B49B46A922B1BBE3858"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certification by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission</header><text>The Foreign Claims Settlement Commission shall—</text><paragraph id="HBB77BF161E07400BA7F1D82D99E56CB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, publish in the Federal Register a notice of a process for filing claims on behalf of compensable living victims of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism, which shall include a deadline for the filing of claims of not later than the date that is 60 days after the date of publication of the notice;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB4570140426448BA825A1E78739FF17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 60 days after the end of the period for filing claims described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H1D726A05C23A4F1596189A4C1F53D4D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine if each individual who submitted a claim under that paragraph is a compensable living victim of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02FEC7FEA9364379930277820F8D79F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approve the claim of each individual the Commission determines under subparagraph (A) to be a compensable living victim of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0F1460575BD421E887BC803D3A293FA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>upon approving a claim under paragraph (2)(B), certify approval of the claim to the Secretary of the Treasury for purposes of authorization of payment under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA9F2E2B73D004146947C27A57A538304"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payments authorized</header><text>Upon receiving a certification from the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under subsection (a)(3), the Secretary of the Treasury shall make payments from the Fund to compensable living victims of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism in accordance with subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F541EBBEFF141CEA554BCE4277E97C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compensation</header><paragraph id="HE6221463F37744B3AF22ED54AA0632D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon a certification by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under subsection (a)(3) of the claim of a compensable living victim of Libyan State-sponsored terrorism, the claimant (or, in the case of a deceased claimant, the personal representative of the claimant’s estate) shall be entitled to an award in an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H726D284AA9CD4EB68EE2BAFC5BC488DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$42,066,338, divided by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB71D89A5E54ACFB52F68C7EACEBDA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of claims certified under subsection (a)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EAD7681862F4294B7452D0B1D823CC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representative</header><text>If a putative claimant that otherwise qualifies for compensation under this section is deceased, a personal representative may bring a claim on behalf of the estate of the claimant.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

