<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB0DBAEBD3E4A4046A37AA18741D25D72" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6606 IH: Opportunities for Success Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6606</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reauthorize the Federal work-study program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6334B8F9A0F4C11A5893F9A44B5ADDD" style="OLC"><section id="H06EE4A0C110E4466A0633EB3C54B499D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Opportunities for Success Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H43F79506F4E74D5EA4D34B6D0F5A5803"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose; authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 441 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-51">20 U.S.C. 1087–51</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H086A702F133C4FD29BAC232E00F761E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>part, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</quote> and inserting</text><quoted-block id="H4AB5AA28E7844EA398200078D3345FC2" style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>part—</text><paragraph id="H5C485933FE0C43BBA28D6764B6C951BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,500,000,000 for fiscal year 2027;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC99424E849B4C05AA782B3A780CA883"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$1,750,000,000 for fiscal year 2028;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E3918B6F2C742E2A6C40541A6ACA5BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2029;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F2A8A55386E4325A0BF74010D10D78F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$2,250,000,000 for fiscal year 2030; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2E9E86DAF1840C1BA3D87D64173081F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$2,500,000,000 for fiscal year 2031 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D3D826B29124C5FB6494E4846777437"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HC3D44B8107DB4375B00F0C97B037FAE7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>child development and early learning (including Head Start and Early Head Start programs carried out under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>)),</quote>, before <quote>literacy training,</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96919647E08D41248B51F294468753E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C8FA4A1D57440F0BAB9DBA58E37C5DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A6D781F87D24295BB43DD05AE14026D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC7A35B9E9B0A48FA81FBF9695B788B99" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HB9623ED03450479C9C486761575FCC57"><enum>(5)</enum><text>work-based learning designed to give students experience in any activity described in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4), without regard to whether credit is awarded.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DBBF5765B1A4EE7B0A99A58F7CCDBBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFC478607CC2D443988A5791D51A85916" style="OLC"><subsection id="H4AF2CB113D0F4026A6BF9DE3C95B8D36"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Work-Based learning defined</header><text>For purposes of this part, the term <term>work-based learning</term> means sustained interactions with industry, community, or academic professionals in real workplace settings that—</text><paragraph id="H25E337C8CC224499AFCDD18CDF6147EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include on campus opportunities; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F21CEAD8BFC439DBC4C2765A4EF11B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>foster in-depth, first-hand engagement with the tasks required of a given career field that are aligned with a student’s field of study; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F9C9661CAE144319CB9396DC1E464A5"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include internships, fellowships, research assistant positions, teacher residencies, clinical experiences, community services, administrative positions, participation in cooperative education, and apprenticeships registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H5423B20B455B483E8067E5EB7272E583"><enum>3.</enum><header>Allocation formula</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 442 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-52">20 U.S.C. 1087–52</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H6745A2292BD3420598F443EFC050C67B" style="OLC"><section id="H37A41BA1C9AF41F9AD8636D99CF69F4F"><enum>442.</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><subsection id="H8BFAAF3A54354FF5AB6CBF4E96D1738A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservations</header><paragraph id="H7CE1F539365143409BA71632FE45AEAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reservation for improved institutions</header><subparagraph id="HBDF9701F85744A3DACFC84EA4F45E670"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amount of reservation for improved institutions</header><text>Beginning with fiscal year 2027, for any fiscal year in which the amount appropriated under section 441(b) exceeds $700,000,000, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H8C64FDF6E6D147348B0966B45DDF1716"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reserve the lesser of—</text><subclause id="HBB5971F7FA7F49DF8B811A882C4A5CC1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount by which the amount appropriated under section 441(b) exceeds $700,000,000; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HC6504A92A9F04EE08C6BC075E5CD2500"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$150,000,000; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H244972ADB2FD46CE85B22584AA75AD8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allocate the amount reserved under clause (i) to each improved institution in an amount equal to the greater of—</text><subclause id="HBE3CC268FEDC46FCA3CFFF6F1CAA3D55"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount that bears the same proportion to the amount reserved under clause (i) as the total amount of all Federal Pell Grant funds awarded at the improved institution for the second preceding fiscal year bears to the total amount of Federal Pell Grant funds awarded at improved institutions participating under this part for the second preceding fiscal year; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD6BF5C4AC16B4EBA8A97B5F45DA19A77"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDF705E63FEC4F7D976FF991CA41ECCB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definition of improved institution</header><text>As used in this paragraph, the term <term>improved institution</term> means an institution that, on the date on which the Secretary makes an allocation under subparagraph (A)(ii)—</text><clause id="HE67754B543BE4633B8CD956964345033"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an institution of higher education (as defined under section 102) participating under this part; and</text></clause><clause id="H79B47817D63842749F41159D74465B9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to—</text><subclause id="H5F483424F80E46E7B4C030E143DC601C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the completion rate of Federal Pell Grant recipients at an institution, is in the top 75 percent of all institutions participating under this part for the preceding fiscal year;</text></subclause><subclause id="H21440D85AA764C598A48C96B6635DCEC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of students at an institution who are Federal Pell Grant recipients, has a greater percentage of such students at the institution than at least 50 percent of the institutions participating under this part for the preceding fiscal year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD2CDDCD7383244D0A27E030720231EAA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the annual increase in the completion rate of Federal Pell Grant recipients at an institution, has an annual increase that is greater than the annual increase of at least 50 percent of the institutions participating under this part for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68093E093B02431E9E55B08560A2FC07"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Completion rate</header><text>For purposes of determining the completion rate of an institution under this section, a Federal Pell Grant recipient who is either a full-time student or a part-time student shall be counted as a completer if, within 150 percent of the normal time for completion of or graduation from the program, the student has completed or graduated from the program, or enrolled in any program of an institution participating in any program under this title for which the prior program provides substantial preparation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBDABEB2731A48AFA18F75166B167B18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservation for grant program</header><text>From the amount appropriated under section 441(b) for a fiscal year and remaining after the Secretary reserves funds under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall reserve $30,000,000 to carry out grants under section 449.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4490D14AEE4B86B0BE7256FC7A2699"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reallocation of amount returned by improved institutions</header><text>If an institution returns to the Secretary any portion of the sums allocated to such institution under this subsection for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall reallot the excess to improved institutions on the same basis as under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C8EF9CFF82047E291802FCEB1B7B0A6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Beginning 1 year after the first allocations are made to improved institutions under paragraph (1)(A) and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall make publicly available—</text><subparagraph id="HC09C9FFE66A04C318CAB0CAB1DEF134A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the improved institutions that received funding under that paragraph for the prior fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88911B6ABF654BEB9225D69B48D83A1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each such improved institution—</text><clause id="H712695ECBF8E4BD19D89EC5E71599145"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the percentage of students who are Federal Pell Grant recipients;</text></clause><clause id="H0C48F4E5089B45CAA1BFE17C7E90FB5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the completion rate for students who are Federal Pell Grant recipients; and</text></clause><clause id="H9133985160B342DCAC557C994797D9F0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a comparison between the information described in clauses (i) and (ii) for the prior fiscal year and such information for the fiscal year that is two years prior.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21E7525306D34278BE518D8D926F0319"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation formula for fiscal years 2027 through 2031</header><paragraph id="H77817E0EA5144D6B89F58E07F8589D38"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From the amount appropriated under section 441(b) for a fiscal year and remaining after the Secretary reserves funds under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall allocate to each institution—</text><subparagraph id="HD7CF250453F64985B0CC3E5F33E1DD85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2027, an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="H2DA1C8C4A9924236B6A1F8666158F56B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>90 percent of the amount the institution received under this subsection and subsection (a) for fiscal year 2026, as those subsections were in effect with respect to that fiscal year (in this subparagraph referred to as <quote>the 2026 amount for the institution</quote>); or</text></clause><clause id="H4F0CD0CAA7404E108A11AEFD7C430543"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fair share amount for the institution determined under subsection (d);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D6EA0307DB04B5E90C24B2C60D4EF18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2028, an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="HB2EA2230E8EA46818BA3533ACCB5E370"><enum>(i)</enum><text>80 percent of the 2026 amount for the institution; or</text></clause><clause id="H77821C5B4AB64BB893FFAF85AADFB269"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fair share amount for the institution determined under subsection (d);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF672B3BA5B547FF89BD3971252D97C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2029, an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="HBF672873075E4A1C8B8B4DE8CCE135B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>60 percent of the 2026 amount for the institution; or</text></clause><clause id="H36A9F6C5240547D38B6D7370D0FFCD38"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fair share amount for the institution determined under subsection (d);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3965D0A73DE4AE89118EC11DA5C60C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2030, an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="H4D15B80C51FE4C1880F9E65D4630D9E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>40 percent of the 2026 amount for the institution; or</text></clause><clause id="H5B512EBCE68241BB9168AAE117197EC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fair share amount for the institution determined under subsection (d); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FA8173DA3254096B996EB4D8E3041E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2031, an amount equal to the greater of—</text><clause id="H206ACB04B24B459AB83736CFC4FF6149"><enum>(i)</enum><text>20 percent of the 2026 amount for the institution; or</text></clause><clause id="H1900F6445E6C461692D48CFFD3C8FAA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the fair share amount for the institution determined under subsection (d).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9890DD222E29491C97D049C39084986D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ratable reduction</header><subparagraph id="H44225FCA25C140409E785584E25BD648"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the amount appropriated under section 441(b) for a fiscal year and remaining after the Secretary reserves funds under subsection (a) of this section is less than the amount required to be allocated to the institutions under this subsection, then the amount of the allocation to each institution shall be ratably reduced.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CE09DD69AA048E2A11D3B5FC3AECD1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional appropriations</header><text>If the amounts allocated to each institution are ratably reduced under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year and additional amounts are appropriated for that fiscal year, the amount allocated to each institution from the additional amounts shall be increased on the same basis as the basis on which the amounts under subparagraph (A) were reduced (until each institution receives the amount required to be allocated under this subsection).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22C39218AB1A4573833603857D34388C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation formula for fiscal year 2031 and each succeeding fiscal year</header><text>Except as provided in <internal-xref idref="H0E45373E7C204BF6889DCC93593EF5DF" legis-path="442.(d)(4)">subsection (d)(4)</internal-xref>, from the amount appropriated under section 441(b) for fiscal year 2031 and each succeeding fiscal year and remaining after the Secretary reserves funds under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall allocate to each institution the fair share amount for the institution determined under subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H79D44FB7887C41469DAE0BC43D4D2525"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determination of fair share amount</header><paragraph id="H981AE658133240408B6D32028DC890D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The fair share amount for an institution for a fiscal year is the sum of—</text><subparagraph id="HD315F4065162490DA38ABA0231B9D94C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>100 percent of the institutional undergraduate student need calculated under paragraph (2) for the preceding fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H080895577F734B589CA272F7866861DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>25 percent of the institutional graduate student need calculated under paragraph (3) for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H118B658B746C4196AC0FCEF5B61F0E30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institutional undergraduate student need calculation</header><text>The institutional undergraduate student need for an institution for a fiscal year is the sum of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1B4C7AA2FF3641B489FB72911B5CF345"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An amount equal to 50 percent of the amount that bears the same proportion to the available appropriated amount for that fiscal year as the total amount of Federal Pell Grant funds awarded at the institution for the preceding fiscal year bears to the total amount of Federal Pell Grant funds awarded at all institutions participating under this part for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2C6165757D2488EA7B53B0BA900ACBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An amount equal to 50 percent of the amount that bears the same proportion to the available appropriated amount for that fiscal year as the total amount of the undergraduate student need at the institution for the preceding fiscal year bears to the total amount of undergraduate student need at all institutions participating under this part for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4C6BBC6026B4DDE90608BB6604B29E8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institutional graduate student need calculation</header><text>The institutional graduate student need for an institution for a fiscal year is the amount that bears the same proportion to the available appropriated amount for such fiscal year as the total amount of the graduate student need at the institution for the preceding fiscal year bears to the total amount of graduate student need at all institutions participating under this part for the preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E45373E7C204BF6889DCC93593EF5DF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligibility for fair share amount</header><text>Beginning in fiscal year 2027, the Secretary may not allocate funds under this part for a fiscal year to any institution that, for at least two of the three fiscal years preceding such fiscal year, has—</text><subparagraph id="HB3FDA563444847BBA1139CE6ECC27DB1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a student population with less than 7 percent of undergraduate students who are recipients of Federal Pell Grants; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B06A91505F74C1C86643FC74291248E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an institution that enrolls only graduate students, a student population with less than 5 percent of students who have a student aid index of zero.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFCBC0EE7BBC4699AFA8B9F9B825B149"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>The following definitions apply to this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H367F318AFF0F424B910FD9DD9D1C0732"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Available appropriated amount</header><text>The term <term>available appropriated amount</term> means—</text><clause id="HA1A779C803AE49F6BA7B5D7852A2C4DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount appropriated under section 441(b) for a fiscal year, minus</text></clause><clause id="HD58000EAACAF41598697020A180FD3AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amounts reserved under subsection (a) of this section for that fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59897A362F39469CB83DA97CFC32C216"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Average cost of attendance</header><text>The term <term>average cost of attendance</term> means, with respect to an institution, the average of the attendance costs for a fiscal year for students, which includes—</text><clause id="H023BCAC2045E4E658EA5F94D8EDE8FE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>tuition and fees, computed on the basis of information reported by the institution to the Secretary, which includes—</text><subclause id="H6C560272BB80427FB325DB68D2609DC9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>total revenue received by the institution from undergraduate and graduate tuition and fees for the second year preceding the year for which it is applying for an allocation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H97AA6305FCE14487B5B6FCBDEEA17962"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the institution’s enrollment for that second preceding year;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H99F230C7FE1E425796999253ADC9BC80"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>standard living expenses equal to 150 percent of the difference between the income protection allowance for a family of five and the income protection allowance for a family of six for a single independent student; and</text></clause><clause id="H31A534D092634C2E9BF51739F0C30B94"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>books and supplies, in an amount not exceeding $1,000, adjusted annually thereafter in accordance with inflation as determined by the Department of Labor’s Consumer Price Index for the previous calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E36687164C7412B8A42992795B3D3A6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Graduate student need</header><text>The term <term>graduate student need</term> (except when used as part of the term <term>institutional graduate student need</term>) means, with respect to a graduate or professional student for a fiscal year, the lesser of the following:</text><clause id="HF2DE662E02EA49EEA693D1AE739B5784"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The amount equal to (except the amount computed by this clause shall not be less than zero)—</text><subclause id="HF858B4CB44CD41C382210DCAC9651753"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average cost of attendance for the preceding fiscal year, minus</text></subclause><subclause id="HD570401326474521B96B3E7CD6AAD80E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the graduate or professional student’s student aid index (computed in accordance with part F of this title) for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFD869BBFBA86482F8FE26586993FF466"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The maximum annual loan amount for a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan for a graduate or professional student, as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA539C727EE34F9483E083AA33248854"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Undergraduate student need</header><text>The term <term>undergraduate student need</term> (except when used as part of the term <term>institutional undergraduate student need</term>) means, with respect to an undergraduate student for a fiscal year, the lesser of the following:</text><clause id="H9D36011406394D7CB8D0EEA58269D9E0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total of the amount equal to (except the amount computed by this clause shall not be less than zero)—</text><subclause id="H3C591E80B1F74A599F62A84E45942300"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the average cost of attendance for the preceding fiscal year, minus</text></subclause><subclause id="H5666B698276F4D5E847852FC307E8753"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the undergraduate student’s student aid index (computed in accordance with part F of this title) for the preceding fiscal year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4AA8C4C922F14A108D5144D16BC3177B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total of—</text><subclause id="HFCEA02190BE44F368EAE061FB51FFEE5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the maximum annual loan amount of a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan applicable to such undergraduate student; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6EFBBC106694458C8F388D8C388A58A6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">only in the case of a student who receives a Federal Direct Stafford Loan for such fiscal year, the maximum annual loan amount of a Federal Direct Stafford Loan applicable to such undergraduate student.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4CD93DBA9EE4522BBA0B06F981235CF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Return of surplus allocated funds</header><paragraph id="HF91F162CD5494540903C150163C9860E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except with respect to funds returned under subsection (a)(3), if an institution returns to the Secretary any portion of the sums allocated to the institution under this section for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall reallot the excess, in the following award year, to institutions that used at least 10 percent of the total amount of funds granted to the institution under this section to compensate students employed during a qualified period of nonenrollment (as such term is defined in section 443(f)) on the same basis as the basis on which fair share amounts are determined under <internal-xref idref="H79D44FB7887C41469DAE0BC43D4D2525" legis-path="442.(d)">subsection (d)</internal-xref>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79808EA69A948008C50204E8A73B986"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Each institution shall, to maximum extent practicable, use funds received pursuant to this subsection to compensate students employed in work-based learning positions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1AAD31E65774FA08D5CDBC879FD555A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retained funds</header><subparagraph id="HF2CA2AEEC83C4204ABB16C8714490817"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amount returned</header><text>If an institution returns more than 10 percent of its allocation under paragraph (1), the institution’s allocation for the next fiscal year shall be reduced by the amount returned.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8993FE2F968E43118E01A090F95FDF55"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive subparagraph (A) for a specific institution if the Secretary finds that enforcing that subparagraph would be contrary to the interest of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2F0F6898CF96426696BE9950F6A44A70"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Filing deadlines</header><text>The Secretary may require applications under this section, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H657D4880E7A74EA7AAB0C8D01F3A995E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants for Federal work-study programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 443 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-53">20 U.S.C. 1087–53</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7E8599B5E7FC45BDB538B0C0E92E246C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HC8248994B6664550A9ED1CF76AFEC628"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H967A24DC22ED4575B46C7228D91B1019" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H5C6649BC17A843B6856747E1A0644295" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that funds granted to an institution of higher education pursuant to this section may be used only to make payments to students participating in work-study programs, except that an institution—</text><subparagraph id="HEEB8567011E44DAF9E1BDBA80FE2BFC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall, beginning in fiscal year 2028—</text><clause id="H99FCBAF0F6144371875DCF23CF8597A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use at least 3 percent of the total amount of funds granted to the institution under this section for that fiscal year to compensate students who have exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2)) and are employed in a work-based learning position during a qualified period of nonenrollment, as defined in subsection (f);</text></clause><clause id="H0B2D0D3CC03149CCA55CDBC7C4267733"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use at least 7 percent of the total amount of funds granted to the institution under this section for that fiscal year to compensate students employed in work-based learning positions; and</text></clause><clause id="H98617AC63F8849489E851C3DE90F2393"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use at least 7 percent of the total amount of funds granted to the institution under this section for that fiscal year to compensate students employed in community service, and shall ensure that not less than 1 tutoring or family literacy project (as described in subsection (d)) is included in meeting the requirement of this subparagraph,</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">except that the Secretary may waive a clause under this subparagraph with respect to an institution if the Secretary determines that enforcing that clause would cause hardship for students at the institution; and</continuation-text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBFE016A8B1B4A1F8809233AABB2D240"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may—</text><clause id="HB41303B0142E4274AE7F790D8C88F748" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use a portion of the sums granted to it to meet administrative expenses in accordance with section 489;</text></clause><clause id="HF5741889F62D4A30A04B76675920DD5E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use a portion of the sums granted to it to meet the cost of a job location and development program in accordance with section 446; and</text></clause><clause id="HB2340404A0564FBE8997A49E1D726D5C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>transfer funds in accordance with section 488;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CDA3E46471E45ED988A585D31A53E42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><clause id="H7C9E249617154E59964CAAF70283FC4A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$300</quote> and inserting <quote>$500</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H5FBC16096B1147038D19DF1B909E3C72"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>except as provided under subsection (f),</quote> before <quote>provide</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDE5B6DF444D4DE3A7A3489AD34E6008"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><clause id="HEBDF3E98C3E948A4BE17CFD97168F3B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="HE5D1D5B169344E45A4DCEEC818271075"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; and</text></clause><clause id="H3E9CBC6DDC8A49F9B690BDA854AF882B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC195DDDE6907443496DFE91D710A933B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HE22B6BFFEF42436ABE583532C03534E9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal share shall equal 100 percent if the institution is eligible for assistance under title III or title V;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA36A5F87E014A418E8A1DCE0AAD9B1C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text><clause id="H2225B940127649C6AC01253F64730832" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>who demonstrate exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2))</quote> after <quote>students</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HFF31ABF185354EAE835CE368C1AC12FC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and prioritize employment for students who are currently homeless individuals described in section 725 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11434a">42 U.S.C. 11434a</external-xref>) or foster care youth</quote> after <quote>institution</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA52350C8713495E816A862D30A18109"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>vocational</quote> and inserting <quote>career</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D94F4E68C1E4B00B4FC56F054ABE73E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in paragraph (8)(A)(i), by striking <quote>or vocational goals</quote> and inserting <quote>career goals</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58298AADA180447D8D5342DCDA21F6AE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H011AF770573F4C66B70D7AC78DCFAAB8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (11) as paragraph (15); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8A85FC70D0B4888B83F29EC54938A21"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (10) the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block id="H1B3829BE25D34E27931398C4DC9D1D41" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H2D9EEABBC1C54E1183964A0865653C38"><enum>(11)</enum><text>provide an assurance that compensation of students employed in the work-study program in accordance with the agreement shall include reimbursement for reasonable travel (not including the purchase or lease of a vehicle) directly related to the work-study program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E3B842AFD0C4E0A955675284FA008CA"><enum>(12)</enum><text>provide an assurance that the institution will administer and use feedback from the surveys required under section 449A to improve the experiences of students employed in the work-study program in accordance with the agreement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18D490D1393F44FEA0410FC2538C4ACF"><enum>(13)</enum><text>provide an assurance that the institution will collect data from students and employers so that the employment made available from funds provided under this part will, to the maximum extent practicable, complement and reinforce the educational goals or career goals of each student receiving assistance under this part;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H667DD02F40C746BF931F5A015D3EE845"><enum>(14)</enum><text>provide an assurance that if the institution receives funds under section 442(a)(1)(A), the institution shall—</text><subparagraph id="H209EC72709194CE5B675522893B57DDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use the funds to compensate students employed in the work-study program in accordance with the agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D1106EC3BA348A19E14D747E53AA156"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prioritize the awarding of the funds (and increasing the amount of each award) to students—</text><clause id="HE47BC8DD096A43A1B338EBCB684250C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who demonstrate exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2)); and</text></clause><clause id="H84357FC86D8943769CB61C81C72A1C30"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who are employed in work-based learning opportunities through the work-study program in accordance with the agreement; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2D8DF1A4E84CC5BDE1E7BA75EA566A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H338C1C25970F49A59B2BD95A674FA1BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H04C2679129B6437A91839327439704D6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H882CEE8333954DA59F4532F74F4D9694"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide that—</text><subparagraph id="H74BA3D09453846D3998DBA7EACC8F11C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an institution that has not received a waiver from the Secretary, such institution will not use more than 25 percent of the funds made available to such institution under this part for any fiscal year for the operation of the program described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7FA52C08A36476691B62D2FC3024697"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an institution that has received a waiver from the Secretary, the institution will not use more than 50 percent of the funds made available to the institution under this part for any fiscal year for the operation of the program described in paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94FBDD7BD4CC49E7BB81D3247ACFBC45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><clause id="H386C4D0C0844486FA70F1BD85E90FD90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and complement and reinforce the educational goals or career goals of each student receiving assistance under this part</quote> after <quote>academically relevant</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HB46013BFDE304232AD50464C8B985B41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE140AAD9007405BBAE12C8F049ADA44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC160BDEFA7D246988E4784293E9AC7CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H4CF9DDA45FC143DBA4F9BA754EA9C0A9" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H978498ECA28B4D07B5E0A546CA5F78B5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide an assurance that the compensation of students employed in the work-study program in accordance with the agreement shall include reimbursement for reasonable travel (not including the purchase or lease of a vehicle) directly related to such work-study program.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D3C44B84A1B408695AC1F58899D9A1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HC0A88D02F8554761A5731A542EF657C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>In any academic year to which subsection (b)(2)(A) applies, an institution shall ensure that funds granted to such institution under this section are used in accordance with such subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>An institution may use the funds granted to such institution under this section</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55E060EAB82A4FBDA06113E8CA659D8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>travel</quote> and inserting <quote>reasonable travel (not including the purchase or lease of a vehicle)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C9B838E72B649C7BF720C0DBBBA87DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H3669155443F345E8AF852270E2D4C7A8" style="OLC"><subsection id="H0574D43876CD43E992E6467633177A4A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualified period of nonenrollment</header><paragraph id="H833F90A8DAC34CFB9AC5A62BFF9DD0D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A student may be awarded work-study employment during a qualified period of nonenrollment if—</text><subparagraph id="HBF541B442B4440EEB74573E09BD4AECE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the student demonstrates exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2)) in the award year prior to the qualified period of nonenrollment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD6229297C7B4D039C52A339CAB8B82B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the student is employed in a work-based learning position; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72DC12339C81437EAC5C95CF6BC2B276"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the employment—</text><clause id="H44976AB893864DCFA92A0CF1D718967B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves less than 25 percent administrative work; and</text></clause><clause id="HAEA1BDF0E65A49129A26B8815A80739A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is for at least 20 hours per week, unless the institution waives that requirement—</text><subclause id="HB59FA627410B405C95469D90358440B5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at the request of the student; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HC1E5E365828A45D6941FE2A0B5BD6638"><enum>(II)</enum><text>based on a finding by the institution that the requirement presents a hardship in finding a work-based learning position for the student.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5CA969C0EFA4D69B7D28324CF4B0AA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funds earned</header><subparagraph id="H58D89335310B4D5399A4D776F24C2C6F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any funds earned by a student (beyond standard living expenses (as such term is described in section 413D(c)(3)(C))) during the qualified period of nonenrollment less than or equal to $2,500 may not be applied to the student’s cost of attendance for the next period in which the student is enrolled.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H763378BC8E5F495B9265395BFDD7DA73"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excess funds</header><text>Any funds earned by a student (beyond standard living expenses (as such term is described in section 413D(c)(3)(C))) during the qualified period of nonenrollment in excess of $2,500 shall be applied to the student’s cost of attendance for the next period in which the student is enrolled.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB5958FEB62E43A78DF8BC27E9E6F9AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of qualified period of nonenrollment</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>qualified period of nonenrollment</term> means, with respect to a student, a period of nonenrollment—</text><subparagraph id="H3E2873BC6E50481F9EF954AE3FBDEEAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that occurs between a period of enrollment and a period of anticipated enrollment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H459C60248D194A758FFD21EB45569AED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the duration of which is no longer than 6 months.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1C1747FF6004431AF2B74EDFC16F17E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Cooperative education</header><paragraph id="H345A4F8542ED443DA1D804EE54D66551"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A student may be awarded work-study employment for participation in cooperative education on—</text><subparagraph id="H80B6263312E448B09088CFF31620B62A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a part-time basis; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEB8FF58872B496E9DA42F3A0CED5A26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a full-time basis for a period equal to or less than 6 months.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8CA2FC933C34CF4B845A46950DAFBC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private agreements for cooperative education</header><text>As part of its agreement described in subsection (b), an institution of higher education may, at its option, enter into an additional agreement with the Secretary that provides for the operation by the institution of a program of cooperative education of its students (on the basis described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1)) by a private for-profit organization under an agreement between the institution and the organization that complies with subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H776C76BEDB484CE08546AE97109D784F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Full-time basis period</header><text>The period specified in paragraph (1)(B) may be non-consecutive and include participation during qualified periods of nonenrollment (as defined in subsection (f)(3)). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC57C372E4C5246A3BC53244768D2E069"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cooperative education defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>cooperative education</term> means a program of alternating or parallel periods of academic study and work-based learning designed to give students work experiences related to their academic or career objectives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4674EB6A814D48C0800AFF61DFEE2321"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Notification regarding SNAP</header><paragraph id="HCFAC6D5229C541D98ADD23D6B5D0F8AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H55C7F9A544BC4125949FF6F36908A828"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution receiving a grant under this part shall notify (by email or other electronic means) each eligible student of their potential eligibility for participation in the Supplemental Nutritional Assistance Program (SNAP) under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>) and the process for obtaining more information, confirming eligibility, and accessing benefits under that program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BC96674F85E48A98015999C87D844FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The notice under this paragraph shall be developed by the Secretary in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, and shall include details on eligibility requirements for participation in SNAP that a student must satisfy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16092480238143089EE6CF05E30FCD4F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The notice under this paragraph shall, to the extent practicable, be specific to the student’s State of residence and shall provide contact information for the local office where an application for SNAP may be made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD40ECA39062C449FA2C4EBBE9AB98A73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evidence of participation in federally financed work-study program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice under paragraph (1) shall include an official document notifying the recipient that they are potentially an eligible student sufficient for purposes of demonstrating that the exclusion from ineligibility for participation in the SNAP under section 6(e)(4) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2015">7 U.S.C. 2015(e)(4)</external-xref>) applies to the student.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEA8BC83082E42799FF070BCE6481574"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall provide guidance to States and institutions of higher education on how to identify and communicate with students who are likely to be eligible for the SNAP, including those eligible for a State or federally financed work-study program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61E9BF511CAB4E45AFC3807A0A00F04B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this subsection, the term <term>eligible student</term> means a student receiving work-study assistance under this part.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H53C3BD3DBE8644F7BD96512311900CFF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Flexible use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 445 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-55">20 U.S.C. 1087–55</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H78AA1204DD174F95AD38BAF84E0B7BF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB04F62E98C57495C882ECEABC8E85939" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HC07D2CDEB10B43C8B9C8E267F3896D85"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In addition to the carry-over sums authorized under paragraph (1), an institution may permit a student who completed the previous award period to continue to earn unearned portions of the student’s work-study award from that previous period if—</text><subparagraph id="H97280CFD39C246DE9E1607A7D1AB5E7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any reduction in the student’s need on which the award was based is accounted for in the remaining portion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43E6A2E17222467CAFB81D89250D6C2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the student is currently employed in a work-based learning position.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H656426FF6FB84717A84C88FB6FD0187C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>10 percent</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>20 percent</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD64D3623ED5148FEB07FE836EFA86425"><enum>6.</enum><header>Job location and development programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 446 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-56">20 U.S.C. 1087–56</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDF32B72298FC459285DA1E05138BB7DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H58F0FC23927D4558A09AB282A28412F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>10 percent or $75,000</quote> and inserting <quote>20 percent or $150,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC03C30D574394878A8D9F318FDE12112"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>vocational</quote> and inserting <quote>career</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H956A8AB981BE4BB68F317C22BE8BA4CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H91E252D1F5834016B038618AE24A53EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) and (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF55C8F04F2240FCA4F6859C91D59661"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (3) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC9871E69191E42A89B2C14416C68750F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HBED005B5D9DC452BAAB2A83CEED17F3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide satisfactory assurance that the institution will prioritize placing students with exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2)) and Federal work-study recipients in jobs located and developed under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H981FD9259AC042889AD138F32B392DF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide satisfactory assurances that the funds available under this section will be used to locate and develop work-based learning positions;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BA78767466E45459D883BF9608423C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period and inserting</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H41619C92E5E44A8F8A788FF7D5FBBC9C" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC0B6908E884E450682B3EA44DD1DDDB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of students employed in work-based learning positions through the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B219B291F914F78A83211E65AFD4BDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of students demonstrating exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2)) who are Federal work-study recipients employed through the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A1C9C98D65C49A4958755085F700C59"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of students demonstrating exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2)) who are Federal work-study recipients employed in work-based learning positions through the program.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H7662D3493E3E45D98D30F7C747550935"><enum>7.</enum><header>Community service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 447 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-57">20 U.S.C. 1087–57</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H17BF4A3B62BC4B3A95CFE68E05A175A0" style="OLC"><section id="HE1FCA4AADB9046B4B337A2349C2991E1"><enum>447.</enum><header>Additional funds to conduct community service work-study programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each institution participating under this part may use up to 10 percent of the funds made available under section 489(a) and attributable to the amount of the institution’s expenditures under this part to conduct that institution’s program of community service-learning, including—</text><paragraph id="HD520189278334D449FD4088395B8601D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>development of mechanisms to ensure the academic quality of the student experience;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H032EE39436864167AE42FEF2835BE4C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring student access to educational resources, expertise, and supervision necessary to achieve community service objectives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11823226F12742A2AAE9470836E48E9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring, to the maximum extent practicable, that the community service-learning program will support the educational goals or career goals of students participating in the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24E07777E51A4D53A4F0FD307B3E5124"><enum>(4)</enum><text>collaboration with public and private nonprofit agencies, and programs assisted under the National and Community Service Act of 1990 in the planning, development, and administration of those programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06C2F0D9A65F46059FFBD6420C2AA2DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recruiting and compensating students for community service-learning (including compensation for time spent in training and for reasonable travel (not including the purchase or lease of a vehicle) directly related to the community service).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7F058DF927EA493DAB905B7A9707652D"><enum>8.</enum><header>Amendments to work colleges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 448 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-58">20 U.S.C. 1087–58</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD83D97B1ECB5459C9F52E42E618EA825"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>student</quote> after <quote>comprehensive</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33FA7BF339EE4CDFA7CB2A4307AA95E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(D), by inserting <quote>student</quote> after <quote>comprehensive</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A23CC741CF146E69847CBF8897009BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HBAEA216DCC414E0E856B6CA6EB3A874D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Each eligible institution</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H06593BB235A94DF7B79075246376B612" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HFA9695AFD98941FC92D15041E38FD34F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each eligible institution</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2764C7B9FE6841DCA3A5B48DF3F0FADC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H002C804D5B704980A7F1183424F9649D" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H2660E0D65C2243C094B2018D8DE327AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application dates</header><text>The Secretary shall require an eligible institution that submits an application under this section for the first time to submit the application at least 5 months prior to the application due date for returning applicants.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H998E6F62091444DFAD6A5BC489A2FFD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="H09382A26A89746129F09D2FF6D38CB0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H1312E453469846BD89F70039FEAE6CB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFDA13C1A9FE34C089126F4A05E2FF3DE" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H0A9A8C115FBA4E599F9FD45FFAB3E64D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is accredited by an accrediting agency or association recognized by the Secretary pursuant to part H, has operated a work-study program under this part for at least the 2 years preceding the date of the determination, and has operated a comprehensive student work-learning-service program for at least the 2 years preceding the date of the determination;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H8C8A481624E341A18D26E8CC72F83435"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>student</quote> after <quote>comprehensive</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H284EFDBDB14446EC95F88DAD54DA515C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by inserting <quote>student</quote> after <quote>comprehensive</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF934FC66F3C949F79A68AA501867238C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H05E887A7ECF349729585CCEE8B81B009"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (F) as subparagraphs (B) through (G), respectively; and</text></clause><clause id="H3F97AD06714E4CB29A5D810038031EF6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting before subparagraph (B), as redesignated by clause (i), the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5B9690A0708444FFA804C79CEEB63A24" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HE7F3A98C6A714946A38230452F2EA210"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a 4-year, degree-granting program;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HA05A44B5E0B44B6E84CCF0993AC57120"><enum>9.</enum><header>Pilot grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-51">20 U.S.C. 1087–51 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H38F097AE82174859972AC66035B9CDD9" style="OLC"><section id="H59955C37A2A047C68D157AD37C15F6AB"><enum>449.</enum><header>Work-based learning opportunities pilot grant program</header><subsection id="H5BDB2F166D5748B4BE012B96F7303DA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="HE9530B99B8774D3BB503EB12932C50FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible institutions participating under this part to establish or expand a program to develop work-based learning positions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57FE455E01F34CD7B9860E7E70DE2777"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="H7A9CD6ABF0244F228515DE8A048C08CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of not more than 4 years, but may be renewed by the Secretary for a period of 2 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63956E7198C7496BA2AEACD139A0219B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>A grant under this section may not be in an amount greater than $1,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D6B851090064FB1B565760F94E8C342"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be considered for a grant under this section an eligible institution participating under this part shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan that describes how the eligible institution will establish or expand a program to develop work-based learning positions that will—</text><paragraph id="H57585A3FF9144B7AB2E784BC9EAEF052"><enum>(1)</enum><text>benefit students who demonstrate exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A0B7EAE55A64984ABD7DB92004A8F15"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify in-demand industry sectors and occupations (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>) and as determined by the Bureau of Labor and Statistics, State departments of labor, and local boards (as defined in such section 3)) and develop partnerships with high-demand employers (including nonprofit organizations, joint labor-management organizations, for-profit firms, or public agencies);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF96EABB19B6749628ED09D98EA8E1B3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>involve participating employers in evaluating and improving the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H462EF378E4E54677B84825E14E1B849D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>track and report academic and employment outcomes for participating students; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D7F62144C724AD6B3BF61BD32C15BFD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>be able to continue after the end of the grant term.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC8AB81213CD428284183EEA4B1E62F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Institutions receiving grant funds awarded under this program shall use these funds to pay wages for students participating under this program and develop work-based learning positions that—</text><paragraph id="H42EA10F7EEB84424927DA8651B4FF238"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are for a period of at least 12 weeks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C6D1A6820B240DDAFF4C0FBA898B769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve students who demonstrate exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48D17AD3BF3B4CACB64BE0C93F527AE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limit administrative work to no more than 25 percent of the position;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CB66145556448F4B09B4CE606EBE1B1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide a minimum of 15 hours of work per week during periods of enrollment and 30 hours per week during periods of nonenrollment, except that this requirement may be waived by the institution in consultation with a student;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFD00EAD9F614287B4751C7BBFEE2903"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include career coaching from participating employers (including mock interviews, resume writing assistance, career exploration, and counseling on applying for and obtaining employment); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H723EE4A74C5442ADB4536852E355B8DE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide participating students with opportunities to meet with employers in fields or industries related to those of participating employers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00C27B0D616045E7B8DDFC75C7323B84"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On a date that is before the date on which the period of the grant received by an eligible institution under this section terminates, the institution shall submit a report to the Secretary including—</text><paragraph id="HB2F73519A1814836B2595753CB090C1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the completion rate (as described under section 442(a)(1)(C)) with respect to students participating in work-based learning positions under the pilot program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98486C1A07964A29AD50905BE69E2CA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the results of the work-based learning opportunities program for which the institution received the grant, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA367817A587640AAAD8012198C59908F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participating students’ satisfaction with the program as reported in surveys under section 449A;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF62DCB2D0E9142DBBFDCD32303C078C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the types of jobs in which participating students were employed and the types of duties performed in those jobs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C05E944F8A24C538430ADF7D7346B92"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the academic programs of the participating students;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2964F7C232C14F40B109FBD126A8FC11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the share of participating students who worked at another job, in addition to the one under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6602216721D44788AF4BC6A97915FCD1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the percentage of participating students who, during the second quarter after completing their academic program, are in education or training activities or unsubsidized employment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEB177A863EE4F36AE3B57A5EDB50D26"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of participating students employed in in-demand industry sectors or occupations as described in subsection (b)(2) within 2 quarters of completing their academic programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53C1091AD80A479FA0497E4E986035E7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>other items as deemed relevant by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0297D86A4AF4BD9990517D73ADFCF97"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reservation of funding for such program</header><text>From the amount appropriated under section 441(b) for a fiscal year and remaining after the Secretary reserves funds under section 442(a)(1), the Secretary shall reserve $30,000,000 to make grants under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H897E8FB1FD6B4801AF0CB975F96A8825"><enum>10.</enum><header>Department activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-51">20 U.S.C. 1087–51 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5B0DB621385F4CE395A0269BDB9DE854" style="OLC"><section id="H173B43FB9375488EB4C035EB5767B588"><enum>449A.</enum><header>Department activities</header><subsection id="H590A7B0555F74FA38D2B0ABCBB70ABA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Surveys</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall develop, in consultation with work-study administrators from institutions of higher education, participating employers, and participating students—</text><paragraph id="HB3DF81C42BD3493CB61E5C0A0099FC4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a consumer-tested electronic survey for students awarded work-study employment under the Federal work-study program under this part that—</text><subparagraph id="HEDC95EB5D0D34480963D4EDFF999E714"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measures each student’s satisfaction with the Federal work-study program, including—</text><clause id="H855D35BF606E4FACB99141CB5C6D6B7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any complaints the student has with respect to the program;</text></clause><clause id="HD1E38582147E433E846A714656066E1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount and quality of the on-the-job training the student received;</text></clause><clause id="HA4DBE3124A704A818741071490593120"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the amount and quality of on-the-job supervision and employer feedback the student received;</text></clause><clause id="HF09DCC6A41E94C0A8E24421F73F285DA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the amount and quality of information provided by the institution about the work-study program and job opportunities and the availability of work-study staff at the institution;</text></clause><clause id="HB9B3E055EABA4ACA9ADE158CBDB61215"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the quality of the assistance provided by the institution to the student in finding a work-study job and the availability of types of jobs; and</text></clause><clause id="HF15152C9714244D69FF1BDCD45C028FE"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the student’s overall satisfaction with the work-study program;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF666D1001C5C44A482AFE290168A9D77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>measures the applicability of work-study employment to the educational goals and career goals of each student;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9929DFA91414F64BA163EB573A545E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>elicits an assessment by each student of the capacity to manage time between work-study employment and coursework;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE50399BC87C44ACC9C80EADCB9F01A18"><enum>(D)</enum><text>measures, with respect to the program—</text><clause id="H07F40F5315D04C438CF789A8EC8E80DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the award amounts under the program;</text></clause><clause id="HEB1F7570BAC74E2D8ECC92B70391739C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the average number of hours students worked per week, and the wages received for that work;</text></clause><clause id="H8425FD6503F94CB798B1A156EB8FE466"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of on campus jobs and off campus jobs;</text></clause><clause id="HD63CC783AD4940A8BC969B08F80CE7D3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how students located work-study positions;</text></clause><clause id="HE6BCB03666EA4224B7CEDCEABAC48D3D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the work performed at each job;</text></clause><clause id="HB47A7396F88C47D9834414E9D0AFBEEF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>whether students worked additional jobs while employed in a work-study job (and the reason for any additional job);</text></clause><clause id="HEC8292CE153B46728C12FC85A10BD141"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>whether the work-study employment had an impact on the student’s academic performance; and</text></clause><clause id="HEFB82E58F68D4752894BE412B82740AF"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the voluntarily disclosed demographics of students awarded work-study employment; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEFF2367FF8A47C4A4878EB3218DFE8B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>includes such information as the Secretary may require;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A338F25BA81408A92B6FB48D239FA4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a consumer-tested electronic survey for employers of students described in paragraph (1) that—</text><subparagraph id="HDC6CD5A3E9284DE4AF3301355B201DCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>measures each employer’s satisfaction with the Federal work-study program, including—</text><clause id="H3FF07BB7191B4211AAC980108DCBD39C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which the employer is satisfied with its ability to accommodate students’ schedules;</text></clause><clause id="H94452D1A05BA424EB2D7DB3E7E871B16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the extent to which student-employees are prepared for the duties advertised for the job; and</text></clause><clause id="H5940B922124D4CC0A4E4DBF811930882"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the extent to which the employer is satisfied with opportunities to make recommendations for improving institutions’ academic programs;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H792715B828764B89A3B480609F9234FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>elicits an assessment by each such employer of—</text><clause id="H3D455FCA12084A1FB8581CDF4985EBD3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any complaints the employer had with respect to the program;</text></clause><clause id="HB53257E1FE2545C49057FB6EF91470EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any skills or knowledge necessary for the job that student-employees are lacking; and</text></clause><clause id="HD9DD6A0C762E436BA0261996312F488B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the extent of outreach from institutions to the employer; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FDCCFB8854D4711A088C2DE932EEBE8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes such information as the Secretary may require; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE33135A37E6F44EB9AD3DD1569168987"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a consumer-tested electronic survey that, not less than once every 4 years, with respect to each institution of higher education participating in the Federal work-study program, measures—</text><subparagraph id="H336E280C167A4AC6BBBFBEC182C1B655"><enum>(A)</enum><text>methods used to recruit on-campus and off-campus employers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07A1616FE255478CB483B81528EF6CEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if an institution operates a job location development program—</text><clause id="HF504A866DEBA4C19B42984190A57A4AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the share of jobs filled on-campus and off-campus;</text></clause><clause id="H08F8439507734B788584C06BEE6C46BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the share of jobs filled by—</text><subclause id="H388D03B0C4D645E79D81D8B1FFDA068E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>work-study recipients; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HED9A05E7583A4AC2B13F1874CC1C1FDF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>students who demonstrate exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2));</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF5CD159B493E4917B5B8B4AE1E3A554A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the primary factors considered in matching work-study students and jobs;</text></clause><clause id="HD760A692CCBC4C66B3B622B3C36790E8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the share of students employed in work-based learning opportunities; and</text></clause><clause id="H9D127CC3E2534E1E85B549A3B65331E5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the share of students employed during qualified periods of nonenrollment, including the share of students with exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2)) employed during qualified periods of nonenrollment;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD71986DEF1544E1B97B9FBEB3AAB13C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the institution’s Federal and non-Federal contributions toward work-study wages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A946B8764124FCE8DE8090FF84CE83B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the primary factors considered in awarding students work-study and in determining the amount of the award;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5069DC8AB4B145DF91E3538292AE2598"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the acceptance rate among students who were offered work-study aid; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CDED93B14E043839C7751B9BE2452F3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other information the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC74D4EB2FB124BDA8CF9F3FF5646255D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Results</header><text>The Secretary shall develop an online portal—</text><paragraph id="H86AC3C0340CC434CBF5ED641624C2C62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for students, employers, and institutions of higher education to access the surveys required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E480E24212B4B6C8F79FCFA83E96706"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to compile the results of those surveys.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8647CBA5449E4AEA9F93F4CFC3428E2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not less than once every 4 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress that includes—</text><paragraph id="H22EA9983EF024C488251564E568CA942"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the data collected under this section (redacted for personal information);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C3F688FA184783AB811BB909F0E892"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to students employed in work-study through the Federal work-study program—</text><subparagraph id="HE7AF263EC4AD462796A50054934B46A6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the types of jobs the students participated in;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AD7E638CACA4021A76050942A1317FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average hours worked per week;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E19094DA54C436498E64B1EAFA59077"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the average award amount;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F1AC289BD4E48BEB6B311E5264D5A13"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the average wage rates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28A7236DB99B40FDB52DC209E61AD7EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which students enter employment with skills and knowledge gained from work-study participation that have prepared them for the job; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62641FCC641543069CA15A97101453B1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the students’ satisfaction with the program and primary complaints;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0CB2020B76345D396B6372BD230759B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the extent to which institutions conduct outreach to employers and engage them in discussions on improving academic programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2CFC5B8B9CC4A09A803AB31065C88EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent to which institutions conduct outreach to students and make jobs readily available;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF16E880907E5420AA793E6EB3987B2AF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the extent to which the work-study employment aligns with students’ academic programs or career goals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E306B52BF14445A99B50D25E00810E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the employers’ satisfaction with the program and primary complaints; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD572E22AEFE5466D95903518116E3DE8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BB3E7B3FD214EFABDB0163B048341D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><paragraph id="H43BB14C0548F4BF79229A102B63996C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In consulting with the entities described in subsection (a) to create the electronic surveys required under that subsection, the Secretary shall engage with—</text><subparagraph id="HEC4307FC877A46C3887456AF9FCA9216"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a representative sample of institutions of higher education participating in the Federal work-study program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B56F3F82916450299591604AC6CEAC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a representative sample of employers participating in the Federal work-study program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1464700481F743D3A5349BFA49C062E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a representative sample of students participating in the Federal work-study program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B2B8D05AE8140A3969BBC48E90B8979"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Response rate</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HDD5BD42F7FC746C2A3FD4C41471941B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with a survey consultant to develop a target response rate with respect to the electronic surveys required under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FD8A1AA1E624B0988BD20BF9680E2FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide guidance to institution with respect to the developed target response rate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9634533BB42483389CA42382BBF2D06"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H0AD65CF93BB140C0AB336144AA2A0D0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to institutions participating under the Federal work-study program under this part to—</text><subparagraph id="HCB224844A5B9427691C20E8642B68527"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with the amendments made by the <short-title>Opportunities for Success Act of 2025</short-title> and the regulations issued pursuant to those amendments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6A5EF0E6EC24B0BA4AF08C9C2425D6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>administer the surveys described in subsection (a) to students and employers participating in the Federal work-study program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52341F3F1DD54FFDBE16E714C6368C44"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure that Federal work-study positions align with students’ educational goals or career goals to the maximum extent practicable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E7E2EA760044D279DF002EF610DF4DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue guidance and provide technical assistance to institutions to support improved partnerships and coordination among financial aid, career services, and academic advisors to administer the Federal work-study program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H604C7FE58A3E42ACABA2A87D5F066B18"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 to carry out subsections (a), (b), and (c).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H1D51AA6F7C264B4E918A080EC12649B2"><enum>11.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The amendments made to the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) by sections 1 through 10 of this Act shall take effect on October 1, 2026, and shall be effective for fiscal years beginning on and after such date.</text></section><section id="H5CE774F9191D4EE58A35D123A1D05199"><enum>12.</enum><header>Study and report</header><subsection id="H0120A9C3CDD4480894E8B919666D5084"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on best practices for assisting students participating in the Federal work-study program under part C of title IV of the Higher Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1087-51">42 U.S.C. 1087–51 et seq.</external-xref>) with—</text><paragraph id="HFF5AE923281D45879BEA2E5752CC379E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>connecting to off-campus employers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80031275CCC34010A0C9CC42BC50403B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>procuring work-based learning opportunities through the program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A9CE010EC4D4AF49B5A43F322AC2E91"><enum>(3)</enum><text>procuring employment that aligns with students’ educational goals or career goals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18FFA51130424D1C9FD5AE7D2D511A3C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>locating employment through job location and development programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F433BF6D744C70889555E302DD24BC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procuring employment in in-demand industry sectors or occupations (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22C405ABAD53413082E3D0D093C90BF9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>balancing employment with academic programs to improve graduation and completion rates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H818A253C53C1403999309A6DDDC233A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>with respect to students with exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070b-2">20 U.S.C. 1070b–2(c)(2)</external-xref>))—</text><subparagraph id="HFAECD5EF83C04D59B80CC44A2C5DD856"><enum>(A)</enum><text>locating and coordinating work-study employment during qualified periods of nonenrollment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AB50EE2C6C34C918BACBC4772DA22EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing participation in the work-study program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14BB47E4365D40A0BFF83E48688D44AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>limiting the need for additional employment outside the work-study program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H004C33601D9A49878B6A23887166FB67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress, and make available to the public on the website of the Government Accountability Office, a report summarizing the findings of the study required under <internal-xref idref="H0120A9C3CDD4480894E8B919666D5084" legis-path="12.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

