<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE56E2C28FCAE497091FE581DC260E919" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9734 IH: Protecting Patients from Automated Denials Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9734</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish requirements for the use of artificial intelligence in prior authorization denials by Medicare Advantage organizations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6BFE68F4831B43E2A1AC4DCAD3423BEE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H66F119F27BD84B78A6280BDAF4FB7E34" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Patients from Automated Denials Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9217E23E3D0A487695051A9C86E7CDA6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishing requirements for use of artificial intelligence in prior authorization denials under Medicare Advantage</header> <subsection id="H15E1D445F961498DAF700677934E880C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1852 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H62D6B001435E4452A18479AF9B5A7BCA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H9DB30566EFFE48888171F58479162422"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Requirements for use of artificial intelligence in prior authorization denials</header> 
<paragraph id="H627A0B5C435446EC83BDDC9927144553"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2027, an MA plan that imposes a prior authorization requirement with respect to an item or service for which benefits are available under such plan may not deny a request for prior authorization with respect to such item or service based on the output of artificial intelligence, unless the following requirements are met:</text> <subparagraph id="HABAA9E821BB14B809A0E8B6B39E4B13C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Before such denial is issued, such denial is reviewed and approved, under the clinical direction of a medical director of such MA plan, by a qualified physician reviewer.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F4EA762EF254F08B4FC0C1AE977298D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such qualified physician reviewer provides to such MA plan a signed attestation that, in reviewing and approving such denial—</text> <clause id="HCC4CDEE6EC7148289554C4D08F93DCBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such qualified physician reviewer exercised medical judgment that was independent from such output;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3542F10A186D43D5B11EFA0DFFCD8FA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such denial was not generated or dictated by artificial intelligence; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD7925C4808784D388442BD928D10650E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any software used in preparing such denial was used only for administrative purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BA5EEFB47D84F28986860CAEB6FB3B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such MA plan provides to the provider who submitted such request—</text> <clause id="HBB319976809642AEADEDDAAA52A8EE62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of the signed attestation described in subparagraph (B);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE586F4AA73FB4C00BD45C9CAAC4D9F76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an opportunity to communicate directly with such qualified physician reviewer; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2D6BC0579F424E058D5B5DEF0E4D0D81"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an opportunity to discuss with such qualified physician reviewer the proposed individualized clinical basis for such denial.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56677070F9E648388BF0F8E78DE168D7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such MA plan discloses to the individual to whom such denial is issued and to such provider—</text> <clause id="H1FB5608C67F6490C952B8D922D38ABBA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that artificial intelligence was used as part of such denial; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H43BD33BBFB1240B183EF718BE6C63966"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the National Provider Identifier number of such qualified physician reviewer.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0586031D6380429788F8339B25AFBDD1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such MA plan makes, and maintains for not less than 10 years after the date on which such denial is issued, records with respect to such denial about—</text> 
<clause id="H4639AB24EC39424EACB0CCBD784F3896"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of artificial intelligence;</text></clause> <clause id="H34B9E0B1A4074780ADEFBB2EC4F1DB27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the review and approval by such qualified physician reviewer under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H90BDD9179A7347EDBCCBC26814584B6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information provided under subparagraph (C), including a copy of the signed attestation described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCE8A54B7189414E8FFBD61F9F6D3616"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 31, 2027, and every 90 days thereafter, an MA plan that imposes a prior authorization requirement with respect to an item or service for which benefits are available under such plan shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes, with respect to the most recent 90-day period for which such data is available, information with respect to any requests for prior authorization for such an item or service that were denied based on the output of artificial intelligence, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5F56C01499A848C285E2668498A5F6A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any signed attestations provided under paragraph (1)(B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63BFA6CF73EC4F9D90E74429C9653A4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any algorithm, decision protocol, or documentation associated with such output.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H943C0CD580B64F66ADAA4E80693EECAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oversight authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an MA plan that imposes a prior authorization requirement with respect to an item or service for which benefits are available under such plan, the Secretary may audit and inspect any use of artificial intelligence by such plan that is associated with such requirement, including by—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E9E4D65843A4BDEB08B34618957640E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviewing data related to denials of requests for prior authorization;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC860C0943C9741CE9F4AE93DBFFBBE5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>examining whether qualified physician reviewers provided signed attestations under paragraph (1)(B);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D423668472D49879FE785B34FCF9F17"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reviewing such signed attestations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83EA99951AD541EC9E396FFF5D839D67"><enum>(D)</enum><text>comparing outputs of artificial intelligence to denials of requests for prior authorization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8514307F8EF466D961165F2AAEBB15F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assessing the rates of such denials that were overturned or did not satisfy the requirements of paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H01DDB2A231B54EBAB82EE0AB5E90EAB9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>reviewing internal policies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DBD37A697784EBAAE4F8B7267EF7066"><enum>(G)</enum><text>interviewing employees; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18241B237C664AC3A26FE78F93C33046"><enum>(H)</enum><text>reviewing any algorithm, decision protocol, or documentation related to such use.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E9235B5EB8445E48A6842B32A77F1CC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB6AF446B1BBD4143B3F02627D23747EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Artificial intelligence</header><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>) and includes technology that—</text> <clause id="HC1B180FE680B421CAEA3DBB667C4C891"><enum>(i)</enum><text>produces synthetic content in response to prompts using patterns learned from data;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6FB34D259A2B459D9A00B1687D4BF0DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>acts with autonomy and purpose by executing tasks proactively and independently with minimal or no human intervention; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF25F32DE42A446FA90E474FA8C41F7D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>interfaces with external systems and tools to take meaningful action, make decisions, set goals, and operate beyond initial training data.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BBB8C2A79994299A6B1F0CEDCA1984E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified physician reviewer</header><text>The term <term>qualified physician reviewer</term> means, with respect to an item or service for which a request for prior authorization is submitted to an MA plan, a physician who—</text> <clause id="H0D7AB90406E346F4BE4870CE86F0C169"><enum>(i)</enum><text>possesses a current and valid non-restricted license to practice medicine in the State where such item or service will be furnished;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8C0C522117AD41928F71DC7EAC30CAAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is board-certified or eligible under the rules and guidelines of the American Board of Medical Specialties or American Osteopathic Association in a specialty that correlates with the specialty of the provider who submitted such request; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8EEC5BAC8DD14D4B9AC103283449A760"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has experience practicing in such specialty.</text></clause> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HEEA6B513EBB94A248FA50F5BC0BF9C0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Promulgation of regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue a final rule to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

