<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2AEB63FF3B804BEC9351DD6709D037DD" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1379 IH: Condemning Lebanese Hezbollah’s repeated violations of ceasefire agreements and calling for the Lebanese Government to ensure Lebanese Hezbollah immediately ceases all attacks and disarms, in accordance with the ceasefire.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1379</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden of Maine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Condemning Lebanese Hezbollah’s repeated violations of ceasefire agreements and calling for the Lebanese Government to ensure Lebanese Hezbollah immediately ceases all attacks and disarms, in accordance with the ceasefire.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Lebanese Hezbollah is a United States-designated Foreign Terrorist Organization that has killed hundreds of Americans, including 220 United States Marines and 21 other service personnel in a bombing attack on the Marine compound in Beirut, Lebanon, on October 23, 1983;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on November 27, 2024, Israel and Lebanon agreed to a ceasefire, consistent with United Nations Security Council Resolution 1701, that required, as a condition of its continuation, the complete cessation of Lebanese Hezbollah fire and the full evacuation of Hezbollah operatives from the South Litani Sector;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, notwithstanding that agreement, Lebanese Hezbollah has repeatedly violated the ceasefire by launching rockets, missiles, and drones against Israeli communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, on January 8, 2026, the Lebanese Armed Forces claimed to have taken operational control of southern Lebanon with the goal of disarming Lebanese Hezbollah and asserting sovereignty;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, despite a ceasefire reached on April 16, 2026, Lebanese Hezbollah has launched thousands of rocket, missile, and drone attacks toward northern Israel, endangering the lives of Israeli and Lebanese civilians and threatening the fragile diplomatic progress underway;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Lebanese Hezbollah fighters continue to operate south of the Litani River in defiance of the ceasefire’s terms, using Lebanese territory as a base for attacks against Israel and undermining Lebanese sovereignty;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on June 3, 2026, Israel and Lebanon reached a ceasefire agreement calling for Lebanese Hezbollah to cease its attacks and withdraw fighters from the South Litani Sector, and in which the United States, Israel, and Lebanon reaffirmed that <quote>the future of the relationship between Israel and Lebanon must be decided by the two sovereign governments</quote>, and in which Israel and Lebanon reaffirmed that <quote>they have no hostile intent toward one another and committed to continuing direct negotiations toward a comprehensive agreement between the two countries</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Lebanese people have made clear that they do not wish to live under the influence of the Iranian regime, and the United States stands with the Lebanese people in their desire for a sovereign, stable, and peaceful Lebanon;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Lebanese Hezbollah’s attacks serve the interests of the Islamic Republic of Iran, that has committed to the destruction of America’s ally Israel;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States has a vital national interest in a stable and sovereign Lebanon, a secure Israel, and a region free from Iranian-backed proxy aggression; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States, Israel, and Lebanon have condemned the Islamic Republic of Iran’s ongoing destabilizing activities and agreed that any ceasefire resolution must not run through Tehran: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HEF555D81855F4D91BC8EE5B34330AD42"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HA0701EFFBC5C4F47B929BB877E643BDB"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9208AD7ADC1B4104A8FEC848F0EBFAA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strongly condemns Lebanese Hezbollah’s flagrant and repeated violations of ceasefire agreements, including its undermining of Lebanese sovereignty and hostile attacks against Israel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FD54558A4CE4D82A28AF23374662A5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>calls on the Lebanese Government and the Lebanese Armed Forces to ensure that Lebanese Hezbollah immediately cease all attacks against Israel and removes its weapons and military infrastructure from the South Litani Sector in accordance with the ceasefire’s terms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1B7944A94E44AABBE6C4EFDB0B13E44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports the United States-brokered direct negotiations between Israel and Lebanon, and urges all parties to proceed swiftly and in good faith; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71C01A03AD9A470A9A0099B13A84E5BD"> <enum>(4)</enum> <text>reaffirms, consistent with the June 3, 2026, Joint Statement, that the future of the relationship between Israel and Lebanon must be decided by the two sovereign governments and rejects any attempt by any state or non-state actor, including Iran or Lebanese Hezbollah, to deny the Lebanese people their sovereignty and freedom.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

