<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3FB1728B9F294DC8A215B3E0BC098F5D" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1233 IH: Expressing support for the recognition of April as National Foster Sibling Connections Month.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1233</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260429">April 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Expressing support for the recognition of April as National Foster Sibling Connections Month.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas sibling relationships are among the most important bonds in human development, contributing to children’s emotional stability and long-term well-being;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas for children who experience abuse, neglect, or instability, sibling relationships often serve as their most consistent source of support and belonging;</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas, when children enter foster care, the preservation of sibling relationships is critical to maintaining permanency, reducing trauma, and driving successful outcomes;</text>
        </whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that approximately 53 to 80 percent of children in foster care are separated from at least 1 sibling;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas research demonstrates that sibling separation in foster care is associated with increased placement instability, behavioral challenges, and adverse mental health outcomes;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas current child welfare data systems often fail to accurately track sibling separations, particularly in cases involving adoption, resulting in a systemic undercounting of the scope and impact of this issue;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this data gap limits the ability of policymakers, practitioners, and advocates to understand and address the harms caused by sibling separation fully;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is within the national and moral interest of the United States to make progress in ensuring that no child is separated from their siblings;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas advocates across the United States are working to advance policies and practices that prioritize sibling placement, visitation, and lifelong connection; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas increased awareness of sibling separation in foster care would elevate the voices of foster care alumni and promote policies that prioritize maintaining and restoring sibling relationships: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H16F7BEB1E2474BB595ED8536094748F9"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1B300A3B007341BBA2F80932E613D6BF"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9509FDC886164DF0876DA91990526E15"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expresses support for the recognition of National Foster Sibling Connections Month;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAD3ECC8841C4F30BABDDC1EC2FE0849"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges the critical importance of sibling relationships for children and youth in foster care;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFAD8060FC704D80A3555BA78A3DB418"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages Federal, State, Tribal, and local agencies to prioritize policies and practices that promote sibling placement and lifelong connection;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0DD8B4CEBC1409C96E9A4B814B5E1E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports efforts to improve data collection and transparency regarding sibling relationships and separations in foster care; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FF77074A0DB4CEEAF5B30E98C043A4B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls upon policymakers, child welfare professionals, advocates, and the public to raise awareness of and address the needs of siblings impacted by foster care.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

