<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95AE2DA169384FF3BBC5AC0E8BAD4F8F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6264 IH: Path to Affordable Homes Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000307">Mr. James</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Conservation and Production Act to require the consideration of additional factors prior to updating revised Federal building energy efficiency performance standards, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE7AC57AE59A74300AEB814EA763D9BBD" style="OLC"><section id="H7CA2C53C93694FBEB9E3E3CF3F6F71AD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Path to Affordable Homes Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0041774BFDC0451EB8CA076BCE3B482F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consideration of additional factors relating to revised Federal building energy efficiency performance standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 305(a)(3)(B) of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6834">42 U.S.C. 6834(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE609460C6B93484B8F2642A3A2544FF9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD7FD132412CD4410B20CAB0F1B8E3109" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0AF4571178A34E1588D34276241099EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of approval of each subsequent revision of the ASHRAE Standard or the International Energy Conservation Code, as appropriate, the Secretary shall determine whether the revised standards established under this paragraph should be updated to reflect the amendment based on—</text><subclause id="H07EA72380EE34FDD8EC823754F814FFA" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the cost-effectiveness, technological feasibility, and potential effect on the reliability of the electric grid of the requirements under the amendment;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB86215B5397543C5B9B5E3E6F93D0841" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the extent to which such requirements directly relate to energy efficiency; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D834E2EC3034845A692C31269E2E956" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether such requirements would result in a building being required to transition to consuming a different type of energy or consuming energy generated from a different source.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H72E7D6C14B614F17910D2A0BB74882D3" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to update the revised standards in accordance with clause (i), if the Secretary determines under clause (i)(III) that requirements under an amendment would result in a building being required to transition from consuming fossil fuel-generated energy to consuming energy generated from a different source, the Secretary shall consider such determination a negative factor against making such update.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

