<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H789B01BC7D004FA0B4809EC26223666F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6520 IH: SNAP Data Transparency and Oversight Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000490">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require States to
 provide recipient-level data to the Secretary of Agriculture upon request.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C573077E3FD41CCB0D2BD7946BEE495" style="OLC"><section id="H2D9B4F32BC1741AB9E659CEC1A256041" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SNAP Data Transparency and Oversight Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H68A01775CE9A4783A928903E0930F41F"><enum>2.</enum><header>State requirement to provide SNAP recipient data to the Secretary of
 Agriculture</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2020">7 U.S.C. 2020</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5E894DAA704048158F84CC0C1927A0EE" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7C2A0758F6AA441E826F8A93E50017DB"><enum>(y)</enum><header>Provision of recipient data to the Secretary</header><paragraph id="H61827F143D56480DBF8BAAA77D146B5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As a condition of participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program, each State agency shall, upon request of the Secretary, provide to the Secretary recipient-level data, case file information, or any other program data necessary for the administration, oversight, integrity, or enforcement of the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2074FA45BB30404CA4FB52F7309927A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Data required under paragraph (1) shall be transmitted in such form, manner, frequency, and within such time frame as the Secretary may prescribe, including through secure electronic data transfer systems designated by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE6138525E8B42C1AB886F95877D48AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A State agency shall provide the requested data not later than 30 days after the date of the Secretary’s request, unless the Secretary establishes a shorter timeline for urgent program integrity, audit, or investigative purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6581AAAAA1C1410E83D9D466965D1B83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Failure to comply with a data request issued under this subsection may result in the withholding or suspension of Federal administrative funds under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H025952B5E12B4D8DA192ADFB3FDF8F5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all data received under this subsection is subject to applicable Federal laws and safeguards governing the privacy and security of program records, including the Privacy Act of 1974.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB7793D418CF4B4BA4FA5C6DF3D006F4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such data may be disclosed to any Federal law enforcement and investigative agency, and law enforcement and investigative agency of a State, for purposes of administering or enforcing this Act, regulations issued under this Act, or any other Federal or State law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3D3C4FEBC9421E8D01D0BE6D01E907"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit any existing authority of the Secretary to access State data or records for program oversight, enforcement, audit, or evaluation purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>


