<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA73AED966DAB40D89039A8BDA674BD67" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7501 IH: Safe Flights for Passengers and Flight Crews Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7501</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000600">Mr. Langworthy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to issue certain regulations eliminating public charters from being eligible for on-demand eligibility under part 380 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9D9C745076D4E8CA15A831DC4B6BD64" style="OLC">
<section id="HBAB514A4AAC74EF2BA532A8BD416A221" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Flights for Passengers and Flight Crews Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H470BA754ABA64B45943A34082C444E3E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>On-demand eligibility</header> <subsection id="H853BC763D68044FB8426B3BA79658D23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and beginning 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, any passenger-carrying scheduled charter operation shall be regulated by the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration as a domestic operation or a flag operation, as the case may be, under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, when operating an aircraft having a passenger-seat configuration of more than 9 passenger seats, excluding each crewmember seat.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H640BF2AE5CB24F549C859C7B4968A83F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of subsection (a) shall take effect 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, regardless of whether the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration has issued regulations to implement such requirement.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H14346FFA9EA247CEB188386EE455349B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Passenger-carrying scheduled charter operation defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>passenger-carrying scheduled charter operation</quote> means any common carriage passenger-carrying operation for compensation or hire conducted by an air carrier or commercial operator that is a public charter operation under part 380 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, for which the certificate holder or its representative offers in advance the departure location, departure time, and arrival location. </text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

