<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26133-TCN-ND-W5R"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 613 ATS: A resolution recognizing the Army-Navy football game as America’s Game.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260225">February 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S374">Mr. Cotton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S357">Mrs. Fischer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S355">Mr. Cruz</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">A resolution recognizing the Army-Navy football game as America’s Game.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2009, the annual football game played between the United States Military Academy and the United States Naval Academy (referred to in this preamble as the <term>Army-Navy Game</term>) is played on the second Saturday of December;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Army-Navy Game is a tradition dating back to 1890, serving as a living symbol of patriotism, unity, and the true spirit of college football, and inspiring current and future service members;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Cadets and Midshipmen that play in this game exemplify American values of service, sacrifice, and leadership;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas any competing college football games risk diminishing the singular national attention and patriotic spirit that the Army-Navy Game inspires, including its role in celebrating current, and motivating future, service members;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas it is in the national interest to preserve the Army-Navy Game as the only college football game during its broadcast time slot;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Federal Communications Commission has an interest in understanding how broadcasting impacts access to, and prominence of, events that serve the United States; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Department of Defense has an interest in ensuring that the Army-Navy Game continues to create public engagement with the Armed Forces and military service academies: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That it is the sense of the Senate that—</text><paragraph id="id3140684b79c249219eec3141560fc6d4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the annual football game played between the United States Military Academy and the United States Naval Academy (referred to in this resolution as the <term>Army-Navy Game</term>) is a cornerstone of the collegiate sport tradition of the United States and an important influence on military recruiting;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5240e578e89a4e1d9c190964c02608b2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Army-Navy Game should retain its preeminent and exclusive status as the only college football game played on the second Saturday of December aired during its scheduled time slot to promote nationwide viewership, shared civic engagement, and recognition of the service and sacrifice of members of the Armed Forces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1de08de9137348669258efefdc868646"><enum>(3)</enum><text>broadcasters, collegiate athletic associations and conferences, and institutions of higher education should avoid scheduling college football games during this time slot; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idce9eaa5a942648a9884043c7452814d7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relevant Federal agencies should review existing policies to enhance coordination around, and the public promotion of the civic importance of, the Army-Navy Game.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

