<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26079-S4K-WT-0XW"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3828 IS: Combining Laboratory Expertise to Accelerate Novel Solutions for Minimizing Accumulated Radioactive Toxins Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3828</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260211">February 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To accelerate the development, demonstration, and deployment of advanced technologies and innovative solutions that support the environmental cleanup missions of the Department of Energy, help prevent the future generation and accumulation of nuclear waste from both current and anticipated future nuclear activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combining Laboratory Expertise to Accelerate Novel Solutions for Minimizing Accumulated Radioactive Toxins Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAN SMART Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id76580d2f5d4845b1ab8a40a64dd39ce4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id622fa9b4bbfa467988ccaf5e9bd01b24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id4921ec79b7df4dc6ae6e193e9a6998bc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f5429975e2949ec817de89ab592c142"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id43f51fe296b64738926448a459a60958"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3739798c625a47fb9f1c2d8b30f0614c"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd436f948b2f9419e956247de4b27d64d">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f5b6e92c3a2430a88a2b7b368c1219c">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfbd3cfa1e2d7435aba2fcf41a65caea2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Energy for Environmental Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0cb755fbd42e40abae345799d122edb5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The term <term>Chair</term> means the Chair of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfd5cf349bd945c68a9e410444daf338"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Core national laboratories</header><text>The term <term>Core National Laboratories</term> means the Idaho National Laboratory, the Los Alamos National Laboratory, the Oak Ridge National Laboratory, the Pacific Northwest National Laboratory, the Sandia National Laboratories, and the Corporate Lab.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id06b5ef7203e74d20885144bf6283d118"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Corporate lab</header><text>The term <term>Corporate Lab</term> means the Savannah River National Laboratory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ided443e7923ce4883b5e784d296e03700"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideb21cb9b58ba407f81af20da1065a101"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means Director of the Office of Legacy Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id586a0a9b78534fee8dce612d5c0b23cc"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Federal site life-cycle estimate</header><text>The term <term>Federal site life-cycle estimate</term> means the scope, cost, and schedule profiles of work activities, including sunk costs and other relevant metrics, of work activities pertaining to the cleanup mission for an individual site of the Office of Environmental Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id73c1498ba5254f04bbf8fbfeb5d4b496"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Framework</header><text>The term <term>Framework</term> means the Technology Development and Deployment Framework developed pursuant to section 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida3511563f3544065b07e2c6bc178a196"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Memorandum</header><text>The term <term>Memorandum</term> means the memorandum of understanding entered into pursuant to section 4(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf1bbd60f844845e587f733fd62704618"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Network</header><text>The term <term>Network</term> means the Network of National Laboratories for Environmental Management and Stewardship established pursuant to section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd42d91d2229946af9e33fbbccdcbde53"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4e3163f7f5394e57ad666ac927ae9524"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Site</header><text>The term <term>site</term> means any outstanding defense- and non-defense-related nuclear waste site that is undergoing environmental remediation and facility decommissioning under the responsibility of the Office of Environmental Management, and any site that is undergoing long-term maintenance and surveillance under the responsibility of the Office of Legacy Management.</text></paragraph></section><section id="ida86127be78b04011bb1e47b96a707608"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of the network of national laboratories for environmental management and stewardship</header><subsection id="id6f0c976b705e4b159ce98c071e2e9c76"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a steering committee to be known as the <quote>Network of National Laboratories for Environmental Management and Stewardship</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="id0ea4776ccebe4a5a88bf429990c9658c"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Network shall advance the scientific and technical expertise of the National Laboratory system in support of the environmental cleanup mission of the Office of Environmental Management and the long-term surveillance and maintenance mission of the Office of Legacy Management through support for research, development, demonstration, and deployment of treatment technologies, disposal methods, and other capabilities—</text><paragraph id="idea5591ff2f574b408c94bc486bb52c4b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to minimize the impact of environmental contamination and risks to public health and the environment from radioactive and hazardous waste and materials from defense-related nuclear activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id61f1df18bd034b49871d2f164842aff4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to lower lifecycle cleanup costs for sites;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0dd8e2fb82544e0f8b5d1a8858721eee"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to accelerate cleanup schedules or reduce the timeframe of site decommissioning; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60137121ddc048c392199bdfdd4dedf9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to address high-priority technical challenges in cleanup operations, or otherwise improve the effectiveness and safety of cleanup methods.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3bd5be329ce94a8f8f4c46375100470e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>At the direction of the Assistant Secretary and the Director, the Network and its participants shall—</text><paragraph id="id5d90f894893c4ce59ba4f99d00ebea50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>leverage National Laboratory partnerships to develop alternate treatment technologies, disposal methods, strategies, and other capabilities to assist in the cleanup and long-term management of sites, in order to improve the cost, timeframe, effectiveness, and safety of cleanup methods;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5af9a380906442f3a4f193d68085237f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify and coordinate technical support resources and capabilities to address emergent events associated with environmental cleanup and long-term monitoring of sites and facilitate the deployment of viable alternative treatment technologies, disposal methods, and other capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fb87bb462d845ba89e705da0c7317dc"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct scalable performance testing, evaluation, verification, and validation of alternate treatment technologies, disposal methods, and other capabilities to demonstrate the potential cost, safety, and performance benefits of such capabilities in comparison to those currently deployed in support of the environmental cleanup mission of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69fe376a197a43a2bb814b006c58f871"><enum>(4)</enum><text>leverage relevant infrastructure at the Core National Laboratories, including the recently constructed Advanced Manufacturing Collaborative facility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida8a30c176bf14f0a88cbb794a7eb8610"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conduct independent programmatic and technical reviews of plans or activities of the Department at the national or site level, including assessments of technology performance and alignment with respect to the programmatic priorities of the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id55ae509aed90406484d4e186352eb2ff"><enum>(6)</enum><text>collaborate with the contractors and staff of the Department, other Federal agencies, academia, industry, and other relevant entities to ensure best practices are being exchanged and to identify opportunities for technology transfer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8150292eeb4d4e2a8ad744438465795f"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide scientific and technical analysis to the Department and to stakeholders, as directed by the Department, regarding environmental cleanup, waste disposal, and long-term stewardship policy options and issues;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1e220436fa474476b8df4c3e4bd25c83"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provide an integrated science and technology perspective to support near- and long-term strategic planning for the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management at sites, including conducting analyses of alternative technologies and treatment methods and providing input on their insertion into the cleanup mission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74c1f5e2bce54a05a3048a2c87c1153c"><enum>(9)</enum><text>coordinate and serve through the Corporate Lab as a liaison among the Department and contractors of the Department and the National Laboratories with capabilities relating to the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management that have been developed and supported across all of the program offices of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id91c3f8ce654447c780b191c4a3c1138b"><enum>(10)</enum><text>provide technical expertise to inform contract decisions and language, research and development investments of the Department, and technical feasibility of contractor proposals consistent with all appropriate and applicable compliance requirements to mitigate potential conflicts of interest;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id76c515ef750b453293f7d58da4f6fe70"><enum>(11)</enum><text>assist the Department in developing and maintaining career pathway training opportunities in environmental remediation science, with a focus on engaging historically underserved or marginalized populations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id115a22986b614908ad8444332b51ff4e"><enum>(12)</enum><text>other duties as determined by the Assistant Secretary and the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfde1eaef82784d0eafac648ea182a110"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Network shall be comprised of a representative from—</text><paragraph id="id136afddcec5b493581f2278b89b4eee2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each Core National Laboratory;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee1ae95c1715449fbf32d927fa5f929e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each of the other National Laboratories with stewarded competencies for research activities associated with the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management, including the Argonne National Laboratory, the Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory, the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory, the Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, the National Energy Technology Laboratory, and the SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfcc0bd81d47d48e48d7a52d24ebb5c3a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other National Laboratories or entities at the request of the Assistant Secretary or the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide5c082c5641041ae929fdbef4aafd23f"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Leadership and responsibilities</header><paragraph id="id92f1851752a240f4bd46a1f196a7a411"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The leadership of the Network shall be composed of—</text><subparagraph id="id9cbef99676424c6f90403108a23f20e5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a liaison from the Office of Environmental Management, designated by the Assistant Secretary, who shall be responsible for National Laboratory stewardship, coordination of resources, and guidance and oversight of the Network regarding the needs of the Office of Environmental Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id203afd394d64490289be510b39d999f2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a liaison from the Office of Legacy Management, designated by the Director, who shall work directly with the Director and members of the Network to fulfill the needs of the Office of Legacy Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd86ece39963849b7be9e6c4e0ed49314"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Executive Director, who shall—</text><clause id="idf32057b2c1f1464bb2ab8d74c2692b2d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be affiliated with the Corporate Lab and appointed by the Network Chair and Network Co-Chair; and</text></clause><clause id="id7d78102022b94f81a559887e00558327"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>work on behalf of all National Laboratories to coordinate the day-to-day needs of the Network;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca4f73b48e504309bdfbce586dd0a04a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an official representative from each Core National Laboratory, who shall be designated by the respective Laboratory Director or Chief Research Officer, and who shall be responsible for coordinating and procuring the full complement of capabilities and resources from the relevant National Laboratory in order to fulfill its obligations with respect to the Network; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37ef0bc269fc49fdb564f2da10f8426c"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ad hoc representatives, who are Federal Government employees or employees of the management and operating contractors of the National Laboratories, and who may be—</text><clause id="ide4557506c316428cb4d193346de3a7d9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>representatives of other National Laboratories, as needed based on the work undertaken by the Network; or</text></clause><clause id="id11695098428b439ca0e8f7c51f320efb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>additional representatives from the Core National Laboratories, as needed and subject to the approval of the Network Chair and Network Co-Chair, with concurrence of the liaisons of the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a6205ae10874f2291bc89b1372500d4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Network chair and Network co-chair</header><subparagraph id="id4f27903d3779451c9050f0f2c3ccb702"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Network Chair</header><text>The Laboratory Director for the Savannah River National Laboratory shall—</text><clause id="id484c7bd2d4a44318ab393d8967035950"><enum>(i)</enum><text>serve as Network Chair;</text></clause><clause id="id22e9867ace1b434d87d564ac25096a7f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>report to the Assistant Secretary and the Director; and</text></clause><clause id="idf5113ec820c546ccbefe697057628978"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensure the overall effectiveness and coordination of the Network.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63fad81fcc49468a80b16a788d400fff"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Network Co-Chair</header><text>The Network Co-Chair shall work with the Network Chair to ensure the overall effectiveness of the Network and shall rotate annually among the Directors and Deputy Directors of the Core National Laboratories.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id761ed9b395d04c5a9a573b2b1f602a8b"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Participation of nonmembers</header><paragraph id="id53f59d028f114075b887db01351303ca"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Engagement</header><text>The Network may engage stakeholders, such as industry experts, educators, nonprofit stakeholders, and advisory groups, for the purpose of receiving mission-relevant information from such stakeholders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id02110f4aa79341feb7f891840da799f2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations on participation</header><text>The Network shall prevent the regular and systematic participation of stakeholders at meetings of the Network, unless otherwise authorized by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida43e0e06d0734605abb986989e43b75b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on nonmember input</header><text>The engagement of nonmembers shall be limited to the provision of individual advice and recommendations, unless otherwise authorized by this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1d08fe9703cd45239a5aa09edb426152"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary and the Director, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes a summary of—</text><paragraph id="id73fcbd73ab5244438cecda37d2e8fbba"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the major activities of the Network during the prior year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcab55e6d38204479824927307904c2bd"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the major science and technology efforts of the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management during the prior year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id200272ad0f424e1dbcfce48bac6b88f0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the state of technology adoption and alignment across the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id37edb8aa12ef4d9a998f27e9083c6cc8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="idb12a9ac6a6c044a888d4d721d17c806f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$55,000,000 for fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter to support the development and implementation of activities specified under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a4da6bc14964e22b21ed2133564496f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for fiscal year 2027 and each fiscal year thereafter to support the operation and coordination of the Network.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id411f258787b245f19d41f1f379553e2a"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Other environmental cleanup challenges</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary and the Director, may enter into an agreement with any Federal agency to utilize the capabilities of the Network to address radiological hazards and environmental contamination challenges at locations where the Office of Environmental Management and Office of Legacy Management do not have primary cleanup responsibilities, if and only if the agreement—</text><paragraph id="idb6a1d21f8a1e426b990b001aca281694"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is subject to the availability of the existing appropriations of the Department, except for those authorized in subsection (h), and to the extent possible leverages existing appropriations and resources from the Federal agency with which the agreement is made;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id38a9e6b8999d47dcbac301a4fa993a82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>does not utilize resources made available to support the cleanup missions of the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Legacy Management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idded3e089b9a44891aabbf6bfa7668c30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>does not utilize the capabilities of the Network in a manner that would prevent or otherwise limit the Network from fulfilling responsibilities specified in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idef7545e7fa9943868be8a161dbb83dc8"> <enum>(j)</enum> <header>Inapplicability of federal advisory committee act</header> <text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply with respect to the Network or the activities of the Network.</text>
                        </subsection></section><section id="id71ff23a94e7049d8af5cc84fb7ca14a8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Coordination with other Department of Energy offices and other Federal agencies on environmental management research</header><subsection id="id9378e2551d3c4568ae228d5eccf7d7ca">
                                <enum>(a)</enum>
                                <header>In general</header>
 <text>The Secretary, in cooperation with the Network, shall improve coordination across the Department and the Federal Government on science and technology efforts applicable to the environmental cleanup mission of the Office of Environmental Management as necessary to procure sufficient expertise and resources to address the full range of research challenges and needs identified by the Office.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="id1752e5e9d7ab48639c2f89dc24d13691"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency Working Advisory on Technology Excellence in Environmental Cleanup</header><paragraph id="id756a1f0785de4a8886ec7152b6e05e97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish an advisory group to be known as the <quote>Interagency Advisory Group on Technology Excellence in Environmental Cleanup</quote>, which shall—</text><subparagraph id="id37fd89b0068f4997a19335f137631250"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinate relevant technology transfer activities among the National Laboratories, the Technology Transfer Working Group of the Department, and other appropriate Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id906c5547d28141e981e68049f344c578"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate the exchange of mission-relevant information and best practices, including information on technology transfer practices, developments in environmental remediation science and treatment methods, and alternative approaches to radioactive waste management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcd7b3fdbad2a4da391edcbcb5e117418"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify and recommend technologies developed within and outside of the jurisdiction of the Department with potential applications for the Office of Environmental Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id05a116621ecf462f9c1c05a75af2a5ad"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identify and recommend opportunities to utilize the services and expertise of the Network to assist in addressing cleanup challenges at locations where the Office of Environmental Management does not have cleanup responsibilities, as described in section 3(i); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id438651074a0448c6a371fcfaccba6aa6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop and disseminate to the public and prospective technology partners information about opportunities and procedures for technology transfer with the Network.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id74f2735120364a4a8b46925a33d2efd9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Composition</header><subparagraph id="idaf90f5295eb249daa03ac022fb65e4fe"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Advisory Group shall be comprised of representatives selected from—</text><clause id="id68c4ed3c1ad04bcab51e1e46ca76c29d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Core National Laboratories;</text></clause><clause id="idec798f1d5fd34938810ddad9d6afedc9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Office of Environmental Management;</text></clause><clause id="ide4bfbf91dc67437480ec3586cc11c7a4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Office of Legacy Management;</text></clause><clause id="idbf985755e0bd4fef8103f264bc652847"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Office of Nuclear Energy;</text></clause><clause id="id799ef71cbf34471e90fbad5a722f273e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the Office of Science;</text></clause><clause id="id31a171918bb146ba8d5c20ee4197e5d8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the National Nuclear Security Administration;</text></clause><clause id="idb40a3ca8b13c4dbf948cf677e5b7cab7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></clause><clause id="idd5934289d7d34e369cdc6d08a4f5664d"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Nuclear Regulatory Commission;</text></clause><clause id="ide62f92c433d344dc84a8f12be88223bb"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management;</text></clause><clause id="ida4db8d47554b4d94986765253ac02ea9"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the National Park Service;</text></clause><clause id="id3af948213e5741da801a99a4b92b0e2d"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Affairs;</text></clause><clause id="id4b7a707f76204a3f90beb3e497302d3c"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>the United States Forest Service;</text></clause><clause id="iddcb42eae1e02418fb515dbc778e36186"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>such other Federal agencies with relevant science and technology expertise, as the Secretary determines, including agencies within the Department involved in technology development relating to radioactive waste disposal or environmental remediation;</text></clause><clause id="id934b518fd9b14202a83fb8698ab5004f"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>State and Tribal governments;</text></clause><clause id="idad452316aba84b768a0f5fbd7982cba8"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>academia; and</text></clause><clause id="idf0091498158446cfbb858f271027bfa7"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>the private sector.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id431871ccce4248bbae627b3769da2f99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall serve as the Chair of the Advisory Group.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c6980560816402c92d3ee5fe1b0de3e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Group shall meet not less frequently than once every 180 days.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id60b88cdc8cd54871a5a96b2db2ef9f56"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Inapplicability of Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/10">Chapter 10</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Federal Advisory Committee Act</quote>), shall not apply with respect to the Advisory Group or the activities of the Advisory Group.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idddc42d8f648f4651b99f53be29f5cbea"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Partnership with Office of Science</header><paragraph id="idac6be4f31a104fb8972fa98dcf304850"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary and the Director of the Office of Science of the Department shall enter into a memorandum of understanding to facilitate improved coordination and cooperation between the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Science on areas of basic research that are applicable to the environmental cleanup mission of the Office of Environmental Management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide4bd70d0f60f4a2c999efdd4910d6f51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Basic research needs workshops</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Memorandum takes effect, and on a periodic basis thereafter, the Director of the Office of Science, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary and the Network, shall administer a workshop to solicit the input of relevant Federal agencies, academia, industry, the National Laboratories, and other relevant entities—</text><subparagraph id="id94f30896ca214f6e9ca520819ff97441"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify the major basic research needs of the Office of Environmental Management; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb18c6aa11894b588238adc687f0940c"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop strategic research plans to advance knowledge and technological capabilities to address the basic research needs identified in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id75822b5830cd4be897dbf6d8971e7cc3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="ide9bb1795412e4091875ca4a5784a652a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial workshop report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the initial workshop described in paragraph (2), the Assistant Secretary and the Director of the Office of Science shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report summarizing the major findings of the workshop, including gaps in basic research knowledge relating to the environmental cleanup mission of the Office of Environmental Management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9a4150c12da64d1abf78505f8278b4f7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Not later than 1 year after the Memorandum takes effect, the Assistant Secretary and the Director of the Office of Science shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report summarizing the steps that the Office of Environmental Management and the Office of Science have taken to fulfill the obligations of the Memorandum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id42ea5bd0bead4d4586f78396a397c412"><enum>5.</enum><header>Program management protocols of the office of environmental management</header><subsection id="iddc8e3948735a4289ab8303bc3957d104"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the request and direction of the Assistant Secretary, the Network shall provide an integrated science and technology perspective to assist the Office of Environmental Management in implementing and enhancing established, technology-focused strategic plans, roadmaps, and program management protocols as necessary to incorporate leading program management practices and facilitate safe, timely, and cost-efficient cleanup of sites.</text></subsection><subsection id="id575270accf1b4413b1627c18f4945512"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technology development and deployment framework</header><paragraph id="idf604b2194c194a39aa4e7bd031f4446a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall direct the Network, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary, to develop and update biennially a framework to be known as the <quote>Technology Development and Deployment Framework</quote> that outlines—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8dfda41283934a68a54dfd4fb9aa39f4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the key science and technology objectives of the Office of Environmental Management; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id042fdeca2c3744f99f4f52e0dd72fe99"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an integrated strategy to assist the Office of Environmental Management in—</text><clause id="id7226179675c741d1b8aefa9cb34ab1b9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>selecting safe, effective, and cost-efficient approaches to resolve technically complex challenges or reduce the cost, time, and scope associated with the cleanup mission;</text></clause><clause id="id16c021a089844807a58ea97c6901623b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>advancing the development, demonstration, and deployment of new innovations, such as alternate treatment technologies, disposal methods, and other capabilities; and</text></clause><clause id="idf0a53902333b4c3d96002442181448da"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>maximizing the benefits of existing research and technology investments.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idae78a30dc8944fd7bd2aa2fca1a83bcc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The Framework shall complement and support existing program management protocols, strategic plans, and roadmaps of the Office of Environmental Management and, at minimum, shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide5121dc33c3c47cb9e81206e10eda21d"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emphasize support for a wide of range of research and technology development activities, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idec22f8b16f8d4beea19f913dfe1b3357"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applied technology research and technology development programs that seek to—</text><subclause id="id53d103da73cc471a9448f4f633151b52"><enum>(I)</enum><text>improve existing technologies or mature early concept and emerging technologies as specified under section 4406A(a) of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2586a">50 U.S.C. 2586a(a)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause><subclause id="id5771d0b984574b2596a74565e5d0c00f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>pursue breakthrough innovations or improvements to the cleanup mission that substantially lower lifecycle cleanup costs and schedules or address technically complex cleanup challenges, as specified under section 4406A(b) of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2586a">50 U.S.C. 2586a(b)</external-xref>);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6d3a919e7b6146609ee5268bea2aa1a8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>basic research;</text></clause><clause id="idc1333a7f5b70497e8e20e3384bedfcab"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>scientific studies and technical issue resolution to support evaluation and selection of technologies for insertion into the cleanup mission; and</text></clause><clause id="id024c1435fad84d4490c3d9c14af9bb89"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>research that addresses both near-term, site-specific needs and long-term, program-wide needs;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf32c649e5b914eb8843ca3740f44b722"><enum>(B)</enum><text>summarize the major focus areas and objectives of the science and technology efforts of the Office of Environment Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida41105a9ffa54f6c96f2e1c17f81e0cd"><enum>(C)</enum><text>detail plans to leverage relevant advances and expertise in other technology development programs across the Department, the National Laboratories, academia, private industry, and other technology providers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3831f91293c541869a7b26a1951f99ce"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support the development or maintenance of a workforce pipeline that leverages the capabilities of institutions of higher education, especially those serving minority or historically underserved populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id109bed78b01f4150a26277796d70d833"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Corrective action plans</header><text>Section 4713 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/2753">50 U.S.C. 2753</external-xref>) is amended by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb73fb2f36b84c0c8b5ad2c5abe72485"><subsection id="id441020e7d8be4bdc8c60206dd2f2cee9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Corrective action plans for defense environmental cleanup projects</header><text>If a root cause analysis for a defense environmental cleanup project is required under the project management protocols of the Department of Energy or under subsection (c)(3), then—</text><paragraph id="idc325196e27604291ac89deb5e6582a4a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the site contracting entity, in consultation with the site manager and Assistant Secretary, shall develop a corrective action plan to address the underlying causes for the cost or schedule change identified in the analysis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc16a9495b1574e1fba747427a8c4234a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary, at the conclusion of the corrective action plan, shall—</text><subparagraph id="id0862aa94049c41608b8e608cd65b8973"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an independent review that includes an assessment and validation of the efficacy of the corrective measures utilized;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5d0075eeeb6b4edabb03b82e90c71034"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees the outcome of the assessment described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc539fc89907b44798a2f8c5646182f05"><enum>(C)</enum><text>certify to the appropriate congressional committees that program management measures are in place to manage the cost and schedule of the project and mitigate against future cost overruns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

