<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2CBC4315009249C185DF0081BF028EC0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8025 IH: Protecting American Streaming and Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8025</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for an investigation of Canadian digital trade practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7DCBFE2F4DCE4BFDA959775799EF99D7" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5FABFD30ED5C403897EC693ADE154AAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting American Streaming and Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4158323DEA1544D1BB77B55B93FAE5E0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA59792B3145D42C19B74A02E9100C965"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Digital trade is a critical engine of the United States economy, allowing American companies to deliver innovative audiovisual and audio products and services globally, creating high-paying jobs in the United States and exporting American culture and values.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H801DCA7AC8D847A98949B845B70DD0A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA), which entered into force on July 1, 2020, includes a robust digital trade chapter intended to prevent discriminatory barriers and ensure a level playing field for North American digital service providers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90DE482C543C4A8E9C806BC8648F363A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canada’s law, the Online Streaming Act, empowers Canadian regulators to apply <quote>contribution</quote> and <quote>discoverability</quote> obligations to audio and audio-visual content, resulting in a revenue-based tax that targets American companies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9FE205137CE48EE86302A165493AA93"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Canada has chosen to exempt domestic streaming companies from these obligations, while applying strict obligations to U.S.-based companies. The contribution obligations currently require U.S. companies to pay mandatory high-percentage contributions based on models derived from traditional broadcasters and direct these funds exclusively to domestic cultural funds. They also require U.S. audio streaming companies to pay twice because royalties paid by audio services to Canadian rightsholders are included in services’ taxable revenue. Discoverability obligations potentially require U.S. companies to undertake costly and technically burdensome platform modifications, including the implementation of invasive data collection and reporting systems, to enforce content prioritization or quotas. These obligations are discriminatory and place a disproportionate burden on United States commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6FDF549037584012851D0307F5109F7E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These measures appear to contravene Canada’s commitments under the USMCA to provide non-discriminatory treatment to United States digital products and services and avoid unnecessary barriers to digital trade, and appear to be unreasonable, discriminatory, and excessively burdensome towards United States commerce. These measures also appear to be a prohibited performance requirement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA442D9CFB1E433B97980C54DCF5D3B6"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canada has invoked the USMCA <quote>cultural industries</quote> exception to defend measures like the Online Streaming Act that affect audiovisual and music services. However, the exception traces to the Canada-U.S. Free Trade Agreement era and retains a legacy definition of <quote>cultural industry</quote> centered on traditional publishing, recordings, and broadcasting, rather than modern means of digital delivery.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H179E44963A6F483FB4A7165218A9354B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If left unchecked, Canada’s discriminatory digital policies will set a harmful global precedent, encouraging other nations to adopt similar protectionist digital sovereignty regimes that target successful United States streaming companies and content producers. Trading partners such as Australia, Brazil, Israel, and others have adopted or are considering similar discriminatory digital policies that primarily impact U.S.-based services. Additionally, even within Canada, Quebec is considering an overlapping regime targeting United States companies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C8C850D804940D2A95BB6E066B52BE5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>It is in the national economic interest of the United States to enforce its rights under trade agreements and statutory authorities and take appropriate action to address foreign practices that are unreasonable, discriminatory, and burden or restrict United States commerce.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H26F5113DF08D4DB9ADE5A846AFB8D64E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Investigation of Canadian digital trade practices</header> 
<subsection id="HCF8B020035FD490E94CB4533ABF1D87C">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Trade Representative shall initiate an investigation under section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411</external-xref>) to determine whether Canada’s implementation of its Online Streaming Act (Bill C-11), including the related regulatory actions of the Canadian Radio-television and Telecommunications Commission (CRTC), constitutes an act, policy, or practice that is unreasonable or discriminatory and burdens or restricts United States commerce.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD9F155C1611A4BB69FEE1C608986EE95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultations</header><text>In conducting the investigation required by subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8BD94EDB6AE84528A993039F13F9FD37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with affected United States businesses providing online audiovisual or audio streaming services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6AB5E4F230B4256A3A67528204A42F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek information from relevant trade associations, labor representatives, and cultural organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50ACCF9D47B84AB1AE9F95F59A21AB36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate with the Department of Commerce, the Department of State, and the United States International Trade Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26C8185305984E55B2D2899EDC9BBBE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determinations and action</header> 
<paragraph id="H29FAEA9E10F14873823245BAAFE876E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affirmative determination</header><text>If the Trade Representative makes an affirmative determination under subsection (a), the Trade Representative shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H7DFEC233F4F546C6BED427A7D4FFEFC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publish such determination in the Federal Register; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H984F133B1A0A479295AB98C73FF04329"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider appropriate action under section 301(c) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411(c)</external-xref>), which may include the suspension of trade agreement benefits or imposition of duties commensurate with the burden imposed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H183C3DFEBCB04D0597AC111B80A926D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Negative determination</header><text>If the Trade Representative makes a negative determination under subsection (a) and determines that no action described in paragraph (1)(B) is warranted, the Trade Representative shall transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a report explaining the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2FED9255B84149C9A9AA18D74B537757"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H157BDB3E148B4CFCB0F293BBE16972D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Trade Representative shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text> <paragraph id="HB44D4B28DCEC440CA2DC531B25A999C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation of the requirements of section 3;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E7D71933E4D4B339A51A0727FFF3414">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Canada’s regulatory implementation schedule for the Online Streaming Act (Bill C-11); and</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76C9B8F400FE4D6AB884F0860C82DCAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the preliminary findings on the impact of these measures on United States digital service providers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA344D92B9D62411784B851A6E4D24EFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quarterly updates</header><text>The Trade Representative shall submit updates to the report required by subsection (a) on a quarterly basis for a period of two years describing—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB285217D62514C34A17BD33FB009011B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consultations held with affected stakeholders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE96D9B17433453F9698D90208281903"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any remedial or enforcement actions undertaken; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F005B109E0F4D6EA1CEE4306D14913F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the state of bilateral engagement with Canada on digital trade issues.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC6E6D720E7BE49DDB80D3527B97CE3AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public summary</header><text>The Trade Representative shall make publicly available a non-confidential summary of each report and update submitted under this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7AA383F055BA4D59A801BA3C75769F22"><enum>5.</enum><header>Retaliatory actions if Canada fails to remedy discriminatory measures</header> 
<subsection id="H59694D75AF094B6AB133CBB9A7F2DCBB">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Determination of non-Compliance</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 180 days after publication of an affirmative determination under section 3(c)(1), the United States Trade Representative determines that Canada has not taken satisfactory steps to remove or amend the discriminatory measures identified in the investigation with respect to which the determination was made, the Trade Representative shall take appropriate action under section 301(c) of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2411">19 U.S.C. 2411(c)</external-xref>).</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H89AD0502C91A43EEB8F79946C5B8331E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Forms of action</header><text>Actions under subsection (a) may include—</text> <paragraph id="H68F13A83A3394BB2BD3EA32FF52C5676"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the suspension, withdrawal, or modification of trade agreement concessions or benefits to Canada under the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement or other agreements; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A727C8F71C74D2F8F12B2070377C961">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the imposition of additional duties on goods of Canadian origin in amounts commensurate with the harm from implementation of Canada’s Online Streaming Act (Bill C-11).</text>
        </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HFB3B9E1C54BE4E6A8C65B1EC9EF086A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice and consultation</header><text>Before taking any action under this section, the Trade Representative shall—</text> <paragraph id="H49BAAFBC950041CF9E895943AA19A7E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify the appropriate congressional committees of the proposed action; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47086C0551634541AF6F21C9AE4B22DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with affected stakeholders to ensure that measures are targeted, proportionate, and minimize unintended consequences for United States consumers and allies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC4128BBD964F4B4A94D94A08C10F3CE3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of action</header><text>The Trade Representative may terminate any action under this section if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEA86A203CAFC4AA4B6FBFAA793738007"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Canada eliminates or modifies the measures to the satisfaction of the Trade Representative; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H529E2073DF32441FA6E1D95A3B8FBF4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Trade Representative notifies Congress in writing thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9B105F55F3544BE8A31B5FF591F0D2A4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relation to other global free trade agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To the extent that any other foreign country with which the United States has in effect a free trade agreement takes actions that are similar to the actions of Canada described in section 3(a), the Trade Representative shall apply the provisions of sections 3, 4, and 5 to such other foreign country.</text> </section> <section id="HB81B297CAE72413AB1EC1D84250D0D2D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCF43BC41D9BB48CD9F225E735C5583A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H11B5DDFEC84E405B8035F990C793395C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEE97D76811F0441B9C550C79D1F0497D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Finance of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC20DE2EECF74CD7A296BD6DC2D72545"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>online streaming service</term> means any digital service delivering audiovisual or audio programming to users in Canada via the internet.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

