<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1A91218BEBD94CDF9EFB7D0A49920207" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5959 IH: North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5959</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251107">November 7, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To reauthorize the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE4DF792AAAF34F6E9F954B86F7D511A1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2E13741DD8844F628944FAB23F27E33B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H05A7525B65D24BB28BF96E6138CE70F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0024ADF0B5D3498C95E29436A4C63645"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/108/333">Public Law 108–333</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7801">22 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>) and subsequent reauthorizations of such Act aimed to promote the protection of human rights, documentation of human rights violations, transparency in the delivery of humanitarian assistance, and the importance of refugee protection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAC81F9D19B449F2ACD2A1ECAA6B9CF6"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>According to the State Department’s 2023 Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, there are <quote>widespread reports of political prisoners and detainees … most external estimates were between 80,000 and 120,000; some NGOs placed the figure as high as 200,000.</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8588D085D06B4999940B77B56B00819E">
                <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>North Korea continues to hold a number of South Koreans and Japanese abducted after the signing of the Agreement Concerning a Military Armistice in Korea, signed at Panmunjom July 27, 1953 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Korean War Armistice Agreement</quote>), and refuses to acknowledge the abduction of more than 100,000 South Koreans during the Korean War in violation of the Geneva Convention.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9BFC5B708A542C283287B80FC75DF77">
                <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>According to the State Department’s 2023 Country Reports on Human Rights Practices, there are significant human rights violations in North Korea, which include <quote>arbitrary or unlawful killings, including extrajudicial killings; enforced disappearance; torture or cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment; … and extensive gender based-violence.</quote>.</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFB4F29B8F87497E9BC45046A807788A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The effects of the COVID–19 pandemic and North Korea’s strict lockdown of its borders and crackdowns on informal market activities and small entrepreneurship have drastically increased food insecurity for its people and given rise to famine conditions in parts of the country.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC469516702AA40359DDC2E76EAFC6D88"><enum>(6)</enum><text>North Korea’s COVID–19 border lockdown measures also include shoot-to-kill orders that have resulted in the killing of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF63E82D6C1C4A7CBA7D2653D1A8207C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>North Koreans attempting to cross the border; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H822BEBD4B55946F3A686E3A67B42389D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least 1 South Korean official in September 2020.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H169DCE7A9970433F86AA4372108C064B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Government of the People’s Republic of China is aiding and abetting North Korea’s human rights violations by forcibly repatriating North Korean refugees to North Korea where they are sent to prison camps, harshly interrogated, and tortured or executed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB0D5620DF384236BA0DA78559C52318"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>The forcible repatriation of North Korean refugees violates the People’s Republic of China’s freely undertaken obligation to uphold the principle of non-refoulement, as a state party to the Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees, done at Geneva July 28, 1951 (and made applicable by the Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees, done at New York January 31, 1967 (19 UST 6223)).</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E435C13A9E747D4B3D0986CF368CD7D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>North Korea continues to deny freedom of religion and persecute religious minorities, especially Christians and followers of Shaminism. Eyewitnesses report that Christians in North Korea have been tortured, forcibly detained, and even executed for possessing a Bible or professing Christianity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DBE6212B0764BF29405DA762CF3A3EA"> <enum>(10)</enum> <text>The position of Special Envoy on North Korean Human Rights Issues was vacant from January 2017 to December 2022, even though the President is required to appoint a Senate-confirmed Special Envoy to fill this position in accordance with section 107 of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7817">22 U.S.C. 7817</external-xref>). In January 2023, President Biden nominated Julie Turner as Special Envoy on North Korean Human Rights and Issues. She was confirmed in July 2023.</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H08E859E819004B9EA8AA22AE66CE10DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HFCCBC80ACEB542A3B6CAD78494C05C66"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the human rights and humanitarian conditions within North Korea remain deplorable and have been intentionally perpetuated against the people of North Korea through policies endorsed and implemented by Kim Jong-Un and the Government of North Korea;</text>
            </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6950C35946BA4BAF830319C2422B5405"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promoting information access in North Korea continues to be a successful method of countering DPRK propaganda and the United States Government should continue to support nongovernmental radio broadcasting to North Korea and promote other emerging methods in this space;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA68951F14C414D3AAAABE75800E76201"><enum>(3)</enum><text>because refugees among North Koreans fleeing into the People’s Republic of China face severe punishments upon their forcible return, the United States should urge the Government of the People’s Republic of China—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1CC44C304ED040BDB90A52A19F80161F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to immediately halt its forcible repatriation of North Koreans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC6D116E357540C5B5BA01F7BA1A5628"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to allow the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (referred to in this section as <quote>UNHCR</quote>) unimpeded access to North Koreans within China to determine whether they are refugees and require assistance;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0E142812BE584FB0894CA6EBB5CF5658">
                    <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to fulfill its obligations as a state party to the Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees, done at Geneva July 28, 1951 (and made applicable by the Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees, done at New York January 31, 1967 (19 UST 6223)), and the Agreement on the upgrading of the UNHCR Mission in the People’s Republic of China to UNHCR branch office in the People’s Republic of China, done at Geneva December 1, 1995;</text>
                </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A8D0EAABE1045339D8A59E62FF88FEE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to address the concerns of the United Nations Committee Against Torture by incorporating into domestic legislation the principle of non-refoulement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15CD0A632414401CA0E0A3538E77649C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to recognize the legal status of North Korean women who marry or have children with Chinese citizens and ensure that all such mothers and children are granted resident status and access to education and other public services in accordance with Chinese law and international standards;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69D2B98C41A14062AE728E8FA876FBCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States should continue to promote the effective and transparent delivery and distribution of any humanitarian aid provided in North Korea to ensure that such aid reaches its intended recipients to the point of consumption or utilization by cooperating closely with the Government of the Republic of Korea and international and nongovernmental organizations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF262F1559FF74B1082226924DA0320DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States currently blocks United States passports from being used to travel to North Korea without a special validation from the Department of State, and the Department of State should continue to take steps to increase public awareness about the risks and dangers of travel by United States citizens to North Korea;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8D3E2D20B654C17A87A0F2C4169C762"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United Nations has a significant role to play in promoting and improving human rights in North Korea and should press for access for the Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in North Korea, as well as for the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06933D0E67484A969579D3C29E98FD38"><enum>(7)</enum><text>North Korea should repeal the Reactionary Thought and Culture Denunciation Law and other draconian laws, regulations, and decrees that manifestly violate the freedom of opinion and expression and the freedom of thought, conscience, and religion;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1DABEA2C9824B92AA589639E628558E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the United States should expand the Rewards for Justice program to be open to North Korean officials who can provide evidence of crimes against humanity being committed by North Korean officials;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB61C9101C0544D7A218B1054A18506A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the United States should continue to seek cooperation from all foreign governments—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H18BAC77BD766414293917C744D97F388"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to allow the UNHCR access to process North Korean refugees overseas for resettlement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D25D2F0F8414B22ABBEFF8E9E09DBCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to allow United States officials access to process refugees for possible resettlement in the United States; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57AE4F87DAB44A8E87F3DCA80054FD8F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Secretary of State, through diplomacy by senior officials, including United States ambassadors to Asia-Pacific countries, and in close cooperation with South Korea, should make every effort to promote the protection of North Korean refugees, escapees, and defectors.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H91B86E379E404F9591E9C3C623AEB4B6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reauthorizations</header> <subsection id="HFD5B3A2712CF4B96BD7214F4686B6D59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Support for human rights and democracy programs</header><text>Section 102 of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7812">22 U.S.C. 7812</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H38C5EC15B35844F294EB528F2CF1735A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2030</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A0EE89E0322446B84E8BFDF2B8B9496"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H91F2029BA432490390F01BD2DE3FD2DA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HFA4B5A41AB5948458E43F058463B266C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually for the subsequent 5-year period, the Assistant Secretary for the Bureau of East Asia and Pacific Affairs shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the activities undertaken in the preceding 12 months to coordinate and promote efforts to improve respect for the fundamental human rights of the people of North Korea, including—</text> <paragraph id="HFA724484512F44A8B2F9F670550A3F23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any engagements in discussions with North Korean officials regarding human rights;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7FF0B15E82C2400A87B7900880B00BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any support for international efforts to promote human rights and political freedoms in North Korea, including coordination and dialogue between the United States and the United Nations, the European Union, North Korea, and the other countries in Northeast Asia;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14AF7858491B45B18D79DBC206197C6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any consultation with nongovernmental organizations that have attempted to address human rights in North Korea;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A63D836CACA45F78A759B1C62A21340"><enum>(4)</enum><text>detailed descriptions of the programs and activities supported through the funding authorized in subsection (b);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C72E83CF66B4DB08C538876A0A42464"><enum>(5)</enum><text>detailed descriptions of any strategies developed to improve human rights conditions in North Korea, including technical training and exchange programs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE78942B8F344DC4B4EB94CE448E5AB9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>an action plan for supporting the implementation of the United Nations Commission on Human Rights Resolution 2004/13.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6C02CECFA01F47B79AADD5D797981618"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions To promote freedom of information</header><text>Section 104 of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7814">22 U.S.C. 7814</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H884B9228F84C4C6AA236FF1077FB6C9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2030</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0A30F517D584AF89263B9B99765325D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2030</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0D2BC4F6068647B4AC65CFC5FD6ED4C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance provided outside of north korea</header><text>Section 203 of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7833">22 U.S.C. 7833</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA3B62A388B014F278A9F9780D8F1A07D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2), by striking <quote>103(15)</quote> and inserting <quote>103(17)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC8B90DD36DE04370BE220A8B6DADE3D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by striking <quote>2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2025 through 2030</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H262FAFFAA1D149308A961DC65250B0BB"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Annual reports</header> <text>Section 305(a) of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7845">22 U.S.C. 7845(a)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2030</quote>.</text>
            </subsection></section> 
<section id="H8CCCE44725974DB99DD6706B56065E34"><enum>5.</enum><header>Actions to promote freedom of information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7811">22 U.S.C. 7811 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H5EDA6B20149844C19062FC692D2086B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending section 103 to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA210629571B1448FA7C0BB5A9AD984CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H6A622F3353A34727819C0909F12E1FC5"><enum>103.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HD27D12F8CFFD4251B6C6B2C42459D569"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should facilitate the unhindered dissemination of information in North Korea by increasing its support for communications platforms that effectively reach the people of North Korea; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FC65BB3AEB14470AA76E6DC3CF37486"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all United States Government mediums intended to communicate directly with relevant international audiences should increase content dissemination above current levels to North Korea.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EF4E4437C9045B7AAED3EAF6D0B502C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 104(a), by striking <quote>Broadcasting Board of Governors</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>United States Government mediums intended to communicate directly with relevant international audiences</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFEDF677CDFF74F62AB969E833474CA66"><enum>6.</enum><header>Special envoy for north korean human rights issues</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 107 of the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7817">22 U.S.C. 7817</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (d) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H1FD2BDF97A9B4D0C9C9FDD632E92178B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HAF7453D333184BA1AF240ED3F89701B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on appointment of special envoy</header><text>If the position of Special Envoy will remain vacant for 1 year or longer without any presidential nomination to appoint a new Special Envoy, not later than 90 days before the date on which such position becomes vacant for 1 year, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes the efforts being taken to appoint a new Special Envoy.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H4671C07F209045D5BF08A557C5C320CB"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sense of Congress regarding Korean American divided families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H45C45D5CAF834E3084A37095E0CCEC2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States and North Korea should begin the process of reuniting Korean-American divided family members with their immediate relatives through ways such as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCA1F7625E81E4AD780418B1543CF1AB2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying divided families in the United States and North Korea who are willing and able to participate in a pilot program for family reunions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9D8094E518FB4A909944CC29CCC1EC71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>finding matches for members of such families through organizations such as the Red Cross; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A8EFC4B0D5D4CA59EDA0C47B2BE47C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>working with the Government of South Korea to include American citizens in inter-Korean video reunions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2BBF3C3FCDC44258DB12D4FF3447241"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the institution of family is inalienable and the restoration of contact between divided families whether physically, literarily, or virtually is an urgent need; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7406156E6614E3181F5307B376CFB20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States and North Korea should pursue reunions as a humanitarian priority of immediate concern.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

