<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0532B4E0ECBB4D29BE926DF861849170" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8072 IH: Safety in Shared Skies Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8072</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to test and certify each automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast out transponder system on a Department of Defense aircraft that is operated in United States airspace, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC288FFF441CC4EC281042F92EF37AF9D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBD313071ADFA4E18837F4F21D68E710B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety in Shared Skies Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD0CCA059E6FA4EC587EC049B0CC6ED38"><enum>2.</enum><header>Testing and certification of automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast out transponder systems on Department of Defense aircraft</header> <subsection id="H3B375AE1DD134F7A9C7349F1C3A61BA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Uniform standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall establish uniform standards under which the Secretary shall test and certify, at least once every 90 days, each automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast out transponder system installed on a Department of Defense aircraft if the aircraft is operated in United States airspace.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7D5ACB900B2D4BECBCD18AD39AE35F69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter until the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes, for the period covered by the report, a detailed description of the testing and certification conducted pursuant to the uniform standards established under subsection (a), including a description of any failures of an automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast out transponder system.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE13BA06A8A894DBEBC1039072A90F169"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inspector General audits</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than the date that is two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H928046C3F8434BD68CDC626168640760">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>conduct an audit to ensure the Secretary is in compliance with the testing and certification requirements under subsection (a); and</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B0A0969F63A4527B9FC184C3A12F8A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE034569D3734ABFBBE3279F7713DD6B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the audit; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6DB314E65F9A4FB1B205BB8BD745305E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the recommendation of the Inspector General as to whether the reporting requirement under subsection (b) and the audit requirement under this subsection should be extended.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

