<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H788C2DABFD5643C88F4EB4FB3FDA2BBD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8160 IH: Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder Awareness and Research Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8160</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260330">March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000381">Ms. Ansari</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001136">Mr. Conaway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To expand research, improve awareness, and increase access to treatment for individuals affected by Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEAB1B565E7A64B32AC755EFD8B378BCA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H874D0157D33D45DAB1CB185BD78AD091" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder Awareness and Research Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3976E629088E411BA8F6C21DC547F4A2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6023341FBB114C7F837B106E4ABA5859"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder (referred to in this section as <quote>PMDD</quote>) is a severe, chronic, and often disabling medical condition affecting an estimated 5 to 8 percent of women and people assigned female at birth of reproductive age. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CEBD5010A8A49399633D62262039CEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">PMDD is characterized by extreme mood shifts, irritability, depression, anger, hopelessness, tension, anxiety, and physical symptoms, such as difficulty concentrating, change in appetite, decreased energy, over or under sleeping, or joint and muscle aches, in the luteal phase of the menstrual cycle, significantly impairing work, education, and daily life. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H520CE613CA0A4AA08FE4570E4F808C11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Despite its prevalence and debilitating impact, PMDD remains under-diagnosed, under-researched, and stigmatized. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3252213ED5EB49C58CEF26FE1F516364"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Early detection, effective treatment, and increased public and provider awareness are essential to improving quality of life for individuals living with PMDD.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE817BF9602874C26A1F52921C916965B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research with respect to Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder (PMDD)</header> 
<subsection id="HFEEE7C599EC74CA98AF3ABE0D90599FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6185D9F6B46C41E9A2BDB57FBACD6FDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand and intensify research on Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder (referred to in this section as <quote>PMDD</quote>), including the causes, risk factors, diagnosis, and treatment of PMDD;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C77266351F141E9A1A95E9EFEC794FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support clinical trials to develop improved treatment options for PMDD; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE985DAA009494E4E9ACDE038B5461BBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure adequate representation of diverse racial, ethnic, and socioeconomic populations in PMDD-related research.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA13CE7A876254A17976DF119601BB2D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Surveillance and Data Collection</header><text>The Secretary shall collect and publish data on—</text> <paragraph id="HD814E1C5177C4564A6307BC61BCC13C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the prevalence and incidence of PMDD across populations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D220F3FDA9B4C648FFD5AFC2946729E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the economic and workforce impact of PMDD; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC938DA193DFC4BF8AB1F1C9078843F3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>barriers to diagnosis and treatment of PMDD.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2F26E0F930164C0687F48AC9D8DA2F80"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as is necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HBA2B5ECC584244AFAE5C11F00B145C4C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Education and dissemination of information with respect to Premenstrual Dysphoric Disorder (PMDD)</header> <subsection id="HEDA563140AD54B7ABADEFD91502D93E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a public health awareness campaign that is designed to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H800CCB8F33FC492A981FAAB7CF16528B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>raise patient and health care provider awareness of PMDD symptoms and treatment options;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41578CD47D7D4502A172058B621726EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce stigma associated with menstrual health conditions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F3EC500421A4B81942AF2DFB3F40E13"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourage individuals to seek timely medical care.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8C8AFC7731824EF4A3C775D3F12E8B22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provider education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall develop, and disseminate, continuing medical education materials to ensure that health care providers have sufficient knowledge—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEA03EB3EB8FF4992B9458526DC314BEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to accurately diagnose PMDD;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42AF9D9A28754BF5AC98845002B3CFA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to distinguish PMDD from other mental health and gynecological conditions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8DF08E8E383243259023797A849B0338"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide evidence-based care.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H80810D9209224F8A9E398224F39EBDD9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with existing awareness, education, and outreach programs and activities of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD3F7D5948CB843D68B419E75470208CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as is necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H42C92CF0FE42490E94342E20D5F9995C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants To train health professionals with respect to PMDD</header> <subsection id="H7B60BC282FC342AD8A140812FE6A2EEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities for the purpose described in subsection (b). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H40E64023B798476BBBE5A430ADC8DB0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be used to develop, establish, or expand training programs (including accredited residency programs, fellowships, or other related clinical training) for physicians, registered nurses, nurse practitioners, physician assistants, pharmacists, other health care providers, and students and trainees to improve care, treatment, or management services for PMDD.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4B53D2F708C14D7899C062C28E5EC667"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an entity shall— </text> 
<paragraph id="HE8533AD5BB2D4E4B9022936499412DCF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be— </text> <subparagraph id="H60D16E122AE94542BCC004F9BB0A074C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an accredited school of medicine or osteopathic medicine; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE97B3E4F672D4BF094D09CB811CCE4A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an accredited nursing school; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H893428828E0242CE8A3324722B3709E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an accredited school of pharmacy; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB68DAAC0DB041B583F8C963E4827675"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an accredited public or nonprofit private hospital; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F56E0DA83A540A18CD1EB4ABEED2D27"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an accredited medical residency program; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9CB6DDA1151E4F308663B5D4C2B496F0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an accredited nurse practitioner residency program; or </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0EF7A741DFDF444FA0BAE6E1BD94146A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a related training program for clinicians, allied health professionals, or social workers that interface with affected populations, which may include hospitals and research institutions, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC1FA64DE9B5D4D3180036D273A394372"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H99B0AAA8C06A4E298F490E45349A0C81"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training opportunities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall expand outreach activities to support and expand training programs, fellowships, and other opportunities for students, faculty, and trainees (including continuing medical education) or establish new training opportunities to address barriers to access to— </text> 
<paragraph id="H7E7E395988F648579CACFEED1DDDEAE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>primary and specialty care services to support mid-life women’s health; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD17FDDD1AD64B38A4A32F5773A4D622"><enum>(2)</enum><text>early detection, diagnosis, treatment, and care services for perimenopause, menopausal symptoms, and related chronic conditions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H78A1F9D576D64C00B87D798BB6979C62"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as is necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H34A0608BD63940ADA9C0E5B296A45E2A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report on impacts on PMDD research and treatment</header> <subsection id="H2959E709A5904FC7849891CBEC9022EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on progress made in—</text> 
<paragraph id="H43C1EF3C80194B82A5C87387EBAC53AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expanding PMDD research;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC77503F413144529191C75C4C9B21FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improving awareness of, and education on, PMDD; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2D2BFB445F9B4DF18DD9CF2C75C59C01"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing access to diagnosis of, and treatment for, PMDD.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2B6681FD5B90444CB7AFB0763035C24A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as is necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

