<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA26466-LFG-PN-X2Y"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4418 IS: Lowering Input Costs for American Farmers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4418</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260428">April 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S411">Mr. Marshall</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit the imposition of any duty on the importation of phosphate fertilizers under section 122 or 301 of the Trade Act of 1974, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lowering Input Costs for American Farmers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id8c0f14e42c5b4bc5804ffaaf39a266a0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Access to phosphate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1304">19 U.S.C. 1304 et seq.</external-xref>), beginning on the date that is 7 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, any duty imposed under section 122 or 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2132 and 2411) shall not apply to any article—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9be8771a48e44afa91b1e91ac0b512a"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">classified under heading 3103 or 3105 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b36d75faef84e0a8e40571ee2fd65b1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">imported from the Kingdom of Morocco.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id86f09a2be8ce4f27a71d865c4d0135ba"><enum>3.</enum><header>Revocation of countervailing duty orders</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd55e0cc98aa3488199b89d1c3f75782a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective on the date that is 4 business days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the countervailing duty orders issued with respect to phosphate fertilizers imported from the Kingdom of Morocco and the Russian Federation (issued on April 7, 2021) shall have no force or effect with respect to imports from the Kingdom of Morocco.</text></subsection><subsection id="iddcad5d43a9834c62b0239b193a1a3b88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Beginning on the date described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Commerce shall promptly take any necessary action to ensure that no duty or cash deposit is collected in violation of subsection (a), with the exception of any duty assessed pursuant to an administrative review that was completed before the date described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id024721e3dcaa4f9ebfcf13a66c93b766"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Refund</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall refund to the importer of record any cash deposits paid by the importer pursuant to the orders described in subsection (a) with respect to an import from the Kingdom of Morocco that do not fall into the exception described in subsection (b).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

