<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09E4844836764B789EEF8DF70676B887" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7292 IH: To amend the National Quantum Initiative Act to require a biennial report on the progress of the Subcommittee on Quantum Information Science of the National Science and Technology Council in implementing the national workforce strategic plan, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7292</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260130">January 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000622">Mr. Riley of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Quantum Initiative Act to require a biennial report on the progress of the Subcommittee on Quantum Information Science of the National Science and Technology Council in implementing the national workforce strategic plan, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45D8D5D5566548A599634A7F80DADD40" style="OLC"><section id="H7AE839B8CD1E4372959E6DD8C2436097" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Biennial reports on progress of the Subcommittee on Quantum Information Science in implementing the national workforce strategic plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (f) of section 103 of the National Quantum Initiative Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8813">15 U.S.C. 8813</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentences: <quote>The chairpersons shall biennially submit to the President, the Advisory Committee, and the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the progress of the Subcommittee in implementing the relevant strategic plan developed under subsection (e) and any updates thereto. Each such report shall include a description of such progress and of any challenges encountered, as well as any planned updates to address evolving workforce needs.</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

