<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H9DA641A0190644409C67E946CFBE9134" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9328 : Improving Travel for Military Members Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9328</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve travel for active-duty military personnel and accompanying family, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H124195F2EC4C45F9A244EF4366DA5D59" style="OLC"><section id="HA625CE8F03E745629D93A65B3FB2159E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Travel for Military Members Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6D842D5214F04650BC7268DDEA14BBE8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving travel for active-duty military personnel and accompanying family</header><subsection id="H559F578FA6D84C5A8F7054AB2E1EE429" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) may establish a pilot program at airports to expedite access to security screening for traveling active-duty military personnel and accompanying family members to support and facilitate the ease of travel for such personnel and family members. The Administrator may carry out this subsection only to the extent such access does not compromise security protocols.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD43AA01A89554DD3936480788B46056A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Security requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), the Administrator shall carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="HA048142793E04B2386DBB139B8AC91AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Ensure each passenger described in such subsection is screened in accordance with the vetting status of such passenger under the Secure Flight program of the Transportation Security Administration, in accordance with paragraph (2) of section 44903(j) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3D7EF4AF3746DFAC9C9F5A1DBA0032"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Prevent individuals carrying out screening functions under section 44901 of such title from allowing any passenger into a TSA PreCheck or other expedited security screening lane unless such passenger has received a boarding pass indicating eligibility for TSA PreCheck or such other expedited security screening.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57940993EF8445A6B92605FD4FD06160"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Permit local Administration management to open or close checkpoint lanes and reallocate available resources as needed to maximize security effectiveness and efficiency based on passenger volume.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8095832C246845C79477D4C9D3D421F0" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection of airports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), in selecting airports for such pilot program, the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H8EF748A1434E4A21ABFD517DC70F47B6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give priority to an airport that is not more than a certain distance, as determined by the Administrator, from a military installation (as such term is defined in section 2801 of title 10, United States Code) to which not fewer than a certain number, as determined by the Administrator, of active-duty military personnel are stationed; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4390194AD864AA7BB43193FC8597F37" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider airports with adequate space to accommodate dedicated screening lanes for traveling active-duty military personnel and accompanying family members; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2053A4BC072F4096920F5E80B83260E5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>use any other consideration the Administrator determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D67417BE90648289DC6AC6BC878F679" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), not later than nine months after such establishment, the Administrator shall provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a briefing on such pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H24C5B07A370A4FB49DD6B6C14DF6CEC1" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>If the Administrator establishes the pilot program under subsection (a), the Administrator shall carry out such pilot program for a period of three years.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260713" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 13, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

