<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H77E75261A6484E579C8919A6B28F9643" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6629 IH: Developing Master Plans for Military Service Academies Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6629</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct each Secretary of a military department to develop a master plan for each Service Academy under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6BE29CB560C64204897117BBA3FE408E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H40B3E3F0DFCA4685852B08090CDDEA01" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing Master Plans for Military Service Academies Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H45F48FDFB9DE4000A4D078DC57D269A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Master plans for Service Academies</header> 
<subsection id="HBD6B8B782FC24D56820C577FDDF161A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plans required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Secretary of a military department shall develop a master plan for each Service Academy under the jurisdiction of the Secretary to comprehensively address infrastructure requirements of such Service Academy. Each master plan shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H1F79D93B9E2C4B029476A4BA74C5A904"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Consideration of the requirements of subparagraphs (A) through (D) of section 2864(a)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H03B2F4D83356448A8E7769E02F1F4DFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For the Service Academy that is the subject of a master plan—</text> <subparagraph id="HC74976E340F84AF8ADCD2932FB995F36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of infrastructure located at the Service Academy that is in poor or failing condition on or before the date described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H974D252588454C37AFD3E642CEDAA403"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a plan for replacing, recapitalizing, or renovating such infrastructure not later than five years after such date; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16B35460DFE8473080EE40DFAD71171D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of infrastructure located at the Service Academy that—</text> 
<clause id="HE55765C93E114A3F8249261F540D3F96"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is listed on the National Register of Historic Places (maintained under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3021">chapter 3021</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code) on or before the date described in subsection (b); or</text></clause> <clause id="HED1B23B2A4FA4E72AF2D981DE009FCC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will be eligible inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB31A8CB26E2C4D19B22EC0281464504A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of risks posed by disruptions in energy availability, risks posed by extreme weather (as defined in section 101 of title 10 m United States Code), cybersecurity risks, and risks related to availability of clean water applicable to the Service Academy that is the subject of a master plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7078597822E74B73A38940BAC5DB7A60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each master plan required under subsection (a) shall propose a method to address the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (3) of such subsection not later than five years after the date described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H623C4DDCF497428D89F10A839169AD40"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each master plan required under subsection (a) shall be completed no later than September 30, 2027.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC86078903E7A4CAB85D685DF4385B8DA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, each Secretary of a military department shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on the timeline for the completion of the master plans required under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H30131D9AC9384F3A9A4A1BD1659CBCA1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Submission of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which a Secretary of a military department completes a master plan required under subsection (a) or December 1, 2027, whichever is earlier, the Secretary shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a copy of the master plan.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3E42E61EB08E427D8ABC00FC920E2AE9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Service Academy defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Service Academy</quote> has the meaning given in section 347 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

