<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RIL26682-F3J-RF-K5F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4979 IS: Protecting Retirement Opportunities and Maintaining Income Security for Everyone Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4979</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S287">Mr. Cornyn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S440">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a process to assure the long-term fiscal stability of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Retirement Opportunities and Maintaining Income Security for Everyone Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROMISE Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idb351fb6d0dc94a5b99d218b666bcc889"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of process to assure Social Security Solvency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting the following after section 201:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id705e775a191e4ae79291a9995beda639"><section id="ida027f136a1044ebc8914bc2bd2f89abe" commented="no"><enum>201A.</enum><header>Establishment of process to assure Social Security solvency</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id8cdf2ef5d47e48b69ac9be9cbdb11e17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="ida4292d9903534d40a6b340ba6e4daa46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Long-term solvency</header><text>The term <term>long-term solvency</term> means the financial ability of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund to pay 100 percent of scheduled benefits for a period of at least 50 years that begins on the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb8f8dccda49e41ed94a709a63f2d15df"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Social security bill</header><text>The term <term>Social Security bill</term> means a bill introduced pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(B)(i) or subsection (c)(1)(B)(ii).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id781008747d934c98952b7f8959358735"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Social Security Advisory Board</header><paragraph id="idd597288956924beab670336d51bde974"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Social Security Advisory Board (established under section 703) shall develop recommendations and legislative language to achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds. Such legislative language shall not include provisions that do not change outlays, revenues, or financing with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under this title, the supplemental security income program under title XVI, or the related provisions in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d30d5d619b84cb98e3ac4b7d8ea065e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Request for information</header><text>The Social Security Advisory Board shall, for the purpose of carrying out this section, issue a request for information to the public regarding ways to achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f1da4e2042e4c07b1c2e3b1076887b0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public listening sessions</header><subparagraph id="idbb7924f4e08c404c88876a9b613a9535"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Social Security Advisory Board shall, for the purpose of carrying out this subsection, hold such public listening sessions, sit and act at such times and places, require attendance of stakeholders and production of books, papers, and documents, take such testimony, receive such evidence, and administer such oaths as the Social Security Advisory Board considers advisable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id207dfbb2a95641f6a7bb6071bed42764"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedures</header><clause id="id5b9a6a1e6d5647c6b635c799758036da"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Announcement</header><text>The Social Security Advisory Board shall make a public announcement of the date, place, time, and subject matter of any public listening session to be conducted under this subparagraph not later than 7 calendar days before the date of the public listening session, unless the Chair of the Social Security Advisory Board determines that there is good cause to begin such public listening session on an earlier date.</text></clause><clause id="idbb2ef628435b441692330638a0641b93"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Written statement</header><text>A stakeholder appearing before the Social Security Advisory Board shall file a written statement of the proposed testimony of the stakeholder not later than 2 calendar days before the date of the appearance of the witness, unless the Chair of the Social Security Advisory Board—</text><subclause id="id4af2b4eca4704ab6a9dfa96f7b9c1183"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determines that there is good cause for the stakeholder to not file the written statement; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id85bca00000ff4b22abe090ad18604b64"><enum>(II)</enum><text>waives the requirement that the stakeholder file the written statement.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0b8345cdeb0b4c4faa637878ceca46ac"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical assistance and consultation</header><text>Upon written request from the Chair of the Social Security Advisory Board, the head of a Federal agency (including a legislative branch agency) shall provide technical assistance to, and consult with, the Social Security Advisory Board in order for the Social Security Advisory Board to carry out its duties under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2b9fbb920c34072ada944646f650e5b"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Assistance from Federal agencies</header><text>Upon request from the Chair of the Social Security Advisory Board—</text><subparagraph id="idd40452cbe3b44aa9ae8e39e8381c37f8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Architect of the Capitol shall provide suitable space to house the operations of the Social Security Advisory Board to carry out its duties under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id817d6c6f09f74440b820d9c389f88fdf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Administrator of General Services shall provide the administrative support services and security services necessary for the Social Security Advisory Board to carry out its duties under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcb966d4bcc794676990e2b31ded1c51e"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Temporary exemption</header><text>Members of the Social Security Advisory Board may, for the purpose of carrying out this subsection, work more than 130 days during any period of 365 consecutive days on a full-time basis to carry out their duties under this subsection without such work days being counted against the 130 day limitation under section 202 of title 18, United States Code. The exemption provided under this paragraph shall terminate after the Social Security Advisory Board submits a report to Congress under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide3837542543b43d68125590003d4581a"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than September 14, 2026, the Social Security Advisory Board shall submit to Congress, and make available to the public, a report that contains detailed recommendations and proposed legislative language that meets the requirements described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idecff7dc4183b40c48d9a6686888874c3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration of a Social Security bill</header><paragraph id="ida61b7ebb81ff42eea61c0e9a6de9d0a7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Introduction</header><subparagraph id="idcca320cfc35e4aeba6085ab3d7695b53"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reconvening</header><clause id="id5a9beb9a0a1c41f0a02694a941a83343"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In the Senate</header><subclause id="id875c7e8b89464010afe6cc1c6fac9625"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Convening</header><text>Upon receipt of the report under subsection (b), if the Senate has adjourned or recessed for more than 2 calendar days, the Majority Leader of the Senate, after consultation with the Minority Leader of the Senate, shall notify the Members of the Senate that, pursuant to this section, the Senate shall convene not later than 5 calendar days after receipt of such report.</text></subclause><subclause id="ide82b3d5b0a0345579195b48d61169186"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Adjourning</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3)(A)(vi), no concurrent resolution providing for the adjournment of the Senate for more than 3 calendar days shall be in order until the Senate votes on passage of the Social Security bill under paragraph (3)(A)(v).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idf5e3c74e8ac14ce296d2e628050addc0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>In the House of Representatives</header><subclause id="idf851e641f71549788ede6b7f1973c074"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Convening</header><text>Upon receipt of the report under subsection (b), if the House of Representatives has adjourned or recessed for more than 2 calendar days, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, after consultation with the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives, shall notify the Members of the House that, pursuant to this section, the House shall convene not later than 5 calendar days after receipt of such report.</text></subclause><subclause id="idb29625e10517421ebd7340af60bdcd05"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Adjourning</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3)(B)(ix), no concurrent resolution providing for the adjournment of the House of Representatives for more than 3 calendar days shall be in order until the House votes on passage of the Social Security bill under paragraph (3)(B)(vii).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9f0ff8c0ddae408996e887e8ea75c7a7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Introduction of Social Security bill</header><clause id="idcaba1a6b9c6e418aae18bcd8c3d8e69c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Social Security Advisory Board legislative language</header><text>The proposed legislative language contained in the report submitted pursuant to subsection (b), upon receipt by the Congress, shall (by request) be introduced not later than September 17, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the Senate and House of Representatives are in session, by the Majority Leader of each House of Congress, for himself, or any member of either House designated by the Majority Leader. If the Social Security bill is not introduced in accordance with the preceding sentence in either House of Congress, then any Member of that House may introduce the Social Security bill on any day thereafter. Upon introduction, the Social Security bill shall be referred to the appropriate committees under subparagraph (C).</text></clause><clause id="id2fc3e038b41345d0b681c3ad51a25426" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Members of Congress legislative language</header><subclause id="id04f7e5c63f3b4b108b39459b8c2ce6eb" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case that the Social Security Advisory Board does not submit proposed legislative language pursuant to subsection (b), not later than September 17, 2026, the Majority Leader of each House of Congress, for himself, or any Member of either House designated by the Majority Leader shall (by request) introduce legislative language subject to subclause (II). If legislative language is not introduced in accordance with the preceding sentence in either House of Congress, then any Member of that House may introduce legislative language subject to subclause (II) on any day thereafter. Upon introduction, the legislative language shall be referred to the appropriate committees under subparagraph (C).</text></subclause><subclause id="id893a06375cb74bf38af62dbce859c57f" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Requirements</header><item id="idbed7dafc2cc6453e90f2980dd8880c8c" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In the Senate</header><text>In the Senate, such legislative language shall—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id520c766cc1e14a0b9453368b86f50056"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds, as certified by the Chairman of the Committee on Finance (in consultation with the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration);</text></subitem><subitem id="id25e4299661c14cef9ea39cae0d071846" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>not be introduced with less than 1 Member associating with the majority party and not less than 1 Member associating with the minority party; and</text></subitem><subitem id="idb68d99763b8c4e808cd3b3e7b45c9b24" commented="no"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>not include provisions that do not include changes to the outlays, revenues, or financing with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under this title, the supplemental security income program under title XVI, or the related provisions in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subitem></item><item id="id714255b3387b4ad3b73dada8e9f67634"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>In the House of Representatives</header><text>In the House of Representatives, such legislative language shall—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id26103ec497854990adcfd0b6122fc836"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds as certified by the Chairman of the Committee on Ways and Means (in consultation with the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration);</text></subitem><subitem id="id9c2645fcc10f4ce4a2811fc6913a7381"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>not be introduced with less than 1 Member associating with the majority party and not less than 1 Member associating with the minority party; and</text></subitem><subitem id="id65a4ba8375bc4588990f8e4eb71c119c"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>not include provisions that do not include changes to the outlays, revenues, or financing with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under this title, the supplemental security income program under title XVI, or the related provisions in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subitem></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc040fbe347004e3aa984bc9aa548436b"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Committee consideration</header><clause id="id4553d8ef54904c25b450519b7344c35d"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In the Senate</header><subclause id="ide8f17fc283c54508afa4a9570391e40a"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Social Security bill introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Finance (in this clause, referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subclause><subclause id="idfcc11c22b10541cd8021bd3d276accd5"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>It shall be in order for the Committee to consider and adopt amendments to the Social Security bill. It shall not be in order for the Committee to consider or adopt any amendment to the Social Security bill that causes the bill to not achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds or does not change outlays, revenues, or financing with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under this title, the supplemental security income program under title XVI, or the related provisions in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subclause><subclause id="idbcb9b975443441de9b1cf0b5ce3f791e"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Committee shall report the bill on November 9, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the Senate is in session. If the Committee fails to report the bill within that period, the Committee shall be automatically discharged from consideration of the bill, and the bill shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idb715a7002d2546a8adf50109c77cf182"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>In the House of Representatives</header><subclause id="idab82474a34934c649da84db69c78e074"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Social Security bill introduced in the House of Representatives shall be referred to the Committee on Ways and Means (in this clause, referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></subclause><subclause id="id26980285d0c342998f2cb245c67e66a6"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>It shall be in order for the Committee to consider and adopt amendments to the Social Security bill. It shall not be in order for the Committee to consider or adopt any amendment to the Social Security bill that causes the bill to not achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds or does not change outlays, revenues, or financing with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under this title, the supplemental security income program under title XVI, or the related provisions in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subclause><subclause id="id65b2a7cf41a1415f8c4ce1341954d7b1"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Committee shall report the bill on November 9, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the House is in session. If the Committee fails to report the bill within that period, the Committee shall be automatically discharged from consideration of the bill, and the bill shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idddc71819f7e047fc849e52a58b736486"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Filing deadline and certification</header><subparagraph id="id2e7fb338fcb14c53ad5b05f952956a0a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Filing deadline</header><clause id="id06d62d18b72a4339aaa987d406ee0264"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In the Senate</header><text>Not later than November 9, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the Senate is in session, Members may file substitute amendments, and amendments shall be printed in the Congressional Record on the day such amendments are filed.</text></clause><clause id="id532f215c42184bc88782059ce7f737a2"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>In the House of Representatives</header><text>Not later than November 9, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which that House of Representatives is in session, Members may file substitute amendments, and such amendments shall be printed in the Congressional Record on the day such amendments are filed.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id745354b76c894c1f95cbaf128a626a23"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certification</header><clause id="id3ba4b35ef421482582bd831d0d3f3814"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In the Senate</header><text>Not later than November 16, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the Senate is in session, the Chairman of the Finance Committee (in consultation with the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration and the Parliamentarian of the Senate) shall certify whether the complete substitute amendments filed under subparagraph (A)(i) meet the criteria described in items (aa) and (bb) of paragraph (3)(A)(iii)(II) and print the list of certified amendments in the Congressional Record.</text></clause><clause id="id4e2702a914a04f7f9abfccf7fb9bb6e1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>In the House of Representatives</header><text>Not later than November 16, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the House of Representatives is in session, the Chairman of the Ways and Means Committee (in consultation with the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration and Parliamentarian of the House of Representatives) shall certify whether the complete substitute amendments filed under subparagraph (A)(ii) meet the criteria described in items (aa) and (bb) of paragraph (3)(B)(v)(II) and print the list of certified amendments in the Congressional Record.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id93080f1ec33c4dd597162a8484b915d8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedures</header><subparagraph id="id2ff00959fac4487d9edec13193f31d56"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consideration in Senate</header><clause id="id7df482a9fd724fbcb548ea2b47d1f4c9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order, not later than November 16, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the Senate is in session, for the Majority Leader of the Senate or the Majority Leader’s designee to move to proceed to the consideration of the Social Security bill. It shall also be in order for any Member of the Senate to move to proceed to the consideration of the Social Security bill at any time after that period. A motion to proceed is in order even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to. All points of order, including budgetary points of order, against the motion to proceed to the Social Security bill are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the Social Security bill is agreed to, the Social Security bill shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text></clause><clause id="id079aeea8b8ba4cf99f7d69f23d60572d"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>All points of order, including budgetary points of order, against the Social Security bill and against consideration of the Social Security bill are waived. Consideration of the Social Security bill and of all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith shall not exceed a total of 100 hours. Debate shall be divided equally between the Majority and Minority Leaders or their designees. A motion to further limit debate on the Social Security bill is in order, shall require an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members duly chosen and sworn, and is not debatable. Any debatable motion or appeal is debatable for a period not to exceed 2 hours, to be divided equally between the Majority Leader and Minority Leader. All time used for consideration of the Social Security bill, including time used for quorum calls and voting, shall be counted against the total 100 hours of consideration.</text></clause><clause id="idba14a414a6f749b1b559b6c4c1539c9d"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Restriction on amendments and motions</header><subclause id="idc625f2981c554076a92f3d176348cd6f"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (II), an amendment to the Social Security bill, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the Social Security bill is not in order. All points of order, including budgetary points of order, against the consideration of substitute amendments to the Social Security bill are waived.</text></subclause><subclause id="id14de47ee9f8848d4a096dda5a0935d35"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Substitute amendments</header><item id="idaba3829f2a764ea4b1623ff4cf564239"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be in order in the Senate to consider any substitute amendment to the Social Security bill that, as determined by the Chairman of the Committee on Finance (in consultation with the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration), achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds, with such determination to be submitted by the Chairman for printing in the Congressional Record. It shall be in order in the Senate for the sponsor of a substitute amendment to make minor or technical modifications to such amendment.</text></item><item id="id09f6173dacde4aeba7fe979a763a2513"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Extraneous provisions</header><text>It shall not be in order in the Senate to consider any substitute amendment to the Social Security bill that—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id72f12c355f6946f2bcac87e97c315f29"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds; or</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc09dcfbf66fa4b40840f0bb2d32cb63c"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes provisions that do not change outlays, revenues, or financing with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under this title, the supplemental security income program under title XVI, or the related provisions in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subitem></item><item id="id80ff88a3779649288c9ada171a30fef5"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Limit on debate</header><text>Consideration of any amendment described in this subclause and any debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith shall be limited to 2 hours, equally divided between the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader. Adoption of a substitute amendment shall require an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members, duly chosen and sworn. An amendment described in this subclause is not divisible and no amendment to a substitute amendment shall be in order. All time used for consideration of any amendments described in this subclause shall come from the 100 hours of consideration described in clause (ii).</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="id80b7a121497b4d1c9824ad7b8e15579e"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Adoption of amendments</header><text>If more than one of the amendments described in clause (iii)(II) is adopted, then only the one receiving the greater number of affirmative votes shall be engrossed as an amendment of the Senate. In the case of a tie for the greater number of affirmative votes, then only the last amendment to receive that number of affirmative votes shall be engrossed as an amendment of the Senate. Action on all other amendments shall be vitiated.</text></clause><clause id="idc465b204eef64dd79cb635573355dd9e"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>The vote on passage shall occur immediately following the conclusion of consideration of a Social Security bill, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested. Passage shall require an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members, duly chosen and sworn. If the Social Security bill is passed, the Secretary of the Senate shall cause the bill to be transmitted to House of Representatives before the close of the next day of session of the Senate.</text></clause><clause id="idb04abe4d897749b998490ef5e314f2ba"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Adjournment</header><text>If, by December 18, 2026, either House has failed to adopt a motion to proceed to the Social Security bill, paragraph (1)(A)(i)(II) shall not apply.</text></clause><clause id="idb41b9423c8894819a4ea26bea4f6edfd"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Rulings of the Chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a Social Security bill shall be debatable for a period not to exceed 1 hour, to be divided equally between the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id614b4eec567f4e458e2763026fb8f962"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration in House of Representatives</header><clause id="idca2003c955cb42e69debadf2c1c8f594"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>It shall be in order in the House of Representatives, not later than November 16, 2026, or the first day thereafter on which the House is in session, for the Majority Leader of the House of Representatives or the Majority Leader’s designee, to move to proceed to the consideration of the Social Security bill. It shall also be in order for any Member of the House of Representatives to move to proceed to the consideration of the Social Security bill at any time after the conclusion of that period. All points of order, including budgetary points of order, against the motion to proceed to the Social Security bill are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House of Representatives has disposed of a motion to proceed on the Social Security bill. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></clause><clause id="id5706b9c0fa984f439dd1320ab9e2c711"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The Social Security bill shall be considered as read. All points of order, including budgetary points of order, against the Social Security bill and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the Social Security bill to its passage without intervening motion except 100 hours of consideration equally divided and controlled by the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader, and any motion to limit debate. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the Social Security bill shall not be in order.</text></clause><clause id="idadfbd82f550644aaa44429b31d089e6e"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Appeals from decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the Rules of the House of Representatives to the procedure relating to a Social Security bill shall be debatable for a period not to exceed 1 hour, to be divided equally between the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader.</text></clause><clause id="id0eb172d7cf904f9dbe48c685cc615656"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Application of House rules</header><text>Except to the extent specifically provided in this subparagraph, consideration of a Social Security bill shall be governed by the Rules of the House of Representatives. It shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to consider any Social Security bill introduced pursuant to the provisions of this subsection under a suspension of the rules pursuant to Clause 1 of House Rule XV, or under a special rule reported by the House Committee on Rules.</text></clause><clause id="idb18cb5c0542e40cca8ea9ca1f2e5ee57"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Restriction on amendments</header><subclause id="idf3dfcdef52d3457b8742f686c47b7b71"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subclause (II), no amendment to the Social Security bill shall be in order in the House of Representatives. All points of order, including budgetary points of order, against the consideration of substitute amendments to the Social Security bill are waived.</text></subclause><subclause id="idbbd90a00b90f46238afdd55bf9b0f50e"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Substitute amendments</header><item id="id88a1755313024edbb7a6cbc5228c3389"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be in order in the House of Representatives to consider any substitute amendment to the Social Security bill that, as determined by the Chairman of the Committee on Ways and Means (in consultation with the Chief Actuary of the Social Security Administration), achieves long-term solvency for the Trust Funds, with such determination to be submitted by the Chairman for printing in the Congressional Record. It shall be in order in the House of Representatives for the sponsor of a substitute amendment to make minor or technical modifications to such amendment.</text></item><item id="idf6affa4e32f540ef99487450d6c72f21"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Extraneous provisions</header><text>It shall not be in order in the House of Representatives to consider any substitute amendment to the Social Security bill that—</text><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c3efc0e132046a9af5e429afa276e69"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not achieve long-term solvency for the Trust Funds; or</text></subitem><subitem commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0eca81da8553432dad50cf2eb43fbbea"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes provisions that do not change outlays, revenues, or financing with respect to the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program established under title II, the supplemental security income program under title XVI, or the related provisions in the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subitem></item><item id="id76eb5ace836149d7b2980e96e96a76ac"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Limit on debate</header><text>Consideration of any amendment described in this subclause and any debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith shall be limited to 1 hour, equally divided between the Majority Leader and the Minority Leader. Adoption of a substitute amendment shall require an affirmative vote of a majority of the Members, duly chosen and sworn. An amendment described in this subclause is not divisible and no amendment to a substitute amendment shall be in order. All time used for consideration of any amendments described in this subclause shall come from the 100 hours of consideration described in clause (ii).</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idf57896cad65f4bf9813d5f10ad4d9f81"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Adoption of amendments</header><text>If more than one of the amendments described in clause (v)(II) is adopted, then only the one receiving the greater number of affirmative votes shall be engrossed as an amendment of the House. In the case of a tie for the greater number of affirmative votes, then only the last amendment to receive that number of affirmative votes shall be engrossed as an amendment of the House. Action on all other amendments shall be vitiated.</text></clause><clause id="id1fb28076e6324eb796bcdc93cf83d088"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>Immediately following the conclusion of consideration of the Social Security bill, the vote on passage of the Social Security bill shall occur without any intervening action or motion, requiring an affirmative vote of a majority of the Members, duly chosen and sworn. If the Social Security bill is passed, the Clerk of the House of Representatives shall cause the bill to be transmitted to the Senate before the close of the next day of session of the House of Representatives.</text></clause><clause id="idcefdd73e49374a2dae4f9ba97f03226c" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Vote</header><text>The House Committee on Rules may not report a rule or order that would have the effect of causing the Social Security bill to be approved by a vote of less than a majority of the Members, duly chosen and sworn.</text></clause><clause id="idfff36ee3091e44c68531272fa6790472"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Adjournment</header><text>If, by December 18, 2026, either House has failed to adopt a motion to proceed to the Social Security bill, paragraph (1)(A)(ii)(II) shall not apply.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id752ab04ddece44c69c5409174bd3e863"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rules to coordinate action with other House</header><clause id="id4657196a92654b3d8a6037ae25baccb4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>If, before the passage by one House of a Social Security bill of that House, that House receives from the other House a Social Security bill, then the Social Security bill of the other House shall not be referred to a committee and shall immediately be placed on the calendar.</text></clause><clause id="id5a4cfa94883f40fba36ce3fbbe19ca19"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>If a House that has not voted to proceed to a Social Security bill receives a Social Security bill passed by the other House—</text><subclause id="idfe90fd53f0ad485788e3550c3419141b"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the procedure in the House that has not voted to proceed to a Social Security bill shall be the same as if no such bill had been introduced in that House; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id878dbe39e461484698fe53ccbab56db0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the bill considered in that House shall be the Social Security bill of the other House.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id70d43d65274949a4b2c7824afc9925c1"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Treatment of Social Security bill of other House</header><text>If one House fails to introduce or consider a Social Security bill under this section, the Social Security bill of the other House shall be entitled to the floor procedures under this section.</text></clause><clause id="id66af40df6572491181a2f43077150b40"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Treatment of identical companion measures in either House</header><text>If, following passage of a Social Security bill in one House, that House then receives an identical companion bill from the other House, the Social Security bill of the other House shall not be debatable. The vote on passage of the Social Security bill in the House receiving the Social Security bill shall be considered to be the vote on passage of the Social Security bill received from the other House.</text></clause><clause id="id3803d728598c4fb280ce638d8702a9dc" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Treatment of different measures in either House</header><text>If, following passage of a Social Security bill in one House, that House then receives a Social Security bill from the other House that is different from the Social Security bill passed by that House, the Social Security bill passed by the other House shall be entitled to the floor procedures under this section.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id17bb8e33731e4a5a8b069fa12e8339d3"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Vetoes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the President vetoes the Social Security bill, consideration on a veto message in either House under this section shall be limited to 1 hour equally divided between the Majority and Minority Leaders or their designees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8a6b6f9c99b84fda8bd41c7093d18032" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Suspension</header><text>No motion to suspend the application of this subsection shall be in order in the Senate or in the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc2c9776bdf044dd29a6984991574719b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Decennial review</header><paragraph id="id35ef599815624234920dd822c1a8610f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Review</header><text>If the Social Security Board of Trustees submits a report to Congress pursuant to section 201(c)(2) that finds that the Trust Funds are not able to pay 100 percent of scheduled benefits for a period of at least 50 years that begins on the date such report is submitted, the Social Security Board of Trustees shall notify the Social Security Advisory Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8719c3003a954962a04455cfd39dc50d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id243a615d4f7e45e1a769f4698543c529"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Social Security bill is enacted into law under this section, the following shall apply:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id797b59621a6849609a9a543bd4461651"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Mandatory reports</header><text>If the Social Security Advisory Board receives a notice described in paragraph (1) during a covered year, the Social Security Advisory Board shall submit to Congress a report including recommendations and proposed legislative language that meets the requirements of subsection (b)(1).</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7da12b59e133446db5922c28efa3ce82"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Discretionary reports</header><text>If the Social Security Advisory Board receives a notice described in paragraph (1) during a calendar that is not a covered year, the Social Security Advisory Board may submit to Congress a report described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7a462ce9a18c4c08b97414dcc2eedec3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered year defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>covered year</term> means calendar year 2037 and every 10 years thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfa0ce422e1e94294850fdd14c7efdd4d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If Congress receives a report described in paragraph (2)(A)(i), Congress shall consider the recommendations and proposed legislative language pursuant to the process described in subsection (c), except that the dates described in such subsection and subsection (b) shall apply in the calendar year that such report is submitted.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

