<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD9D7E088E06449A0A4EE07A7E7F112C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8455 IH: Make DC Square Again Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8455</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal an Act entitled <quote>An Act to retrocede the county of
        Alexandria, in the District of Columbia, to the State of Virginia,</quote> and for other
      purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDCB46C13EC2C4BA9AA413FBD30625467" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D214EFDD8724D18A0F17B291797DC3B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Make DC Square Again Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD913EF40853B4CBBAD12B3D8BD8BCA40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7B936522B44440BCA28D3DB5492B482A">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>Article I, section 8, clause 17 of the Constitution known as the Enclave Clause enumerates the power of the Federal Government to <quote>exercise exclusive legislation in all cases whatsoever over such District (not exceeding ten miles square) as may, by cession of particular States, and the acceptance of Congress, become the seat of government of the United States</quote>.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H61C09BACF83744F8AA20F30E8F11A0E8">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The Constitution does not enumerate authority for the Federal Government to retrocede portions of such a district back to states.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC17F6BB4063C423B972C3F31CA7DE33B">
        <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>An Act of Congress approved July 16, 1790, ten miles square of territory was accepted from the States of Maryland and Virginia to serve the permanent seat of government subsequently being known as the District of Columbia.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD054DDE7D0A946FBBD0F9542D5B3AAFA">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>Act of Congress approved on July 9, 1846, the portion of the District of Columbia lying south of the Potomac River was ceded back to the State of Virginia in violation of the intent and meaning of the Constitution of the United States.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H69A539D1DF0248F2B867A7BBB69BA6E9">
        <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>Senator Benjamin Wade of Ohio introduced S. 280 to repeal the 1846 Act of retrocession on April 23, 1866, during the 1st Session of the 39th Congress.</text>
      </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4155B0A7CDF846CB943A8549DE17B0F2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of retrocession and restoration of territory</header> 
<subsection id="H25E25FF9FEFA4164850EFCD39B6761B0">
        <enum>(a)</enum>
        <header>Repeal</header>
 <text>The Act of July 9, 1846 (9 Stat. 35, Chapter 35), entitled <quote>An Act to Retrocede the County of Alexandria, in the District of Columbia, to the State of Virginia</quote>, is repealed.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="H5AE15793C62D449C9E61174168C50849"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>The territory retroceded under the Act repealed by subsection (a), consisting of the area now comprising Arlington County, Virginia, and the independent City of Alexandria, Virginia, is restored to, and shall constitute part of, the District of Columbia.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE149D6667D7F4A6F9FAAE442EA52DB3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Governing law</header><text>Effective on the date of enactment of this Act, the laws of the District of Columbia shall apply to the territory restored under subsection (b), and the laws of the Commonwealth of Virginia shall cease to apply to such territory, except that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H868D9206CF3F47F39B695AB7A22AAACB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all rights, titles, and interests in property held by any person on such date shall remain undisturbed; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE782A91EA3BC4B8CAF17A207D59C5ADB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any civil or criminal proceeding pending in a court of the Commonwealth of Virginia on such date arising in such territory may be concluded in that court as if this Act had not been enacted.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9067040DC689407085E0B4AB1129DF5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the first day of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

