<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-HLA25767-TWC-R1-YM6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 453 ATS: Designating the week beginning September 7, 2025, as “National Direct Support Professionals Week”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 453</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251015">October 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating the week beginning September 7, 2025, as <quote>National Direct Support Professionals Week</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas direct care workers, including direct support professionals, personal assistants, personal attendants, in-home support workers, and paraprofessionals, are key to providing publicly funded, long-term support and services for millions of individuals with disabilities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas direct support professionals provide essential services that ensure that all individuals with disabilities are—</text><paragraph id="id659b57a2dd1c4f128508304b5744b277"><enum>(1)</enum><text>included as a valued part of the communities in which those individuals live;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42ebead1e5104ac788bc50c17d2c90e9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supported at home, at work, and in the communities of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd598d8b0dc38423f92ba61205ea3cc69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>empowered to live with the dignity that all people of the United States deserve;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, by fostering connections between individuals with disabilities and their families, friends, and communities, direct support professionals ensure that individuals with disabilities thrive and provide an alternative to institutional care;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas direct support professionals build close, respectful, and trusting relationships with individuals with disabilities and provide a broad range of personalized support to those individuals, including—</text><paragraph id="id07a2cd335ae94afb978891ee32686bcd"><enum>(1)</enum><text>helping individuals make person-centered choices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb88d9f1ae6ec40a89e141d930c72cfdb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assisting with personal care, meal preparation, medication management, and other aspects of daily living;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf420df58739d4b729c24f11db25beabd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assisting individuals in accessing the community and securing competitive, integrated employment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0a397d2db63549ce8cfb81d30d4f728e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing transportation to school, work, religious, and recreational activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0231713a6e07455fb131e549b421cf66"><enum>(5)</enum><text>helping with general daily affairs, such as assisting with financial matters, medical appointments, and personal interests; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id89f09386196143ff883144ba66b7fbc1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>assisting individuals in the transition to living in the communities of their choice;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there is a critical shortage of direct support professionals throughout the United States, a crisis that was exacerbated by the COVID–19 pandemic, bringing uncertainty and risk to individuals with disabilities;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas direct support professionals do not have their own Standard Occupational Classification for the purposes of Federal data collection, including data produced by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Director of the Office of Management and Budget should, as part of the current revision of the Standard Occupational Classification system, consider establishing a separate code for direct support professionals as a healthcare support occupation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the direct care workforce, including direct support professionals, is expected to be among the fastest growing occupations in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many direct support professionals—</text><paragraph id="idcaa16c2e818843e2863c16807ac040ca"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be the primary financial providers for their families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id67b09aa0385a449f8b50727ae9c4a749"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are hardworking, taxpaying citizens who provide a critical service in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0011533d4c6b43fabc0ea06808e34ddd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>continue to earn low wages, receive inadequate benefits, and have limited opportunities for advancement, resulting in high turnover and vacancy rates that adversely affect the quality of support, safety, and health of individuals with disabilities; and</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Supreme Court of the United States, in Olmstead v. L.C., 527 U.S. 581 (1999)—</text><paragraph id="id28d4943750514dd698ea07a60c2d0dfb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognized the importance of the deinstitutionalization of, and community-based services for, individuals with disabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f36dbe2f1ff4c789917be585ef94e06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>held that, under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>), a State must provide person-centered, community-based service options to individuals with intellectual and developmental disabilities: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id2497c8b556be4dcfa2917e4b44f410d7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates the week beginning September 7, 2025, as <quote>National Direct Support Professionals Week</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ca84f049f9b4a73b9728a9d52886149"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the dedication and vital role of direct support professionals in enhancing the lives of individuals with disabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idacaf1bf2d9194e968cf54d552dda9793"><enum>(3)</enum><text>appreciates the contribution of direct support professionals in supporting individuals with disabilities in the United States and the families of those individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a7cd315994142d38b1b5f68a965427c"><enum>(4)</enum><text>commends direct support professionals for being integral to the provision of long-term support and services for individuals with disabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e8271d4d2814a7e9463650b0428957e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>finds that the successful implementation of public policies affecting individuals with disabilities in the United States can depend on the dedication of direct support professionals. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

