<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAE4BF52CAA3747EFBDB9B32310F6AE9E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6993 IH: Veterans TBI Breakthrough Exploration of Adaptive Care Opportunities Nationwide Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6993</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260109">January 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000301">Ms. Elfreth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000603">Mr. Luttrell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out programs to award grants to eligible entities to conduct research with respect to treatments for traumatic brain injury prospective randomized control trials for neurorehabilitation treatments, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4224EE1E808549F4A701BAE5CDE84340" style="OLC"><section id="HBD57AEE4F6824411A4EA590B4459F306" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans TBI Breakthrough Exploration of Adaptive Care Opportunities Nationwide Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BEACON Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H205CD40C5BA64129BA7213E43E1A3200"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs grant program for supplemental neurorehabilitation approaches to chronic mild TBI treatment</header><subsection id="H9B99E823067C47CC85779E16D248A7B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a grant program (to be known as the <quote>TBI Innovation Grant Program</quote>) to award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) for the development, implementation, and evaluation of approaches and methodologies for prospective randomized control trials for neurorehabilitation treatments for the treatment of chronic mild TBI (mTBI) in veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE82E6E0602104EF0A35167AB85B75908"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity described in this subsection is any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H60C8D7AB807E4C069B8E1357565F240F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAACADDDAC7F42299F891AA9AE3BB93D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An academic institution engaged in research with respect to TBI.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6064F2D495F34647B831A8494CC4E47C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A non-Department health care provider with expertise in neurorehabilitative therapies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1EEA5F3901A4DE6AB096F58962CC8AA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An entity the Secretary determines appropriate for an award of a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B84F1C4B60447F2BCDBD2A7720CD95C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity in receipt of a grant under this section shall use such grant to support activities that include—</text><paragraph id="H9AEF8F42FE044462B044231DBE5714EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designing and testing novel or integrative treatments for mTBI that prioritize patient-centered care, including non-pharmacological therapies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94B75FA3321744C5B0122AD40CC46D92"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conducting clinical studies and assessments to measure the effectiveness of funded approaches to—</text><subparagraph id="H1084D3FF2D6640B2BCB0CE54FCC9A88A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve mental health outcomes among veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CEA6C6099224CF4BD73F0D202E4814F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce suicidality, and common risk factors for completing suicide, including depression and substance use disorders among veterans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE6922358C594B09A2A361DB3E35F7E4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mitigate long-term effects of mTBI;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CDFFD4A54CD428887C349F602EF825D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing training for clinicians and outreach to veterans and their families to improve awareness and accessibility of innovative mTBI treatments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36443F3EEFC54D90A96408ED475E0400"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing partnerships with community organizations, academic institutions, and health care facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs to implement and evaluate best practices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H119B918810CC47A0B424AF88273F8F8D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not award an eligible entity a grant under this section in an amount that exceeds $5,000,000 per fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4ABEC42D69844399A6C869696C46C34F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that the Secretary determines have demonstrated experience in delivering or researching effective treatments for mTBI.</text></subsection><subsection id="H67110FEAE3D5485A810A319F847BB762"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Program administration</header><paragraph id="HC48AABEF73254072BB19883AA24081C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary determines appropriate, including a detailed description of—</text><subparagraph id="H24511D8E7D91455FB5BF71BF059C89D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proposed activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFB396927CEB44FFB321AD7332CAD952"><enum>(B)</enum><text>expected outcomes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1A5DC76ABE14E34B1E119E70011ECB1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>plans for evaluating effectiveness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4655327D816B4D4E8F43CBF8D4F50897"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic reports</header><text>An eligible entity in receipt of a grant under this section shall, not less frequently than annually, submit to the Secretary a report that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report—</text><subparagraph id="H83DDE40659D9464981588E2F7747438F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of how the eligible entity used such grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H368D5A94F36C486E9C90038D4C179BD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a summary of the progress of activities funded with amounts from such grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC682C23DE0094590B9410D537D79DFE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>measured outcomes relating to such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D6E309342114E7D885C569C7B39662E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oversight; annual evaluations</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H9853656F32154E3E8F3DDF54AB34B39A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure rigorous oversight with respect to the grant program under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C51F87E49714BD1B2AF29D049C9CAE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on an annual basis during the period the authority to carry out the grant program is effective, evaluate the efficacy of activities funded with a grant awarded under such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D589DF2CB404E3DBFF978A367830D43" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Coordination with VA mental health services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the grant program under this section aligns with the Staff Sergeant Fox Suicide Prevention Grant Program of the Department to—</text><paragraph id="H5E868FA0791A481EBDB0210C8CC9EB94" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for cohesive and comprehensive support for veterans with mTBI and associated mental health conditions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01CF963908434B1B988F73F0EB128D39" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase research and development on integrated mTBI and mental health interventions outside of the scope of traditional Department of Veterans Affairs pathways, interventions, programs, procedures, and pharmaceuticals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1030622F54BB46CB9C6CBA762BD7886A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H42B0F407E5AB4F649372063B065E7C37" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Available amounts; authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H5BB1693ACA9843D0A8234C1F4FC810FB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Available amounts</header><text>The Secretary may carry out the program under this section using amounts available to the Secretary for general mental health care programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AC00A577D8B4BC4AF3D82E75487B75F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $30,000,000 for fiscal years 2026 through 2028 to carry out the pilot program under this section, which shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H459DDE28234A4141865999E0DF87B021"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Duration; annual review</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out the grant program under this section shall terminate at the end of the 3-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act. During such period, the Secretary shall, on an annual basis, review the effectiveness of such grant program to determine the potential of such grant program for continuation or expansion.</text></subsection></section><section id="H51703CA91F924531B10F2155C88A953F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Veterans Affairs grant program for independent third-party research studies and treatment with respect to supplemental neurorehabilitation treatments for mTBI</header><subsection id="HD115716BE2C6422A9B417C3FC3FBCB45" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish and carry out a research grant program to award grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) for studies and applied programs on approaches and methodologies for the treatment of TBI in veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE5F573A15D694CF4B9E0C2B68E1B1BC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities described</header><text>An eligible entity described in this subsection is any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H3274836B55324F3183C8D07850703E7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An academic institution that conducts significant research on TBI.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCA032D873534709B195850E3CA8A541"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization with—</text><subparagraph id="HC982B83E0B9D495E86C64F5A8DA6F3BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>expertise in TBI research and neurorehabilitation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9DC953E50AE41439A584F8ADFB350D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrated capabilities in clinical trials and TBI treatment evaluation and patient care delivery.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE089931D7D455B849ACD9D859FCCF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An entity, or a partnership among entities, that the Secretary determines appropriate to receive a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A95629CF43747698617F19BBD021FB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary determines appropriate, including a summary of—</text><paragraph id="H1E5A61DC8DF0446791BBDB648691C759"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proposed research and treatment activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F26FE16B3B743C3A64E4BE134E522D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methodology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF78D6CE251024336B39E84720F2BC91F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expected outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14D9297932FA47F7B1D4599035155440"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant categories</header><paragraph id="HFD3EF3AEA99B44D99CF9A207B31A2426"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Pursuant to the research grant program under this section, the Secretary shall, each fiscal year—</text><subparagraph id="HEA9FC9A1B1AD4EC99AF347707501A43A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to the requirement under paragraph (2), award four grants in amounts of not more than $625,000 for exploratory or pilot research and treatment projects; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00C67685A31C43A69CCBA873AF391A00"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">award five grants in amounts of not more than $1,500,000 for collaborative or multidisciplinary research and treatment initiatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E355C4EE600467DADFC1D0A0A91A949"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall award not fewer than three grants described in paragraph (1)(A) to nonprofit organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE7611B8D6FF4C8E944204E5F98AAFA9" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the third-Party organization</header><paragraph id="H492AD5C52BF84EB68B2934D95891FB56" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with an independent third-party organization comparable to the National Center for Posttraumatic Stress Disorder of the Department of Veterans Affairs to—</text><subparagraph id="HE87D83ED73874E8D845F0DDC3272A6D6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administer the research grant program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE116C0A3CEB40FC80A0E01CA05E84CB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out studies and implement efforts that include—</text><clause id="HCC318DED360C420892689D627F79F387" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>analyzing data from TBI treatment methodologies developed pursuant to the research grant program to assess the effect, among veterans, of such methodologies on mental health outcomes and long-term recovery;</text></clause><clause id="HC53DD071D07F4E6282CA26F274B22DDB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying evidence-based best practices and providing recommendations for further research or clinical application; and</text></clause><clause id="H141261D437AF4A17B4DE00B6A446B28D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>randomized, controlled clinical trials to—</text><subclause id="H6C3B5D95A2064668B2C01E4470C032B5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>validate and deliver treatments;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDC1DBE891D00481BA3C26ECB6BC40C32"><enum>(II)</enum><text>establish a standard of care; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H25BD0AD2D8A94233810BE215D060B8E0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>improve access to such treatments for veterans.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA29C1AE671CE4973A3E0DB59D8393121" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The independent third-party organization with which the Secretary enters into an agreement under paragraph (1) shall submit to Congress and the Secretary a comprehensive report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H7BC59D62D4B649D4BE14D3A72BA68B11" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings of the studies required under such agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H824F2775A3A84EECA596253C0607F889" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations with respect to the expansion of successful TBI treatment methodologies and standard of care recommendations, if any, developed pursuant to the research grant program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE3C2CC05FB24506826D62B003626945"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Available amounts; authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HF4C98BE425E04672BD1EF319772C4D44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Available amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use amounts available to the Secretary for the operating budget of the National Center for Posttraumatic Stress Disorder to carry out the research grant program under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCD996A1C7794607B2E5CE274146C043" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8ECB59A41764C4E80F2FE4BC091A77D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date on which the Secretary commences the research grant program under this section, and on an annual basis thereafter during the period the authority of the Secretary to carry out such research grant program is effective, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HE5F6D55F66B7456C980EB20BBF6B5882"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the studies under—</text><subparagraph id="H2D6FE08AA0E24747B8F38DB2641CF815"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 2(f)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA65B98A2D3A418A91911A475C672720"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the agreement required by section 3(e); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H89DAA2A273D742BE9358E06EEA712CD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations of the Secretary with respect to policy and programmatic improvements to services of the Department to treat TBI among veterans.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B458C1D625D48B9A64B1D57B6B9CA1C" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination date</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to carry out the research grant program under this section shall terminate on the date that is three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H46D91076F65748C1B760E868F02D6E88"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H092C9DF74E9B4CCD8343877D9586BE4C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>TBI</quote> means traumatic brain injury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D6FDCEFD608458E99882D6717097060"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>treatment</quote> means clinical interventions, therapeutic devices, or rehabilitation care provided directly to a veteran with TBI.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB84643181F774722A9103E6F70CAE75D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>veteran</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

