<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H752FB8E4432F48679C4BF04B3B2E261A">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6910 IH: United States International Development Corporation Chief Development Officer Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6910</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20251219">December 19, 2025</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To strengthen the development mandate of the United States International Development Finance Corporation, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H6C0D23322BE4443E8FDEA6241E7A50B4">
<section id="H5A22BCF8B40844D0BD057CF98996196A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States International Development Corporation Chief Development Officer Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7F1CAC0BF9BA4134B0A859FC578047F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Chief development officer</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1413(g) of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9613">22 U.S.C. 9613</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HAE8BCBCCCEB84CDEB75AA6B283B3A8E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H36ABFF78E2E74E048540D8A4EE097CC1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text>
<clause id="H4001F4FFE8C64815B3D745E8B1CCA47D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Subject to the approval of the Board, the</quote> and inserting <quote>The</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H93C140CB10754356BC4E9715F2331840"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in development</quote> and inserting <quote>in international development and development finance</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H83224B56BD0B48789977C961D87BBB8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>the Board</quote> and inserting <quote>the Chief Executive Officer</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H538ED6C39E094F1491FBAEB9872726C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H268CC46C45F6407BAEFA157A89303CC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote>AND RESPONSIBILITIES</quote> after <quote>DUTIES</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBA6755DDF8D4838B917B1AE00095EF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (A) as subparagraph (E);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA518F4797F8E438BA1A34F6F798DDA0C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (B) through (F) and inserting before subparagraph (E), as so redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H4BE12BF1D781402ABD31817E36A5E254" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE6B2696EFC6F43638B33EFCCC6E2C826"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advise the Chief Executive Officer and the Deputy Chief Executive Officer on international development policy matters;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9D42509ACEB492A860094A44EDD006A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in addition to the Chief Executive Officer and the Deputy Chief Executive Officer, represent the Corporation in interagency meetings and processes relating to international development;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6FA122D60D954A60BC63D5F4E2AF9E49"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be an ex officio member of the Development Finance Advisory Council established under subsection (i) and participate in or send a representative to each meeting of the Council;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H511D193F6CA64A6189F4B6B9D1765FF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>work with other relevant Federal departments and agencies to—</text> <clause id="H36EAFF1C3995467EAAFA4A82235AD809"><enum>(i)</enum><text>identify projects that advance United States international development interests; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HDDC6019553CA40C98BD2971BDDD4402F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>explore investment opportunities that bring evidence-based, cost-effective development innovations to scale in a manner that can be sustained by markets;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D53B61938E94E4195861CA998650F6D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), as so redesignated—</text>
<clause id="H305FD269692B42E89974F3912E379700"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>coordinate</quote> and inserting </text> <quoted-block id="HDDD1BDD0787F41E6B71377A2D921F4D1" style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support—</text>
<clause id="H5C3C4471CCA744FFBC1666716B33459C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coordination of</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> <clause id="H33B8389DE42E4FCEAE3BE13E31D8A4EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>United States Government</quote> and all that follows through the semicolon and inserting <quote>Federal departments and agencies, including by directly liaising with the relevant members of United States country teams serving overseas, to ensure that such Federal departments, agencies, and country teams have the training and awareness necessary to fully leverage the Corporation’s development tools overseas;</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HEA89C41383054A90B786A21F8100F4D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H6426F026236249D3A2E7E9E9D956A7BD" style="OLC"> <clause id="HCA479F8BBF2647B9AA7D98610B92DED7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>management of employees of the Corporation that are dedicated to structuring, monitoring, and evaluating transactions and projects codesigned with other relevant Federal departments and agencies for development impact;</text></clause>
<clause id="H3BF9509E24584440946FA91D09098A00"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordination of funds or other resources transferred to and from such Federal departments, agencies, or overseas country teams, upon concurrence of those institutions, in support of the Corporation’s international development projects or activities;</text></clause> <clause id="H86442B639E9341D08C899D578CC0370E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>management of the responsibilities of the Corporation under paragraphs (1) and (4) of section 1442(b) and paragraphs (1)(A) and (3)(A) of section 1443(b);</text></clause>
<clause id="H7CDCA3DB94DB440DA026BB438D99A4EE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>coordination and implementation of the activities of the Corporation under section 1445; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3EF83C4A06A440F48FAD4DBA123B1D4E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>implementation of the Corporation’s development impact strategy and work to ensure development impact at the transaction level and portfolio-wide;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2D1E292DE0F54AF7B7F9B57A8EE4F1A5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HA65CCC233FAE4F09A65813CBEDA0BF57" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HBE61007AD4EB4EB581E665FE53C48EDC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>foster and maintain relationships both within and external to the Corporation that enhance the capacity of the Corporation to achieve its mission to advance United States international development policy and interests; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H56B34C0895A4402D9F4B3757EC85084E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>coordinate within the Corporation to ensure United States international development policy and interests are considered together with the Corporation’s foreign policy and national security goals.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

