<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF47AC8E3143E4E72924D158937871B08" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1243 IH: Recognizing the significance of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month as an important time to celebrate the significant contributions of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders to the history of the United States.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1243</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Ms. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000404">Ms. King-Hinds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001123">Mr. Cisneros</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000491">Mr. Tran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000635">Ms. Dexter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the significance of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month as an important time to celebrate the significant contributions of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders to the history of the United States.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the people of the United States join together each May to pay tribute to the contributions of generations of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders who have enriched the history of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the history of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders in the United States is inextricably tied to the story of the United States;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander community is an inherently diverse population, composed of more than 70 distinct ethnicities and speaking more than 100 language dialects;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Bureau of the Census, the Asian American population grew faster than any other racial or ethnic group over the last decade, growing by nearly 55.5 percent between 2010 and 2020, and during that same time period, the Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander population grew by 30.8 percent;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas there are more than 25,000,000 residents of the United States who identify as Asian and approximately 1,800,000 residents of the United States who identify as Native Hawaiian and Pacific Islander, making up more than 10 percent of the total population of the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the month of May was selected for Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month because the first Japanese immigrants arrived in the United States on May 7, 1843, and the first transcontinental railroad was completed on May 10, 1869, with substantial contributions from Chinese immigrants;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas section 102 of title 36, United States Code, officially designates May as Asian/Pacific American Heritage Month and requests the President to issue an annual proclamation calling on the people of the United States to observe the month with appropriate programs, ceremonies, and activities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas 2026 marks several anniversaries, including—</text>
<paragraph id="id534ae28ab2db4f9d94c58aeb49f70699"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the 250th anniversary of the independence and founding of the United States and the recognition of service of Asian Americans in the United States military since the Revolutionary War;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idf5fc6a4ae1a947ffab14ee86389ff144"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the 50th anniversary of Presidential Proclamation 4417, dated February 19, 1976 (41 Fed. Reg. 7741), in which President Gerald Ford formally rescinded Executive Order 9066 (7 Fed. Reg. 1407; relating to authorizing the Secretary of War to prescribe military areas) and condemned the incarceration of United States citizens and lawful permanent residents of Japanese ancestry during World War II; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id655f92e8174b40ab8225863118ac5b60"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 70th anniversary of the election to the House of Representatives of Dalip Singh Saund, the first Asian American, first Indian American, and first Sikh American elected to Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id582bd95dffc84542878aab38b234b0c4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the 80th anniversary of the passage of the amendments made by the Act of July 2, 1946 (commonly known as the <quote>Luce–Cellar Act of 1946</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/79/483">Public Law 79–483</external-xref>; 60 Stat. 416, chapter 534), which allowed Filipinos and Indians to immigrate to the United States and become naturalized United States citizens;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9b232438d2eb4f079c9edb2e00a6ac74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the 80th anniversary of the passage of the First Supplemental Surplus Appropriation Rescission Act, 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/79/301">Public Law 79–301</external-xref>; 60 Stat. 6, chapter 30), and the Second Supplemental Surplus Appropriation Rescission Act, 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/79/391">Public Law 79–391</external-xref>; 60 Stat. 221, chapter 271), which stripped military benefits from Filipino World War II veterans in the service of the United States Armed Forces;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id529bcc5e120e4cdd804193d93f2f8814"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the 105th anniversary of the first premiere of an American film featuring an Asian American woman, Anna May Wong, in <quote>Bits of Life</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idac87890c926240f080e35633831603cb"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the 10th anniversary of the passage of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/157">Public Law 114–157</external-xref>, which removed all references to <quote>Oriental</quote>, a derogatory and antiquated term used to describe Asian Americans, from Federal law;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders have made significant contributions to the United States at all levels of the Federal Government and in the Armed Forces, including— </text>
<paragraph id="id17fcf35e29b246aab3c828a662813e69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Dalip Singh Saund, the first Asian American elected to Congress;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idc3ef71687c0f479dbe5a06cb63c15cf3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Daniel K. Inouye, a Medal of Honor and Presidential Medal of Freedom recipient who, as President pro tempore of the Senate, was the then-highest-ranking Asian American government official in the history of the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id7f038b65a3e643e9bd322a5ae6928bab"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hiram L. Fong, the first Asian American Senator;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id5ae849e8efff415ab5187e68e9f8ba45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Patsy T. Mink, the first woman of color and Asian American woman elected to Congress;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idb213a519e03b40eb816b807e8e452934"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Herbert Y.C. Choy, the first Asian American to serve as a Federal judge;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id1eadc7716cff4b33922a9df46d7954d4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Daniel K. Akaka, the first Senator of Native Hawaiian ancestry; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id503af500977b4077af6ef01811238553"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Norman Y. Mineta, the first Asian American member of a Presidential cabinet;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the 119th Congress includes 25 Members of Asian and Pacific Islander descent;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, the Congressional Asian Pacific American Caucus is composed of 84 Members, and other congressional caucuses work on Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander issues also;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders are serving in State and Territorial legislatures across the United States in record numbers, including in—</text>
<paragraph id="idf3154ab18a0a49d2acaa11778f118f14"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the States of Alaska, Arizona, California, Connecticut, Delaware, Florida, Georgia, Hawaii, Idaho, Illinois, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, Minnesota, Missouri, Nebraska, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, North Carolina, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Tennessee, Texas, Utah, Vermont, Virginia, Washington, Wisconsin, and Wyoming; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idcec234b13573459083e9a128b591bdc0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Territories of American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands;</text></paragraph></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders represent more than 8 percent of Federal judges and hundreds of thousands of Federal employees, including hundreds of staffers of Asian, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander descent who serve as staff in the Senate and the House of Representatives;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the incidence of hate crimes against Asian Americans continues to be nearly 3 times higher than the levels observed before the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas discrimination against Asian Americans, especially in moments of crisis, is not a new phenomenon, and violence against Asian Americans has occurred throughout United States history, including—</text> <paragraph id="ida26739622e7c4a9b876dcabcd912625e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the enactment of the Act entitled <quote>An Act supplementary to the Acts in relation to Immigration</quote>, approved March 3, 1875 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Page Act of 1875</quote>) (18 Stat. 477, chapter 141), which restricted entry of Chinese, Japanese, and other Asian women to the United States and effectively prohibited the immigration of Chinese women, preventing the formation of Chinese families in the United States and limiting the number of native-born Chinese citizens;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id6f55010a9a4a4a1fbb575e64383fed5d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the enactment of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to execute certain treaty stipulations relating to Chinese</quote>, approved May 6, 1882 (commonly known as the <quote>Chinese Exclusion Act of 1882</quote>) (22 Stat. 58, chapter 126), which was the first law to explicitly exclude an entire ethnic group from immigrating to the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="ida74a9e5ef3d845e18e90650c10289563"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the issuance of Executive Order 9066 (7 Fed. Reg. 1407; relating to authorizing the Secretary of War to prescribe military areas) on February 19, 1942, which authorized the forced relocation and incarceration of approximately 125,000 individuals of Japanese ancestry during World War II, the majority of whom were citizens of the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idd55b297fba554db4b270824e89e98ee3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on June 23, 1982, the murder of Vincent Chin;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id10509a40cf054a61abb63428b0c992bd"><enum>(5)</enum><text>on January 17, 1989, the Cleveland Elementary School shooting in which a gunman used an AK–47 to kill 5 children, 4 of whom were of Southeast Asian descent;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id84ab8eb0454d41838bcc3461e0cd26ae"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the rise in discrimination and violence against Muslim, Sikh, Arab, Middle Eastern, and South Asian Americans following the attacks on the World Trade Center and the Pentagon on September 11, 2001;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id3d3bf14faa8f43aab3e43775f8af8b2a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>on August 5, 2012, the mass shooting at a Sikh temple in Oak Creek, Wisconsin, in which a white supremacist fatally shot 6 people and wounded 4 others; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="idf825d7bcc2a640fbb6276832b34495bc"><enum>(8)</enum><text>on March 16, 2021, the murder of 8 people, including 6 Asian women, at 3 separate Asian-owned businesses in the Atlanta, Georgia, region;</text></paragraph></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, in response to the uptick in anti-Asian hate crimes throughout the COVID–19 pandemic, Congress passed the COVID–19 Hate Crimes Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/13">Public Law 117–13</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 265), which was signed into law on May 20, 2021;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in celebration of the contributions of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders in the United States, Congress passed the Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/140">Public Law 117–140</external-xref>; 136 Stat. 1259) to establish a commission to study the creation of a National Museum of Asian Pacific American History and Culture, which was signed into law on June 13, 2022;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, as part of the American Women Quarters Program, the United States Mint has issued commemorative quarters honoring the contributions of—</text>
<paragraph id="id985263d507ff49e4904ae12f55fd7009"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Chinese American film star Anna May Wong;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="id07aeb569d64f4c33a8dd04221629cc3d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Native Hawaiian composer and cultural advocate Edith Kanaka‘ole;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="id9817237d6c9345a8b9e8f1c34956d4c6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Japanese American Congresswoman Patsy Mink; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="idda5720f38b6b4cbe8c2ed26db16279b6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Korean American disability justice advocate Stacey Park Milbern;</text></paragraph></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, as part of the Native American $1 Coin Program, the United States Mint has issued a commemorative $1 coin honoring the contributions of Mary Kawena Pukui, a renowned Native Hawaiian scholar, anthropologist, ethnographer, author, composer, dancer, and educator whose work ensured the preservation and perpetuation of the Native Hawaiian language, history, and culture;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there remains much to be done to ensure that Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders have access to resources and a voice in the Federal Government and continue to advance in the political landscape of the United States; and</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas celebrating Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month provides the people of the United States with an opportunity to recognize the achievements, contributions, and history of, and to understand the challenges faced by, Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HBF3F7BE0F5F9425285298BB27B06FB60"> <section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HBE3144AC16334D34A481870768BC94AB"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text>
<paragraph id="H3AA256A7E7904424A98479BF266A524E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes the significance of Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander Heritage Month as an important time to celebrate the significant contributions of Asian Americans, Native Hawaiians, and Pacific Islanders to the history of the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE150013D11C14168A5F15A6CEFF2667D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that Asian American, Native Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander communities enhance the rich diversity of and strengthen the United States. </text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

