<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C1F377D821D49A4B2FB773714000F33" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7427 IH: Securing Access from Foreign Entities Visiting Internal Sites in the States Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7427</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide threat analyses, including relating to terrorism threats, and guidance to State, local, Tribal, or territorial government officials or employees regarding visiting foreign nationals who seek access to State, local, Tribal, or territorial officials or employees, information, facilities, programs, or systems, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2E35A96AD0846C09BF33BCECC0BAEFF" style="OLC"><section id="HF7DF98BE0F374DEBADD7113007F31F70" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Access from Foreign Entities Visiting Internal Sites in the States Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAFE VISITS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2CEE70F98A8243E3AB7B5131E9A9DF40"><enum>2.</enum><header>DHS threat analyses and guidance related to visiting foreign nationals to State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments</header><subsection id="HC7735416A32B441C9F0A4E309FF49AAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle A of title II of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/121">6 U.S.C. 121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H18D3D55781064838A3A559C4A1DA1DD8" style="OLC"><section id="HCF8E3FDCE1454EFDA15457A532C02DDA"><enum>210H.</enum><header>Threat analyses and guidance related to visiting foreign nationals to State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments</header><subsection id="HE49CD04C82CB440FAA8E23FD9D56D657" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a threat analysis, including relating to potential terrorism threats, reported to the Department by State, local, Tribal, or territorial government officials or employees, regarding any known visits by foreign nationals who—</text><paragraph id="HDD3AC91F969E4C04AB1DF9391942499D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>seek to meet with such officials or employees, or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1503AFE04E8444FE9F64889A3D768895" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek access to State, local, Tribal, or territorial government information, facilities, programs, or systems, and</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">disseminate to State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments guidance based on such threat analysis.</continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H827B95FA5A624310B817B78F57E3EA0B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content of threat analysis and guidance</header><text>The threat analysis, including relating to potential terrorism threats, and guidance under subsection (a) shall contain the following:</text><paragraph id="HDC595887F6B84275B9863F6CB1CE4BCD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Descriptions of high-risk State, local, Tribal, and territorial government targets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17B50389E8BE4558AB3F8FE6093E7DCA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of trends related to visits by foreign nationals who seek access to State, local, Tribal, or territorial officials or employees, information, facilities, programs, or systems based on vetting request information submitted to, by, or through fusion centers (as such term is defined in section 210A) by State, local, Tribal, or territorial governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3304677ED1E43849EB0A3A8C25BE1CD" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Descriptions of actions that may be taken to mitigate homeland security threats, including potential terrorism threats, and protect State, local, Tribal, and territorial officials or employees, information, facilities, programs, or systems.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6454B0C75BEA46BA83ECB215FE6B3F35"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tailored outreach and vetting assistance</header><paragraph id="HB5B4A57556614B41BB212DFF627C9433" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary, based on the threat analysis under subsection (a), identifies a particular State, local, Tribal, or territorial government official or employee or information, facility, program, or system as a high-risk potential target of a visiting foreign national who seeks access to such official or employee, information, facility, program, or system, the Secretary shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H393755542D5748019912BE8E2AAA87DA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conduct outreach to the identified State, local, Tribal, or territorial government and provide information, unclassified or classified at the lowest possible level, regarding such potential target.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD616D7B420D64BD58CAE98C437E2EF4B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide the identified State, local, Tribal, or Territorial government with assistance vetting such a foreign national.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D96D228C183409DA50C159B36AD6D10" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide the identified State, local, Tribal, or Territorial government with additional guidance on specific actions that may be taken to mitigate homeland security threats, including potential terrorism threats, in connection with such visit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H346708680D2E428CBD66A1081D1F5A09" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Debriefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after an identified State, local, Tribal, or Territorial government hosts a visiting foreign national for which the Department provided assistance in accordance with paragraph (1), the Secretary shall request a debriefing from such host State, local, Tribal, or territorial government to maintain awareness of any attempt by visiting foreign nationals to obtain access to officials or employees, information, facilities, programs, or systems of such host State, local, Tribal, or Territorial government, and the techniques used by such visiting foreign nationals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23B5DE624D6940F28F24A0BDED3DDDAA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall annually submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a description of the outreach and vetting assistance by the Secretary under subsection (c) during the immediately preceding six month period. Each report under this subsection shall be submitted together with each corresponding report required under subsection (a), beginning with the second such report under such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H664604F5C30F44D1A22EAC7CB0A18987"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Information defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>information</quote> means data or materials collected, possessed, or prepared by a State, local, Tribal, or territorial government that is not intended for public disclosure or general use.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5D8AB79EB2764BB794A9D2DC93A06CB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research and development</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall, to the extent practicable, coordinate with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security to carry out research and development of a technology to enhance sharing of information to carry out section 210H of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0BDC067C201141ADADD0DC1D9286DCF8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section (b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 210G the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H3BC1D57C92CA4BC5B3614E34E89BE521" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 210H. Threat analyses and guidance related to visiting foreign nationals to State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

