<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6503E90E6BEB4B9F9BCBD82FA7527CC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9729 IH: Human Authority over Autonomous Weapons Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9729</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to ensure that the use of autonomous weapons systems and artificial intelligence-enabled systems by the Armed Forces is subject to appropriate levels of human command responsibility, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE9C2022780934E6EBA96B8421CA4DC84" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE0865244B7F24F29AEC890D3581AD991" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Human Authority over Autonomous Weapons Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE4CFFE5E426B4168961F2C91FC1BA170"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement for human oversight of use of autonomous and artificial intelligence-enabled weapon systems</header> <subsection id="HAFA7A70BCD1F4904A5F45F2153DD0973"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/3">Chapter 3</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/130f">section 130f</external-xref> the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H74FEFB6FBD354124BB8D867FEBF1101F" style="USC"> 
<section id="H71E3B6937C3E49C2A3B4CD1555A0739A"><enum>130g.</enum><header>Human oversight of use of autonomous and artificial intelligence-enabled weapons systems</header> 
<subsection id="H182744B765D245C0A46CB4B8AB5ACA84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Except as provided by subsection (b), the Secretary shall require that any use of force by the Armed Forces involving an autonomous weapons system or artificial intelligence-enabled system is subject to human command responsibility. The Secretary shall establish procedures to—</text> <paragraph id="H7E0B145ABFB54E96ACD98829E55A704F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify each human commander or operator responsible for authorizing, supervising, and terminating any such use of force;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2415B346C24548C9BACB6955B63ACD2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure human oversight, approval, or a human-in-the-loop for any decision to use such a system for an intentionally lethal purpose; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E05F6E06E3E499D98E60D02F79067C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for any such use of force during the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section, ensure that a commander or operator using such a system verifies any target of such system using a secondary source or data that is not exclusively generated by artificial intelligence.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4F7E86145C2C455E879D9552D582BD55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The requirement and procedures under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to—</text> <paragraph id="HC0AAD2BC9D3E476DBC771B6DB09610CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a United States missile defense system; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DC095D8CBCE4018A29F20524BA6DEEC">
                <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other defense system designed to intercept, deflect, or engage missiles, munitions, or other weapons when such weapons are used against the United States or the Armed Forces of the United States.</text>
              </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCA5C4DFCB67F479F9751F9CBB34721E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement and procedures under subsection (a) are in addition to, and shall not be construed to replace, the guidance established pursuant to Department of Defense Directive 3000.09 titled ‘Autonomy in Weapon Systems’ (or any successor regulation).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1BA1BC88270B4D4AB03F0B134F162D30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H385BAE81814B4E2885013650388CFB45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>artificial intelligence</term> has the meaning given that term in section 5002 of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9401">15 U.S.C. 9401</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H849600C5FBA54D679C5E84A094F4DB3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>autonomous weapon system</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D5B391BB1B241E6A1FC2663652C3958"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a weapon system that, once activated, can select and engage targets without further intervention by an operator; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H254C8E5F56D74C1E8E6233390ED58AFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any operator-supervised autonomous weapon system that is designed to allow operators to override operation of the weapon system, but can select and engage targets without further operator input after activation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50A1536A90B148C5982C26B91D8EC785"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the implementation of section 130g of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a). Such report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H8B24DDFEB32646BB8ADF891B85FC0890"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the procedures established by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) of such section; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF5DF661058F641A49C476FE64448A1DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which the use of force by the Armed Forces has been prevented or delayed by reason of such procedures or the requirements of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

