<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H342692A19CFF44BCA071B89FEC8D5ED2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8833 IH: Sister City Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8833</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study to evaluate the activities of sister city partnerships operating within the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H785777F0A39C4542954FE549FB093BFD" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H9AD6D059DC9547A8AA1B7980F4358D2E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sister City Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD7681ECA3EBC4193BC18DCF81788FBF8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H021E5218BE154026B7400C1D55819650"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H30CA67C05ABB46BDB4541AB483392F13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H092CFB7E0BE44A9382A353DAF7BC43E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6251B27C90A445839A3162406669CE85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF5F129863B71485BB16621C2CC0D8D0F">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB4658A86968547A486CFB8405F8ACE4C">
                    <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
                </subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3EE194D54EE54A618FC4D27E766EC8AF">
                    <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
                </subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H86404E0F3B484BB8B4191615816C0A16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign community</header><text>The term <term>foreign community</term> means any subnational unit of government outside of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B65CAB207D64170A863176BA74C711B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sister city partnership</header><text>The term <term>sister city partnership</term> means a formal agreement between a United States community and a foreign community that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H650803D8CCF049FDA03C3F9F7A5668C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is recognized by Sister Cities International; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF544E36CE584AD18384C77A2503FFD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is operating within the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7CE040F7D7D404EAE8FD733E6329453"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States community</header><text>The term <term>United States community</term> means a State, county, city, or other unit of local government in the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H44F0F28A0A43468BAA56AACAD845CB54"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study of sister city partnerships operating within the United States involving foreign communities in countries with significant public sector corruption</header> <subsection id="H87DAA1C8E18845DDBCE2F4F7852DAA57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of the activities of sister city partnerships involving foreign communities in countries receiving a score of 45 or less on Transparency International’s 2019 Corruption Perceptions Index.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA5792C079909404999DA1C9116F12375"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements of the study</header><text>The study conducted under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HC7FE76A0CE094C3DAD444EE808EA6C6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify—</text>
<subparagraph id="H96DC95A16EE04BEFA38CE155E52BC530"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the criteria by which foreign communities identify United States communities as candidates for sister city partnerships, including themes with respect to the prominent economic activities and demographics of such United States communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB7D9B36A63542A7A535491BA0A5C689"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the activities conducted within sister city partnerships;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8DD6F80665F34E82A1824290E5DF6FF2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the economic and educational outcomes of such activities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE4661D9A89E94A09A4928317654ECAD9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the types of information that sister city partnerships make publicly available, including information relating to contracts and activities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1908AEC486074E26B4E21BBA0272AFCF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the means by which United States communities safeguard freedom of expression within sister city partnerships; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H667D2EBCA90B4E5FAC95F0A69C525758"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the oversight practices that United States communities implement to mitigate the risks of foreign espionage and economic coercion within sister city partnerships;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1356345151F149249865A10DC4F6487D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess—</text> <subparagraph id="H2111EFCACA93426A90555D9C30104A5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which United States communities ensure transparency regarding sister city partnership contracts and activities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAA5CEEE95C6A44448A111D68E5DED0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which sister city partnerships involve economic arrangements that make United States communities vulnerable to malign market practices;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39A35FB6A90F4F0E9E7031992FEED925"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which sister city partnerships involve educational arrangements that diminish the freedom of expression;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEB8DB86DC06343CAA22C7630722C2975"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which sister city partnerships allow foreign nationals to access local commercial, educational, and political institutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9078F0B1FBFF4A5FBA66F3E084548A6B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which foreign communities could use sister city partnerships to realize strategic objectives that do not conduce to the economic and national security interests of the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB24C690E3DF0430AB5B2C8E9152A79F9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the extent to which sister city partnerships could enable or otherwise contribute to foreign communities’ malign activities globally, including activities relating to human rights abuses and academic and industrial espionage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF75D75D5CF6341AC8F3E69A41124DF30"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the extent to which United States communities seek to mitigate foreign nationals’ potentially inappropriate use of visa programs to participate in activities relating to sister city partnerships; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A8D21FBF0C0457FB4D10D6A9E5049DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review—</text> <subparagraph id="HA04C4F7D514145398C81200D93F6BAAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the range of activities conducted within sister city partnerships, including activities relating to cultural exchange and economic development;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCB700F32A3C64FE4B469C54A78EB7837"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how such activities differ between sister city partnerships; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE047599DBC349D181FAD879664AC844"><enum>(C)</enum><text>best practices to ensure transparency regarding sister city partnerships’ agreements, activities, and employees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H929FAB44DD184D5A99D43EA13CA7D791"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header>
<paragraph id="HE9F046EFE05B44B2B7326818D0879A21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after initiating the study required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that contains the results of such study, including the findings, conclusions, and recommendations (if any) of the study.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H620874A5F0C34339B1901D39F3752B42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) may include a classified annex, if necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

