<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22C303077EC34B82A69C1425A3A2E36C" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1346 IH: Impeaching Eleanor L. Ross, Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1346</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000485">Mr. Fuller</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Impeaching Eleanor L. Ross, Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H795F697FC2E246F0A6CA77E42C499B24"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HCCB456B333984E878B49EC0B441E2F09"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Eleanor L. Ross, Judge of the United States District Court for the Northern District of Georgia, is impeached for high crimes and misdemeanors, and that the following article of impeachment be exhibited to the United States Senate.</text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H97E09CB919C84CACB5567C72955DB388"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Articles of impeachment exhibited by the House of Representatives of the United States of America in the name of itself and of the people of the United States of America, against Eleanor L. Ross, who was appointed, duly qualified, and commissioned to serve, during good behavior in office, to be United States Judge for the Northern District of Georgia on November 18, 2014.</text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H73EA711DFFC541F990CF545A82E85C5D"><enum/><header>Article I: Misleading and False Statements</header></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H5FC00F18CF964EB9A09C30F339253EEC"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judge Eleanor L. Ross made material false and misleading statements as follows:</text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H92168F0EB3064CE1A87C27ABF8C3AA34"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Between October 2023 and October 2025, Judge Ross engaged in sexual intercourse with a high-ranking official of the Atlanta Police Department inside her Federal courthouse chambers during regular business hours, while actively presiding over criminal cases.</text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H1195CBF261BE45B38059338DFD78D6C2"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">These activities were conducted within earshot of her judicial staff. </text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDA2CEF38E64B42FAA9331792C38EE588"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 30, 2025, Eleventh Circuit Chief Judge William Pryor identified a complaint about this behavior from a law clerk in Judge Ross’s office and appointed a Special Committee to investigate the complaint.</text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="HBE23CEDB034B46639367F1A25B606943"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Committee determined that Judge Ross lied to Chief Judge Pryor as well as to Chief Judge of the Northern District of Georgia Leigh Martin May regarding this sexual activity in her private office. </text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H861D0302327E430DAC9848917122C83B"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Specifically, Judge Ross falsely claimed that she had <quote>never engaged in sexual intercourse in [her] office, nor anywhere else in the Courthouse</quote>, and that she was <quote>not sure who this allegation concerns or whether it is alleged to have occurred with different individuals</quote>.</text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H120982967DB247E38496B850A17D6908"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Even though Judge Ross later admitted her falsehoods to the Special Committee, this occurred after the Special Committee had taken significant actions including a review of security camera footage and sign-in logs; background research on the Officer; interviews of five of the Judge’s former clerks; inspection of the layout of the Judge’s chambers; and laboratory testing of furnishings of the Judge’s chamber. </text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H16D34B7A250A4B0BBE8ABCB0DA0F758A"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Special Committee concluded that Judge Ross engaged in misconduct including sexual conduct in her office during business hours, and made material false and misleading statements to Chief Judge Pryor and Chief District Judge May that had a detrimental affect on the investigation of misconduct and the administration of the district court. </text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="H67F637FBF35040EFA050F155C7410367"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Her actions exhibit a reckless disregard for her professional obligations, proving her wholly unfit to continue holding the office of a Federal judge.</text></section><section section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF7279D96E0094030AAB0776C4612D70F"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wherefore, Judge Ross is guilty of high crimes and misdemeanors and should be removed from office.</text></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

