<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ELT26105-CXW-72-742"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3856 IS: SNAP Data Transparency and Oversight Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3856</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260212">February 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to require States to provide recipient-level data to the Secretary of Agriculture upon request.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H6C573077E3FD41CCB0D2BD7946BEE495"><section section-type="section-one" id="H2D9B4F32BC1741AB9E659CEC1A256041"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SNAP Data Transparency and Oversight Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H68A01775CE9A4783A928903E0930F41F"><enum>2.</enum><header>State requirement to provide SNAP recipient data to the Secretary of Agriculture</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2020">7 U.S.C. 2020</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5E894DAA704048158F84CC0C1927A0EE"><subsection id="H7C2A0758F6AA441E826F8A93E50017DB"><enum>(y)</enum><header>Provision of recipient data to the Secretary</header><paragraph id="H61827F143D56480DBF8BAAA77D146B5B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As a condition of participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program, each State agency shall, on request of the Secretary, provide to the Secretary recipient-level data, case file information, or any other program data necessary for the administration, oversight, integrity, or enforcement of the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2074FA45BB30404CA4FB52F7309927A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text>Data requested under paragraph (1) shall be transmitted in such form, manner, frequency, and within such time frame, as the Secretary may require, including through secure electronic data transfer systems designated by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE6138525E8B42C1AB886F95877D48AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>A State agency shall provide data requested under paragraph (1) not later than 30 days after the date of the request, unless the Secretary establishes a shorter timeline for urgent program integrity, audit, or investigative purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6581AAAAA1C1410E83D9D466965D1B83" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>The Secretary may withhold or suspend funds to a State under section 16 if a State fails to comply with a request for data under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H025952B5E12B4D8DA192ADFB3FDF8F5A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Data safeguards</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3dfe0d7100524e96af682f34408b99f5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that all data received under this subsection is subject to applicable Federal laws and safeguards governing the privacy and security of program records, including section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB7793D418CF4B4BA4FA5C6DF3D006F4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allowed disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data received under this subsection may be disclosed by the Secretary to any Federal or State law enforcement and investigative agency for purposes of administering or enforcing this Act, regulations issued under this Act, or any other Federal or State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3D3C4FEBC9421E8D01D0BE6D01E907"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits any existing authority of the Secretary to access State data or records for program oversight, enforcement, audit, or evaluation purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

