<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H9DA53953277C46F99D964BF5EF92254A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 1163 RH: Prove It Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><calendar display="yes"> Union Calendar No. 552</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1163</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–108, Parts I and II]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250210">February 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001096">Ms. Hageman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20250521">May 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the<committee-name committee-id="HSM00"> Committee on Small Business</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001314">Mr. Bean of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <sponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</sponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000479">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <sponsor name-id="K000403">Mr. Kennedy of Utah</sponsor>, <sponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</sponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00"> Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in boldface roman</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 10, 2025</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require greater transparency for Federal regulatory decisions that impact small businesses, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HSM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H251401CA20264ED1B23C9D4238BD710A"><section section-type="section-one" id="H5FBA1A3189964879BA74FCCE83236D5A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prove It Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA4BEE2B006D6425AB1CAA29DA5B9D30D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Initial regulatory flexibility analysis</header><subsection id="H4B62FD254F11446CA3961BAB52A00E5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">Chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDACA929685524836A7C3E3D9B87E94DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 603(b)—</text><subparagraph id="H109972F433A745F09F246393C7DE2ED1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D73DD07276E4B6BA1560D7B6D0F8DF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3C371F8216CC4CDFAE3112103FFDE4D5" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSM00"><paragraph id="H7315D919805E46C49140049BCB5929B3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>where feasible, any reasonably foreseeable potential indirect costs the proposed rule may impose on small entities, including small entities that—</text><subparagraph id="HD217750C131D4D319EC566F4210E8A28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase products or services from, sell products or services to, or otherwise conduct business with entities directly regulated by the rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6895A7027D77450A95A8447C7133E93F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are directly regulated by other governmental entities as a result of the rule; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF699E94B2D594979A6E38152760DE112"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are not directly regulated by the agency as a result of the rule but are otherwise subject to other agency rules as a result of the rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC94BBA1605647AA8C8157DFADB55D99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 605(b), by striking <quote>The agency</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 10 days after completing the certification described in this subsection, the agency</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H176ADF50FBCD406392174E29056614EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 605 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H134256493F0B49FEBBB261B8338FEE68" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSM00"><section id="H06C8A186134D47F08FE3763492457B72"><enum>605A.</enum><header>Review procedures relating to initial regulatory flexibility analysis certifications</header><subsection id="HCD1032104D594178BA7B8AEC44346FDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Filing a petition To review agency certification of a proposed rule</header><paragraph id="H726D96845F4D425CBA3074D9C54C3891"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any small entity, group of small entities, or organization representing the interests of small entities may petition the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Chief Counsel</quote>) to review a certification published under section 605(b) that a proposed rule will not, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81FD20D3577F4875B4BB5F5780C95929"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The Chief Counsel shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC1292D7EC1D144CE95768BE2D24E5F4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine the method, timing, and form of disseminating a petition described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB62DA3E9061F4D1C8E0AF724189E59DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>display the information described in subparagraph (A) on the website of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration in a conspicuous manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1D53E7874EA4134AA4E8F3E19512F30"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each petition described in paragraph (1) with respect to a certification published under section 605(b) for a proposed rule shall clearly and concisely—</text><subparagraph id="HFADC6598FF5C4F13B68AA5EF5C15E5F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specify the name of the petitioner and a telephone number, a mailing address, and an email address that the Chief Counsel may use to communicate with the petitioner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE97A6C1CF0F8449EBE23726F306FB498"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the petitioner is an organization, provide additional identifying information, as applicable, including the organizational or corporate status of the petitioner, the State of incorporation of the petitioner, the registered agent of the petitioner, the interest of the petitioner in representing small entities affected by the proposed rule and the certification at issue, and the name and authority of the individual who signed the petition on behalf of the organizational or corporate petitioner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A226B2EDEE84D389F4986D5D6E53544"><enum>(C)</enum><text>present the specific problems or issues that the petitioner believes should be addressed or considered through a review of the certification, such as—</text><clause id="HEF9C81110F3D46CBBD33CF62795EDEF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any specific circumstances in which the determination of the certification that the proposed rule will not, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities is incorrect, incomplete, or inadequate; or</text></clause><clause id="HF61C063405E84C18858FB8229C54DFDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>why the proposed rule would, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3717BF7506747B8B94838FB92E2FFA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cite, enclose, or reference any relevant and non-protected or confidential technical, scientific, or other data or information supporting any assertion of the problems or issues with the certification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81A2AA6D71EF4DA3A0CBD555E2D99E2F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>present a proposed solution to the problems or issues raised in the petition, including potential regulatory or compliance alternatives to the proposed rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05C430CCC371439784F6E7947C475FF1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide an analysis, discussion, or argument that explains how the proposed solution described in subparagraph (E) solves the problems or issues raised in the petition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC88B8BB741C642EBB358BE1276F6AC50"><enum>(G)</enum><text>cite, enclose, or reference any other publicly available data or information supporting the proposed solution described in subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H141B64E89E6C496390215E1A55AAA483"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><paragraph id="H2FC107E012904DF48AF9D55E48F59A5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any entity or organization desiring to file a petition under subsection (a) may request a consultation with the Chief Counsel before or after filing the petition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC02C518697E84C94AAE8D56607DCC461"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The Chief Counsel shall—</text><subparagraph id="HA993BF2AD6EA4F9B9140F0E9FA20542F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine the method, timing, and form of requesting a consultation with the Chief Counsel under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDECA2FD1FDF14601A4958861FF8D9AD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>display the information described in subparagraph (A) on the website of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration in a conspicuous manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD35C9C364BB94B86918DF80D58937B8B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on assistance</header><text>In any consultation regarding a petition under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel—</text><subparagraph id="HAB1E72A085F0448B8D3B6FC7A0C32FF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may only—</text><clause id="HC61DB267601D49A2868CAD472B204DA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the process for filing, docketing, tracking, closing, amending, withdrawing, and resolving the petition; and</text></clause><clause id="HF9C136A27C5E410CB4D2CAE7CF8804DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist the petitioner to clarify the petition so that the Chief Counsel is able to understand the issues of concern to the petitioner; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7E821AE99674F6E883CF6E4FAB64654"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not advise a petitioner on whether the petition should be amended or withdrawn.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6259F616BB1549C5A29354600492AD9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prima facie review</header><paragraph id="HEB751318DE1C41EBBA8F346E122CBFD7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of a petition filed under this section with respect to the certification of a proposed rule, the Chief Counsel shall make an initial prima facie determination on the merit of the issues raised in the petition as to the properness of the certification and whether the proposed rule in question would, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBC9A056BBCA4DF99F8C0C7C411AE7A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No further review</header><text>If, following the prima facie review of a petition under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel determines that the issues raised in the petition do not merit further review by the Chief Counsel, the Chief Counsel shall, not later than 10 days after receipt of the petition, inform the petitioner of that determination and the matter shall be closed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H747D621AE1494DEF83B0766F2D358792"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Further review</header><text>If, following the prima facie review of a petition under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel determines that the issues raised in the petition do merit further review by the Chief Counsel, the Chief Counsel shall, not later than 10 days after receipt of the petition, inform the petitioner and the agency that promulgated the proposed rule that the Chief Counsel shall conduct a full review of the certification and proposed rule to which the petition relates under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8EEC5907B6734EC38C872A58E52CBC9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Full review</header><paragraph id="H881E061793D34CB09692AB3E8B1F6BF6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Considerations; meeting</header><text>In conducting a full review under this subsection with respect to the certification made under section 605(b), the Chief Counsel shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1E4F4E711FA444F0B7C3A8A307DC9A8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider—</text><clause id="H19C9693E52464A1C850DCCCE3E2FE2DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the agency that promulgated the proposed rule correctly determined which small entities will be affected by the proposed rule;</text></clause><clause id="H52C3A16C04D246FB924C93E83730D6EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the agency considered adequate economic data to assess whether the proposed rule will have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities; and</text></clause><clause id="HC939A51779EA4BE989BF5FCA23B53C9C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the economic implications of the proposed rule; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2A2CB9B82AC4CCEBD7F9852BC1CB028"><enum>(B)</enum><text>convene a virtual or in-person meeting between the Chief Counsel, the petitioner, representatives of the agency that promulgated the proposed rule who are determined appropriate by the Chief Counsel, and the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs to—</text><clause id="H3AD56430AC514DA8B61EC66F5B455BB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide positions and support for those positions regarding the certification of the proposed rule; and</text></clause><clause id="H3B31FA0978514FB0B0A35EB7847188B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allow the Chief Counsel to ask questions as the Chief Counsel determines necessary to make a final determination as to the validity of the certification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18BA0FC316304BE2AAF53B5457F58268"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Chief Counsel begins a full review of a certification made with respect to a proposed rule under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel shall submit to the petitioner and the agency that promulgated the proposed rule, and publish in the Federal Register and on the website of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, the results of the review conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF69FB1538BE41338C825D825BA0B845"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement to perform analyses</header><text>If, after a full review of a certification made with respect to a proposed rule under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel determines that the proposed rule will, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, the agency that promulgated the proposed rule shall perform an initial regulatory flexibility analysis and a final regulatory flexibility analysis for the proposed rule under sections 603 and 604, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDAF7B29B08F48C0898FA72F65204868"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>If an agency fails to attend the required meeting under paragraph (1)(B) or in any other way fails to assist the Chief Counsel in a full review under paragraph (1) with respect to a proposed rule of the agency, as determined by the Chief Counsel, the final rule shall not apply to small entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31F834FFEFA4494A9C7B6D3273C267E2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>For purposes of judicial review under chapter 7 of this title, a certification made by an agency under section 605(b) for which a petition is filed under subsection (a) shall be considered final agency action as of the date on which the Chief Counsel—</text><subparagraph id="H4C6233AE047F47FEAF0626C5002D6A75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>makes a determination under subsection (c)(2) that the issues raised in the petition do not merit further review; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A8B966DA9EB4EB1AFA88724593975C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publishes the results of a full review of the certification under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H822AE555A2294E67A91C82F7D8712958"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/605">section 605</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H21AF388167604E579B3351CAA476CA98" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSM00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSM00"><toc-entry level="section">605A. Review procedures relating to initial regulatory flexibility analysis certifications.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H17804AB9C3E84E8B8917D7396BACD1C3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Publication of guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 609 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5C018FCC023D43A9AC9472B3A7291814" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSM00"><subsection id="H3AAD7C4116DF47D1B86AEE94D754A96D"><enum>(f)</enum><text>With respect to any rule that an agency determines is likely to have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, the head of the agency shall, on regulations.gov or any similar internet website—</text><paragraph id="HFF60441FBAC94691B01B6A532A512D98"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish all guidance documents and other relevant documents, as determined by the agency, including any updated guidance documents that set forth interpretations of the rule; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3DB5948D02147849DC4213C9A38F449"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow for comments on the documents described in paragraph (1) to ensure that small entities may access and provide feedback on those documents.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE0F30376FDF04403AB526F634A9BF2A0"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review procedures for section 610 periodic review of rules</header><subsection id="HC22309A812544DB4803321E0B291E184"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 610 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4146C9E5881B41FA8FD17E173AD73787"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HE4030EB11DC34F94BA892B68BB64BE27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the following factors</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD302B8B5BB6B444F94AC7E26029E219C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0C2100B384841B9B4D392719EE794DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02BB1F6CAD1C4A8AB8FF6940BAF469A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H247EA062115F46919D329640C013FD20" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSM00"><paragraph id="HBD8977D74CA945B687AD8AC04F545E86"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any indirect costs described in the initial regulatory flexibility analysis under section 603(b)(6), and any other indirect costs that may have arisen during the 10-year period described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A948DF819D43F4AD527CC3A2F5740F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAA09BB925B6A4AC78A0AE306334D84F0" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSM00"><subsection id="H0075CAE9C2A84AF08A9A6D6029DB9BA1"><enum>(d)</enum><text>If an agency fails to conduct a review of a rule as required under this section within the 10-year period described in subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H291EE60C140F44B992A007EC62943BCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration shall notify the agency that the rule has ceased to be effective;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBBC930CC1BD45BEAF5927438C8A4652"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the agency shall publish in the Federal Register a notification that the rule has ceased to be effective, and solicit comments for why the rule should be reinstated; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABDBDB2500C74C35AE79FF6B6C7D35B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if, based on the comments received under paragraph (2), the agency determines that the rule should be reinstated—</text><subparagraph id="H5ED353E604DF4F8182881AA7620B97AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agency shall have 180 days beginning on the date of that determination to complete the review of the rule under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF80A28739E99453FB630D2CDD4777AE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon completion of the review under subparagraph (A), the rule shall be reinstated, notwithstanding the notice and comment rulemaking procedures under section 553 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE668B72B9F694B27AF2D549793AC3C95"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)(2) shall apply with respect to any final rule issued by an agency—</text><paragraph id="HDEEBBF9D731D4914A6FA53827B513C7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>during the 5-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC682B98C00FB4E3E8964FA936246DEDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2DA74951B05C4B848F306C836191994F" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act or the amendments made by this Act. <pagebreak></pagebreak></text></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" id="H115A1EC694DB471B8CBC370150569328"><section section-type="section-one" id="H564AC049B44C4FE0823BC7C5AAFD9A5C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prove It Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA27B35804C234BDFBDC5AB9124C8E81F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Initial regulatory flexibility analysis</header><subsection id="H9F61ADD6DECA460983DE9B9EFB7A71C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">Chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H88B00DFE603B43A9873C60527AD6983D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 603(b)—</text><subparagraph id="HF2B4CF0CA49749CBACB94F04488E3DBC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61297E1025AD4379AA038A72975879B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H726E34A7878B452FA25E250FE22C24AD" changed="added" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" committee-id="HJU00"><paragraph id="HF06DD06684654C42AF740B57CBAF527B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>where feasible, any reasonably foreseeable potential indirect costs the proposed rule may impose on small entities, including small entities that—</text><subparagraph id="H16702809D4A944859B97DB4BA604746F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase products or services from, sell products or services to, or otherwise conduct business with entities directly regulated by the rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E997232CC0C4B1DAED953CB82EE317E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are directly regulated by other governmental entities as a result of the rule; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC49CF361AA0D4C3892F6700CD15842A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are not directly regulated by the agency as a result of the rule but are otherwise subject to other agency rules as a result of the rule.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB3AF3285F544CD0B78D7001C17B2ECA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 605(b), by striking <quote>The agency</quote> and inserting <quote>Not later than 10 days after completing the certification described in this subsection, the agency</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C720FB54FBB4BB8AE4E21118D2F2C88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after section 605 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H13B070310B854A47AA22FEF0C44C4AF0" changed="added" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" committee-id="HJU00"><section id="HEB512527E4E3433294797AFCA0065B86"><enum>605A.</enum><header>Review procedures relating to initial regulatory flexibility analysis certifications</header><subsection id="H91CDC72828BF4F2A8DCF7B50DE3698FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Filing a petition To review agency certification of a proposed rule</header><paragraph id="HAA1F24FEEE734C37AD472A3B1C808B75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any small entity, group of small entities, or organization representing the interests of small entities may petition the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Chief Counsel</quote>) to review a certification published under section 605(b) that a proposed rule will not, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA16AA0C59A846F689B505D315760090"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The Chief Counsel shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1321DF278903457DBB83A88DCBC74516"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine the method, timing, and form of disseminating a petition described in paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67DEC6B919C549FAA972D54C5B7D4157"><enum>(B)</enum><text>display the information described in subparagraph (A) on the website of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration in a conspicuous manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F2225CC19B04FD6B1A3E124E84CCDB2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each petition described in paragraph (1) with respect to a certification published under section 605(b) for a proposed rule shall clearly and concisely—</text><subparagraph id="H47A4E49D91B647C3ABF9FC8944B49E80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specify the name of the petitioner and a telephone number, a mailing address, and an email address that the Chief Counsel may use to communicate with the petitioner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B8F93579C104CA2825C29D90D8BFCD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the petitioner is an organization, provide additional identifying information, as applicable, including the organizational or corporate status of the petitioner, the State of incorporation of the petitioner, the registered agent of the petitioner, the interest of the petitioner in representing small entities affected by the proposed rule and the certification at issue, and the name and authority of the individual who signed the petition on behalf of the organizational or corporate petitioner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BD20F4465B94938A0D2E6D3AB8D40ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>present the specific problems or issues that the petitioner believes should be addressed or considered through a review of the certification, such as—</text><clause id="H9066894E59284840A17744CD881B48C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any specific circumstances in which the determination of the certification that the proposed rule will not, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities is incorrect, incomplete, or inadequate; or</text></clause><clause id="H646CA8A25D044747B0B8BD2CE63A4D6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>why the proposed rule would, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD429FC3734C4D51B0146F0E272937E7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cite, enclose, or reference any relevant and non-protected or confidential technical, scientific, or other data or information supporting any assertion of the problems or issues with the certification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8156CC8859364B0EBA6970FB3C6AAE80"><enum>(E)</enum><text>present a proposed solution to the problems or issues raised in the petition, including potential regulatory or compliance alternatives to the proposed rule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9FC27A5BD3A412D8DC42AF9963D6987"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide an analysis, discussion, or argument that explains how the proposed solution described in subparagraph (E) solves the problems or issues raised in the petition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3F2C6B10A3E46A0BB2F07475707E2C8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>cite, enclose, or reference any other publicly available data or information supporting the proposed solution described in subparagraph (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H519620B9FA7345BE8732D2E19F3A2373"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><paragraph id="H000857064EBF45908F030266E7436E21"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any entity or organization desiring to file a petition under subsection (a) may request a consultation with the Chief Counsel before or after filing the petition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46B99A1A1E184FAA90319AB0AE9A6B7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The Chief Counsel shall—</text><subparagraph id="HBEDC5AA092A34C08981901961E1B1F20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine the method, timing, and form of requesting a consultation with the Chief Counsel under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBDCCE863F6A4F4EB5F1B0F75CE0D426"><enum>(B)</enum><text>display the information described in subparagraph (A) on the website of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration in a conspicuous manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD732193F892949DC8D2AA11886EEF114"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on assistance</header><text>In any consultation regarding a petition under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel—</text><subparagraph id="HCE3EF7730EFC496BB19C2B04D6F8B259"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may only—</text><clause id="H7D32855755F744629FDE8292D05178BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the process for filing, docketing, tracking, closing, amending, withdrawing, and resolving the petition; and</text></clause><clause id="H75D5A07CF1F44255909CDA1884E3CCEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assist the petitioner to clarify the petition so that the Chief Counsel is able to understand the issues of concern to the petitioner; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CCC37E87A4E444F9F0FEFD59C403D23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not advise a petitioner on whether the petition should be amended or withdrawn.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE82820BC90D34FEDA944C417A6581832"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prima facie review</header><paragraph id="H811750BEDD8E427D9EED75C60D918F17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon receipt of a petition filed under this section with respect to the certification of a proposed rule, the Chief Counsel shall make an initial prima facie determination on the merit of the issues raised in the petition as to the properness of the certification and whether the proposed rule in question would, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H957BF62FD08A4A19A33F66EF75D8B490"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No further review</header><text>If, following the prima facie review of a petition under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel determines that the issues raised in the petition do not merit further review by the Chief Counsel, the Chief Counsel shall, not later than 10 days after receipt of the petition, inform the petitioner of that determination and the matter shall be closed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H106BC1231B1748FE9099EF9D9DCB1E60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Further review</header><text>If, following the prima facie review of a petition under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel determines that the issues raised in the petition do merit further review by the Chief Counsel, the Chief Counsel shall, not later than 10 days after receipt of the petition, inform the petitioner and the agency that promulgated the proposed rule that the Chief Counsel shall conduct a full review of the certification and proposed rule to which the petition relates under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2783797E69F4A3483AEB319E504A818"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Full review</header><paragraph id="H25E351BA06E7419A98A6A45188529F57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Considerations; meeting</header><text>In conducting a full review under this subsection with respect to the certification made under section 605(b), the Chief Counsel shall—</text><subparagraph id="H9A11F043F8294C058518769F09160EB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider—</text><clause id="H8BF7EC82626A4ECABD3EA85442616F17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the agency that promulgated the proposed rule correctly determined which small entities will be affected by the proposed rule;</text></clause><clause id="HC602A184831E48D7AA07EFD13AF12060"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the agency considered adequate economic data to assess whether the proposed rule will have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities; and</text></clause><clause id="H9F9E2FEE388840D181E247975B1955BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the economic implications of the proposed rule; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4F159C778B7461F8BE28A4B934EDB69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>convene a virtual or in-person meeting between the Chief Counsel, the petitioner, representatives of the agency that promulgated the proposed rule who are determined appropriate by the Chief Counsel, and the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs to—</text><clause id="HD0F38E9145B34570B6F08EB0CC2F53AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide positions and support for those positions regarding the certification of the proposed rule; and</text></clause><clause id="H055A060B6BAA4081A0E195328C1905D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allow the Chief Counsel to ask questions as the Chief Counsel determines necessary to make a final determination as to the validity of the certification.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE479614FC75D4A169848F2795050D5C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Chief Counsel begins a full review of a certification made with respect to a proposed rule under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel shall submit to the petitioner and the agency that promulgated the proposed rule, and publish in the Federal Register and on the website of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, the results of the review conducted under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13575A46BF6A4967AB44F30B39424473"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement to perform analyses</header><text>If, after a full review of a certification made with respect to a proposed rule under paragraph (1), the Chief Counsel determines that the proposed rule will, if promulgated, have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, the agency that promulgated the proposed rule shall perform an initial regulatory flexibility analysis and a final regulatory flexibility analysis for the proposed rule under sections 603 and 604, respectively.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E0501E93B7D4F939659B2F5C8252F93"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>If an agency fails to attend the required meeting under paragraph (1)(B) or in any other way fails to assist the Chief Counsel in a full review under paragraph (1) with respect to a proposed rule of the agency, as determined by the Chief Counsel, the final rule shall not apply to small entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F05ED78D43646359FDB1B93D0AD7EF1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>For purposes of judicial review under chapter 7 of this title, a certification made by an agency under section 605(b) for which a petition is filed under subsection (a) shall be considered final agency action as of the date on which the Chief Counsel—</text><subparagraph id="H5B8A621CA4BA43409FB4274885266EA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>makes a determination under subsection (c)(2) that the issues raised in the petition do not merit further review; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9BBAE50176A4427BB2F8A35B0324F0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publishes the results of a full review of the certification under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE48463F7A7BC42098D0C7A2FD351F6DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/605">section 605</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H8814B2762588485E81D2B0D377F94FCC" changed="added" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" committee-id="HJU00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" committee-id="HJU00"><toc-entry level="section">605A. Review procedures relating to initial regulatory flexibility analysis certifications.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H8BB37CB6E62744E5AB9B39DC645BE471"><enum>3.</enum><header>Publication of guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 609 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H63058BCE6EF245638B51261484E44366" changed="added" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" committee-id="HJU00"><subsection id="H96E0462D7B0E44849A5C81D7F353EB12"><enum>(f)</enum><text>With respect to any rule that an agency determines is likely to have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, the head of the agency shall, on regulations.gov or any similar internet website—</text><paragraph id="H2CC373A6E2D2499E96D8B3A38AF86036"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish all guidance documents and other relevant documents, as determined by the agency, including any updated guidance documents that set forth interpretations of the rule; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BFB92A7D2B74334804F2443ABF660A0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow for comments on the documents described in paragraph (1) to ensure that small entities may access and provide feedback on those documents.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H73E95B1007624A4292E621B7448F3A18"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review procedures for section 610 periodic review of rules</header><subsection id="H2650776C730D44CB93C15AFE6E2CB8FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 610 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H82A709C3E8474B20830ACE00CDA70733"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HEEF5616625884FD19612ABC6A5AF727B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the following factors</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB2D9BE9065F4C68812F51CCA48B451A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA777A5B229C44F3ADF9217C844FCFBC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD75868BDF55475993CC80C0AF85554F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H556562757295499487ED6EB5EFE476BB" changed="added" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" committee-id="HJU00"><paragraph id="HB0F4F6BE43B3489F8361B4CCDDBD07E8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any indirect costs described in the initial regulatory flexibility analysis under section 603(b)(6), and any other indirect costs that may have arisen during the 10-year period described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AEAB325F62A46BB85F9C8E69AE8F66F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE8D8CBD367B344C8B05F3D18F9C60B87" changed="added" reported-display-style="boldface-roman" committee-id="HJU00"><subsection id="H75FB31043A5C43FB9969E0C040CACB26"><enum>(d)</enum><text>If an agency fails to conduct a review of a rule as required under this section within the 10-year period described in subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H972AC29BDAB54210ADFC82CFAB71B177"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration shall notify the agency that the rule has ceased to be effective;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E351FE1AD3D4B3AB1CA3C2E0BD94A18"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the agency shall publish in the Federal Register a notification that the rule has ceased to be effective, and solicit comments for why the rule should be reinstated; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C44708F8E874DA7AFDA53B6B5A6A216"><enum>(3)</enum><text>if, based on the comments received under paragraph (2), the agency determines that the rule should be reinstated—</text><subparagraph id="HC83F7868BD6C4B5BB711E72BDD026ED9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the agency shall have 180 days beginning on the date of that determination to complete the review of the rule under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB78A33FBC6A42F4848A308EB12B06B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon completion of the review under subparagraph (A), the rule shall be reinstated, notwithstanding the notice and comment rulemaking procedures under section 553 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC52B83A119414C0EAC1559B62245E288"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)(2) shall apply with respect to any final rule issued by an agency—</text><paragraph id="HF8A22DAD6B6C427C919CE2444A8701BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>during the 5-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA3F00AB8D2F4308AD83AD65903BCA9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6EF472490CF9434FBE6BC02590FDEF45" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>No additional funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No additional funds are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of carrying out this Act or the amendments made by this Act. </text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00"> Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

