<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7C45D8A3AB5F41ACAB966312CF5C27AE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7586 IH: American Families First Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260213">February 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001188">Mr. Stutzman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To set restrictions on the sale of single-family homes financed by the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H138B62B549494A09875C3F63462121F5" style="OLC"><section id="H4907325E44454035953B6CA782ED8505" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Families First Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7F3140949C7341D98A49EBD04CC4CC06"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restrictions on the sale of single-family homes financed by the Federal Government</header><subsection id="HAE798F5624974283959FA8281C70036A"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Federal guidance regarding the sale of single-Family homes financed through Government programs</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 180 days of the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Administrator of General Services, and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, as appropriate, shall issue guidance to agencies and Government-sponsored enterprises that, to the maximum extent permitted by law shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="HE3A0143C4A5F4C7EA3DCA2B4D38D420F">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an agency-specific definition of a <quote>large institutional investor</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HAED1723FA9554B61B17537900E890A03">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>prevent providing for, approving, insuring, guaranteeing, securitizing, or facilitating the acquisition by a large institutional investor of a single-family home that could otherwise be purchased by an individual owner-occupant;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0D77D4CEB43B41D9A852D6B20A3304BE">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>restrict the disposing of Federal assets in a manner that transfers a single-family home to a large institutional investor; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H09A80C85B729434888F00A87AC053C34">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>promote sales of real estate-owned properties to individual owner-occupants, including through anti-circumvention provisions, first-look policies, and disclosure requirements.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection><subsection id="HC3B3B265A01842E4A5CD8714354AC1AB">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Exceptions for actions that support individual owner-Occupant housing</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The guidance issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall include appropriate, narrowly tailored exceptions for build-to-rent properties that are planned, permitted, financed, and constructed as rental communities, and such other appropriate, narrowly tailored exceptions as the applicable agency may determine appropriate to further the goal of using Government programs and financing of single-family homes to support individual owner-occupants.</text>
      </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

