<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-AEG26306-243-RR-YXJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4578 IS: Gateway to Careers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4578</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260520">May 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to establish a career pathways grant program.</official-title></form><legis-body><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gateway to Careers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id2931ddc0741846fda98dc3b8e6abfcee"><enum>2.</enum><header>Career Pathways Grant Program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0af75e5876942fdaecc05d5d5c392b5"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle D of title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3221">29 U.S.C. 3221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="idA1E0192EC4014025A57D659E2E79AAA3" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><section id="id7aedddc5311745818142341464d39999"><enum>173.</enum><header>Career Pathways Grant Program</header><subsection id="idDFF32E690F9643CB850FC51ED499A92E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="id12A67C04853D4861931E4EE398577134"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Career pathway partnership applicant</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6d6697447cd84549ba8629f8e451af48"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>career pathway partnership applicant</term> means a partnership that includes—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id403f7e6d1b2d4b99a2a59d42d20118b4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a workforce development partner;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id956b27ba7aea4e77bac027b85a28a4e6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an education partner; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb58e75daa8ea4406a8a249733b359e0b"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employer partner.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id11622568BAA24061B7BEC7F0A969B5B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Workforce development partner</header><text>A workforce development partner described in subparagraph (A) means one or more of the following:</text><clause id="id8C7981DDE593468E9C436DAFFF22394C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A State board or a local board.</text></clause><clause id="id35C0EBDE264847DE87034976A050FFB8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An industry association or other representative of multiple employers in the target industry, including an eligible industry or sector partnership.</text></clause><clause id="id1E2AD76E694C423384EA7C321A578BAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A community-based organization with experience in providing employment, education, or support services relevant to the career pathway and student populations receiving services under the grant under this section.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd1a91ca8d96846d394194a57903ef194"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Another State entity with experience transitioning individuals into the workforce (including through a community rehabilitation program (as defined in section 7 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/705">29 U.S.C. 705</external-xref>))), such as a State comprehensive rehabilitation center.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF3B5D03B849244D2B0CC53ACEA2E462F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Education partner</header><text>An education partner described in subparagraph (A) means one or more of the following:</text><clause id="id9C51D01C21014CE48EB74EFE9A0F9EF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An institution of higher education, as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>), or a postsecondary vocational institution, as defined in section 102(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="id17EAEE7590C948EFB3F1A275C503178C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An area career and technical education school that provides education at the postsecondary level.</text></clause><clause id="id14315cfa32b94225afda9b6a28012eb5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A local educational agency, as defined under section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="idd57308b4f5b44d59a351d09ab6bf000d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An eligible provider, as defined under section 203.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30f87ce0f89945178d16310e0b99dcf5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Employer partner</header><text>An employer partner described in subparagraph (A) means a representative of multiple businesses or other employers in the career pathways field, including small and medium-sized employers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7cecb0565c954b88a6cb6602f069f892"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible industry or sector partnership</header><text>The term <term>eligible industry or sector partnership</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idd375edf7cb6e4084b2cadaff7376992d"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an industry or sector partnership, which shall, at a minimum, include multiple representatives described in each of clauses (i) through (iii) of paragraph (26)(A) of section 3; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26c798403be9410a9365968366dfcefa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a partnership, of multiple entities described in section 3(26) and a State board or local board, that is in the process of establishing an industry or sector partnership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="id3B9D89A4C26D4C809E16F861A1F29B9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Measurable skill gains</header><text>The term <term>measurable skill gains</term> has the meaning given the term in section 361.155(a)(1)(v) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD50C69E5E76848DCA89B0FE9E20E9DB6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0489bba50a704df7af10c0422b22b1a2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Universal design for learning</header><text>The term <term>universal design for learning</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4D027F3CEDDC4CB1AB62927F641E7653"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program established</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4ee2922c66854f80bd76f5a39bf9c009"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall establish a career pathway grant program, through which the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to State workforce agencies to enable the State workforce agencies to award subgrants to career pathway partnership applicants to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7f71ebc049b5488b952f36fcc2430d9d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant awards to career pathway partnership applicants</header><text>In the case of a State in which the State workforce agency does not apply for a grant under this section, the Secretary may award a grant to a career pathway partnership applicant to carry out the activities described in subsection (e) in such State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide0b940e7212f448e9b5ce08412401a63"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application for grants</header><text>A State workforce agency that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="id84fb12793b734bdbac9b87e1239cd10f"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Geographic equity</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure an equitable geographic distribution of such grants, including to rural areas and other regions that have traditionally been underserved by regional economic development and industry or sector partnership activities.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id863a3e70eff047a0b71d40bc5f0a4a8e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Subgrants to career pathway partnership applicants and technical assistance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida80abbd6480e4ff1a45cf559b48115b7"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A State workforce agency that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9dd4813d96004a5880b9131f07e70fb6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to award subgrants to career pathway partnership applicants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb2e6e64d31104ec598de1b1fc63dbc34"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide technical assistance in applying for subgrants under this section to eligible career pathway partnership applicants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5C6328F7B90C42B6890C6B41367B1868"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>A career pathway partnership applicant desiring to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the State workforce agency, at such time and in such manner as the State workforce agency may require. Such application shall include the following information:</text><subparagraph id="idf8336290aa5e4b978e3696bf77dbd8c3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the career pathway program that will be supported under the subgrant, including a description of the in-demand industry sectors or occupations that will be targeted and the industry-recognized credentials or other recognized postsecondary credentials to be awarded.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf379837f3d6d45a3b00e46ec69cf331d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of how the career pathway program supported under the subgrant is aligned and coordinated with other employment, education, and support services offered in the geographic area served under the subgrant, including those provided under this Act, the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2301">20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.</external-xref>), the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>), the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), and the program of block grants to States for temporary assistance for needy families under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09ab6f5ff78d472fbe5c25c291339041"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the populations that will be served under the subgrant, including an analysis of any barriers to employment, such as supportive services, including in postsecondary education, access, and completion, that such populations face, and an analysis of how the services to be provided under the subgrant will address those barriers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida5524de09d8d4769b24619ff0c6ca5b1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the activities and services to be provided under this subgrant, consistent with paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce7ed9b9590546babbd63783f46ba535"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description of the performance outcomes that the career pathway partnership applicant plans to achieve, including a description of how the career pathway partnership applicant will evaluate and measure student progress and measurable skill gains along a career pathway.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf571eddf72144688ae34f33ad3ec973c"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Such other information as the State workforce agency may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2d1b9869836345b48e42b7e8ccaa3b1b"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding subgrants under this subsection, the State workforce agency shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ca90b7606154293945b32eca0c0a34c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>give priority to career pathway partnership applicants that include as a partner in the partnership a public institution of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree, including 2-year Tribal Colleges or Universities under section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>), public 2-year State institutions of higher education, and the campuses of 4-year public institutions of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students in an associate's degree;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id038ECE99675246E193D1E5032C4CF3CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>give priority to career pathway partnership applicants that seek to serve individuals with a barrier to employment or individuals with a barrier to postsecondary education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1350f0829b5436e8df759b27116b229"><enum>(C)</enum><text>give priority to career pathway partnership applicants that will use subgrant funds for an activity, strategy, or intervention that—</text><clause id="id425530f655bf46afaa8a6a68091f5de5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrates, using evidence-based data, improving student outcomes or other relevant outcomes based on—</text><subclause id="id898f5bb47e3a4ec1809117e112408bd4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>strong evidence from not less than 1 well-designed and well-implemented experimental study;</text></subclause><subclause id="id8641117239fe4deea768ff0611808855"><enum>(II)</enum><text>moderate evidence from not less than 1 well-designed and well-implemented quasi-experimental study; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id8a1be9840fd04871ae45c9ed16ee73f8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>promising evidence from not less than 1 well-designed and well-implemented correlational study with statistical controls for selection bias;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id212be7c6cf244451abf0bc456083d280"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates a rationale based on high quality research finding or positive evaluation that such activity, strategy, or intervention is likely to improve student outcomes or other relevant outcomes; and</text></clause><clause id="ide4cbeb6ef3d8491fb98c61979b9bafb2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>includes ongoing efforts to examine the effects of such activity, strategy, or intervention.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d323061c3d848009eb627c09b2c9cd9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><subparagraph id="id4618437C8D3E4D8B90AEAB71BA82FD17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Developing and implementing career pathway programs</header><text>A career pathway partnership applicant that receives a subgrant under this subsection shall use the subgrant funds to carry out activities that support the development and implementation of a career pathway program, which shall include one or more of the following:</text><clause id="id6cb9892304b0425c87a1a5545278038e" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The planning and implementation of agreements between the partners of the career pathway partnership applicant to support seamless transitions between elements of the career pathway program offered by different partners, as appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="idcfecf7a0d95445dba882a4a36f6c81eb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The development and expansion of new or existing programs at the career pathway partnership applicant that utilize integrated education and training strategies, and support multiple entry and exit points for working learners, which may include—</text><subclause id="id4ab630613f7e4abb9dd08c2c7f24283d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>dual-enrollment approaches for secondary students or disconnected youth seeking to participate in a career pathway program;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3b1ba9c409a14827b5fffd64e7142a92"><enum>(II)</enum><text>strategies that help working students and other nontraditional and adult student populations access skills and recognized credentials; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6e9f5da6f7de45feb5a68d017b6d3d35"><enum>(III)</enum><text>strategies that incorporate the principles of universal design for learning and other evidence-based practices known to support individuals with disabilities.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ide223b1d016ef417ca4cf25bd0018665d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The provision of evidence-based professional development for faculty and other staff at the career pathway partnership applicant, which may incorporate the principles of universal design for learning, as appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="id6822f20a424e4a85a9865c1cdf57f3de"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The acquisition of equipment necessary to support the delivery of career pathway programs supported through the subgrant, and minor alterations to support the use of the equipment.</text></clause><clause id="idc7e5d6deb72e42edb5d22d9ab9f43b95"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any other evidence-based activities identified by the career pathway partnership applicant as necessary to support the development or implementation of career pathway programs, as long as such activities are clearly outlined in the subgrant application.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b97dbdeb3f64e2dac0958c2a535a7f4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Student support services</header><text>In addition to the activities described in subparagraph (A), a career pathway partnership applicant receiving a subgrant under this subsection shall use subgrant funds to provide student support services to students engaged in career pathway programs to enable career pathway program participation and completion, which may include—</text><clause id="id72f20486e2e34c18abd90bdd4fbf2ef5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the provision of direct support services such as childcare, transportation, mental health and substance use disorder treatment, assistance in obtaining health insurance coverage, and assistance in accessing the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children established by section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>), housing, and other benefits, as appropriate;</text></clause><clause id="id666edfba83814ed0b843818d5c87e8e9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>offering career pathway navigation and case management services, including providing information and outreach to target populations to encourage individuals to take part in programs and service offerings; and</text></clause><clause id="idfeff2f2b41d0452a95a230d4aaa411d2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the provision of emergency grants to help students facing financial hardships that may impact enrollment or completion of an element of a career pathway program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf9a2959c057b4ef7b8b008bd7116f5c7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="id4A52FD16CF0E4FF48E8FC5ABA2C09087"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Report to the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State workforce agency receiving a grant under this section shall submit a report to the Secretary, on an annual basis, describing—</text><clause id="idcb3bf9ac3db94faab997d6a0d116240b"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the activities provided under the subgrants awarded under this section, including activities carried out directly by career pathway partnership applicants;</text></clause><clause id="ide77186490c65451cbdb178753a19a2cf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the students receiving services under the subgrants, disaggregated by age, race or ethnicity, gender, barriers to employment, and income;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd718e4c1ef7141dfa80dfe9876330619"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the quality of jobs in which students receiving services through a career pathway program carried out through subgrants under this section are employed after exit from the program; and</text></clause><clause id="idfc11de855c6344e19ba52476b0571154"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>indicators of performance for students receiving services through a career pathway program carried out through subgrants under this section, disaggregated by participant type as described in clause (ii), including, at a minimum—</text><subclause id="idedafc439480244ee92d190f8be869ab3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment prior to enrollment in the career pathway program;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida2d76ff6584f4fb298041ee93b02de48"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after exit from the program;</text></subclause><subclause id="ida32303e65d5c4000ad8daf1f6408dd60"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the fourth quarter after exit from the program;</text></subclause><subclause id="idbabc283ead78406682c16062de633dff"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the median earnings of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment prior to enrollment in the career pathway program;</text></subclause><subclause id="idb278cb0d68134a83ba6372916bb00645"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the median earnings of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after exit from the program;</text></subclause><subclause id="ide751c9dcfee84ff29bb2eb48f2c91929"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who obtain a recognized postsecondary credential, or a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent, during participation in or within 1 year after exit from the program;</text></subclause><subclause id="idda9c86d51c4241cc9efd9ed1ff68ea9f"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who, during a program year, are in an education or training program that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential or employment and who are achieving measurable skill gains toward such a credential or employment; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id0D5DF606201C4A2580F87AFB32B313B1"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants receiving support services, disaggregated by type of service.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4704d47f97c74348882988be687ca1c7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report to Congress, on a biennial basis, on the information submitted to the Secretary under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idAB8A6BA94EC64256A7C3EE446F5A9545" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duration of awards</header><text>Each grant and subgrant awarded under this section shall be for a period of not more than 4 years. A career pathway partnership applicant may apply for subsequent subgrants after the completion of a subgrant period.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9b3c32373d904202b3b4d049032aa7d2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation and administration</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idecb64574a2b54c338d302a76671a3dfc"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 1 percent and not more than 3 percent of the funds made available under subsection (h) for each fiscal year to—</text><subparagraph id="id60c0a37ab7714fc5a4cac0a40c3112eb"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a rigorous, independent evaluation of the activities funded under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id790c78f7f4534a00a5c0c5fe5760c73b"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disseminate and promote the utilization of evidence-based practices related to career pathway programs for postsecondary students; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc9360ad538d44163bd8f938807570955"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 3 percent of the funds made available under subsection (h) for each fiscal year for administrative costs associated in carrying out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idadf35a945f11463dbd8f8e4255ea31c9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the activities described in this section, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2027 and for each subsequent fiscal year thereafter.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H81245617DE664E6AB785DBD1070B1ABF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 172, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD2B2C3E7681A48E5B38D35F6CCC59B8D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 173. Career pathways grant program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

