<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94A916A0EB5B4074B31E30362F30CF5B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6989 IH: Public Health Nursing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6989</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108">January 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out activities to establish, expand, and sustain a public health nursing workforce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H76F5E9BBC2E247D5ADFA1127031F9176" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H37C50D94E95E4B6797149E86E87F49BA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Health Nursing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H855F6A9332994469A6AD0A629F0A378F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public health nursing workforce</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part E of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/294n">42 U.S.C. 294n et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69569BA8BF604C2EA434F292A73905CD"> 
<subpart id="H6DB7ED723F68491B9F0E5DEBD6E30D71" style="OLC"><enum>4</enum><header>Public health nursing workforce</header> 
<section id="HE833F0CB46CC4583AB4AB04146462805"><enum>780.</enum><header>Public health nursing workforce</header> 
<subsection id="HF8E6E58A3D64417FBD1A4E863A5E7101"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out activities relating to establishing, expanding, and sustaining a public health nursing workforce, including by making grants to State, local, and territorial public health departments.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H882D3973EC8A4DA2855E06E1D1AB648C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds for public health departments</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H15F234FC2CDA477887861718649CB05D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recipient of a grant under subsection (a) shall use the grant funds for the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H91D35A0CDC2148E78CBDCA3B405FE5F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs (including wages and benefits) relating to the recruiting, hiring, and training of licensed registered nurses to serve as public health nurses—</text> <clause id="HEE7419EE1B004ADC8F8B06C5499A3A20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who are employed by the State, territorial, or local public health department involved, particularly in medically underserved areas; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB2B2E3A833D04B2DA31DD053B92908FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who work in public health facilities, including mobile health clinics and acute care hospitals, or who provide home visitation.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4842007C3BF4E1199A326376A2D2AA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Costs of medical supplies, including personal protective equipment, necessary to carry out the activities described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H296041B1AC1C4322A599A03BB273F75A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Administrative costs and activities relating to grant activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H122298B44B294BA3987198B0AFCE2F9F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text>The recipient of a grant under subsection (a) may make subgrants to local health departments to be used for the activities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA6B507086D504C5CB59AE31060793268"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting recipients of grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to applicants that—</text> <paragraph id="H99C7D332C9984380A3A2BBD90558635E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>propose to serve—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5DDF2D010656412D82A688FA21649787"><enum>(A)</enum><text>areas with populations that have a high rate of chronic disease, infant mortality, or maternal morbidity and mortality;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0659FA85E96B42AA91185167D62245A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>low-income populations, including medically underserved populations (as defined in section 330(b));</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEEE16A07127C46119DED71EF2A9D1A8C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>populations residing in health professional shortage areas (as defined in section 332(a));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE484C262CBC24446AFE154AB138FB969"><enum>(D)</enum><text>populations residing in maternity care health professional target areas identified under section 332(k); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE55EFED56C3F40EFBE430F0D38139FFF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>rural or traditionally underserved populations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78D9D6988DD2471FA65F4BE60C4E3255"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrate a plan for providing services, to the maximum extent practicable, in the language and cultural context more appropriate to individuals expected to be served by the program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BCC699C98384C08908627E24E31A4B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have a documented collective bargaining agreement with 1 or more labor organizations representing employees of the applicant or have an explicit policy not to interfere with the rights of employees of the applicant under section 7 of the National Labor Relations Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB463FDC7CD5D4961A3D613FF6E503B06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Maintenance of effort</header><text>The recipient of a grant under subsection (a) shall agree to maintain expenditures of non-Federal amounts for activities described in subsection (b) at a level that is not less than the level of such expenditures maintained by the recipient for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the recipient receives such a grant.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA50196B3DD5498D81B3FD195CE8B7EC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Public health nurse defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>public health nurse</quote> means a nurse providing health care services and education regarding preventive health, nutrition, infectious diseases, chronic disease management, and maternal health, prenatal, and postpartum care in order to improve maternal and infant health outcomes.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H343431015FF94F3F9E438B79F0A3AC4B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $5,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2035.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

