<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H612F804106AA4C3491B9F1923EF9B4AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7161 IH: No Private Bounty Hunters for Immigration Enforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7161</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260120">January 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the use of Federal contractors to perform certain enforcement activities under the immigration laws, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H78A0D2875C6C4824B6C65E99F462642A" style="OLC"><section id="HDE0B9874AB884254AFA21A94E0BB44ED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Private Bounty Hunters for Immigration Enforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H54D1AB61DC0A46E8A2BBD4E981303B21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on the use of contractors to enforce the immigration laws</header><subsection id="HA9E5A87370B14DD7921AF7D6223B35F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain DHS contracts</header><paragraph id="H625F6F820172457B988844BDF7032288"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security—</text><subparagraph id="H0523370A09BA4B68A2E49A5E989C9FCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not enter into any contract or memorandum of understanding with any person after the date of the enactment of this Act to perform skip tracing, surveillance, or location verification for the purpose of civil enforcement of the immigration laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40655E5B280F446FB61E1BE952B51D5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall—</text><clause id="HE825BB4CE9DD4B4681709F2C126DB375"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">terminate any contract or memorandum of understanding of the Department of Homeland Security in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act that provides for the performance of skip tracing, surveillance, or location verification for the purpose of civil enforcement of the immigration law; and</text></clause><clause id="HC0C8CD34F4B54740BC74DF8F9C726E3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">amend any contract or memorandum of understanding of the Department of Homeland Security in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act not described under clause (i) to prohibit the performance of skip tracing, surveillance, or location verification for the purpose of civil enforcement of the immigration laws under such contract or memorandum.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80E3A678DB5E4705A138BAA4E2490DE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to subcontractors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person with which the Secretary of Homeland Security has a contract or memorandum of understanding, or any subcontractor thereof at any tier, may use a subcontractor to perform any function prohibited under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE857B65D9DB147FC9406B93411FA62AE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on use of Federal funds</header><paragraph id="HA14CECF829FF4E45B30877EB4D15A5F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), no Federal funds may be used to pay a private entity on a per-person or bonus basis for locating an individual who is subject to a civil immigration detainer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02AE191BD0DC42E59DC45963DCF92714"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) does not apply to the use of a publicly available data analytics tool operated solely by a Federal contractor performing an administrative data management function under direct Government supervision that does not involve—</text><subparagraph id="H8233E1A306CD403592B6CD8E8DBD725D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>field surveillance of, or personal contact with, the individual subject to the detainer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA372B4BC314438AA7BE20E463B61E25" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an activity prohibited under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE80E00074A0B43769CEB17B9245A51EB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall conduct an audit of each contract of the Department of Homeland Security to ensure that each such contract complies with the limitations under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3E3A7BE1414E4E4295620F77D2CE02C5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>skip tracing</term> means the practice of locating an individual using an address, employment data, social-media, or other personal data.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

