<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS26662-FFF-0J-008"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4335 IS: Helping Ensure Reliable Opportunities in Child Care for Military Families Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4335</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260416" legis-day="20260414">April 16 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S376">Ms. Ernst</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To address the challenges of providing child care opportunities for military families, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC7B42F67DBD145288B8D1D8D123C724D"><section section-type="section-one" id="H71A4C41816014EC5B6552D8ADCAE6C76"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Helping Ensure Reliable Opportunities in Child Care for Military Families Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HERO Child Care for Military Families Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H31D7C2913638435DA5F0767C04192D43"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of eligible child care providers for Department of Defense programs</header><subsection id="HC21801B14EAF43DB929BE0560E7D746C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Removal of prior service requirement</header><text>Section 1798(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDA3F108EBDBC462CAB695F6D978D481A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the semicolon and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7F7121AEE8A4F1E8E539839D2C7760A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB781F0FBA714941A51901A94556E912"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EDEF8CB41BB4393B3B3249B1116F42B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National service volunteers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/88">chapter 88</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1792">section 1792</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAD027AF7DBB4634971C96068D9783A4"><section id="HD0AED8F75AB643F1ADA3DC9650DEFC79"><enum>1792a.<?LEXA-Enum 1792a.?></enum><header>Child care employees: additional authorities</header><subsection id="H69086EF6D6044464AE7A138D83672882"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National service volunteers</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC8A3752491FD41CDBED8FB788056427F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may seek to enter into an interagency partnership with a Federal agency with the ability to place individuals described in paragraph (2) in military child development centers in accordance with national service laws and with all the benefits accorded to such individuals under those laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H374D8CDA12C3413999310FCCDE65457C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An individual described in this paragraph is a participant, including a volunteer or national senior volunteer, under the national service laws who is trained in education services and is in compliance with hiring requirements for military child development centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91B5EA423D1B4C76812C2D231A1186C0" indent="up1"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>In this subsection, the terms <term>participant</term> and <term>national service laws</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12511">42 U.S.C. 12511</external-xref>).</text>
 </paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HC60C1DF9C62F4F279F2A0F38ECC9A117"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preclearance of child care employees at military child development centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1792a of title 10, United States Code, as added by section 2(b) of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF82CAF7783B048CE80563A2BBE6B39D6"><subsection id="HEC5239507589448E9FF5C4C9D0082030"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preclearance of child care employees at military child development centers</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6547FE901A0F421183D3BD82A152D3AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than June 1, 2027, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall prescribe regulations, including by revising Department of Defense Instruction 1402.05, relating to background checks on individuals in Department of Defense child care services programs, or any successor instruction, to provide for preclearance of individuals applying to be child care employees at military child development centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7E9733093543BF9236B5416CF0E377" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In prescribing regulations under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AABCA3707FC4CCC9D3E695FB6362859"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specify a length of time, not to exceed one year, for the preclearance of an individual to be valid for purposes of employment at military child development centers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3C286A3DB140479ABB67D59614021EBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require annual reverification for a child care employee who received preclearance to be conducted not later than one year after the date of the preclearance of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE3A50C3A8E84454AA77BAB8F7AE99F1" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67236BF2E7D24FDEBF78A7B99E74D039"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to limit the ability of the Department of Defense to conduct, in accordance with regulations and policies of the Department, additional or more current or recent background checks on individuals who have received preclearance; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF183B58A4874BF9BFCEBF9C7C3E2439"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to require the Department—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H991252D7FD0D42EC8122B8BF5AC7626C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hire an individual who received preclearance; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D62C0799F97445EA30E6E82F1CE7FE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide any appeal or right of action to an individual who received preclearance and was not selected by the Department for an open position as a child care employee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D65B1050BEE4EBDA57BD3EBE3ED1F4A" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>preclearance</term>, with respect to an individual, means the individual obtains a background check, including a fingerprint check by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and a State Criminal History Repository check, and a health screening to be a child care employee at a military child development center, without regard to whether there is an open job for a child care employee at the time of the background check and screening are conducted.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE985F649A7E24C1C8E08E44CC20D05DD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of job-sharing arrangements for child care employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1792a of title 10, United States Code, as amended by section 3 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BB0027BFEC34A29B8E2BF328F7B792B"><subsection id="H3E60801729354E1F8C799BEC523601F3"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Authorization of job-Sharing arrangements for child care employees</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEB3200BBAD9942BEA47F2727B3FFF39F"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>Consistent with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/34">chapter 34</external-xref> of title 5, and policies of the Department of Defense permitting part-time employment and job-sharing arrangements for civilian personnel, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the use of voluntary job-sharing arrangements for child care employees at military child development centers.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HCF66EA2C033E49338AD6E6AE828988C1" indent="up1">
            <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>The Secretary may authorize job-sharing arrangements under this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HCFEB1C94CC00417A89C67B2377B45619"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>to expand the pool of qualified child care employees available to meet the needs of military families;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H80FCCBD572EC473FA40EEB09A940FE02">
              <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>to accommodate individuals unable to work full-time schedules as a result of caregiving, education, or other personal circumstances;</text>
            </subparagraph>
            <subparagraph id="H371C655A3975472A8DF0D1E66C399793">
              <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>to reduce staffing vacancies and workforce turnover; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA074C675ACFD46C6BAB5EE4D9B5C20C4"> <enum>(D)</enum> <text>to support continuity and reliability of child care services for military families.</text>
            </subparagraph>
          </paragraph>
          <paragraph id="HEBF53DA328F8457BBD8A095717297AA5" indent="up1">
            <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>In this subsection, the term <term>job-sharing arrangement</term> means a work arrangement under which the duties and responsibilities of a single full-time child care employee position are shared by two part-time child care employees, each serving not fewer than 20 hours per week.</text>
          </paragraph>
 </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H051775616C8D407E8C92EF88245F8347"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limited access to certain benefits for child care employees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1792a of title 10, United States Code, as amended by section 4 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA73BB27DFACF4224BCA66E8F89591223"><subsection id="HBA60DD37DD7E487B9FC24C23039D3F3E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limited access to certain benefits for child care employees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFBAA64ACD12C4B258ADAA6631387F024"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense may authorize child care employees working at military child development centers to receive limited access to benefits described in paragraph (2) if the Secretary determines such access is necessary to support recruitment and retention of child care employees and continuity of child care services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5FEFF45B3234126BD37811163DA7F3C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The benefits that may be provided to a child care employee under paragraph (1) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA8DB0B301E5E42D9A62B29FFF0D0AC3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Commissary and exchange privileges, on days on which the employee is providing child care services on a military installation, on the same basis as civilian employees of the Department of Defense under Directive-type Memorandum 21–003 or any successor Department of Defense issuance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1566B14720E4C43BD5C69C85E7B58B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Use of MWR retail facilities, including fitness centers, if the Secretary determines that authorizing such use will support the stability of the child care workforce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H155D9CBE6A15438DB6853102202605CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Tuition assistance and referral bonuses under terms and conditions comparable to similar workforce recruitment and retention programs authorized for other civilian and contractor workforces of the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA4D02A31A9748B1BFE8AE8DDC2A7DE5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such other limited benefits as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB879D106E04B423FA48D3518FF213F25" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB01F87E7F1D9481183FB4EEB2ADD866E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A child care employee who receives a benefit under paragraph (1) may not transfer the benefit to any other person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEF87BFDB5784D5593D01AB1E720B785" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary may revoke a benefit provided to a child care employee under paragraph (1) at any time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC37C2AAD7194E9889AA56F81606045B" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall issue guidance to implement this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8588E91C146C401181A3E3EFB9A132E4" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>MWR retail facility</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1063 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7D6C78A1E6F74B8E9F1077036BA55702"><enum>6.</enum><header>Department of Defense child care readiness data system</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/88">chapter 88</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1799">section 1799</external-xref> the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52679E206DAD4E0E91186D501B25AC91"><section id="HB5A7BEC4EB434D0EBA560004A2B0D328"><enum>1799a.<?LEXA-Enum 1799a.?></enum><header>Child care readiness data system</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE4FEC614B5C34C3AB824F05E28144D08"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall establish and maintain a unified, Department-wide child care readiness data system (in this section referred to as the <quote>System</quote>) to assess, monitor, and manage child care capacity and child care workforce readiness across the Department of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB7EC7557C6C488582730275B8D99501"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required data elements</header><text>The System shall include information on the following:</text><paragraph id="H37C775C8729B4236A82F4F43927E3792"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Child care capacity and utilization, disaggregated by military installation and region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93336086E15A49788EA1BDE79BFB09D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Child care workforce staffing levels, vacancies, turnover rates, and compensation ranges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9196AC71F75C496084E7AC80722557A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Child care waitlists, disaggregated by—</text><subparagraph id="HF98F95D4994D4D8EBC523278F5241203"><enum>(A)</enum><text>families with no access to child care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H730EB52004D7445391A4CE4B21242BE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>families using temporary child care or child care located off a military installation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB4BCB11929A46FC8C9969F66D86320E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>families requiring child care during nontraditional hours.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51DF33E5E853429E845BC1B168859B7A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Demand for child care by age cohort, with specific identification of children under age 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68A4DD0DD7AA4D00889E55E154BFB0E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Utilization and attrition data for fee assistance programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB2575CE5C1A49F490A06FF65A88E9DB"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Geographic areas with persistent unmet child care needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7816038629A34D19B1D982C3C2F96A76"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF170799288849908639C5A005731623"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Standardization and updates</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H332E3D0926134CC88CAA123965045B58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">standardize the collection of data on child care across the military departments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD180E4D22E94436A42C47F739C45F4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update the information in the System not less frequently than every 90 days.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7D35E81CADEC4C69B3D157DC76A6A249"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefings required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall brief the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives on—</text><paragraph id="HD8C00A9F8BEA4F89B4E2B62E91707879"><enum>(1)</enum><text>findings derived from the System;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE87B9CD24D445FAAABF3B5F04D58D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>actions taken to address any gaps in child care availability identified through the System; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9637B74652A9413B9263B1C971B5B6EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or regulatory authorities or funding required to reduce the unmet need for child care.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H6C1ABCD35437474CB387E8C7BD46C02C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on child care waitlists</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E29436F13D64244A5D678FA7598F799"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code) a report on waitlists for child care across the Department of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection id="H552427842CFD4974857A3E73A99AA0DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HB522D7F608A34735B047E0F4FD5ED74B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of steps being taken to centralize systems and collect data on waitlists for child care across the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CB2E1776A334BF09DE32CC2C4BA9C8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of data that the Department has on child care waitlists.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFCD37AC9D7A40CC920D3F93157F0AB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of steps being taken by the Department to resolve discrepancies or misleading information in the data, such as children being counted on multiple waitlists simultaneously and inclusion of children who are receiving child care services but are on waitlists for purposes of obtaining alternative child care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H051137C8D630419D93C024F9210D7853"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis of what proportion of waitlist spots represent unmet need for child care as opposed to duplicate entries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FFE79D4A65B4ED7BDE4C0932CD5AEDE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A plan for improving data collection on child care waitlists.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9344EA11BC044A379F6C08BD9D757B59"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report on relationship between child care availability and readiness</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code) a report that analyzes the relationship between child care availability and each of the following:</text><paragraph id="HB9E62157767A4B29A8998A806FA87139"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Military readiness and training participation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F4311A6365F4618B5E6B7BA636D7B6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Retention and separation decisions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47875A434CEA42B7BF0A0F456E875A07"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Families in which two parents are members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF20AA9DA16664D7B99569ABA15415357"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">High operational-tempo units.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD764BB1C297E47CBA4CCAE5602382146"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Workforce participation of military spouses.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

