<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H950B046A8BFE450DBC902ADB48094D84" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7588 IH: Eliminating Fraud in the CFPB’s Complaint Database Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7588</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260217">February 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 to require the attestation of certain information as part of the consumer complaint submission process, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6899340FA9644F6CB200263DA67FA8A8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0A3B708C63FA4A18A830724C5A17B783" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminating Fraud in the CFPB’s Complaint Database Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HED06695B302B4891927ECC696794A382"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collecting and tracking complaints</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1013(b)(3) of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5493">12 U.S.C. 5493(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8C49608082B54B6FB628D1B7306EFC72" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H7C9851825B064F91886F29299AC2BCF5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Consumer Attestation</header> 
<clause id="H4D2D39B72F514926BE8393BB16BDDEC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall require, using such verification mechanisms as the Director determines appropriate, each person who submits a complaint to the unit established under this paragraph to attest, under penalty of perjury, that—</text> <subclause id="HD284DC1E1A9D41FA97DF534782137112"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the information and documentation provided in the complaint is true and accurate to the best of the consumer’s knowledge;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H597A0F23B6DF4B31881BF994C6DD8EA7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the complaint is being submitted directly by—</text> <item id="H9D4AEC2CA77842F189CDC5CF8073BBED"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the consumer; or</text></item> 
<item id="H9A6AA4EAF1E544848625A6292CB2707D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a representative authorized to act on the behalf of the consumer who provides sufficient proof of identification and a written document signed by the consumer that permits the third party to act on the behalf of the consumer specifically as it relates to submitting a complaint to the Bureau; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H3B915CBCFDCC44ABB0066B4FB2D55C55"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the consumer directly informed the covered person who is required to respond to complaints under subsection (b) and (c) of section 1034 to which the complaint relates of the issue about which the consumer is submitting the complaint not less than 60 days before submitting the complaint to the Bureau.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HCD47842F32D84A74BDCA196763D901AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director finds, when carrying out clause (i), that a complaint submitted in the name of a consumer was not submitted by such consumer or by a representative authorized to act on the behalf of such consumer, the Director shall to the degree practicable—</text> <subclause id="HD99C6122572643E6B115E31D65ED31E3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inform the consumer in whose name the complaint was filed that such complaint was submitted in their name, without their authorization; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H01E7A07EA3C94DF1A22B86203B242A3E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to the covered person who is required to respond to complaints under subsection (b) and (c) of section 1034 to whom the complaint relates the name of the person who submitted the complaint without the authorization of the consumer.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC6185E695E8F4130A6060A34A71D08BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Sufficient proof of identification defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>sufficient proof of identification</quote> means information or documentation that identifies a protected consumer and a protected consumer’s representative and includes—</text> 
<subclause id="H1DD05981261A4BAFBAB735AC47E7050A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a social security number or a copy of a social security card issued by the Social Security Administration;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD226E4DA7CE243249770A0397548A1FF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a certified or official copy of a birth certificate issued by the entity authorized to issue the birth certificate; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1AA7066672F14C90B71F6F024CA64D25"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a copy of a driver’s license, an identification card issued by the motor vehicle administration, or any other government issued identification.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C337127397E4FE786EFE54CBEA443E4"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Closure of duplicative, frivolous or unauthorized complaints</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">—</text> 
<clause id="H0CB57FDD9BE94D609102F2C1989C4210"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered person who is required to respond to complaints under subsection (b) and (c) of section 1034 that receives a consumer complaint from the unit established under this paragraph may, upon reasonable determination, close such complaint without further action if—</text> <subclause id="H1EA5EB66281144D993E90205E87BF2F2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the complaint, as determined by such covered person—</text> 
<item id="H0828C1CA4D6749C1B944CF50100F2237"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is duplicative of a previously submitted and resolved complaint submitted by the same consumer relating to the same issue;</text></item> <item id="H4CF7EE713F984011BDB30EFFD35F9EB6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is frivolous or lacking a basis in fact;</text></item> 
<item id="HDD4587639A0F489A802C6AD41E40DFCA"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was not submitted by the consumer or an individual authorized to act on the behalf of the consumer; or</text></item> <item id="H2B1FC8FDD9AA4F349221C7C85F54000E"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>was submitted for a fraudulent or misleading purpose;</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6581061350994813AEC231AEE9858476" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such covered person was not directly informed by the consumer of the issue about which the consumer submitted the complaint not less than 60 days before the consumer submitted the complaint; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H306672A575664E6FB8153E1D5AD30C55" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such covered person was directly informed by the consumer of the issue about which the consumer submitted the complaint and such covered person responded to such consumer in a manner that remedied the issue raised by the consumer; or</text></subclause> </clause> 
<clause id="H4C8E1B0107A343778512CFBA6E2FF576"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Recording</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered person who is required to respond to complaints under subsection (b) and (c) of section 1034 closes a complaint under clause (i), such covered person shall notify the unit established under this paragraph of such closure and the reason for such closure and such unit shall record such information in the database established under this paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7050A094298464DAE0384928C86030F"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header> <clause id="H450BE14C1C32486580C6EB0C122847F2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Bureau shall ensure that narrative content included in complaints submitted by consumers to the unit established under this paragraph and narrative content included in responses from covered persons who are required to respond to complaints under subsection (b) and (c) of section 1034 who receive complaints from the unit established under this paragraph remain confidential and are not published or made publicly viewable.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H54E20CE3E4C143D196DD6DD7DADD8E58"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Aggregation of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau may publish aggregated data about complaints received from consumers and analyses of trends in such complaints if such data and analyses do not include personally identifiable information or specific narrative content that could reasonably be linked to an individual consumer or covered person who is required to respond to complaints under subsection (b) and (c) of section 1034.</text></clause></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

