<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAE9D695EA5B34DCAB217A67FB94F2DC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6863 IH: To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve transparency with respect to the suspension of Medicare payments pending an investigation into a credible allegation of fraud.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6863</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve transparency with respect to the suspension of Medicare payments pending an investigation into a credible allegation of fraud.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD5DB5C480BA84BF48DA700E1A59E14F7" style="OLC"><section id="H724B3A851FDD49C4848567189EA10038" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Auditor Transparency Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CAT Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HADF472A2C66242898E7179FA32146E31"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HB3231DF276284998A03588BEEE354311"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 2020, 139,000,000 individuals received health care coverage through the Medicare or Medicaid programs, costing the Federal Government approximately $1,500,000,000,000. Of these funds paid by United States taxpayers, $3,100,000,000 were discovered to have been fraudulent claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7294E9D911F145C383D00C22268B85B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ensuring the integrity of the Medicare and Medicaid programs is crucial to preventing fraud, waste, and abuse and safeguarding the financial sustainability of these important programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFAE20C9C0B04E18B33C7FF7F4488B69"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Even though the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) utilization of Unified Program Integrity Contractors (UPICs) has shown to be effective at identifying bad actors defrauding the Federal Government through the Medicare and Medicaid programs, current Federal law and regulations have shown to be harmful to most providers who are submitting Medicare and Medicaid claims in good faith.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03DBA062707B41BCA6D32A8BE6EA466F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Existing law provides CMS and UPICs broad authority and discretion to suspend Medicare payments for up to a year pending the investigation of <quote>credible allegations of fraud</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62AA72BF656C42959AA2F64DD98A6C2D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>However, current law does not require adequate transparency from CMS or UPICs into the nature of the alleged fraud before Medicare payments are suspended. Current law also does not require CMS or UPICs to provide adequate due process to providers whose payments have been suspended to challenge or cure the allegations of fraud prior to the suspension of Medicare payments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89208EE123C24511909D6CFB7C082BDE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In addition, anecdotal reports have shown that some UPICs extend the suspension of Medicare payments on a routine basis so that they may have additional time to finish their audit despite not providing evidence that the continuation of a payment suspension is necessary to protect the integrity of the Medicare program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED57DAE4F08F49F2A7E2DA1710D30884"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The broad authority to suspend Medicare payments pending the investigation of a credible allegation of fraud without adequate due process or transparency places the financial viability of many Medicare providers acting in good faith at risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07438AEB300848DAB385313ED17B54AF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>If Medicare providers acting in good faith close their doors as a result of the unnecessary suspension of payments by CMS or UPICs, Medicare beneficiaries and the American public could face additional barriers to access to necessary health care services as a direct result of unfair Federal law and regulations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H241BEC77956F4EFD9E35C4687C61606E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving transparency in suspension of payments pending investigation of credible allegations of fraud under Medicare</header><subsection id="H7B2DB311B7D948A486D6F88FE93AD2D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1862(o) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(o)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H447C4EC47CF0480B9F3B738BD8AF5803"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H6BC12E295A8547EBA612AF1E36135504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary may suspend</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (5), the Secretary may suspend</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4889A5C6B40049E4B9C7D721D9B1ADEB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>An investigation of a credible allegation of fraud, and the suspension of payment pending such investigation under the preceding sentence, may only exceed 180 days if the Secretary determines there is good cause to extend such investigation and suspension.</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E465196461E47EF833D129DB15C0081"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="HC4D7852A681B45C9901B461372127482"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>a fraud hotline tip (as defined by the Secretary)</quote> and inserting <quote>the following items</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7A78B62770A4231968C379D68434154"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>credible allegation of fraud.</quote> and inserting</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD8DC6F5898C34F4DA64F51276A86B1F6" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>credible allegation of fraud:</text><subparagraph id="H99EA0E76FA3141D6A2239F078761461C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A fraud hotline tip (as defined by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2195FA1B69C744C0B7CD810DEDE0BA7E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mere error (as defined by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB26330256FE5497B86A4F1F966128A11"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A billing error found during the course of an audit that is attributable to human error.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64399806285444DA8B62C201B0A7973F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block id="H2CE3EF87D2F749FF96F8A891120D9F97" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HC76FEBEB3DF04BA69C8C0A8AA1E3F212"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transparency in suspension of payments</header><subparagraph id="HDA216026F2524E57BD17E6BF4B0FF2D1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may only suspend payments to a provider of services or supplier under this title pursuant to paragraph (1) if—</text><clause id="H210DE2F427094E669C210FE14155FA0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to <internal-xref idref="H7F771579C5F24A4E859F174EB29D86C6" legis-path="(5)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>, not later than 30 days before the date on which the payment suspension begins, the Secretary provides such provider of services or supplier with information about each credible allegation of fraud that is the basis for the payment suspension, including—</text><subclause id="HEBE3E45042774CE58061B1D6603F8423"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the specific nature of each credible allegation of fraud;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5D9A9E48E226462BA3499FF37D42494E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date of the alleged fraud; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4D36CBE7D57A463F954E203B4FE2A5C9" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the basis of the credible allegation of fraud, such as whether the allegation is based upon—</text><item id="HBD24C59C418742CC90B95795F503BEED" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a fraud hotline complaint;</text></item><item id="HB9A42E829A2246FD8894E0513151588B" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>data mining of data with respect to claims for payment under this title, title XIX, or title XXI; or</text></item><item id="HAB0B6B0E4E784483AF1C7C2D3D7E4A66" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a pattern identified through audits of providers of services or suppliers; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HF2EB422C5DE24122A998C83D9F3C6140"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 30 days during such payment suspension, the Secretary provides such provider of services or supplier with—</text><subclause id="H50D1642339544C96BEA5B488CA0E610E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a detailed, up-to-date list of the findings of the investigation;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD613959AA24C494380B515432747390D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an anticipated timeline for the completion of the investigation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD0A9EBE80BB7463CBEE3A17D2B518E2B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an opportunity to ask the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services questions regarding the payment suspension and the investigation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F771579C5F24A4E859F174EB29D86C6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary may elect not to provide a provider of services or supplier with the information described in <internal-xref idref="H210DE2F427094E669C210FE14155FA0C" legis-path="(5)(A)(i)">subparagraph (A)(i)</internal-xref> if the provision of such information would compromise the integrity of the investigation, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services and State auditors (as appropriate).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB67D96C2815F414190BB4A2231751A16" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Failure to provide information</header><text>If the requirements described in <internal-xref idref="HDA216026F2524E57BD17E6BF4B0FF2D1" legis-path="(5)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> are not met with respect to the suspension of payment to a provider of services or a supplier under this title, the Secretary shall immediately resume such payment, and shall pay to the provider of services or supplier the amounts not paid due to such suspension and any interest accrued with respect to such amounts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D44F61E25A4123A43B1573DF7FC781"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year (beginning with fiscal year 2025), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following information with respect to such fiscal year:</text><clause id="HD43C89A74F9E473E8CD14B733A6A9FAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of payment suspensions issued as the result of a pending investigation of a credible allegation of fraud under this subsection, section 1860D–12(b)(7) (including as applied pursuant to section 1857(f)(3)(D)), or section 1903(i)(2)(C).</text></clause><clause id="HDA3D34B7429A40B4AB8DDA4E4835C9C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The basis of each such credible allegation of fraud.</text></clause><clause id="HBBD753878BED4E339BA431DE3B129298"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The average duration of a payment suspension described in <internal-xref idref="HD43C89A74F9E473E8CD14B733A6A9FAC" legis-path="(5)(D)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>.</text></clause><clause id="H862D269B764647F79C7A643B5B7CF1DA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The average duration of an investigation of a credible allegation of fraud described in <internal-xref idref="HD43C89A74F9E473E8CD14B733A6A9FAC" legis-path="(5)(D)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>.</text></clause><clause id="HDA360CFA361E4A11998B2C14CFB81661"><enum>(v)</enum><text>If applicable, the average time between the completion of an investigation into a credible allegation of fraud described in <internal-xref idref="HD43C89A74F9E473E8CD14B733A6A9FAC" legis-path="(5)(D)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref> and the reinstatement of payments to the relevant provider of services or supplier.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18CE6D5A69744B9F82A53B7F6680E051"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Appeals</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>CAT Act of 2025</short-title>, the Secretary shall provide an independent process by which a provider of services or supplier under this title that has received notice of a payment suspension due to a pending investigation of a credible allegation of fraud pursuant to this subsection may appeal such suspension and receive a resolution of such appeal in a timely manner.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FA3472EFAEC48299E91632083850D4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Stakeholder consultation</header><text>In developing the appeals process required under section 1862(o)(6) of the Social Security Act, as added by subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall consult with relevant stakeholders, including providers of services and suppliers under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>), title XIX of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), and title XXI of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>), as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2ECC0F0FDED6427EA51A1E397AE42800"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to any investigation of a credible allegation of fraud under section 1862(o) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395y">42 U.S.C. 1395y(o)</external-xref>), section 1860D–12(b)(7) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112(b)(7)</external-xref>) (including as applied pursuant to section 1857(f)(3)(D) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)(3)(D)</external-xref>)), or section 1903(i)(2)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396b">42 U.S.C. 1396b(i)(2)(C)</external-xref>) that is initiated after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

