<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-GOE26341-H5J-DT-X8Y"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S5010 IS: New Opportunities for Business Ownership and Self-Sufficiency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 5010</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260716">July 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules governing the State administration of self-employment assistance programs.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HC9C3275A6211421E968B098B40DCB95D"><section section-type="section-one" id="H5E1ACBD5089647BBAA306514B79CF6AE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>New Opportunities for Business Ownership and Self-Sufficiency Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NO BOSS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H93C8902AEA634860AD00ED93D557C4A9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of rules governing State administration of self-employment assistance programs</header><subsection id="H76AD85030DFE47B48BB408FDCB6AED74"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Elimination of requirement that participants are likely To exhaust regular unemployment compensation</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3306">Section 3306(t)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subparagraph (B) and by redesignating subparagraphs (C) and (D) as subparagraphs (B) and (C), respectively.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H768911E235DC4E2FAD0494B3F7731E00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Modification of requirement To participate in self-Employment assistance activities</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3306">Section 3306(t)(3)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5BDB81F15E724B66B6A7BA73018CF7C6"><subparagraph id="HF7B1EAD4682A4F129D9C1B8AAFA33D8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are participating in self-employment assistance activities which are approved by the State agency and either—</text><clause id="H4816405CB6054CF982EB6F804BCF00FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include entrepreneurial training, business counseling, and technical assistance; or</text></clause><clause id="HDD62249361774BE08649BBF91864B344"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are performed pursuant to a business plan and market feasibility study submitted by the individual and approved by the State or an agency designated by the State; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H23BD0904FCBE41E2A5F77C1CC13394D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, except that nothing in this section shall be interpreted to prevent a State from amending its law before the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9656A6E22BAF4B329EED9FFE1020DB41"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Issuance of regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall, after public notice and comment and subject to approval by the Office of Management and Budget, adopt regulations to administer this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE07971D19D2D400888C80D41CFD74974" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Issuance of guidance</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall provide guidance to State workforce agencies that includes—</text><paragraph id="H89029C322A014036989A92539963DC75" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a model list of self-employment assistance activities that fulfill requirements of the program under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3306">section 3306(t)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EE5CB82342A422A8603CAC3A68C93D5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>best practices for verification of completion of such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

