<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25L84-MWM-SP-JM2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3571 IS: Keeping Our Agents on the Line Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To limit the authority of U.S. Border Patrol personnel to their traditional border security duties, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keeping Our Agents on the Line Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idcb478ebbe6e64199b5ec627978a3bad8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Senate finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id27ba466c831c433dae1dae38500a29b4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For many years, representatives of the U.S. Border Patrol have requested to return to their traditional border security duties on the line to avoid certain administrative tasks, such as processing asylum seekers and children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2b219331501f4cfca3e04f473b22e9c8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>During 2025, U.S. Border Patrol—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf671045b25944fdba96cc398a3e04d5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has apparently been delegated nationwide interior arrest authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7b69084e8cba43b4b53ad3c8702cf62d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as a result of nationwide interior arrest authority, has duplicated the functions and purpose of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, while failing to receive the commensurate training;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbcd564a21b9c488e8c731215c51766c1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has made numerous arrests in the interior of the United States, many without a judicially authorized warrant, including arrests of United States citizens; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd9aa6d1173ad48b4874119b5fa46b426"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is no longer limiting its patrols within a reasonable distance from the line at the United States land border.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idce3327b52f2c45bfb29fa2e08f785456"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Many violent encounters recorded by United States citizens and residents have involved U.S. Border Patrol agents who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d10d1b1b1cb40e194573f7d415d9705"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are primarily trained to patrol the line at the United States border; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id240e7ef7dbc349879bec8402fd517b6a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not sufficiently trained to manage complex criminal investigations typically handled by other Federal law enforcement agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id41d7da4d1b594730a41b99c9b60fc3be"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Despite this lack of training, U.S. Border Patrol agents have been roaming the interior of the United States and arresting United States residents, including United States citizens.</text></paragraph></section><section id="idf8a48a3bbb8042a692297d58fc049f2e"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reaffirming the 25-mile limitation for U.S. Border Patrol officers and employees</header><subsection id="id9e1b9078db4d43169482832a11976c1e"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id589066848fac4f27a542bc6cea1c3e55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immigration officers and employees of u.s. border patrol</header><text>The term <term>immigration officers and employees of U.S. Border Patrol</term> means any employee, contractor, or detailee who performs services for U.S. Border Patrol.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id989db9155e5442b98fb8056d714b2e6a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reasonable distance</header><text>The term <term>reasonable distance</term> means a distance not greater than 25 miles from any United States international land border or territorial sea.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9cc5a99940634b72a1721eefc5b8e5ad"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules for U.S. Border Patrol</header><text>No authority, power, or permission granted under section 287 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357</external-xref>), may be exercised by immigration officers and employees of U.S. Border Patrol beyond a reasonable distance.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc391c26731f641699fd050e392b04b95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on delegation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, immigration officers and employees of U.S. Border Patrol may not be delegated, deputized, or granted any authority to operate beyond a reasonable distance unless such authority is granted based upon—</text><paragraph id="idf8607d7354204479ad6bfa777f6c0e9b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a lawful request made by an appropriate State or local official to an immigration officer or employee of U.S. Border Patrol, in accordance with State or local law, to assist in an emergency situation in which lives are in immediate or imminent danger; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide0646431de094eeaa16c855cd429941d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the President's declaration of a major disaster under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idd254f227cc064138a1cc7f1cd34b448e"><enum>4.</enum><header>Checkpoint and arrest data collection and reporting</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide336c988e5844420a01f01ad00e982fa"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Checkpoint data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner for U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall—</text><paragraph id="id64696303facb421c9ebe258ccb9795e0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish milestones for determining the feasibility of a checkpoint performance model that allows U.S. Border Patrol to compare apprehensions and seizures to the level of illegal activity passing undetected through the checkpoint;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id627ea33ba118426c87fb89b719abce8b"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">post the findings and supporting data collected pursuant to paragraph (1) on a publicly accessible website not less frequently than annually;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id504981f5c56941f1bbb0f7490728ce1f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish internal controls for managing the oversight of the accuracy, consistency, and completeness of checkpoint performance data; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id74fadf4d122c4e828492693f47bc492f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>publicly report on the total number of those subjected to an encounter at a U.S. Border Patrol checkpoint, disaggregated by the number of United States citizens, lawful permanent residents, and aliens.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8c3d1559d1264797a567bbeccbbad7fa"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Arrest data</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commissioner for U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall—</text><paragraph id="ida193a32bf1fa4690aba01e07630fb47f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>document and publicly report on the number of agents operating in the interior of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide8ebc40252cf470790914fc0af3d4937"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide detailed information regarding each such agent’s training with respect to conducting searches and seizures in compliance with the Fourth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States; and</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="id292d9881396742c4830387becce7551c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>document and publicly report on the disposition of each interaction such agent has while in the interior with a United States citizen, a lawful permanent resident, or another alien, including whether such person was arrested, detained, stopped, or charged with a crime or a civil offense.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

