<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26070-KYS-H3-SWF"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 594 ATS: Supporting the contributions of Catholic schools in the United States and celebrating the 52nd annual National Catholic Schools Week.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 594</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260129">January 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S420">Mr. Schmitt</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the contributions of Catholic schools in the United States and celebrating the 52nd annual National Catholic Schools Week.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Catholic schools in the United States are internationally acclaimed for their academic excellence and provide approximately 1,700,000 students with more than an exceptional scholastic education;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Catholic schools instill a broad, values-added education, emphasizing the life-long development of moral, intellectual, physical, and social values in young people in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Catholic schools serve the United States by providing a diverse student population from all regions of the United States and all socioeconomic backgrounds with a strong academic and moral foundation, including, according to the 2024–2025 National Catholic Education Association survey of elementary and secondary Catholic schools in the United States—</text><paragraph id="id6823fb6850f943bf8910eea5813afc1c" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>34.9 percent of students from racial minority backgrounds;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id433a2f610f184f759da0fad0593cff57"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">15.4 percent of students of Hispanic heritage; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide1078615ed4a4468931dadd49d758311"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">21.8 percent from non-Catholic families;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Catholic schools are an affordable option for parents, particularly in underserved urban areas;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Catholic schools produce students who are strongly dedicated to their faith, values, families, and communities by providing an intellectually stimulating environment that promotes spiritual, character, and moral development;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Catholic schools are committed to community service, producing graduates who hold <quote>helping others</quote> among their core values;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the total Catholic school student enrollment for the 2024–2025 academic year is approximately 1,700,000, and the student-teacher ratio is 10 to 1, according to the 2024–2025 National Catholic Education Association survey of elementary and secondary Catholic schools in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Catholic high school graduation rate is 98.6 percent, with 83.7 percent of graduates attending 4-year colleges;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the week of January 25, 2026, to January 31, 2026, has been designated as <quote>National Catholic Schools Week</quote> by the National Catholic Educational Association and the United States Conference of Catholic Bishops;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2026, National Catholic Schools Week marks a significant milestone and celebrates its 52nd anniversary, having been first established in 1974; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the theme for National Catholic Schools Week 2026 is <quote>Catholic Schools: United in Faith and Community</quote>, which reflects the fact that Catholic schools, united in their faith, expand beyond the walls of the classroom to include the parents and families of students as integral parts of the school community: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id30cdc174cad2409280399538e821d1ea"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the goals of National Catholic Schools Week, an event—</text><subparagraph id="idb00c0263a9e34aef93255208d2022f02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cosponsored by the National Catholic Educational Association and the United States Conference of Catholic Bishops; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide8ae283ad5834011ab55bc713320e547"><enum>(B)</enum><text>established to recognize the vital contributions of the thousands of Catholic elementary and secondary schools in the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb3bee5caa6c447db9b61c261dcd2c29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>applauds the National Catholic Educational Association and the United States Conference of Catholic Bishops on their selection of a theme that all can celebrate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc6c24b2a164245a1b505c0a2ed35fc9c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supports—</text><subparagraph id="id327d7bcb168b4e35b44edaa05154dea1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the dedication of Catholic schools, including the students, parents, and teachers of such schools, across the United States toward academic excellence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide67fbde5667c4f0bb5704121c9635a55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the key role they play in promoting and ensuring a brighter, stronger future for the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

