<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-ROS25K56-PWN-M2-3LG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3229 IS: No Tariffs on Groceries Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3229</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFI00">Committee on Finance</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To limit the authority of the President to impose duties on articles of food.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Tariffs on Groceries Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf662cb1d0f604ca395e092e811b9bbc5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on authority to impose duties on articles of food</header><subsection id="idb67880cdced04bb8bf13a9c01ac85b21"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On or after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may not impose any duty or tariff-rate quota on an article of food unless—</text><paragraph id="ide7eef32c308c462fa1dc33db1023d85a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the President transmits to Congress a request to impose the duty or quota; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idafb32a0f33d247158ef997b106a93eee"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there is enacted into law a joint resolution of approval under subsection (c) with respect to the imposition of the duty or quota.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idaed2fb76b5d64c41aca4b3d13cf37db2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The limitation under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to an antidumping or countervailing duty imposed under title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1671">19 U.S.C. 1671 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id1d0b8b4484384549b13df6a97e0fd318"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint resolutions of approval</header><paragraph id="id36e7b9debc5345cd943b460312c9c596"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>joint resolution of approval</term> means a joint resolution the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress approves the imposition of the duty or tariff-rate quota with respect to ___, request for which was submitted to Congress on ______.</quote>, with the first blank space being filled with a description of the article and the second blank space being filled with the date the request under subsection (a)(1) was submitted to Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c0c4620875a4ac596c6dcfb6ab27735"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction</header><subparagraph id="id8a790f55104b4763b225ab7278a9edcb"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Joint resolution of approval</header><text>A joint resolution of approval with respect to the imposition of a duty or tariff-rate quota may be introduced in either House of Congress by any Member of that House during the 45-day period beginning on the date on which the President submitted a request under subsection (a)(1) with respect to the duty or quota.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida5e94cfa795e4024ac7168c3fc1b9929"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Expedited procedures</header><text>The provisions of subsections (b) through (f) of section 152 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2192">19 U.S.C. 2192</external-xref>) apply to a joint resolution of approval to the same extent that such subsections apply to joint resolutions under such section 152.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb45767eb9c34451386db306b3f5749dc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules of the Senate and the House of Representatives</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph id="id9834564ae86742ff9fea1a2207072c43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution of approval, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7a26845641cb405f82d06c4073fbec18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id5ce86680514f44ae938e0860fbe4d6be" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Article of food defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>article of food</term> means—</text><paragraph id="idc2f5916b5cfb4bf1be2a66fc17781514" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>food for use;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idebd5e238712a49629ec4adb318f65f85" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>products chiefly used as food for animals or as ingredients in such food;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9857303d61a34a0e86652e91e1d90867" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>agricultural commodities (as defined in section 102 of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5602">7 U.S.C. 5602</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd23113ca1e9f4849900920b78f83b7df" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>articles used for packaging and containing articles described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94f81192a8b749289f61f71c33e73ded" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>seeds, fertilizers, manures, and agro-chemicals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

