<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26134-SJV-CT-K85"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4149 IS: Social Determinants for Moms Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4149</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to convene a task force to develop strategies and coordinate efforts to eliminate preventable maternal mortality, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Determinants for Moms Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H43591A3BB8664E8790FB6C48E29BD3D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Task force to address the United States maternal health crisis</header><subsection id="H12589B67EEE94D2FA2032DF3253E0C89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall convene a task force (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>) to develop strategies and coordinate efforts between Federal agencies and other stakeholders to eliminate preventable maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities in the United States, including actions to address clinical and nonclinical causes of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1B4A23EB3ADF48FEAF2BFCF57D1EE634"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ex officio members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force shall consist of the following ex officio members (or a designee thereof):</text><paragraph id="H2807B4B28565404791B9E2777C3D937C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A878D94756942108DEDCCEDE8B4176A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6001619646B49B591F9927BAAD4FC4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC47616F8811640E5902DC068070B4955"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB3CE803B2CD4DD49263FB3046A464CE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70AEDBFC7AE04FD2B63F5516AFE81D90"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77E9DD4FF9084AFF8BF0158B4776EB76"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6BCD291AF834CD7B83457170E04B149"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA42C930CCFAF42179E496719819334C8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Indian Health Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEBE234335B343D7964970C134DF0C56"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56BB5A6B58734AFDA6BEAB5B95395875"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7f4c9a21bf8d4b1f9c66551e44c724bb"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Director of the Tribal Health Research Office at the National Institutes of Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F8A74F8494F4668B7DB4CF90516BAE7"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C850176374B41E78DC6B235752CCEDD"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18EE4F79E0734FE381F9F0EA8B9AC10E"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Deputy Assistant Secretary for Women’s Health of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB043F12BBE045DDA94EE3FC2F0A44A8"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H324D813EE7FE446E8B5A4600D7BE7F36"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office on Violence Against Women at the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC884EF6F32FD48EBB54371613106E131"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appointed members</header><text>In addition to the ex officio members of the Task Force, the Secretary may appoint the following members of the Task Force:</text><paragraph id="HB7AB1A5FCB664ECD8FFD8B6E952F83E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Representatives of patients, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3FD5997BBD724C44A8F06E8D30916317"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a representative of patients who have suffered from severe maternal morbidity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED9FD26CC5454E00987E203BE46FF04A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a representative of patients who is a family member of an individual who suffered a pregnancy-related death.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E15D3E46344C3FB72E2D168D023495"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Leaders of community-based organizations that address maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health with a specific focus on racial and ethnic disparities. In appointing such leaders under this paragraph, the Secretary shall give priority to individuals who are leaders of organizations led by individuals from demographic groups with elevated rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5355013e22a44bfe90d408cdca39155b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Leaders from the Indian health care system, including leaders from Tribal Epidemiology Centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09119641F8864F7FB33BAC563958E123"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Perinatal health workers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF7DB73DCC5A48BC9EBBC616BE627D44"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A professionally and geographically diverse panel of maternity care providers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB27316D9E62E413DB9E95E866D0D94E0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other maternal health stakeholders outside of the Federal Government with expertise in maternal health, including social determinants of maternal health.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE411EF5C62C2401FA8FCF53957C67324"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select the chair of the Task Force from among the members of the Task Force.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB20616AB960245449AF112D4D736047D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Topics</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing strategies and coordinating efforts between Federal agencies and other stakeholders to eliminate preventable maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities in the United States under this section, the Task Force may address topics such as—</text><paragraph id="H973273B7326345329A55A7E150C3CE23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>addressing barriers that prevent individuals from attending prenatal and postpartum appointments, accessing maternal health care services, or accessing services and resources related to social determinants of maternal health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABE981EA908040449A7F7385A0100F24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing access to safe, stable, affordable, and adequate housing for pregnant and postpartum individuals and their families;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEF69D8FC1C245238B96AD2B31BBB01B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>delivering healthy food, infant formula, clean water, diapers, or other perinatal necessities to pregnant and postpartum individuals located in areas that are food deserts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H417DE301E9734AE39B0705D91CA74775"><enum>(4)</enum><text>addressing the impacts of water and air quality, exposure to extreme temperatures, environmental chemicals, environmental risks in the workplace and the home, and pollution levels, on maternal and infant health outcomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70A3F3A76768444788C1E53DF519A6D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>offering free and accessible drop-in childcare services during prenatal and postpartum appointments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB381698883A441D78A44D357351CEB52"><enum>(6)</enum><text>addressing the clinical and nonclinical needs of postpartum individuals and their families for the duration of the postpartum period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H033E5E1E22D84597A2EE8CB827ECF161"><enum>(7)</enum><text>engaging with nongovernmental entities to address social determinants of maternal health, including through public-private partnerships;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF18C435529C04F6CA2ECC262001AD205"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">addressing the impact of domestic or intimate partner violence on maternal health outcomes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F9CF3D0D48745DF8E8F8BC1ECAF0031"><enum>(9)</enum><text>other topics determined by the chair of the Task Force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53A5669D2A76433990F34D07770D9A88"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Task Force shall submit to Congress and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services a report that—</text><paragraph id="H50CF86215B0F43CEABF7D23EDC99C6E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the efforts of the Task Force to develop strategies and coordinate efforts between Federal agencies and other stakeholders to eliminate preventable maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AD29A3796244CDDA9D950723EBCB48C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides an overview of actions taken by each member of the Task Force described in subsection (b) to eliminate preventable maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1B42F376C084F2C8E0E9053FD7063F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides recommendations on Federal funding amounts and authorities needed to implement strategies developed by the Task Force to eliminate preventable maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E6B9E34AFF340E5A4DD435E8CC48F3E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides recommendations on actions that stakeholders outside of the Federal Government can take to eliminate preventable maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2F27A0E549144CB94D66F10EB785B05"><enum>(5)</enum><text>addresses other topics, as determined by the chair of the Task Force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1BBDF3AD1F04D5981849C2630372391"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1013 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to the Task Force with respect to termination.</text></subsection></section><section id="H53FB818D557143038041F73D5D6202DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sustained funding to address social determinants of maternal health</header><subsection id="H5FED4F83DB95423DB2C551849D5187C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to address social determinants of maternal health to eliminate maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, and maternal health disparities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5DFB75207C024F74BF748064D2F6DDFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be—</text><paragraph id="H89E56428CA714325A7E63940A937E330"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a community-based organization, Indian Tribe or Tribal organization, or Urban Indian organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6907ED0C2BC8412886AF073A28C61315"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a public health department or nonprofit organization working with an entity described in paragraph (1); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7954EB5FC5AB41B2A42BE92143E64DE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a consortium of entities described in paragraph (1) or (2) that includes at minimum one entity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4DE52E4DFED44C7F97C40D7EC24855B2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0412ACED0BC4FEF9C9E1CE7BB2C12EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an eligible entity that is operating in an area with—</text><paragraph id="H2C5ACD38BDFE4828B5BCA3EE8009EDAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">high rates of maternal mortality, severe maternal morbidity, maternal health disparities, or other adverse perinatal or childbirth outcomes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87F30FCDA61246A5A5F09EEAA8808A84"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a high poverty rate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAB7476739C943F9ACEDF9C63D55765D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may use the grant to address social determinants of maternal health such as—</text><paragraph id="H29798D0B4E63494187F00D9F8D8C517C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>housing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1259BCDC290F448597890423AB1A89B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40A6609606BC408B8D7420263D2FB369"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nutrition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB89A9C7EF764DF1BE5628B5D420C3B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>employment, workplace conditions, and other economic factors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D59BA6D5D064F0F8F4EBC410A652B11"><enum>(5)</enum><text>environmental conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H200D10D8EAB944C59A9DFCBCFB3D23EC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>intimate partner violence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA70AEC5305544C7493E219DC31191C29"><enum>(7)</enum><text>other nonclinical factors that impact maternal health outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1228486F3C68405CA9ECB555D337236E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide to grant recipients under this section technical assistance to plan for sustaining programs to address social determinants of maternal health after the period of the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8946C1B30CCF4C75A933E5DB97A171BE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="HBF47B71E80024A348F8B2A97AC835692"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grantees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after an eligible entity first receives a grant under this section, and annually thereafter, the eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary, and make publicly available, a report that describes the status of activities conducted using the grant. Each such report shall include data on the effects of such activities, disaggregated by race, ethnicity, gender, primary language, geography, socioeconomic status, and other relevant factors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H675E5F980D1E47ADA8CC7A9DDA9B2DE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Not later than the end of fiscal year 2031, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="HD172BB0B28F54129A00EE013FD51D6DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of the reports under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5EE7AF9826C4999A1E8722AEDA1883E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for future Federal grant allocations to address social determinants of maternal health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F0B47723DF14C9D844CE6DCDFDB42C6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

