<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAEACC1C7A11A466E8CCF3A60DCB58DB1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7761 IH: Heirs Education and Investment to Resolve Succession of Property Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7761</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize and improve the relending program to resolve ownership and succession on farmland, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFC5C812F1E1D4A6E957C4F92E6242892" style="OLC"><section id="H4788F2067F5248AEACC4124C9952ED48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Heirs Education and Investment to Resolve Succession of Property Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H97386FEFA5914438BC3A6715B25C835E" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of the heirs property intermediary relending program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 310I(g) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1936c">7 U.S.C. 1936c(g)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2023</quote> and inserting <quote>2031</quote>.</text></section><section id="H975CBBDD89EC4328BEC4E86E19D4EDEE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements for heirs property resolution through direct public interest legal services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 310I of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1936c">7 U.S.C. 1936c</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H90FBB69E7CAA45F5B6A425C282410C7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f) and (g) as subsections (g) and (h), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ECDB9A9F05B43579C4858FC9045F2FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF30F787ED4C14622A56ED4EA15FDE6B7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H777270CBB281423E95973960C1B6BE11"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements for heirs property resolution through direct public interest legal services</header><paragraph id="HF795506A3C304644A52C3119626821B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall enter into cooperative agreements with eligible entities to provide legal or accounting services to underserved heirs, at no cost to the underserved heirs, to assist in resolving issues related to ownership and succession on farmland or forest land that has multiple owners. Such a cooperative agreement must be for any of the following purposes:</text><subparagraph id="H11A03DE7C952411FB3AC3345B55679E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To assist with transitioning land to agricultural production.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9B70F05241A4091B6F4AFDD0CC8ED48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To maintain land in agricultural production.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE06B9F5F84554822A01310B87CCBA76F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To increase access to programs administered by the Secretary through the resolution of real property claims in order to allow real property owners to meet land ownership eligibility requirements for participation in a program administered by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E7503DC564947898AE47F0A12487BB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration of cooperative agreements</header><subparagraph id="HDB7391644C1244BD97E0F510E848E2B9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><clause id="H8D8560018B6E45ED835616721C44E155"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A cooperative agreement under paragraph (1) shall be in effect for not more than 4 years, subject to clause (ii).</text></clause><clause id="HF47707E11780460CBE343B1AF41B73B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>The Secretary may re-enter into a cooperative agreement with the same or a different eligible entity to provide continued services for heirs if property ownership is not resolved within the initial term of the original cooperative agreement, and the entity certifies that the entity understands that the cooperative agreement is not guaranteed to be funded for more than 4 years after the commencement of the original cooperative agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACFBFAE61F184569B2EFCFA6A8E51A89"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Management of performance</header><clause id="HC3D070307FDA41C291616D9ADC19E302"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>An eligible entity must provide annual reports to the Secretary summarizing the progress made during each fiscal year towards achieving the goals of the cooperative agreement for the heirs for whom services are provided under the cooperative agreement.</text></clause><clause id="HCB5EA83FA302406C9CD3576DACCAD62D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Information and data</header><text>The Secretary may require an eligible entity to provide the Secretary with such information or data, other than personally identifiable information or data, as the Secretary deems necessary to determine that the eligible entity is making acceptable progress.</text></clause><clause id="H9B99D46270C849498AE540853F382DA7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effect of failure to demonstrate success</header><text>If an eligible entity providing services under such a cooperative agreement does not demonstrate success, as determined by the Secretary, in resolving or reasonably attempting to resolve the property claims of an heir, the Secretary may terminate the agreement, or elect to not enter into a new cooperative agreement with the eligible entity after the initial term of the original cooperative agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B6180DBED54401D839968A605A9B308"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary may utilize requests for public input or the formal rulemaking process to effectuate this subsection. At a minimum, the Secretary shall make publicly available the criteria for selecting an eligible entity to enter into an agreement to provide services, the administrative and performance requirements for cooperative agreements under this subsection, as well as codify within its internal policy its implementation process.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DEE1C52587E4E37807D62CFB5E44015"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Heirs property not in farming</header><text>On a limited basis, and when determined by the Secretary to meet the purposes of a program administered by the Secretary and to expand access to such a program, the Secretary may allow an eligible entity to provide services at no cost to an heir who is not an underserved heir if—</text><clause id="HA873DA20956044FE9921DA1666F5BBA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the land with respect to which the services are to be provided is not farmland or in agricultural production, but could be viably productive for agricultural, conservation, or forestry purposes;</text></clause><clause id="HDAF64FF35FDB49F1AFFDEA26F67838BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the heir satisfies all other requirements of the definition of <quote>underserved heir</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HC6ED9593C5AA4D73B0CA4460EA493DFC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the heir can provide proof to substantiate that the heir is in control of the real property; and</text></clause><clause id="H43A6732AFB094D9886529A4EDF945B25"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the heir certifies to the Secretary that the heir intends to apply for, and make a good faith effort to enroll the land in, a program administered by the Secretary once property claims to the land are resolved through services provided under a cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47BFFFB4C30E411D8924B69E92734F43"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H99D22BD9ABCE4540A2E69700E10AFD60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a nonprofit organization that—</text><clause id="HD1C907BBDC394BA699B091F2EE3FBD37"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides legal or accounting services to an underserved heir at no cost to the underserved heir; and</text></clause><clause id="HBDDBA450B7E6467BA42C702BF031065B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has demonstrated experience in resolving issues related to ownership and succession on farmland or forest land that has multiple owners.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80C0C231281543B9ADF8404F2E1423E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limited resource heir</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An heir shall be considered a limited resource heir for purposes of this subsection if—</text><clause id="H1AC2E447CDB44F2A91627969219057BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total household income of the heir is at or below the national poverty level for a family of 4, or less than 50 percent of the county median household income for the 2 immediately preceding calendar years, as determined annually using data of the Department of Commerce; or</text></clause><clause id="HFFBF4BA8DDCE4ABD833B3142F6DEC5E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the property of the heir for which legal services are provided pursuant to a cooperative agreement entered into under this subsection is in a persistent poverty community, as determined annually on the basis of data from the Department of Commerce, or a socially vulnerable area, as designated by the Centers on Disease Control and Prevention.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3275898EE404EE886020A24A8B04688"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Underserved heir</header><text>The term <term>underserved heir</term> means an heir with an undivided ownership interest in farmland that has multiple owners, who is—</text><clause id="H83FEB9F3B89D4F1ABAAA89F3F1E0D75F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a limited resource heir;</text></clause><clause id="H649F3C48D3264F96AAB5C0E951730863"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a member of a socially disadvantaged group (as defined in section 2501(a) of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990); or</text></clause><clause id="HBAE47EA84A4C47819E4FB8D7C0A9D9CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a veteran (as defined in section 101(2) of title 38, United States Code).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1552BC35A19F46B49639E78A018B72D6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><text>Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare, make public, and submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a written report on the activities carried out under this subsection in the year covered by the report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07B62F0965E74D8B90A977B04A50E726"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitations on authorization of appropriations</header><subparagraph id="H2368618123AF4B63828B12F29EF08CE6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out this subsection, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5347D755CDA48599F12283E2266647D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds for administration</header><text>The Secretary may expend for administrative purposes not more than 3 percent of the amounts made available under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H4C41BD9109AB47F198FC0999042734C5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual report on operations and outcomes under the relending program to resolve ownership and succession on farmland</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 310I(g) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, as so redesignated by section 3 of this Act, is amended by striking <quote>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall</quote> and inserting <quote>The Secretary shall annually</quote>.</text></section><section id="H8551BA0231EC409D9A5C78656E22D3BE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports on land access and farmland ownership data collection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12607(c) of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2204i">7 U.S.C. 2204i(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2023</quote> and inserting <quote>2031</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

