<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3477251B94F14256AD597FCF10E7371B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8984 IH: Respect Our Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8984</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Department of Homeland Security from constructing, acquiring, renovating, or operating any new processing site or detention center without providing a mechanism for public comments regarding such activity, entering into a signed, written agreement with appropriate State and local officials, and providing Congress with advance notice of such activity.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H85C8D7FF184E417B8E9BB7AA7D937A44" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDE8389DF98EC45BAB90F3F59AD2A88D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Respect Our Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0243AA06DBC947AA8F6F2BB85BAA12EF"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62CFBFEF85934408A67B83A47B8081E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate local government officials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate local government officials</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC4E75299D1314E5DB4E0D198E568D3DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mayor, county executive, or equivalent elected official of the town, city, county or other local jurisdiction in which a new processing facility or detention center will be located; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E0D45B63F03499CA4980B56F0FDB541"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a majority of the town council, city council, county council, county commission, or equivalent legislative authority in which a new processing facility or detention center will be located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC98462474A714121B796787816AEE736"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New processing site or detention center</header><text>The term <term>new processing site or detention center</term> means any facility operated by, or pursuant to a contract with, U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, including any facility designed under the Detention Reengineering Initiative, that, beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, will be used to temporarily hold persons pending the resolution or completion of immigration removal operations or processes.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB6570E1F1BC4213988753FCB07F72BB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirements for new CBP and ICE processing sites and detention centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Department of Homeland Security or any other Federal agency may not initiate the construction, acquisition, renovation, or operation of, or otherwise acquire an interest in real property to be used as, a new processing site or detention center for U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement until—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC4CE04EDDC04CA4BEB6641403551128"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the relevant Federal agency issues a public notice in the Federal Register that—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD32B7E3B6EF0480BB6018E61CF8EF659"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is open for public comments for a period lasting at least 30 days;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEB99A55BEB364BA0979F35D1574F8641"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the scope of the construction, acquisition, renovation, or operation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BABDCDFCB69433E8463F87953F11CCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes information regarding such agency's due diligence process, which shall explain how such agency will comply with—</text> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA148571D999E402783B9F85C22E458CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal guidance and standards related to immigration detention; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B4F248EBED845B49081577B9EECC934"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicable environmental regulations;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H677660F12CCD4DE49EA06E4FEDD89F8F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>includes any other information or documentation relevant to such new processing site or detention center; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA3B51D461CA401D9D040D90A1D99BF7"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes an economic impact analysis and an engineering review that addresses the site or center's waste exportation, water usage, and electrical demand;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC72AC6EB7D0446ABF1E0D64F09BF5EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">after the conclusion of the public comment period, the head of the relevant Federal agency—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BA1E082F87D422E90B35EA25EE1F881"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">considers and responds to significant comments received in accordance with subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBEAA0606101E42848E2004E6DB199F33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enters into a signed, written agreement with appropriate local government officials and the Governor of the State in which such processing site or detention center will be located that authorizes such construction, acquisition, renovation, or operation, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H300F257DA0664A14BD76DB94316DFB56"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 30 days has elapsed since the head of the relevant Federal agency submitted a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> regarding such planned construction, acquisition, renovation, or operation that includes a fully executed copy of the agreement described in paragraph (2).</text>
            </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

