<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26316-KD9-XW-GNG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3900 IS: Iran Human Rights, Internet Freedom, and Accountability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3900</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S433">Mr. McCormick</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To promote human rights, internet freedom and accountability in Iran, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Iran Human Rights, Internet Freedom, and Accountability Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc20af7e73de6458cb3756dcf0d95ee64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; statement of policy</header><subsection id="id7ee9bd3b8d784feb9d1ca0eb5526e0fc"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id308b6b1a632e412a998c518fac313bc6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For nearly five decades, the people of Iran have endured brutal repression under the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran, a regime that denies basic human rights, silences dissidents, and responds to peaceful protest with violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8b408635aa36414a91657a8212228954"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The people of Iran have repeatedly and courageously taken to the streets to demand economic opportunity, human rights, dignity, and freedom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7c469df076874456b8334431b13caed0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>During the 2026 protests, the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran responded with brutality by reportedly killing tens of thousands of people and wounding thousands more, arresting tens of thousands, and restricting internet access and telephone lines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde7d11de527a4e838da60fe45c151153"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The people of Iran are protesting the Iranian regime’s economic mismanagement, corruption, internal suppression, and unjust executions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1d28e18ff48a489eb5b3594601a5cbaa"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Access to free expression, open information, and uncensored communication are fundamental human rights and critical to the survival of the Iranian protestors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b03194fb6f646c799c85a2ee91c5900"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Thanks in part to United States-funded efforts to support human rights and open internet access, the Iranian people are consistently found to be one of the most pro-American populations in the Middle East.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8bf83eff0bdc4310b40d43e55d840eb3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The inspiring 2022 Women, Life, Freedom protests demanded an end to the Islamic Republic and its violence, particularly against Iranian women and ethnic minorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd9adb09b2db44f9b7a6b8a6ffb6ceb2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The barbaric so-called <quote>morality police</quote> and other arms of state suppression have a lengthy history of repressing the Iranian people’s fundamental freedoms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id033bccb058e7418db4976d9a8fda000e"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Iranian regime has engaged in systematic efforts to intimidate, harass, detain, and harm political dissidents, activists, and journalists both within Iran and beyond its borders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide8a637a00d9e4795ac58b4c152b177da"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The people of Iran deserve the right to dignity, democracy, and self-determination and to be free from the brutality of the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide2d36a0f1ad24f5194627d89e0c161c0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="id270729e875334e248bf8162368926fda"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to recognize the right of the Iranian people to freely determine, through free and fair elections, the future leadership of their country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea81703e35b048f5bad199352726bb75"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to facilitate the immediate expansion of unrestricted internet access and civilian lines of communication across Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc9ef24838aee4cee9cc4d6a286e648a3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support the internationally recognized human rights of Iranians and United States programs to assist Iranian civil society, including in their credible documentation, reporting, and accountability efforts of abuses in Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id947e07028f4441208ad981aab24fae18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to fully enforce sanctions against regime violators of internationally recognized human rights and their family members, including any family members and associates in the United States that continue to directly or indirectly provide support to the regime; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a7547773adc46f0823de8b6fe066efc"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to work in coordination with its allies to consider appropriate measures to deter further lethal violence against protesters.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="iddeee2e67a84e4d4496e5c295cfd05fe8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improved coordination of efforts to promote internet freedom in Iran</header><subsection id="id58a6665796c84af19090daef6e223d65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties of the Secretary of State</header><text>The Secretary of State shall be the Federal official with the primary responsibility for—</text><paragraph id="id149a893381324ebf9fd45713247a270e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting widespread internet freedom in Iran and expanding access to information for Iranian citizens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id17fbbb7bc5cd4b1c89ab1a179273dc71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinating all efforts carried out by Federal departments and agencies that relate to digital freedom initiatives in Iran; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide1361b05cf0e4a64862615a8d916dbb2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serving as the principal official responsible for updating and carrying out the strategy required under section 414 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfaad5e726db64fcb88a3b48d6eb1d439"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Updates to comprehensive strategy To promote internet freedom and access to information in Iran</header> <paragraph id="id596706b38f9f49159a9aac1baad8f439"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Updates</header> <text>Section 414 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
          <subparagraph id="id7815998f1e6e4586a35a7d71537c2cd5">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>by striking <quote>Not later than</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) <header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">Initial strategy</header-in-text>.—Not later than</quote>;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id295812e82de64905ad6e43e3288d1335">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>by redesignating paragraphs (11) and (12) as paragraphs (14) and (15), respectively;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id36d4316b322248419aab0014ba18780b">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>by inserting after paragraph (10) the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida6cd3f78c02a4732943fa8be6dcb6858"> <paragraph id="id4be6cee4041743bb90fb1813b1dc9800"> <enum>(11)</enum> <text>evaluate the use of virtual private networks and direct-to-cell satellite technologies by civil society and internationally recognized human rights activists in Iran and develop strategies for increasing the accessibility of such networks and technologies;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="id2c001ec4944a452cb7b6fe5639188d5c">
                <enum>(12)</enum>
 <text>work with the Department of the Treasury and the Department of Commerce to ensure enforcement of sanctions does not impede companies providing to Iranian civilians the technology and other tools necessary to access the open internet;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <paragraph id="id5ecc2483283c4854ae1dc51eb06bad12">
                <enum>(13)</enum>
 <text>assess the ability of the Iranian regime to cut off all access to the internet and develop a strategy to circumvent internet blackouts for Iranian civil society;</text>
              </paragraph>
              <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id29e356ff4d38454eb0e3fa55836739f3">
            <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end of the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id49773a7df6be44dea244c9748227e21c"> <subsection id="id5600444ab2914359832057cbf57bf122"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Updates</header> <text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies as appropriate, shall review the strategy under subsection (a) on an ongoing basis and update the strategy as appropriate, taking into account the results of such review.</text>
              </subsection>
              <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
            </quoted-block>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idd80622b4528546b48d3495c7afa5aa2d">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
          <header>Submission of first updates</header>
          <subparagraph id="id0be8ff4989b24f35bb5c178414adf420">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
            <header>Submission</header>
 <text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall—</text>
            <clause id="idceb1f0b104aa4c0eb638f6032b9b290b">
              <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>review and update the strategy pursuant to section 414(b) of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>), as added by paragraph (1); and</text>
            </clause>
            <clause id="idbe583525a443474faf3d3e527f527333">
              <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>submit such updated strategy to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text>
            </clause>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="id47d90116fc1f409da181b2b7ca6bef02">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
            <header>Form</header>
 <text>The strategy under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in an unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection></section><section id="idb5f278b7dcc2478e9899717f3710bc32"><enum>4.</enum><header>Internet freedom and censorship circumvention</header><subsection id="id35c8ffe1b1684fe5b011b4f16d2b5806"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Internet freedom report</header><paragraph id="id718deb83d474456985f66beae2cd474c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Federal Communications Commission and the Department of the Treasury, shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that updates and supplements the report required under section 5124 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/159">Public Law 118–159</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf47682d66c8542d784031aaff7cbb7d0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional matters to be included</header><text>Updates to the strategy required in section 5124 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754a">22 U.S.C. 8754a</external-xref>) shall also include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id1e04cd8eda084470ba956a4465be7bf5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the feasibility of using direct-to-cell wireless communications technologies to expand internet access for the people of Iran, including technical, regulatory, and security considerations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id85ed4d399061446293140da56edb25b5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of how drone-based platforms, signal-jamming technologies, and related countermeasures could impact the feasibility, security, economics, and resilience of such direct-to-cell wireless communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id70f269c069834889bd786f4b4f3c7a2f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A survey of terrestrial and non-terrestrial telecommunications service providers currently active in Iran, including—</text><clause id="idad5e9339714d4eca98a4f23499cbff44"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether such providers are state-owned or state-controlled;</text></clause><clause id="idef6641d8abb04f8b90d66d884b559ca9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the extent of foreign participation or investment in such providers;</text></clause><clause id="id0a5dc0a55d38457eac3a4a71970ef4b7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the implications of such ownership and control for communications freedom and censorship; and</text></clause><clause id="id6ffffb00e8a94df5816fa58ea2dde2b8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other relevant information to assess the opportunities and risks associated with terrestrial and non-terrestrial communications technologies in Iran.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id53a02f9bdc57466995cd245bab54690f"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide6ed32e1552d438f96444da28d1c708b"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension and increase of authorization for Iran Internet Freedom Grant Program</header><text>Section 5124(b)(5)(A) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754a">22 U.S.C. 8754a(b)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and not less than $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030</quote> after <quote>$15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 and 2026</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc7b8b8fd91ca44df8c8d9f0837ac45f7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development of internet access technologies</header><paragraph id="id2b39c754ab144c54832638be9f5c33ac"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Department of State, in coordination with the Department of Defense, the United States Agency for Global Media, and other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall form a joint working group (referred to as the <quote>Working Group</quote>) to support the development of low-cost, easily scalable, and rapidly deployable technologies to counter internet shutdowns or limitations on network access abroad, particularly those imposed by adversary countries, to enable populations to overcome such restrictions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25f7f0f430c746edbfe94a379203f27d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>In carrying out the responsibilities under subsection (a), the Working Group shall prioritize the following objectives:</text><subparagraph id="id3af843cb74974305a5783b5953318931"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Identifying and supporting the development of technologies capable of overcoming internet blackouts and network disruptions imposed by an adversary country and facilitating internet and network access, including—</text><clause id="idfb8aae9324424f71acd08e2282ca7444"><enum>(i)</enum><text>low-earth orbit satellite internet infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="id69adf79a30ec43f3b143892dbc7c4da9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>mesh networking solutions; and</text></clause><clause id="id4890a9e68bf44873b3a1ea101e412eea"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>portable and deployable communication systems.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id853632fc698b444187e2cfe4a0d6bad0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Virtual private networks (commonly known as <quote>VPNs</quote>), including—</text><clause id="idb65a97722fbd4a41a1842961babef8e7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collaborating with industry, academia, and relevant stakeholders to accelerate the research, development, and deployment of such technologies;</text></clause><clause id="id9e8fd1dca8564cd8912da09e3de83366"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conducting pilot programs and field experiments to test the effectiveness and scalability of developed solutions in real-world settings; and</text></clause><clause id="id77c6ec6aff6345e5a07180772db2867f"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing technical assistance and resources to partner organizations, governments, and nongovernmental entities engaged in efforts to expand internet access.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0cafdff90f5d4be08a2216b0f68da651"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identifying and evaluating off-the-shelf technologies that could be rapidly procured and deployed to address internet access challenges in targeted regions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf3b98838a3bf41e69a49d94f813c6447"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaboration with the Federal Acquisition Institute</header><text>The Working Group shall collaborate with the Federal Acquisition Institute to leverage expertise in acquisition processes and practices related to carrying out the objectives under paragraph (2) with the aim of—</text><subparagraph id="ida73ba01899d8429a90c5d560baa88410"><enum>(A)</enum><text>integrating best practices in defense acquisition into the research, development, and deployment processes of technologies developed by the Working Group to facilitate internet access;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c740ef498de44db9c1b0c57f34b4dce"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring that technologies developed by the Working Group align with acquisition priorities and strategies of the Department of State and the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id519d9271fb2d4b4e88e022d3da941da5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing training and educational opportunities for the Working Group on acquisition principles, regulations, and procedures, with a focus on technology development for countering censorship and related restrictions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id64ff74273fcd4d30b860bbcaa154c34e"><enum>(D)</enum><text>fostering dialogue and exchange of knowledge between acquisition professionals and innovation specialists to enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of defense technology acquisition related to internet access technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide1162ef6f44c4277a8607d4273ca5ff4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>collaborating on the development of acquisition strategies that prioritize the rapid acquisition and deployment of technologies aimed at countering censorship and restrictions on internet access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcd8265f725bb4a0fb663987fd5b56f65"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the United States Agency for Global Media, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an annual report detailing the progress, challenges, and outcomes of the efforts undertaken pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd948f309f9414f9f85800e6fcba2ec52"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year 2027 through 2030 to carry out the activities described in this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf6c9c5de990e4e6693195f0559405d78"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5737dcd4903547c68fcfa2824d68cb5e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2931050cc7464be0b24534bfe96a51b5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idee7682162cb249cb85c9b0f65a66956b"><enum>5.</enum><header>Identification of individuals supporting human rights violations</header><subsection id="id43b363157f2342d7a7044ead9019f98a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after receiving a written request from the chairman or ranking member of any of the appropriate congressional committees regarding whether a foreign person has engaged in the conduct described in subsection (b), the President shall—</text><paragraph id="id8916470bb7b54993982a385528147117"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine whether the foreign person has engaged in such conduct; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb46dd9e0002e4981a17903ab7545de30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to such chairman or ranking minority member a written justification detailing whether the President imposed the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to such person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idea537c256ce9475da12de0101bfacd0a"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conduct described</header><text>The conduct described in this subsection is knowingly providing material support for the Iranian regime’s abuses of internationally recognized human rights, censorship, or repression of the Iranian people, including—</text><paragraph id="id2844d6c3d5364136a8e33ce62f1c216c"><enum>(1)</enum><text>selling, supplying, or transferring censorship technology, surveillance tools, or internet shutdown capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id462796e794734ff687990090bcbd8118"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any conduct sanctionable under part 562 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (Iranian Human Rights Abuses Sanctions Regulations); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8aec9d66e00e426893c705f5417c529b"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any conduct sanctionable under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id693de9ce25994d2e9314e507f3793d46"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7cf8b2c107544e1089fccb2a3a477f4e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc06597bff17b45e6902b904f6c91888e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idbcb8e642f122438daa017c59137016a5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Strategy on Iran broadcasting and human rights assistance</header><subsection id="id9e32914e02e443a69a5206cbccddf1e2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><paragraph id="id5ee4fed572a34206ae57ccf1e9b28146"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy to expand and enhance United States and international broadcasting efforts and United States programs to support the protection and promotion of internationally recognized human rights in Iran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1ba58adc3b184a53b2abee68eab413d9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements of the strategy</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id93074326504a4731b6d7857c84279795"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a comprehensive review and assessment of current United States Government and international broadcasting efforts targeted at Iran, including Voice of America Persian Service, Radio Farda, and other relevant programs, including their reach, effectiveness, and vulnerabilities to Iranian regime censorship, as well as United States Government efforts to support internationally recognized human rights and democratic civil society, including efforts to assist in the credible documentation of abuses of internationally recognized human rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd21eb96bf7b14010bc5398af9d68d0ba"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specific plans and initiatives to ensure the Iranian people have reliable access to accurate, uncensored, and unbiased news coverage, including through satellite broadcasting, digital circumvention tools, shortwave radio, and emerging technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id91e66ab25a874f6e939f2badb63723a3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>programs to support independent Iranian journalists, media outlets, and citizen journalists, including grants for equipment, training, secure communication platforms, and capacity-building for Persian and other local language media;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb4778218568e44109f4d33d0a0e64c3d"><enum>(D)</enum><text>programs to support and train Iranian civil society;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb86373ba90ad4621bd05cd64e3821f0f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordination mechanisms with international partners, the private sector, and diaspora communities to amplify credible independent media;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb365d2b766df4c5abdf06664c9b20bbc"><enum>(F)</enum><text>annual performance metrics and benchmarks for audience reach, content impact, and program outcomes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5f1fdee27b4f47c8a1f67be323031d22"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a multi-year budget and resource requirements plan to implement the strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ffe54aa9cc643928ebc3bb539a3376a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required in subsection (a) shall be transmitted in an unclassified form and may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id063bb569bcd14be2b79fc66d66ea0141"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report on Near East Regional Democracy (NERD) expenditures</header><paragraph id="iddc8f69ef118748fbad7486a428be6403"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report examining Federal expenditures under the Near East Regional Democracy (NERD) account over fiscal years 2024 and 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4b9e136a74924651836d6a2fd0b6dcd3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id01318e04c2864ba4871c64ab9485a751"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed accounting of all NERD funds obligated and expended for Iran-related programs, including broadcasting, media support, civil society assistance, and human rights initiatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb9de5730efff41dfb2e5cc7c7079affc"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the processes used for grant allocation, contractor oversight, vetting of recipients, and measuring program outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31c924ce59984b2a9f6525a35b34d9ff"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of such programs in advancing United States policy objectives, including expanding information access and supporting independent media within Iran; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc1de01307627492bb754bcf8f1abbdcb"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for improving transparency, accountability, and impact measurement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idbad975a0a5b347c2ba13e1163608cbdf"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy and the GAO report required under this section shall each be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="id24c59d88d6b549ce85852c623b1b1596"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id1dab8eb273824b1aa8103687e6b29151"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2a923fa11ae14ce884126a0c213530dd"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id45484b73eb3a4b7691b30d00673b68f3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Cybersecurity capacity for civil society in Iran</header><subsection id="ide5aa7d52ab9c440bb961b0da245dd10a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training and tools</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall establish programs—</text><paragraph id="id3845f7c6f3764ad5b3b843fcd2fc186a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to deliver remote or in-person cybersecurity training to journalists, defenders of internationally recognized human rights, and civil-society actors in Iran;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9694a0ff4294c64afa22c294aa00ace"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to furnish vetted open-source or commercially available digital-safety tools, including VPN services and end-to-end encrypted messaging applications; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide791c68192b84f57a2354a5c1cca2e87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide multilingual educational materials that warn Iranian users about regime-controlled applications and phishing campaigns.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4ef7e35932a2418da884082c65d56ae2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting and evaluation</header><paragraph id="id82a4437476d947ca991245bf8c760448"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quarterly metrics</header><text>The Secretary of State shall track and, on a quarterly basis, make available to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives aggregate metrics on the number of trainees, incident-response cases, and unique users of supported digital safety tools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5a0e7de0678648cb91e66b56cbdab66e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Independent evaluation</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program carried out under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide6218ccdf4cd4483b90f94d043df3532"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to supersede or limit existing authority under section 404 of the Iran Threat Reduction and Syria Human Rights Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8754">22 U.S.C. 8754</external-xref>) or any other provision of law related to internet freedom programming in Iran.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc5e13379a62b4d5d949852bcde3d1c2f"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <text>There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2030 to carry out the activities described in this section.</text>
 </subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id41862716d3264c27a1879e7c10a5ff44"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed as authorizing the use of military force.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

