<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H21C3638995FB4B5FBA9E3A2E82F7B5C1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9529 IH: No Official Presidential Returns On Furtive Individual Trades Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260629">June 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on net capital gain accrued while serving as President of the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1329566ED9A940C1B255DF7E49466405" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1E1C8CCD8BBD473A938D3256F5419F6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Official Presidential Returns On Furtive Individual Trades Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NO PROFIT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HF783FE56FC3E4D0DB7DB71747F68A915"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposition of tax on net capital gain accrued while serving as President of the United States</header> 
<subsection id="H283968A6383A4CC38055F32E91BD96D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1">Section 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6CC0529E3A694684A1A6B9847EE82D6A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE5C9034807EF41E082E54FB70DE5D54C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Special rules for net capital gain accrued while serving as President of the United States</header> <paragraph id="HF55BAA55C5BA44E7AB7C5886003E869A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a taxpayer has a qualified net capital gain for any applicable taxable year, the tax imposed by this section on such gain for such taxable year shall be equal to 100 percent of such gain. Proper adjustments shall be made in the application of this section to ensure that gain subject to tax under the preceding sentence is not subject to additional tax under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BA376F3C30A4111A0EE0E794619CF76" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mark to market</header><text>In the case of any capital asset other than a qualified capital asset which is held by a taxpayer at the close of any applicable taxable year—</text> <subparagraph id="H12F5C93F2E7A4EABB78AFD172CCE66B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such taxpayer shall recognize gain or loss on such capital asset as if such capital asset were sold for its fair market value on the last business day of such taxable year, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H58186A9F063B4D2BA84E04332F04BD83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any gain or loss shall be taken into account for such taxable year.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Proper adjustments shall be made in the amount of any gain or loss subsequently realized for gain or loss taken into account under the preceding sentence.</continuation-text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3502537681BD4D27BB9949B21A232CA3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD16B326449A6467CB731544318C08C87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualified net capital gain</header><text>The term <term>qualified net capital gain</term> means, with respect to any applicable taxable year, an amount equal to the excess (if any) of—</text> <clause id="H790CB9397BBC480FB1FE9F63BF23CB2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of gain from the sale or exchange during such taxable year of any capital asset other than a qualified capital asset, if and to the extent that such gain is taken into account in computing gross income, over</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3201D7743DE7481E9EC24EE039EC1024"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the aggregate amount of loss from the sale or exchange during such taxable year of any capital asset other than a qualified capital asset, if and to the extent that such loss is taken into account in computing taxable income.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H249A4DB6DCD24B9A8BEDA78711BCB23D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified capital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified capital asset</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer, any capital asset which, at all times during which the individual is serving as President of the United States, is not held by such taxpayer other than in a qualified blind trust (as defined in section 13104(f)(3) of title 5, United States Code).</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C94FE89D650426C8154C73E74114B29"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicable taxable year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable taxable year</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer, any taxable year during any portion of which the individual served as President of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H23F0E567FF974BEDB3452FF96644769F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2024.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

