<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-TAM26105-PCF-X7-CW3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S1157 RS: Women and Lung Cancer Research and Preventive Services Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 308</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 1157</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250326">March 26, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20260128">January 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a review to evaluate the status of research on lung cancer in women and underserved populations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD13DF92EAFBF432E9547A46D4011B9EE"><section section-type="section-one" id="HF83745C18E6B4189B11E5A7E11482FAF" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women and Lung Cancer Research and Preventive Services Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBAA39A82B3F04EDBB3B4B427859809C1" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency review to evaluate and identify opportunities for the acceleration of research on lung cancer in women and underserved populations, greater access to preventive services, and strategic public awareness and education campaigns</header><subsection id="H503E271CF9A84D5888D755600DDC087D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall conduct an interagency review to evaluate the status of, and identify opportunities for the acceleration of research related to—</text><paragraph id="H4DD7C2F3867649039654935635E8B334"><enum>(1)</enum><text>research on lung cancer in women;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB810622392C24BD59C5AFDD537672471"><enum>(2)</enum><text>research on lung cancer in underserved populations that meet the eligibility criteria for lung cancer screening as recommended by the United States Preventive Services Task Force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EF6A24C5C5E4C14BB3C9D5D375718D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>access to lung cancer preventive services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD0ED47EFF34409994F4526A6AB98BA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>strategic public awareness and education campaigns on lung cancer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD08F9DE9C28D4B58A933DFFE69DDBAE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The review and recommendations under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H952147D427C241049FE3DDA03DB56101"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review and comprehensive report on the outcomes of previous research, the status of existing research activities, and knowledge gaps related to lung cancer in women and underserved populations in all agencies of the Federal Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78688D0F7E0143E7BCFC931DA9484776"><enum>(2)</enum><text>opportunities for collaborative, interagency, multidisciplinary, and innovative research, that would—</text><subparagraph id="HB9DFC27E64344578BA783D2D6CF0628E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage innovative approaches to eliminate knowledge gaps in research on lung cancer in women;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE65BDDEAFD224110B4DC8C14FBA226D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate environmental and genomic factors that may be related to the etiology of lung cancer in women; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AD42076E30F449296FCB79D89E9DDC0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>foster advances in imaging technology and techniques to improve risk assessment, diagnosis, treatment, and the simultaneous utilization of other preventive services and activities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00B9BBB4A1C74B20B055283D9942ADA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>opportunities regarding the development of a national lung cancer screening strategy to expand access to such screenings, particularly among women and underserved populations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EB005F42C504373AE4AC7EB5B46AA58"><enum>(4)</enum><text>opportunities regarding the development of a national public education and awareness campaign on—</text><subparagraph id="HD4EDFEB73702433895A634E41B40B2F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lung cancer in women and underserved populations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06EEDCF20C654FE98586C31E48581566"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the importance of early detection of lung cancer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA37402FB5BC942CE84FFD6387C5887FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the review conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id4ab1b629-7556-406d-b010-69a0917e00ab" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Women and Lung Cancer Research and Preventive Services Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9a972d12-a774-4a5c-93ba-b2c33557abe4" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency review to evaluate and identify opportunities to improve lung cancer prevention and treatment in women</header><subsection id="id5058856f-66bd-404e-ad48-9d58b2ecb22a"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall review and, as necessary and appropriate, update Federal programs, activities, and strategic plans related to lung cancer research, prevention, diagnosis, and treatment for purposes of—</text><paragraph id="idcf478f22-085a-4f5c-b881-ab53591c71f2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying and addressing knowledge gaps and improving health outcomes related to lung cancer in women and populations with few known risk factors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0fb3417e-4181-443c-b74c-48a05085f76d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improving lung cancer screening rates among populations recommended by the United States Preventive Services Task Force to receive such screening.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9a6635d2-c925-4e6a-a751-cfaa149a1cb6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The review under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="idde8cbd80-d67d-40a9-8ceb-0734a954b22e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of findings from research on lung cancer in populations described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), the status of ongoing federally funded research on lung cancer in such populations, and knowledge gaps related to lung cancer in such populations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc23f55df-e59a-4afd-8d51-d0185c76efbb"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consideration of additional research opportunities, including through interagency collaboration and multidisciplinary projects, that would—</text><subparagraph id="idd19af694-5c6b-4a38-9c6e-7bc102aee4c5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eliminate knowledge gaps in research on lung cancer in women, including an evaluation of any environmental and genomic factors that may be related to the etiology of lung cancer in women; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfcc9bccee64b44beb8744065d344659a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve screening rates among populations described in subsection (a)(2); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51115ca6-adb0-4662-b421-c254231ef01d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>foster advances in technology and interventions, including biomarker testing, to improve lung cancer risk assessment, diagnosis, and treatment; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idefbb0af3-2c2e-4101-ad15-f5809536fdd7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a review of current public health strategies, and consideration of alternative evidence-based strategies, related to lung cancer screening and diagnosis, including an assessment of the need for additional public awareness and education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8738caa1-17e8-413c-81c7-c73f4b5c06a1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on the review conducted under subsection (a), including—</text><paragraph id="id359800fa8c784ef5804ea97b1298bb09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of research findings, ongoing research projects, and knowledge gaps described in subsection (b)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id24f6fedaa3dc481c84a82e320395f5ec"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any changes made by such Secretary or the head of any other Federal agency to Federal programs, activities, or strategic plans based on the findings of the review; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida252a8aff0564d77b4c59964fbc5c6b5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any additional changes to Federal programs, activities, or strategic plans recommended by the Secretary based on the review, and any statutory or other barriers that impede implementation of such changes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>January 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

