<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H5B66BA9A643B45BB8A896230AD03392B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 2289 RH: American Broadband Deployment Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 532</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2289</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–614, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20250324">March 24, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001093">Mrs. Houchin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000478">Mr. Fry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name> with amendments</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 24, 2025</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that an eligible facilities request under section 6409(a) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 is not subject to requirements to prepare certain environmental or historical preservation reviews.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HIF00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H98284E29D43048BE9B0AE13456F11942"><section id="H3D288ADA7CD14ABA86754588A7C6A152" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HA7195A0F2A7E44D79748F3263538EB6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Broadband Deployment Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF8898C3D06734B53A1C01BF3856B044A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><toc-entry idref="H3D288ADA7CD14ABA86754588A7C6A152" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD674A2C8D0214A528D1D4BE9E791F5C8" level="title">Title I—State and Local Siting Processes</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFAA33B29FA904FCAB1F5FC6F147CE33C" level="section">Sec. 101. Preservation of local zoning authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4FAFCD1E1302403380D4C7B4AF56498E" level="section">Sec. 102. Removal of barriers to entry.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2FF704491D5A4B97B3EB54DB95B01708" level="section">Sec. 103. Requests for modification of certain existing wireless and wireline communications facilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF67EBF79E556477887736902A12ADBBC" level="title">Title II—Cable</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H193CE6A157A94D029CABF6A3C9C8EB5D" level="section">Sec. 201. Request for new franchise.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9BAB08D7A4124A2181AA654076484241" level="section">Sec. 202. Request regarding placement, construction, or modification of cable equipment.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H35600E52C1B4490987537C64C8C886EB" level="section">Sec. 203. Cable franchise term and termination.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H55FEB91477904516A5E43316B80B8F4D" level="section">Sec. 204. Sales of cable systems.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H607725D0F33B412881A64E23C79698C1" level="title">Title III—Environmental and Historic Preservation Reviews</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2DFCFA3751784B65950F5F50057FF37B" level="section">Sec. 301. Application of NEPA and NHPA to certain communications projects.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1C30A2925B684A72A5F311EB8C4251E9" level="section">Sec. 302. Presumption with respect to certain complete FCC forms.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9AAE4E67C20543B8A504DC6A3658BFF6" level="section">Sec. 303. Rule of construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0861136C0C994F989E85D64E5F02BAC5" level="section">Sec. 304. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H57E971B3FCE547199A105A54DB25F9E5" level="title">Title IV—Other Matters</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1C2C5FEE74E8452780FBCB8218B6AE25" level="section">Sec. 401. Timely consideration of applications for Federal easements, rights-of-way, and leases.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD71822106B094E0BA77282CFAAA0B811" level="section">Sec. 402. Report on fees.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="HD674A2C8D0214A528D1D4BE9E791F5C8"><enum>I</enum><header>State and Local Siting Processes</header><section id="HFAA33B29FA904FCAB1F5FC6F147CE33C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>101.</enum><header>Preservation of local zoning authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 332(c) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/332">47 U.S.C. 332(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (7) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H40FAD67A7C374CE6A895521E8A78F806" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><paragraph id="H538D11835E474AC782C71A23F8B79E68"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Preservation of local zoning authority</header><subparagraph id="H53DD609A1D33420EA38DBC145C97256B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>General authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in this paragraph, nothing in this Act shall limit or affect the authority of a State or local government or instrumentality thereof over decisions regarding the placement, construction, or modification of personal wireless service facilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD8D2E67943E4976A64749AEA0540DAA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><clause id="HBC163E49FDFB4ED898E8C6BBB714FDDE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The regulation of the placement, construction, or modification of a personal wireless service facility by any State or local government or instrumentality thereof—</text><subclause id="H7F3ACF800CAE465E86E69CBE1EDB9583"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall not discriminate among personal wireless service facilities or providers of communications service, including by providing exclusive or preferential use of facilities to a particular provider or class of providers of personal wireless service; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H650FFDE6D24046598D43B7C2E1C70A60"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall not prohibit or have the effect of prohibiting the provision, improvement, or enhancement of personal wireless service.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD5B398B10522408E9E1C03D69FB29749"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Engineering standards; aesthetic requirements</header><text>It is not a violation of clause (i) for a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to establish for personal wireless service facilities, or structures that support such facilities, objective, reasonable, and nondiscriminatory—</text><subclause id="HE80CFAFA078C4A7DB8A978167BB5E9B4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>structural engineering standards based on generally applicable codes;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD77F36D3F5D74B68A14563FCF6BB86A0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>safety requirements (subject to clause (vi)); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H6706899B1B2640A08343EB4499C1C806"><enum>(III)</enum><text>aesthetic or concealment requirements, unless such requirements prohibit or have the effect of prohibiting the installation or modification of such facilities or structures.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H51B0679C5F4A4AB8968796FA38BFD9BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Timeframes</header><subclause id="HC0542C89D8A64C06ACBF6B71C1B267BB" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local government or instrumentality thereof shall grant or deny a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a personal wireless service facility not later than—</text><item id="H175B4AACF2A248E399DDFACE78D783BD" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a personal wireless service facility that is not a small personal wireless service facility—</text><subitem id="HCBFCEE39CFD04D5FA172BD7AD918FB94" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the request is for authorization to place, construct, or modify such facility using an existing structure, including with respect to an area that has not previously been zoned for personal wireless service facilities (other than small personal wireless service facilities), 90 days after the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality; or</text></subitem><subitem id="H32BE3CD5F18B43799F4AF2665472AE4C" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>if the request is for any other action relating to such facility, 150 days after the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H7972A4763F85465A9D8F98250A5A3637" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a small personal wireless service facility—</text><subitem id="HFEAFCC79BB8F47808C5C1B4672C04F0E" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the request is for authorization to place, construct, or modify such facility using an existing structure, including with respect to an area that has not previously been zoned for personal wireless service facilities, 60 days after the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality; or</text></subitem><subitem id="H64D6889FE4F94A48B626F09E3563CCED" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>if the request is for any other action relating to such facility, 90 days after the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality.</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H098DCE7611B248EF8980E683B10ABFC9"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Treatment of batched requests</header><text>In the case of requests described in subclause (I) that are submitted as part of a single batch by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality on the same day, the applicable timeframe under such subclause for each request in the batch shall be the longest timeframe under such subclause that would be applicable to any request in the batch if such requests were submitted separately.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC14EA3EB7C064BFAAFF17D8D5DF97322"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The applicable timeframe under subclause (I) shall apply collectively to all proceedings, including related permits and authorizations, required by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof for the approval of the request.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF54BE490F5BA4448A58DAB083245D2E8"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>No moratoria</header><text>A timeframe under subclause (I) may not be tolled by any moratorium, whether express or de facto, imposed by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof on the submission, acceptance, or consideration of any request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a personal wireless service facility.</text></subclause><subclause id="H023EAEA93607480BB2E3745D4850739D"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Tolling due to incompleteness</header><item id="H77511CFE46C44190ADB2B0CC252AC96B"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Initial request incomplete</header><subitem id="H78DFEB41A0D0406D9F5FB380388B590F"><enum>(AA)</enum><header>Small personal wireless service facilities</header><text>If, not later than 10 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a small personal wireless service facility, the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in item (cc) with respect to the request, the timeframe described in subclause (I) is tolled with respect to the request and shall restart at zero on the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></subitem><subitem id="H05AD849EB2CC4686BD8EA994745320F3"><enum>(BB)</enum><header>Other personal wireless service facilities</header><text>If, not later than 30 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a personal wireless service facility that is not a small personal wireless service facility, the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in item (cc) with respect to the request, the timeframe described in subclause (I) is tolled with respect to the request until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></subitem></item><item id="HA852F1BF6BCE49D69753E9A48F55C5EB"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Supplemental submission incomplete</header><text>If, not later than 10 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a supplemental submission in response to a written notice described in item (cc), the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in item (cc) with respect to the supplemental submission, the timeframe under subclause (I) is further tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a subsequent supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></item><item id="H0BAFEBC16CD14173BC5AC58A213A85C2"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text>The written notice described in this item is, with respect to a request described in subclause (I) or a supplemental submission described in item (aa) or (bb) submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof by a requesting party, a written notice from the government or instrumentality to the requesting party—</text><subitem id="HF41A348238FA4BA38DC4E541701DEB22"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>stating that all of the information (including any form or other document) required by the government or instrumentality to be submitted for the request to be considered complete has not been submitted;</text></subitem><subitem id="HF2AF3368EFBB4C73B9695FFD9D9B0E50"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>identifying the information described in subitem (AA) that was not submitted; and</text></subitem><subitem id="HC949B8EB3CB74718A1A8A94996D4E966"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>including a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the government or instrumentality requiring that such information be submitted with such a request.</text></subitem></item><item id="H5283B05ADE844C9DA09FE4FF5B9B701B"><enum>(dd)</enum><header>Limitation on subsequent written notice</header><text>If a written notice provided by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to a requesting party under item (bb) with respect to a supplemental submission identifies as not having been submitted any information that was not identified as not having been submitted in the prior written notice under this subclause in response to which the supplemental submission was submitted, the subsequent written notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HBE885A718384418ABD20C4781B514047"><enum>(VI)</enum><header>Tolling by mutual agreement</header><text>The timeframe under subclause (I) may be tolled once, for a period of not more than 30 days, by mutual agreement between the State or local government or instrumentality thereof and the requesting party.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5B7CA6B2F4584762AA2F1FAD96C9FA1B"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Deemed granted</header><subclause id="HB42E972984134749BBF4FFCF32D64FD8"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a State or local government or instrumentality thereof fails to take final action to grant or deny a request within the applicable timeframe under subclause (I) of clause (iii), the request shall be deemed granted on the date on which the government or instrumentality receives a written notice of the failure from the requesting party.</text></subclause><subclause id="H61E19ECC06C043D88C6601521B54868B"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>In the case of a request that is deemed granted under subclause (I), the placement, construction, or modification requested in the request shall be considered to be authorized, without any further action by the government or instrumentality, beginning on the date on which the request is deemed granted under such subclause.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H89152F1FD68D45B48836B734ACA16330"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Written decision and record</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any decision by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to deny a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a personal wireless service facility shall be—</text><subclause id="HE58A84AD172C4482A32B7617725C1623"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in writing;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBA3D5FC186AE44E7A3D9F8693EC01E2A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDB9B0FDE4A2F45EFBA677D0DFBC32853"><enum>(III)</enum><text>publicly released, and provided to the requesting party, on the same day such decision is made.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2A8E7B88E2894F78B0EFD9CE1357608A"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Environmental effects of radio frequency emissions</header><text>No State or local government or instrumentality thereof may regulate the operation, placement, construction, or modification of personal wireless service facilities on the basis of the environmental effects of radio frequency emissions to the extent that such facilities or structures comply with the Commission’s regulations concerning such emissions.</text></clause><clause id="H7D872E6646804163976EB7E8112C641D"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent permitted by law, a State or local government or instrumentality thereof may charge a fee to consider a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a personal wireless service facility or a fee for use of a right-of-way or a facility in a right-of-way owned or managed by the government or instrumentality for the placement, construction, or modification of a personal wireless service facility, if the fee is—</text><subclause id="H216C7ADA5E8E47368BC40A019313B7BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>competitively neutral, technology neutral, and nondiscriminatory;</text></subclause><subclause id="H544546E4F260485BB4027D45013C92CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>established in advance and publicly disclosed;</text></subclause><subclause id="HEFA079004AD540529B3D5532AF7527F5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>calculated—</text><item id="H59508BA9FAC044838295B491DFF1B64D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>based on actual and direct costs for—</text><subitem id="HFA710D0609AB4C5381E917B04DC5DC11"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>review and processing of requests; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H9983654FF6AE4088A6AD5B9176658332"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">repairs and replacement of components and materials directly resulting from and affected by the placement, construction, or modification (including the installation or improvement) of personal wireless service facilities or repairs and replacement of equipment that facilitates the placement, construction, or modification (including the installation or improvement) of such facilities; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H37CA9CEE2EB94E169826E37F230AC117"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>using, for purposes of item (aa), only costs that are objectively reasonable; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB91CD12BC4C34275AFB8FEB58DADA371"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>described to a requesting party in a manner that distinguishes between—</text><item id="H0862FD69EC3848539A1ADF0BF8BDF63E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>nonrecurring fees and recurring fees; and</text></item><item id="H7A7B19200E4B4D0B840FFDEC0DBE116A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of facilities on which personal wireless service facilities are already located and facilities on which there are no personal wireless service facilities as of the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD2479DC6683467A899E879E6847C827"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Any person adversely affected by any final action or failure to act by a State or local government or any instrumentality thereof that is inconsistent with this paragraph may, within 30 days after the action or failure to act, commence an action in any court of competent jurisdiction, which shall hear and decide the action on an expedited basis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7F20DCC67DE46B9B6DCCCBF1B4C0939" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>When request considered submitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this paragraph, a request to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof shall be considered submitted on the date on which the requesting party takes the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party—</text><clause id="HF32A657352F44C20AA3E72DCEB37E094"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit such request in accordance with the procedures established by the government or instrumentality for the review and approval of such a request; or</text></clause><clause id="HEE172EA8BAC84C7890384578FA7C588B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a government or instrumentality that has not established specific procedures for the review and approval of such a request, to submit to the government or instrumentality the type of filing that is typically required to initiate a standard review for a similar facility or structure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA45EF9E948D04DD6A2500E6E8FA14C37"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to affect section 6409(a) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H319CECFEF559455DB239F80A02E03DEC"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Effect of regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any regulation promulgated by the Commission to implement this paragraph (including any interpretation of the requirements of and terms used in this paragraph contained in any such regulation) shall be binding on a court in any action under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB787C3AD0D3648F7AEF93098B0CEF7BB"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="H96EA92690F34418CAEC76DF0BC5D05DA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Antenna</header><text>The term <term>antenna</term> means an apparatus designed for the purpose of emitting radiofrequency radiation, to be operated or operating from a fixed location for the transmission of writing, signs, signals, data, images, pictures, and sounds of all kinds.</text></clause><clause id="HF0C7C43BD8BF442B8748C6398AFA1867"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Communications network</header><text>The term <term>communications network</term> means a network used to provide a communications service.</text></clause><clause id="H2C151A2437F049648B5F8968BBD51834"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Communications service</header><text>The term <term>communications service</term> means each of—</text><subclause id="H8E277A18A72F4A3F8C3A36895F7F85E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cable service, as defined in section 602;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCA10BA60167547E497AE7CFCE16DD61A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information service;</text></subclause><subclause id="H45B9E54EC5AB4E35BE556F00E033916B" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>telecommunications service; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H25D6E9200E2D4D6BA91452BBD87415D5"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>personal wireless service.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0DB38CAC697246B7A95BA3382DE6788F"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Generally applicable code</header><text>The term <term>generally applicable code</term> means a uniform building, fire, electrical, plumbing, or mechanical code adopted by a national code organization, or a local amendment to such a code, to the extent not inconsistent with this Act.</text></clause><clause id="HC236217B5644486ABCD1BDB1A2B45422"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Network interface device</header><text>The term <term>network interface device</term> means a telecommunications demarcation device and cross-connect point that—</text><subclause id="H9CF4BAA4E8C14B55BDDF6CC91885F909"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is adjacent or proximate to—</text><item id="H548CE5B33DD94971B6364E7CA1252368"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a small personal wireless service facility; or</text></item><item id="H797D64BAB48142BBB6C4342939155A38"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a structure supporting a small personal wireless service facility; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HE94F9D315ED5443E8620ABCF1912C752"><enum>(II)</enum><text>demarcates the boundary with any wireline backhaul facility.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF0A767E69D454BC8BF0E1B45A1ECE777"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Personal wireless service</header><text>The term <term>personal wireless service</term> means any fixed or mobile service (other than a broadcasting service) provided via licensed or unlicensed frequencies, including—</text><subclause id="H9334B11AF34E4A1F9FE10C897218F6B6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>commercial mobile service;</text></subclause><subclause id="H055985E8B1FD4C949A9EC7A924ED29FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>commercial mobile data service (as defined in section 6001 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1401">47 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="HBC83179B715E4526827C4F9BF07B53A0" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>unlicensed wireless service; and </text></subclause><subclause id="H026A76EFE8D6453481C872B0FF656E4A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>common carrier wireless exchange access service.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H576A3F3824224700AE82EC3D57BFEE86"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Personal wireless service facility</header><text>The term <term>personal wireless service facility</term> means a facility used to provide or support the provision of personal wireless service.</text></clause><clause id="HFB1EED57D5634F71961E5FC461F2D9D1"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Small personal wireless service facility</header><text>The term <term>small personal wireless service facility</term> means a personal wireless service facility—</text><subclause id="H86F3D680F77546ABBF1A3E5DD6515A67"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that is mounted—</text><item id="HEB022D3BC21B44E28F5276D593D69374"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>on a structure 50 feet or less in height (including any antenna); or</text></item><item id="HD56C9A1FD7B64F38BD891D42BAFE7649"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>on a structure not more than 10 percent taller than other adjacent structures;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HE83CEEEC17254567A3F02376FAF4A30D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that does not extend the structure on which such facility is mounted to a height of more than 50 feet or by more than 10 percent, whichever is greater; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H52CE53F7DB044BF3878DF5A6EF26053B"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which each antenna is not more than 3 cubic feet in volume (excluding a wireline backhaul facility connected to such personal wireless service facility).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H059BC87DFA304D7B8B566E5AC410D47F"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Unlicensed wireless service</header><text>The term <term>unlicensed wireless service</term>—</text><subclause id="HBDA30A221B944A1E904AD4AC90A89129"><enum>(I)</enum><text>means the offering of telecommunications service or information service using a duly authorized device that does not require an individual license; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5821C95E3E0646C3862F3913EAFB653F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not include the provision of direct-to-home satellite services, as defined in section 303(v).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEE50135CEA664EABBF7D1AE23D3DFBD5"><enum>(x)</enum><header>Wireline backhaul facility</header><text>The term <term>wireline backhaul facility</term> means an above-ground or underground wireline facility used to transport communications service or other electronic communications from a small personal wireless service facility or the adjacent network interface device of such facility to a communications network.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H4FAFCD1E1302403380D4C7B4AF56498E"><enum>102.</enum><header>Removal of barriers to entry</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 253 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/253">47 U.S.C. 253</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HDDD063A95B0F40ECA92F954C7D6BEB58" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><section id="HE65E5574E1F9439FBB6F7F5149258B81"><enum>253.</enum><header>Removal of barriers to entry</header><subsection id="HB1609BB889074849AFCFC5505D68030D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No State or local statute or regulation, or other State or local legal requirement, may prohibit or have the effect of prohibiting the ability of any entity to provide, improve, or enhance the provision of any interstate or intrastate telecommunications service.</text></subsection><subsection id="H40E03010D9624EEE8542D353D7296FBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Placement, construction, or modification of telecommunications service facilities</header><paragraph id="H6AD64335787F4C48B15A3DE05C2AE764"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on discrimination</header><text>The regulation of the placement, construction, or modification of a telecommunications service facility by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof may not discriminate—</text><subparagraph id="HE281DE2CCEAE4DA8A8E3EA95880D5CD7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>among telecommunications service facilities—</text><clause id="H5668D54E345B4A0883FFFB9DD027D8E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based on the technology used to provide services; or</text></clause><clause id="HA047B7E895354356A82961FC80E97E00"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based on the services provided; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16E3F13898AB49DD8B76E8DCB2BFFA00"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">against telecommunications service facilities, as compared to the regulation of the placement, construction, or modification of other facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA641844A7E88411B86A073EC02B6373C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeframe to grant or deny requests</header><subparagraph id="H436030223CF5416EB5A2F7F79DDDB893"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local government or instrumentality thereof shall grant or deny a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications service facility not later than—</text><clause id="HC8748DF016DA42BAB8D6413E118322C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the request is for authorization to place, construct, or modify such facility in or on eligible support infrastructure, 90 days after the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality; or</text></clause><clause id="H9E3605678C384843ADA19BCA9C517304"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any other action relating to such facility, 150 days after the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFBB5550C97C456A8FCAB65DA0AB6DCF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The applicable timeframe under subparagraph (A) shall apply collectively to all proceedings, including related permits and authorizations, required by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof for the approval of the request.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B7408C8232548BC98A08D99EA1FC870"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No moratoria</header><text>A timeframe under subparagraph (A) may not be tolled by any moratorium, whether express or de facto, imposed by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof on the submission, acceptance, or consideration of requests for authorization to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications service facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A01C489C31B40B5B813690428D13C6F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Tolling due to incompleteness</header><clause id="HFB359A554C5C4DBFB75B8E3A9D854C85"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial request incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 30 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications service facility, the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the request, the timeframe described in subparagraph (A) is tolled with respect to the request until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="H22EF5137C17545048B540596682A8E3B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supplemental submission incomplete</header><text>If, not later than 10 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a supplemental submission in response to a written notice described in clause (iii), the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the supplemental submission, the timeframe under subparagraph (A) is further tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a subsequent supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="H6FFDC91F85DB49D18EF542B36DE62C84"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written notice described in this clause is, with respect to a request described in subparagraph (A) or a supplemental submission described in clause (i) or (ii) submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof by a requesting party, a written notice from the government or instrumentality to the requesting party—</text><subclause id="H3C2DB5C634764F3F8BD2D346FD59794D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>stating that all of the information (including any form or other document) required by the government or instrumentality to be submitted for the request to be considered complete has not been submitted;</text></subclause><subclause id="H72B9BD186B6F4842B74A8C11E41F21E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identifying the information described in subclause (I) that was not submitted; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H24E7E28382C841A58E91E65B14E463BF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>including a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the government or instrumentality requiring that such information be submitted with such a request.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB7E3104BCBB74171AB6D4157002BB477"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Limitation on subsequent written notice</header><text>If a written notice provided by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to a requesting party under clause (ii) with respect to a supplemental submission identifies as not having been submitted any information that was not identified as not having been submitted in the prior written notice under this subparagraph in response to which the supplemental submission was submitted, the subsequent written notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB33E062F5D3D40E2BE5DD1861CE21EBD"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Tolling by mutual agreement</header><text>The timeframe under subparagraph (A) may be tolled once, for a period of not more than 30 days, by mutual agreement between the State or local government or instrumentality thereof and the requesting party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8427C644AB544BFB5E062505816B975"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deemed granted</header><subparagraph id="H0B7153296ED648AB9C989CD0B3A5513F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a State or local government or instrumentality thereof has neither granted nor denied a request within the applicable timeframe under paragraph (2), the request shall be deemed granted on the date on which the government or instrumentality receives a written notice of the failure to grant or deny from the requesting party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F0421641ECB4E99BF60EAAE9769384C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>In the case of a request that is deemed granted under subparagraph (A), the placement, construction, or modification requested in such request shall be considered to be authorized, without any further action by the government or instrumentality, beginning on the date on which such request is deemed granted under such subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62808CEEB18E4883942CBFE443E3CD1D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Written decision and record</header><text>A decision by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to deny a request to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications service facility shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H67BA9DBB2A7B4B10A19CBC39EA721FEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in writing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23C987B109E546688E4A7B5319B0D81C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE90DFAD4FB94867A1042DDC1E336881"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicly released, and provided to the requesting party, on the same day such decision is made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H929C24B5D58048918F17FCEFBF37F04B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fees</header><subparagraph id="HD4FB35CE930F43C59525A2A28CF93A2A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To the extent permitted by law, a State or local government or instrumentality thereof may charge a fee that meets the requirements under subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="H97FB75899C8D4C8383426856460282DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to consider a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications service facility; or</text></clause><clause id="H9A54FEA6E3BA41CAABF75AEBC8B74E8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for use of a right-of-way or a facility in a right-of-way owned or managed by the government or instrumentality for the placement, construction, or modification of a telecommunications service facility.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09A4534EFC2841768F82BFBD7D8BC15F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A fee charged under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text><clause id="HB0465330EE1842238EB63C147856C891"><enum>(i)</enum><text>competitively neutral, technology neutral, and nondiscriminatory;</text></clause><clause id="H91E87D592C824B25B31443C28CC18291"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>established in advance and publicly disclosed;</text></clause><clause id="H2DB02774EE43443EAD8D7D20F27B7C04"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>calculated—</text><subclause id="H0A34537879134EB58E53679F2F7CC3FC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>based on actual and direct costs for—</text><item id="H62A4ACBCD3FD4EEEAC14FA6BE8DD6C93"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>review and processing of requests; and</text></item><item id="HA78647C7DAFA4F0CAB1C6D3DEEF8249C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>repairs and replacement of—</text><subitem id="H464D2637C5944466A811F8931786CCC6"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>components and materials directly resulting from and affected by the placement, construction, or modification (including the installation or improvement) of telecommunications service facilities; or</text></subitem><subitem id="H4A04892F2ECE4C6FB0DD9B3500233635"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">equipment that facilitates the placement, construction, or modification (including the installation or improvement) of such facilities; and</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="HAD27CA63BC6A4937929F6C26A0EE9412"><enum>(II)</enum><text>using, for purposes of subclause (I), only costs that are objectively reasonable; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA025D6285A3E43D5B1E4C9BB5364C4B1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>described to a requesting party in a manner that distinguishes between—</text><subclause id="H46FF324EB0EE427384494AB42B941F39"><enum>(I)</enum><text>nonrecurring fees and recurring fees; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2AE3B0E7481D460E8A5489E4A9E7DDA1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of facilities on which telecommunications service facilities or infrastructure for compatible uses are already located and facilities on which there are no telecommunications service facilities or infrastructure for compatible uses as of the date on which the request is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82C582AFA3CD47A8A6458AB9A1938C21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><paragraph id="H02DF70D35A2F464EA51B081BCC94FC08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person adversely affected by a State or local statute, regulation, or other legal requirement, or by a final action or failure to act by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof, that is inconsistent with this section may commence an action in any court of competent jurisdiction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42D83375C3BA40F3B21ADED03C5AA02D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph id="HFFB8C061765444008C7069E303D1CCB2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Expedited basis</header><text>A court shall hear and decide an action commenced under paragraph (1) on an expedited basis.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51337605EF064D7F94C49CAC7BD89949"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final action or failure to act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action may only be commenced under paragraph (1) on the basis of a final action or failure to act by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof, if commenced not later than 30 days after such action or failure to act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E34B4C79A144254A105896BB036A366"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Preservation of State regulatory authority</header><text>Nothing in this section shall affect the ability of a State to impose, on a competitively neutral and nondiscriminatory basis and consistent with section 254, requirements necessary to preserve and advance universal service, protect the public safety and welfare, ensure the continued quality of telecommunications services, and safeguard the rights of consumers.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC0D1C4DD777849988F82B486620DEF45"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Preservation of State and local government authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as explicitly set forth in this section, nothing in this section affects the authority of a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to manage, on a competitively neutral and nondiscriminatory basis, the public rights-of-way or to require, on a competitively neutral and nondiscriminatory basis, fair and reasonable compensation from telecommunications providers for use of public rights-of-way, if the compensation required meets the requirements of subsection (b)(5).</text></subsection><subsection id="H900C24497CE242E69DE9DF562EC18040"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Preemption</header><paragraph id="H6D70BBE9E1864B6886E11B89312318F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, after notice and an opportunity for public comment, the Commission determines that a State or local government or instrumentality thereof has permitted or imposed a statute, regulation, or legal requirement that violates or is inconsistent with this section, the Commission shall preempt the enforcement of such statute, regulation, or legal requirement to the extent necessary to correct such violation or inconsistency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB08FC16B0F73443D818FDBEC7A569FAA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after receiving a petition for preemption of the enforcement of a statute, regulation, or legal requirement as described in paragraph (1), the Commission shall grant or deny the petition.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6082B793F91441D28BA21ACA8B960CCD"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Commercial mobile service providers; cable operators</header><text>Nothing in this section shall affect the application of section 332(c)(3) to commercial mobile service providers or section 621 to cable operators.</text></subsection><subsection id="H08B27B5EA2C7444A88B2AE4E651CC360"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rural markets</header><text>It shall not be a violation of this section for a State to require a telecommunications carrier that seeks to provide telephone exchange service or exchange access in a service area served by a rural telephone company to meet the requirements in section 214(e)(1) for designation as an eligible telecommunications carrier for that area before being permitted to provide such service. This subsection shall not apply—</text><paragraph id="HFD1266340711401E8289B3EEA02ADDAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to a service area served by a rural telephone company that has obtained an exemption, suspension, or modification of section 251(c)(4) that effectively prevents a competitor from meeting the requirements of section 214(e)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBACEB72B5E0849999FEC4AD0267CA39D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to a provider of commercial mobile services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA1DBEAE5689C4408B7CC387ADD4ECE19" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>When request considered submitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, a request to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof shall be considered submitted on the date on which the requesting party takes the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party—</text><paragraph id="H78D2817B332C48C7A830BDC1E304F042"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit such request in accordance with the procedures established by the government or instrumentality for the review and approval of such a request; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1F121916524485AEE187E82D10EEE0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a government or instrumentality that has not established specific procedures for the review and approval of such a request, to submit to the government or instrumentality the type of filing that is typically required to initiate a standard review for a similar facility or structure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FE7F730F08B4C148FEF7BDC8F083303"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Effect of regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any regulation promulgated by the Commission to implement this section (including any interpretation of the requirements of and terms used in this section contained in any such regulation) shall be binding on a court in any action under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B024C852A764045A95F48E8A2C33C74"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H23AE92108E4A4E3FA238A74B85899666"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible support infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>eligible support infrastructure</term> means infrastructure that supports or houses a telecommunications service facility (or that is designed for or capable of supporting or housing such a facility) at the time when a request to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof for authorization to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications service facility in or on the infrastructure is submitted by the requesting party to the government or instrumentality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5010016BBBB841A5964AF179B733FCD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Telecommunications service facility</header><text>The term <term>telecommunications service facility</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H8D882A739DF64EFCBC7279CC8E56092D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a facility that is designed or used to provide or facilitate the provision of any interstate or intrastate telecommunications service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C9465247F1C4766AC362CC70698160D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a facility described in subparagraph (A) that is used to provide other services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H2FF704491D5A4B97B3EB54DB95B01708" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>103.</enum><header>Requests for modification of certain existing wireless and wireline communications facilities</header><subsection id="H0F50293DAE28434ABE7590C3984B2796"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6409 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD66E5EE9624348E9871BAF945461A0C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Wireless</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Communications</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66EF3FD182B24311A8449838862AA2DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H9526A874DFE740F78EDDC1207D968E8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>a State or local government</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H739FA6B9EB864289933CDE22FC3C531A" display-inline="yes-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><text>a State or local government or instrumentality thereof may not deny, and shall approve—</text><paragraph id="H7473578CEAF7492CB382C8D6BC3B5FBA" indent="down1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any eligible facilities request for a modification of an existing wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H483AA2D03B554F8F898FAAA404F146B7" indent="down1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any eligible wireline communications facilities request for a modification of an existing wireline communications facility that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such facility. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8D503425B1F465E958759621D0D3B4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF27AC8BA70F94A53BA5FE6F16071B94C" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><paragraph id="H0465072E12E8470FA1220301F71AD5DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><subparagraph id="H4EAC627E393E4F258B67D8E8183BBC06"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deemed approval</header><clause id="HA69A0E50A7204F329194540BDC524395"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a State or local government or instrumentality thereof does not, before or on the date that is 60 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a request as an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request (as the case may be), approve the request or make the determination and provide the written notice described in subparagraph (B) with respect to the request, the request is deemed approved on the day after the date that is 60 days after the date on which the requesting party submits the request.</text></clause><clause id="H1FA780D13A8E43EE8130E5AE9B1CC941"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a request that is deemed approved under clause (i), the modification requested in the request shall be authorized, without any further action by the government or instrumentality, beginning on the date on which the request is deemed approved under such clause.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1671FB5986BA44AEAE84D1DB1A53EAD5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination request is not an eligible request</header><clause id="HBFA49C3B68344221B9FFABA68C24BF8C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Determination described</header><text>The determination described in this subparagraph is a determination by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof that a request described in subparagraph (A)(i) is not an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request (as the case may be).</text></clause><clause id="HFE81CFE00BDF4FDB854D32152D84F1D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written notice described in this subparagraph is a written notice of the determination described in clause (i) provided by the government or instrumentality to the requesting party that clearly describes the reasons why the request is not an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request (as the case may be) and includes a citation to a specific provision of this subsection or the regulations promulgated under this subsection relied upon for the determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H187AC0271AD2438FB30ACA6E9420C19B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Tolling due to incompleteness</header><clause id="H60B18B994F584F2F8F677F56D619BF98"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial request incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 30 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a request described in subparagraph (A)(i), the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the request, the 60-day timeframe under subparagraph (A)(i) is tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="H165698BF3DDB4E9783751C807A790806"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supplemental submission incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 10 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof a supplemental submission in response to a written notice described in clause (iii), the government or instrumentality provides to the requesting party a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the supplemental submission, the 60-day timeframe under subparagraph (A)(i) is further tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the government or instrumentality a subsequent supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="HF449FD0CF1EE4CB7AF18103E1F31B652"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written notice described in this clause is, with respect to a request described in subparagraph (A)(i) or a supplemental submission described in clause (i) or (ii) submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof by a requesting party, a written notice from the government or instrumentality to the requesting party—</text><subclause id="H1D9DC1D7B1754CFFB124E491DE552F54"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">stating that all of the information (including any form or other document) required by the government or instrumentality to be submitted for the request to be considered complete has not been submitted;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7B926B9F6EBE48629D531438FCDC88B1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identifying the information described in subclause (I) that was not submitted; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA7192D405C33466DB5EFAC5397AB1344"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">including a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the government or instrumentality requiring that such information be submitted with such a request.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAF6A871AC6EF4D27A7B01D6C1BAB5C75" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Limitation</header><subclause id="H44E391872F8C466C9F4E16D9C9114BD7" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Initial written notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a written notice provided by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to a requesting party under clause (i) with respect to a request described in subparagraph (A)(i) identifies as not having been submitted any information that the government or instrumentality is prohibited by paragraph (5) from requiring to be submitted, such notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></subclause><subclause id="H96C5285C12C94C998D5DC5545CC93BBE" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Subsequent written notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a written notice provided by a State or local government or instrumentality thereof to a requesting party under clause (ii) with respect to a supplemental submission identifies as not having been submitted any information that was not identified as not having been submitted in the prior written notice under this subparagraph in response to which the supplemental submission was submitted, the subsequent written notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C04D82442D942FBA1E18902BDC603C4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Tolling by mutual agreement</header><text>The 60-day timeframe under subparagraph (A)(i) may be tolled once, for a period of not more than 30 days, by mutual agreement between the State or local government or instrumentality thereof and the requesting party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13852C88EEEB4FDDA9C791B09E4DB4BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block id="H101DB2835A0941319B2D25A6880A5236" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><paragraph id="H0856C6AF805F4A04AF93842EEF01D08C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>When request considered submitted</header><subparagraph id="HD4C8C1824BA74CA4872E531471B76F4E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, a request described in paragraph (2)(A)(i) shall be considered submitted on the date on which the requesting party takes the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party—</text><clause id="H0541B02F07A84E43BE62ABA3EBBE024E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit such request in accordance with the procedures established by the government or instrumentality for the review and approval of such a request; or</text></clause><clause id="H1003529A7455471BA3634D3153C227D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a government or instrumentality that has not established specific procedures for the review and approval of such a request, to submit to the government or instrumentality the type of filing that is typically required to initiate a standard review for a similar facility or structure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5DBAAD1153C47EAA005347A6D602A55" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No pre-application requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local government or instrumentality thereof may not require a requesting party to undertake any process, meeting, or other step prior to or as a prerequisite to a request being considered submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A4CAB74A29E4317A0ECD309BBF72560"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Limitation on required documentation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or local government or instrumentality thereof may require a requesting party submitting a request as an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request to submit information (including a form or other document) with such request only to the extent that such information is reasonably related to determining whether such request is an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request (as the case may be) and is identified in a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the government or instrumentality requiring that such information be submitted with such a request. A State or local government or instrumentality thereof may not require a requesting party to submit any other documentation or information with such a request.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23C9DAE4E5AD4CBDA3B2D370E6F936A8" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph id="H67F02EB55CC64009AF0125D5ABBA9CD4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requesting party may bring an action in any district court of the United States to enforce the provisions of this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1E840467DC74E6FBB1478C1F8100135" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expedited review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A district court of the United States shall consider an action under subparagraph (A) on an expedited basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30D5C05B00D649A39E27A83978D9D31F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Effect of regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any regulation promulgated by the Commission to implement this subsection (including any interpretation of the requirements of and terms used in this subsection contained in any such regulation) shall be binding on a court in any action under paragraph (6).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBA3337F680E401FA8EB7AE3B52339E9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection: </text><subparagraph id="HE8785EAB44B64FA3A7872A391A082B34"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible facilities request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible facilities request</term> means any request for a modification of an existing wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure and that involves—</text><clause id="HBC3D430C89FA4C4BB684255921253DAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collocation of new transmission equipment;</text></clause><clause id="H5E4ECBFE671A4EC8A063A5C96855A997"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>removal of transmission equipment;</text></clause><clause id="H4955BA8396A3416EAC482A1431138373"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>replacement of transmission equipment; or</text></clause><clause id="H93983BAC69AB4BBEB88D8748FD128C5A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>placement, construction, or modification of equipment that—</text><subclause id="HBED3F56B8378400AB20452F677C2B1CE"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improves the resiliency of the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCDEF7BE277E74219A8087E5DFFAFCDAB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides a direct benefit to public safety, such as—</text><item id="H97503FF100AB4CDCB55D8A7D24542B0F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing backup power for the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure;</text></item><item id="H060A76713CD5448B871B28A06928B058"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hardening the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure; or</text></item><item id="H547FE5453F384132819C2CAA1C68DD2F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing more reliable connection capability using the wireless tower, base station, or eligible support structure.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB7579F12C534834BBF0F9A71FCA29E6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible support structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible support structure</term> means a structure that, at the time when an eligible facilities request for a modification of such structure is submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof, supports or could support transmission equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63485CEA17BC40DA9BD744E156DAA8F1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible wireline communications facilities request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible wireline communications facilities request</term> means any request for a modification of an existing wireline communications facility that does not substantially change the physical dimensions of such facility and that involves—</text><clause id="H08B45910BB1943A0B8D03D3D1B0AF06E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collocation of new wireline communications facility equipment;</text></clause><clause id="H8216688027B546C18CD00D22067BF260"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>removal of wireline communications facility equipment; or</text></clause><clause id="H39832D5A7B8C4CE18C07F9A65B44C4E5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>replacement of wireline communications facility equipment. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H205422C8560A4DAEBED2D8ADB5E2EE2F"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Transmission equipment</header><text>The term <term>transmission equipment</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1.6100(b)(8) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29D13CC0ED2247089D2A35D3090DB240" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Wireline communications facility</header><text>The term <quote>wireline communications facility</quote> means a communications facility installation, to the extent such installation is associated with wireline transmissions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFDDA2CFBA8CB4B8B9EBB444A31DA63A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall issue final rules to implement the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8A906CBA2AE841ED99799D86B6EC0166" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any eligible facilities request or eligible wireline communications facilities request described in paragraph (1) of section 6409(a) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(a)</external-xref>) that is submitted (as determined under paragraph (4) of such section, as added by subsection (a)) by a requesting party on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HF67EBF79E556477887736902A12ADBBC"><enum>II</enum><header>Cable</header><section id="H193CE6A157A94D029CABF6A3C9C8EB5D"><enum>201.</enum><header>Request for new franchise</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 621 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/541">47 U.S.C. 541</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H646AA17B274046A2875CB7FABF73B88C" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><subsection id="HEE1795BA03A04D6A9E53BCB3F0C8D59C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Timing of decision on request for franchise</header><paragraph id="H48756407AEF847C1859A98C411B7EAE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a franchising authority a request for the grant of a franchise, the franchising authority shall approve or deny such request.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E99940D257342F6BCCE7E30F90DDD72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deemed grant of new franchise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the franchising authority does not approve or deny a request under paragraph (1) by the day after the date on which the time period ends under such paragraph, such request shall be deemed granted on such day.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2ED921089D640709DC98FDADBE3CE36" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of this title, the timeframe under paragraph (1) shall apply collectively to all proceedings required by a franchising authority for the approval of the request. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7516821C05F347E585471D89A1075A37" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No moratoria</header><text>A timeframe under paragraph (1) may not be tolled by any moratorium, whether express or de facto, imposed by a franchising authority on the consideration of any request for a franchise.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE82EF195E9C41A6B034D1AC575AEF70" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tolling due to incompleteness</header><subparagraph id="HD9DE272AAA764438949B1B4730538058" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial request incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 30 days after the date on which a franchising authority provides to a requesting party a written notice described in subparagraph (C) with respect to a request described in paragraph (1), the timeframe described in such paragraph is tolled with respect to the request until the date on which the requesting party submits to the franchising authority a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E69E3B9AAF34CA19594DADC01C609E4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supplemental submission incomplete</header><text>If, not later than 10 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to the franchising authority a supplemental submission in response to a written notice described in subparagraph (A), the franchising authority provides to the requesting party a written notice described in subparagraph (A) with respect to the supplemental submission, the timeframe under paragraph (1) is further tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the franchising authority a subsequent supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE6D05D0D786426F98B2C34F8F263CEF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written notice described in this subparagraph is, with respect to a request described in paragraph (1) or a supplemental submission described in subparagraph (A) or (B) submitted to a franchising authority by a requesting party, a written notice from the franchising authority to the requesting party—</text><clause id="HB92F27E2B2454D079A660A1A5D5104C4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stating that all of the information (including any form or other document) required by the franchising authority to be submitted for the request to be considered complete has not been submitted;</text></clause><clause id="HBE9E75F18D824722B9097D58C3AA9439" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifying the information described in clause (i) that was not submitted;</text></clause><clause id="H0A0B609DF6884E1D97951E8C9C971114"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>demonstrating that such information is reasonable and directly related to determining the qualifications of the requesting party to operate the cable system; and</text></clause><clause id="HB0941512B42D47D0B896D455C2286DD9" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>including a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the franchising authority requiring that such information be submitted with such a request.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3BCDB9083584C6A8154C5E0317C9233" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on subsequent written notice</header><text>If a written notice provided by a franchising authority to a requesting party under subparagraph (A) with respect to a supplemental submission identifies as not having been submitted any information that was not identified as not having been submitted in the prior written notice under this subparagraph in response to which the supplemental submission was submitted, the subsequent written notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26950183B9E5462181CFE693AC4CA2AC" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tolling by mutual agreement</header><text>The timeframe under paragraph (1) may be tolled once, for a period of not more than 30 days, by mutual agreement between the franchising authority and the requesting party.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5282B247F1D048A984A687D206537D12" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Written decision and record</header><text>Any decision by a franchising authority to deny a request for a franchise shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H0AFC187354BD4FBFBC9953B91D3748D8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in writing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2419FFB8DB914AB8A7C10D98296BA5B4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59AD83E77B5344ED86554790817C27A0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicly released, and provided to the requesting party, on the same day such decision is made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H967BD3A3E2B64340982F6432616ED791" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>When request considered submitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subsection, a request to a franchising authority shall be considered submitted on the date on which the requesting party takes the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party—</text><subparagraph id="H0C4BC3C7383C461CA149320D6BDFD6F9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit such request in accordance with the procedures established by the franchising authority for the review and approval of such a request; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FDCF6FD710D47558C92E6104D9146CC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a franchising authority that has not established specific procedures for the review and approval of such a request, to submit to the franchising authority the type of filing that is typically required of a cable operator to initiate a standard review for a request related to a franchise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H9BAB08D7A4124A2181AA654076484241"><enum>202.</enum><header>Request regarding placement, construction, or modification of cable equipment</header><subsection id="H6BD9497A5C604190810D6F8F0566256F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 624 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/544">47 U.S.C. 544</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFDFD3DFD5A074308A6FD5DE4B750D6FF" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><subsection id="H54555D86138740A3860E7CAD98827BA7"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Request regarding placement, construction, or modification of facilities</header><paragraph id="H53F6F2D1D46041368252BFCFE75AE6C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No effect on authority of certain entities</header><text>Except as provided in this subsection, nothing in this title shall limit or affect the authority of a covered entity over—</text><subparagraph id="HD96A5B8CE20A4A8E8CD5BAC5645B0668"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">decisions regarding the placement, construction, or modification of covered equipment within the jurisdiction of such covered entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9119D61D0234A2D843ED4AA38B486B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>safety standards for the placement, construction, or modification of such covered equipment. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0AF31B922F42F58346E69B5FCE29F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="H152FBD6ADB6743D48CC4D03F60FB0220" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ability to provide or enhance service</header><text>With respect to the regulation by a covered entity for the placement, construction, or modification of covered equipment, the covered entity shall not prohibit or have the effect of prohibiting the ability of a cable operator to provide, improve, or enhance the provision of service using covered equipment under a franchise granted by such covered entity, or within the jurisdiction of such covered entity, as so may be the case.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C8FB1E8676E4A01978519EC5CEC8175" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No imposition of certain conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity shall not, in connection with a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment made after the date of the enactment of this subsection, impose on the requesting party—</text><clause id="H4463429375DD425E9FE930817BC7609A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any requirement that the requesting party, as a condition of obtaining such authorization, install, or pay for the installation of, any conduit or fiber for use by the covered entity or any person other than the requesting party;</text></clause><clause id="H5176E1C5BDE74F2284EFCAB468043AF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any requirement that the requesting party prepare or pay for the preparation of any environmental, engineering, network design, mapping, or other survey or study unrelated to the request; or</text></clause><clause id="H18272C9014494A9A8B12C109E97A869D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other condition for obtaining such authorization, unless such condition is specific to the precise geographic location at which the covered equipment is being placed, constructed, or modified.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E14C7EF91242DCAC591E88DCD2B40E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Timing of decisions on requests for authorizations to place, construct, or modify facility</header><clause id="H4B0E09375AD44647B7FF603DC1E29679" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Timeframe</header><text>A covered entity shall approve or deny a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment not later than—</text><subclause id="HEF829CC57DF5477B819DB7196A74949D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the request is for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment in or on a covered easement or eligible support infrastructure, 90 days after the date on which requesting party submits the request to the covered entity; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1A1078116AC24B43B37DF7C94D9FFBA5" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the request is not for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment in or on a covered easement or eligible support infrastructure, 150 days after the date on which the requesting party submits the request to the covered entity.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HED75C9B992D44E759A94C6C734BA395C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Deemed granted</header><text>If a covered entity fails to grant or deny a request by the applicable timeframe under clause (i), the request shall be deemed granted and authorized on the date on which the covered entity receives written notice of the failure from the requesting party. </text></clause><clause id="H3D1B1E3B444E4127B3731B7475B0BB27"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of this title, the applicable timeframe under clause (i) shall apply collectively to all proceedings, including related permits and authorizations, required by a covered entity for the approval of the request.</text></clause><clause id="H1B30A1D5913744CD8DE993AD4B250024" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>No moratoria</header><text>A timeframe under clause (i) may not be tolled by any moratorium, whether express or de facto, imposed by a covered entity on the consideration of any request for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment.</text></clause><clause id="HBD325F3B5F8B4EC2B1877A80A58A3424" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Tolling due to incompleteness</header><subclause id="HD43196317D774FCBA96654CA86FF3050" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Initial request incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 30 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to a covered entity a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment, the covered entity provides to the requesting party a written notice described in subclause (III) with respect to the request, the timeframe described in clause (i) is tolled with respect to the request until the date on which the requesting party submits to the covered entity a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E1B2EC55BB5477DBE48E332A4E60BEA" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Supplemental submission incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 10 days after the date on which a requesting party submits to the covered entity a supplemental submission in response to a written notice described in subclause (III), the covered entity provides to the requesting party a written notice described in subclause (III) with respect to the supplemental submission, the timeframe under clause (i) is further tolled until the date on which the requesting party submits to the covered entity a subsequent supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></subclause><subclause id="H642D250468AC41E48F62CA82C09AFC7F" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The written notice described in this subclause is, with respect to a request described in clause (i) or a supplemental submission described in subclause (I) or (II) submitted to a covered entity by a requesting party, a written notice from the requesting party to the covered entity—</text><item id="H17A890854D3746FB8990CE86F9E07468" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>stating that all of the information (including any form or other document) required by the covered entity to be submitted for the request to be considered complete has not been submitted;</text></item><item id="H1DFFCF1CA0A64D359B45F6C31772FDBC" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>identifying the information described in item (aa) that was not submitted; and</text></item><item id="HEA8ED3CE4CF34520A8ADF8DA5FBD2571" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>including a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the covered entity requiring that such information be submitted with such a request.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H18C21A06F07B49898CCC9E791A07A972" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Limitation on subsequent written notice</header><text>If a written notice provided by covered entity to a requesting party under subclause (I) with respect to a supplemental submission identifies as not having been submitted any information that was not identified as not having been submitted in the prior written notice under this subparagraph in response to which the supplemental submission was submitted, the subsequent written notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the requesting party.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H24D717C8426844FE879A28CDDFD59328" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Tolling by mutual agreement</header><text>The timeframe under clause (i) may be tolled once, for a period of not more than 30 days, by mutual agreement between the covered entity and the requesting party.</text></clause><clause id="HA9E8BF443DAD47B99C45FBB93225DB15"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Written decision and record</header><text>Any decision by a covered entity to deny a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment shall be—</text><subclause id="HC349A3F38E6E428588F719A327A4AA3A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in writing;</text></subclause><subclause id="H46797A6093F54F4ABD9E5B169B214A90"><enum>(II)</enum><text>supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2BEDE5505D424750AEAA13D417D21E1E"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicly released, and provided to the requesting party, on the same day such decision is made.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6CED0DDE469C4D458BDFEA34550B4FCD" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>When request considered submitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subparagraph, a request to a covered entity shall be considered submitted on the date on which the requesting party takes the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party—</text><subclause id="H6AAE37266435420F90B341A193718B6D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit such request in accordance with the procedures established by the covered entity for the review and approval of such a request; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H20B4237C4E3B4FBBB4FFC701C9F91EF4" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a covered entity that has not established specific procedures for the review and approval of such a request, to submit to the covered entity the type of filing that is typically required of a cable operator to initiate a standard review for a similar request in a jurisdiction that has not established specific procedures for the relevant review and approval of such a request.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H588EB49BFD994D1E98CED95CCD6E23DF" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Emergency work</header><subclause id="H76AB163D4FD64A388D981EF5BC225A91"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A covered entity shall not require a cable operator to request or obtain authorization for the placement, construction, or modification of covered equipment in or on a covered easement before such cable operator performs, with respect to such equipment, work to repair a system damaged due to forces outside the control of such cable operator.</text></subclause><subclause id="H0CF21E33DE2E4006A9BC8B9CCE5AD61D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>A cable operator shall promptly notify the affected covered entity of any such work before performing any such work.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7CB91E6B1434E0EA032A80B8AFFD352" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fees</header><subparagraph id="H4A64248AA2CE4EC18E9EF9F9E8F25FDD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered entity may charge a fee that meets the requirements under subparagraph (B) to consider a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE03529AD51994D5A8207A7D4E58A3C63" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A fee charged under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text><clause id="H00D3E08F0BDA42E9B21260A4F1D20D7E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>competitively neutral, technology neutral, and nondiscriminatory;</text></clause><clause id="H3DEBC330A7C24262937B1E5F861157B2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>established and publicly disclosed in advance; and</text></clause><clause id="HBCA701D97E174DCDA10BFE7A99437930" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>calculated—</text><subclause id="H445610A4A3C84D209221D14A5C0B61A7" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>based on actual and direct costs for—</text><item id="H9C2F6C65DF1A4AD5B125F2A61A2DE18D" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>review and processing of requests; and</text></item><item id="HE7E13159C5194E44965200CAE0FE93D9" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>repairs and replacement of—</text><subitem id="H6CE2EB34C7044BA480C70DDA03F08909"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">components and materials directly resulting from and affected by the placement, construction, or modification of the covered equipment (including components and materials directly resulting from and affected by the installation of covered equipment or, with respect to the placement, construction, or modification of the covered equipment, the improvement of an eligible support infrastructure); or</text></subitem><subitem id="HE3CA5AA6824D42EC99F85D28018D960C"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>equipment that facilitates the repair and replacement of such components and materials;</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="HBFB5F0C6D81041AB8E066FE0A7DA6062" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>using, for purposes of subclause (I), only costs that are objectively reasonable; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF0FF4904829E4F6DA0CFBA73F466FE6F" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>described to a requesting party in a manner that distinguishes between nonrecurring fees and recurring fees.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6054D46B02BC4BC983F945CCA61F3319"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No relation to franchise fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fee charged under this paragraph to consider a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment may not be considered a franchise fee under section 622. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBC463BF9B8C4BE98C178BA78E50150F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HC07D8837B0CE49B492A360FC06B466DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered easement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered easement</term> means an easement or public right-of-way that exists at the time when a request to a covered entity for authorization to place, construct, or modify the covered equipment in or on the easement or public right-of-way is submitted to the covered entity. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6024042FA914F78A18A1EFCF2ABA9F9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered equipment</term> means equipment or materials (including any cable, fiber, conduit, or electronics) used in or attached to a cable system to provide any service through such system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30C43B1D1E624352930BFECFAF015BB1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means:</text><clause id="HBFC51AF4B39E40478BB90849DA6E11D3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A State.</text></clause><clause id="H537207F9F6F44356B5E0C7836DB180E0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A local government.</text></clause><clause id="H4E8A99E7CFB04C208010E3D434DA6E41" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An instrumentality of a State or a local government.</text></clause><clause id="H91BEC98A680E4A29BCCF56D94678D874" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A franchising authority. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H417C7827FE8542D38A8F621E21C41982"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Eligible support infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>eligible support infrastructure</term> means infrastructure that—</text><clause id="HC42EAA4EB871439B97E24CF9980438F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located within a public right-of-way or easement that—</text><subclause id="HA97304C3C11245648313AF03A9FEE0BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is within the area served by the cable system; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H18D7CC021CAE45258B47782FD249ABD5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has been dedicated for compatible uses; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H42B5286FB9354EAD9628A699853AAA5E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supports or houses a facility for communication by wire (or that is designed for or capable of supporting or housing such a facility) at the time when a request to a covered entity for authorization to place, construct, or modify covered equipment in or on the infrastructure is submitted to the covered entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H75AC1927CADC49A9B2BA502F2A2618AD" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Action on pending requests</header><paragraph id="HD1C767389A9B4056B1844B46E9B60534" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (2)(B) and (4) of section 624(j) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/544">47 U.S.C. 544(j)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), shall apply to a—</text><subparagraph id="HAF0774205FBC49AAB8B6ED6FE46C478B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>request submitted to a covered entity (as such term is defined in section 624(j) of the Communications Act of 1934)—</text><clause id="H8467D0833C0E450CAA0EC42D5E66AF64" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H80F0AA89996D4CCBBF28BED61395ACC1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not been approved or denied by the covered entity on or before such date; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9907FED3D8D4039AE17263F8B69BF31" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a request submitted to a covered entity on or after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06736DC9F80645108067588AFA5D964A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Date of receipt</header><text>The date of receipt by a covered entity of a request described under subsection (a)(1) shall be deemed to be the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H35600E52C1B4490987537C64C8C886EB"><enum>203.</enum><header>Cable franchise term and termination</header><subsection id="H1809EF2730E7480687B181B6324B2B1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Elimination or modification of requirement in franchise</header><text>Section 625 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/545">47 U.S.C. 545</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7E8A558ECDFB46F19A6374C8658B5451" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><section id="HC0A11209D33C4E658831DB557EFBC967"><enum>625.</enum><header>Elimination or modification of requirement in franchise</header><subsection id="H8873D972AC6B4FDBB0F76D913C1F93A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period in which a franchise is in effect, the cable operator may obtain the elimination or modification of any requirement in the franchise by submitting to the franchising authority a request for the elimination or modification of such requirement. </text></subsection><subsection id="H02E09CB866F14EDF90E9187AB5F93131"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elimination or modification of requirement in franchise</header><text>The franchising authority shall eliminate or modify a requirement in accordance with a request submitted under subsection (a) not later than 120 days after the cable operator submits the request to the franchising authority if the cable operator demonstrates in the request good cause for the elimination or modification of the requirement, including the need to eliminate or modify the requirement—</text><paragraph id="H9EDE6A7E88B04373840408992387DD23"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to conform to an applicable Federal or State law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H510A2F9C970F4C50820ECB935B9B62FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address changes in technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49245EAB87324163944026F257D77A1E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to address competitive disparities; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H350F98C5878B4CC4840BFCB4F378BCBD" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the case of a requirement applicable to the cable operator, due to commercial impracticability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF76361C6F8AA4F8D826BE4FF0724FD36" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deemed elimination or modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except in the case of a request for the elimination or modification of a requirement for services relating to public, educational, or governmental access, if the franchising authority fails to approve or deny the request submitted under subsection (a) by the date described under subsection (b), the requirement shall be deemed eliminated or modified in accordance with the request on the day after such date.</text></subsection><subsection id="H666661A7DFAC48388959F25BB59FC99E" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appeal</header><paragraph id="H4D70125CB0464BDF910EB6E9C982F29C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any cable operator whose request for elimination or modification of a requirement in a franchise under subsection (a) has been denied by a final decision of a franchising authority may seek judicial review of the decision pursuant to the provisions of section 635.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38E6A935C28743E99FF7C8563F112FD2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant of request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any proposed elimination or modification of a requirement in a franchise under subsection (a), the court shall grant such elimination or modification only if the cable operator demonstrates to the court that the standards in subsection (b) have been met.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H618434A9A8A04ECEAF3976240516CE16"><enum>(e)</enum><header>When request considered submitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, a request to a franchising authority shall be considered submitted on the date on which the requesting party takes the first procedural step within the control of the requesting party—</text><paragraph id="HDD46274FB0684A32AE01941B901E916E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to submit such request in accordance with the procedures established by the franchising authority for the review and approval of such a request; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE3033ED08954A30A8C9C4634C244AFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a franchising authority that has not established specific procedures for the review and approval of such a request, to submit to the franchising authority the type of filing that is typically required to initiate a standard review for a request related to a franchise. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2A05993F2FC849DCA3E3751FA9222A25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 626 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/546">47 U.S.C. 546</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0B30B3D166774471ADE787C7C417A2B4" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><section id="H32963CF3AF6A4A93BBDC73EE06F7A63B"><enum>626.</enum><header>Franchise term and termination</header><subsection id="HB690AE4557994B6D85C12E422F7A3A16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Franchise term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A franchise shall continue in effect (without any requirement for renewal) until the date on which the franchise is revoked or terminated in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDBD1E77867ED45A59A70EB303BF8187D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limits</header><paragraph id="H1DF0B7A8D2744E6F9B6413E6F79E7977"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition against revocation; termination</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a franchise may not be—</text><subparagraph id="H6C401846F25142A1875764BB97DAD844" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>revoked by a franchising authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDDADFED4861493198F2B193273B5EAA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>terminated by a cable operator; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EBB9DA8B95A454B9585718B8441230E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>revoked or terminated by operation of law, including by a term in a franchise that revokes or terminates such franchise on a specific date, after a period of time, or upon the occurrence of an event.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D1F671F2FE8487089D2CA2E778B473A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>When termination or revocation of franchise permitted</header><subparagraph id="H20A967EFA99742F3BF56DAF362E63254"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Termination by cable operator</header><clause id="HFB144189AF1D441E9997E4C08C4C79C9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A cable operator may terminate a franchise by submitting to the franchising authority a written request to terminate such franchise.</text></clause><clause id="HBAA5FBEBF6CA4404A93CD820A45BFA37"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Time of termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the cable operator submits a written request under clause (i), the franchising authority shall revoke the franchise on the date that is 90 days after the request is submitted to the franchising authority.</text></clause><clause id="HB73CB504DA80420BB4E60531F8EF8230"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Deemed to be revoked</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a franchising authority does not approve a request by the date required under clause (ii), the franchise is deemed revoked on the day after such date.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD25B5A880B146FF966DE15C6145D156"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination by franchising authority</header><text>A franchising authority may revoke a franchise for cause if the franchising authority—</text><clause id="HEF0D51828EC248DD9173AD85EA83D43D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>finds that the cable operator has knowingly and willfully failed to substantially meet a material requirement imposed by the franchise;</text></clause><clause id="H9C608F2FBF96470EB3AA785B0DA75467"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides the cable operator a reasonable opportunity to cure such failure, after which the cable operator fails to cure such failure; and</text></clause><clause id="H6B4DEF7ADEC145C3A767CAB3F788806A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not waive the material requirement or acquiesce with the failure to substantially meet such requirement.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H553ED9DE03514AF5965C2107E20860BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of revocation of franchise by franchising authority</header><paragraph id="HD19B0D402A874F969CE38BCD13AA0DF3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrative or judicial review</header><text>With respect to a determination by a franchising authority to revoke a franchise for cause under subsection (b)(2)(B), a cable operator may—</text><subparagraph id="HB656B85BC0984049B2CD64827F4667B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>petition the Commission for review of such determination; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99F8A493E5874CFCB8C91C3A7DD00946"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek judicial review of such determination pursuant to the provisions of section 635.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H163D4CDCAA3E4F3795862B6D516066E5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission review</header><text>With respect to a petition for the review of a determination brought under paragraph (1)(A), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7BC713CF7D0743F18EBF020859FD483E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the determination de novo; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47868C45AF9342C79BADE50B889B593B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">invalidate the determination if, based on the evidence presented during the review, the Commission determines that the franchising authority has not demonstrated by a preponderance of the evidence that the franchising authority revoked the franchise for cause in accordance with subsection (b)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DEC32C8BD0046AF8305C7F14B8E35FE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Stay of determination to revoke franchise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A revocation of a franchise for cause under subsection (b)(2)(B) may be stayed—</text><subparagraph id="HE2EF78DFB06F4FEC98ADC9CAEDD92E81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case the cable operator petitions the Commission for review of the determination on which such revocation is based, by the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC0A0DCC32AA407ABCDE536CF3FC4E2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case the cable operator seeks judicial review of the determination on which such revocation is based, by the court in which the cable operator seeks judicial review of the determination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H00E8F64FC6724B1CAB382770621F74C9" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE92FB2F7967D4456A275638A509868FB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 601—</text><subparagraph id="HEFC37C3F353E4C9FB33F9DEC236F4A54" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0A9F04CD57D4D8B964B02A32FE59350" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraph (5); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA167964375C47F28CCB97AE8FBF2437" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (5);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95F6F2C08837412CA0F6FEB07BA8B928" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 602(9)—</text><subparagraph id="H9D387C4CF287411C9E2A9BB98E11F505" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>initial</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0B5E648BF41410D9C914406CEACEE2E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>, or renewal thereof (including a renewal of an authorization which has been granted subject to section 626),</quote>; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E548D48CEBC4F288F751899E334AA66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 611(b), by striking <quote>and may require as part of a cable operator’s proposal for a franchise renewal, subject to section 626,</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05AA6164EA2A4727A07FBC9374F55B49" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 612(b)(3)—</text><subparagraph id="H60157AD184E34451B354B6C6A0109EAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or as part of a proposal for renewal, subject to section 626,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB56F112672F14C0AA57DB571DA5C6C80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, or proposal for renewal thereof,</quote>; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80A856661BB044D89FC19AE71FE91590" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 621(b)(3)—</text><subparagraph id="H54F692623E984AC49DE0D03BB90CDE36" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(ii), by striking <quote>or franchise renewal</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BE9E637DCA949EFB628DDA585B2AB2F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text><clause id="H4D47FEBBCEA741E09A57B5584D42FD46"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>initial</quote>; and </text></clause><clause id="HFECABA9E6B634994AD49B26C3531C719"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, a franchise renewal,</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D9C3E5783A342B0BB7F8CCFD108AAE9" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 624—</text><subparagraph id="HE689BE2E538F4D7B8E53E8DFB1BF0235" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>(including requests for renewal proposals, subject to section 626)</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2935D8ECDEED464598037CCBC038D128" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>or renewal thereof</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F139F7410114A409224838D29039849" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 635A(a), by striking <quote>renewal,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H984045E69AFF411A8C38A904D2E13CFA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date; application</header><paragraph id="HA6B566FAABD94C73A119A5FB4A26D060"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall take effect 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE89292AFF84744B6978099223C5F9058"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This section, and the amendments made by this section, shall apply to a franchise granted—</text><subparagraph id="H211AEE6989804EE5B722B0AA21FC14A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on or after the effective date established by paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H764E7EF7B42045FC85BBAAFDFCE10C8C" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before such date, if—</text><clause id="H7342DB687D4740B6AF8253460FC7F8AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such franchise (including, any renewal thereof before the date of the enactment of this Act) is in effect on such date; or</text></clause><clause id="H14347F8BC4234113981C2EB3CAA7BD0A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such franchise is expired and the cable operator has continued to perform under the provisions of such franchise as if such franchise were not expired.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H55FEB91477904516A5E43316B80B8F4D"><enum>204.</enum><header>Sales of cable systems</header><subsection id="HF34A1868FD2A4895959F7084F57AB463"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 627 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/547">47 U.S.C. 547</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6E84D7725F2E46CBA6CF15F492C1C12B" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><section id="H344468B7942D4A74A203B27D764DD282"><enum>627.</enum><header>Conditions of sale or transfer</header><subsection id="H7AF6D405C208433F90ED9911A16EF880" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Value of cable system after revocation of franchise</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a franchise held by a cable operator is revoked for cause under section 626(b)(2)(B) and the franchising authority acquires ownership of the cable system or effects a transfer of ownership of the system to another person, any such acquisition or transfer shall be at fair market value. </text></subsection><subsection id="H1CBF186682BE409F898729FF22F80267"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations on authority of franchising authority with respect to transfer of franchise</header><paragraph id="H15D2CEA7952A4948AA204E603509E0DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A franchising authority may not preclude a cable operator from transferring a franchise to any person—</text><subparagraph id="H1AF8884D5B9E4C38915E64828FB7DDFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to which such franchise was not initially granted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF86A5B1BC5C14E5590343B1C802D5E8B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the terms of the franchise that apply to the cable operator, who agrees to accept all such terms in effect at the time of the transfer. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF3C032A7EB549E989128220492B7232"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>In the case of the transfer of a franchise to a person to which such franchise was not originally granted, a franchising authority may require a cable operator to which a franchise was initially granted to, not later than 15 days before the transfer of the franchise, notify the franchising authority in writing of such transfer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3791A79EBAF74B3E9DB9012B6F44FCA5" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of a franchise defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>transfer of a franchise</term> means the transfer or assignment of any rights under a franchise through any transaction, including through—</text><paragraph id="H5A3235BEA89D451DA70291DBBE2AE521" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a merger involving the cable operator or cable system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59881312D9834316A25DA32B4D06BA1A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a sale of the cable operator or cable system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D5F8998BE248A39603B25ED63F7695" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assignment of the cable operator or a cable system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06ECAD0548FA492CB6864EDD21ADB21B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a restructuring of a cable operator or a cable system; or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4A3A5ABA0F24F259DFC92F7C3BBC701" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the transfer of control of a cable operator or a cable system. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCA762993750F4925A98CB1B424D93228"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section, and the amendment made by subsection (a), shall take effect 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H825B476BA3D643A79C7254DF58130E4D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>This section, and the amendment made by subsection (a), shall apply to a franchise granted—</text><paragraph id="H2F8DD4ED12C54EBE80A6548E958169A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on or after the effective date established by subsection (b); or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A3A040CB5364C41A3C71206127424F2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>before such date, if—</text><subparagraph id="H050E56ECE2A842319480136A0039BB5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such franchise (including any renewal term thereof) is in effect on such date; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC628A351C642464D95484209E6F304F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such franchise is expired and cable operator has continued to perform under the provisions of such franchise as if such franchise were not expired.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H607725D0F33B412881A64E23C79698C1"><enum>III</enum><header>Environmental and Historic Preservation Reviews</header><section id="H2DFCFA3751784B65950F5F50057FF37B"><enum>301.</enum><header>Application of NEPA and NHPA to certain communications projects</header><subsection id="H408D6E2286BE4ECD9D2F0026CB2C91D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H9883356223AB4F418C72183081738368"><enum>(1)</enum><header>NEPA exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal authorization with respect to a covered project may not be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60C5814F2AC84AF0A466B94A4D54FA4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Historic Preservation Act exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered project may not be considered an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82263A81943440CFAC0412978E0D7146"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant of easement on Federal property</header><paragraph id="H3098F69E75474D1FBFBF378E3858C773"><enum>(1)</enum><header>NEPA exemption</header><text>A Federal authorization with respect to a covered easement for a communications facility may not be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>), if—</text><subparagraph id="H645F407EB905481B80C9154532907D8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered easement has previously been granted for another communications facility or a utility facility with respect to the same building or other property owned by the Federal Government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24E11B92DB554B9591CC92123B8CB8AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the covered easement is for a communications facility in a public right-of-way.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H565FF74C3F5A4B98B124E1D68E01E2F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National Historic Preservation Act exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered easement for a communications facility may not be considered an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code, if—</text><subparagraph id="HDB9A6B9744244ED8916BF798708C0EDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered easement has previously been granted for another communications facility or a utility facility with respect to the same building or other property owned by the Federal Government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6002BE69B5A640F488515F53ED6B7181"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the covered easement is for a communications facility in a public right-of-way.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F1E3AF2A1DD4BDFA9D2225965BB37A2" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requests for modification of certain existing wireless and wireline communications facilities</header><text>Section 6409(a)(3) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block id="HEE33999D90AF4F569B37AE8C35732EF3" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><paragraph id="H63862DA40F9D456E9BDF0FFE230D8A63" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of NEPA; NHPA</header><subparagraph id="H7E3F0FA94C1441E7B0B93B949718F234" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>NEPA exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal authorization with respect to an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request may not be considered a major Federal action under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAABECF64428C4D0E9430EB27EABDDF03" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>National Historic Preservation Act exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request may not be considered an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CDA2DB7011147F19A0D78290FD4E3CD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Federal authorization defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>Federal authorization</term>—</text><clause id="H920DA78D41494983A8428C7609D7EE97" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request; and</text></clause><clause id="H2F81B5F324CD4DFBA0FAAC0EA149FDB8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law with respect to an eligible facilities request or an eligible wireline communications facilities request.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H1C30A2925B684A72A5F311EB8C4251E9"><enum>302.</enum><header>Presumption with respect to certain complete FCC forms</header><subsection id="HC992247B15E94578A5E5B67C879F7F85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presumption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a project that is an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code, as determined by the Commission, if an Indian Tribe is shown to have received a complete FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621 (or any successor form), or can be reasonably expected to have received a complete FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621 (or any successor form), and has not acted on a request contained in such complete form by the date that is 45 days after the date of such receipt or reasonably expected receipt—</text><paragraph id="H5BD614E41A084833AA6AF6D51C6F70B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Commission and a court of competent jurisdiction (as the case may be) shall presume the applicant with respect to such complete form has made a good faith effort to provide the information reasonably necessary for such Indian Tribe to ascertain whether historic properties of religious or cultural significance to such Indian Tribe may be affected by the undertaking related to such complete form; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8856CFBDB8A4455E861F0D2142D5ABE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such Indian Tribe shall be presumed to have disclaimed interest in such undertaking.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4421F488CD7441B88D832BCD1AD08666"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Overcoming presumption</header><paragraph id="HAF1F98A843284E39950AB281990CBA94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An Indian Tribe may overcome a presumption under subsection (a) upon making, to the Commission or a court of competent jurisdiction, a favorable demonstration with respect to 1 or more of the factors described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B3A0C56AFB242EEA86C36F65F101F1C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Factors considered</header><text>In making a determination regarding a presumption under subsection (a), the Commission or court of competent jurisdiction shall give substantial weight to—</text><subparagraph id="HBB441844A8CB48539983540B4548806E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the applicant with respect to the relevant complete form failed to make a reasonable attempt to follow up with the applicable Indian Tribe not earlier than 30 days, and not later than 50 days, after the applicant submitted a complete FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621 (as the case may be) to such Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55F593CA6F5044F8A78625CB7BD66970"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the regulations of the Commission, or FCC Form 620 or FCC Form 621, are found to be in violation of a Nationwide Programmatic Agreement of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9AAE4E67C20543B8A504DC6A3658BFF6"><enum>303.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title or any amendment made by this title may be construed to affect the obligation of the Commission to evaluate radiofrequency exposure under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section><section id="H0861136C0C994F989E85D64E5F02BAC5"><enum>304.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="H9589003347724B559F8205AD6B471E86" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chief Executive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Chief Executive</term> means the person who is the Chief, Chairman, Governor, President, or similar executive official of an Indian tribal government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB21D7BF1AD0D4ADA8AFEC521218BD065"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B639AB5DF344A909E550FFA10510BDC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications facility</header><text>The term <term>communications facility</term> has the meaning given the term <term>communications facility installation</term> in section 6409(d) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H794140F21F7C4B0181CECD68C5F38BA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered easement</header><text>The term <term>covered easement</term> means an easement, right-of-way, or lease with respect to a building or other property owned by the Federal Government, excluding Tribal land held in trust by the Federal Government (unless the Indian tribal government with respect to such land requests that the Commission not exclude the land for purposes of this definition), for the right to install, construct, modify, or maintain a communications facility or a utility facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8141D2E9045544BCBC1AF0E3BBF0EABC" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Covered project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered project</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HAC65594EF73242C7B3DA8B38C8D7AA30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A project—</text><clause id="H87968950394C4C2EA1803F4F4AD44E0D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for—</text><subclause id="HCE6E9BB93171451188547C8FD68B13D4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the mounting or installation of a personal wireless service facility with another personal wireless service facility that exists at the time at which a request for authorization of such mounting or installation is submitted to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof or to an Indian tribal government; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H9CCA7C4B89F440FFBBC1E0772BE9107E" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the modification of a personal wireless service facility; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2095553686A9439AB8B53C56AC56A8EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which a permit, license, or approval from the Commission is required or that is otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F89159C34304959AA449994FC34BCEF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project—</text><clause id="H9319135748004729816FD90BC4E3881B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the placement, construction, or modification of a facility for communication by wire in or on eligible support infrastructure; and</text></clause><clause id="H30F45152CFC8422D8045620B630C63B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which a permit, license, or approval from the Commission is required or that is otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80F71FFB83454BD6A4D701E73C58B659"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project to deploy a small personal wireless service facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF749D9ABDDFD494EB56C8AC94E98B558"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project—</text><clause id="H77110445A4FE43BEA36AC21914C2FDD4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the deployment or modification of a communications facility that is to be carried out entirely within a floodplain (as defined in section 9.4 of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act); and</text></clause><clause id="HDDE8CC59F41F44808965370B4C3F3CC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which a permit, license, or approval from the Commission is required or that is otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38D1530CAE934DECBE754D9511D9889F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project—</text><clause id="HCEB91554D09241A292EB5150EAC62F13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for the deployment or modification of a communications facility that is to be carried out entirely within a brownfield site (as defined in section 101 of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>)); and</text></clause><clause id="HE2E9E24136E24E72BEE9633644A11E39"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which a permit, license, or approval from the Commission is required or that is otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3E5F67BB93D415D8398ADD6DE4E4CF5"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project to permanently remove covered communications equipment or services (as defined in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>)) and to replace such covered communications equipment or services with communications equipment or services (as defined in such section) that are not covered communications equipment or services (as so defined).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF018E9C9FCE342E2946C6BC1E5A30934" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A project that—</text><clause id="H3F52DCD0F5EB4D9AA6C1BFD810E19277" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is to be carried out entirely within an area for which the President, the Governor of a State, or the Chief Executive of an Indian tribal government has declared a major disaster or an emergency;</text></clause><clause id="H6266DEF662F84D9B8D659FA9DE1E7874" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is to be carried out not later than 5 years after the date on which the President, Governor, or Chief Executive made such declaration; and</text></clause><clause id="HDDBAB2EF69924757BA3F2264963897E4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>replaces a communications facility damaged by such disaster or emergency or makes improvements to a communications facility in such area that could reasonably be considered as necessary for recovery from such disaster or emergency or to prevent or mitigate any future disaster or emergency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE12D62F7FCC43B6AD652688D0ED5D7E" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project for the placement and installation of a new communications facility if—</text><clause id="HE1B72321B0BE4EA3B37B3E5F83B0F7C3" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such new facility—</text><subclause id="HA7A95F2172AF434694683130B06E3ADD" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>will be located within a public right-of-way; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H66ACADA388FE458584C105F2C4B45B8A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not more than 50 feet tall or 10 feet taller than any existing structure in the public right-of-way, whichever is higher;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4F372F8FF8664D52BBA3AC5B5F86B9C2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such new facility is—</text><subclause id="HF256208C633D465DB50DE247899FC77D" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a replacement for an existing communications facility; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF81BEBCA561D4D32B41C10528E588081" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the same as, or substantially similar to (as such term is defined by the Commission by regulation), the existing communications facility that such new communications facility is replacing;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAE538824A1E84EB08C83B4A0A18ABA9A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such new facility is a type of communications facility that—</text><subclause id="HB1E0CF08D1BB4CE3A1042AEE9F41AEAD" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is described in section 6409(d)(1)(B) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(d)(1)(B)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0D411C16DED94446B7AB4A496D436F58" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>meets the size limitation of a small antenna established by the Commission; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H86DF7556CAFD405F89FFE8322C82482C" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the placement and installation of such new facility involves the expansion of the site of an existing communications facility not more than 30 feet in any direction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1421C05B2D1840E08AD122B5908C107B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A project for the placement, construction, or modification of a personal wireless service facility on an existing tower, building, or structure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7AB05EB73BE47DCBBD2ADCF26806572"><enum>(J)</enum><text>A project for the placement, construction, or modification of a communications facility—</text><clause id="HCD4286BB39654768B77E22B45340FF27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for which the placement, construction, or modification is undertaken pursuant to a geographic area license that has been issued by the Commission or is subject to licensing by rule; and</text></clause><clause id="H2CA8174C652C4EA4A1FCB78E9279D09A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to which filing in the antenna structure registration system of the Commission is not required.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8EE650301BE4A15A26A736F2285A59E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible support infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible support infrastructure</term> means infrastructure that supports or houses a facility for communication by wire (or that is designed for or capable of supporting or housing such a facility) at the time when a request to a State or local government or instrumentality thereof, or to an Indian tribal government, for authorization to place, construct, or modify a facility for communication by wire in or on the infrastructure is submitted to the government or instrumentality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E8BACE8EE85455AA6F483F2469A0F34"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Emergency</header><text>The term <term>emergency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H84AC0840F7CC45A8BDADBD1085ECA681"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an emergency declared by the President, an emergency declared by the President under section 501 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5191">42 U.S.C. 5191</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC7FA30C85F64D03BF6A4F5E13301BC4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an emergency declared by the Governor of a State or the Chief Executive of an Indian tribal government, any occasion or instance with respect to which the Governor or Chief Executive declares that an emergency exists (or makes a similar declaration) under State or Tribal law (as the case may be).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H990038BAF33E4BCA9310FA1EF91EC074"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Federal authorization</header><text>The term <term>Federal authorization</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HC93BC97D9BB14E83A53D209D3E635C71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any authorization required under Federal law with respect to a covered project or a covered easement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5FE13FD24EE4ADE9D9A486BEE97BADE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any permits, special use authorizations, certifications, opinions, or other approvals as may be required under Federal law with respect to a covered project or a covered easement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16AE3B01435944119093F9C7BCF89E42"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Governor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Governor</term> means the chief executive of any State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5D33DDE7D71457A9F76A06E7A77C23D" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Indian tribal government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian tribal government</term> means the governing body of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17BD31072C7D4F95AB2801FD9A926887" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> under section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5130">25 U.S.C. 5130</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B419734E4C145CDA352315DE8635B51"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Major disaster</header><text>The term <term>major disaster</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H7383724727694BE2931F8BCEDBE7C8B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a major disaster declared by the President, a major disaster declared by the President under section 401 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170">42 U.S.C. 5170</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDAA03F1966A4FB3A7E245FDF7FC0FE9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a major disaster declared by the Governor of a State or the Chief Executive of an Indian tribal government, any occasion or instance with respect to which the Governor or Chief Executive declares that a disaster exists (or makes a similar declaration) under State or Tribal law (as the case may be).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E942263655B4A4382D547121E46CDB8" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Personal wireless service facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal wireless service facility</term> has the meaning given such term in subparagraph (G) of section 332(c)(7) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/332">47 U.S.C. 332(c)(7)</external-xref>), as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57D7312DFCC64EBEBAFCD1946144CB7D"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Public right-of-way</header><text>The term <term>public right-of-way</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HCF7E25A4BBE545FBBCBCC2CB2125349E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text><clause id="H88BD4093A68D403E90FEDC79F3B43B3A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the area on, below, or above a public roadway, highway, street, sidewalk, alley, or similar property (whether currently or previously used in such manner); and</text></clause><clause id="H6569DBB555E34C7C9889C4899D73D7F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any land immediately adjacent to and contiguous with property described in clause (i) that is within the right-of-way grant; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DB14D1718ED4B23965A13B3D0EF8B98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a portion of the Interstate System (as such term is defined in section 101(a) of title 23, United States Code).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F371868AC6E4C16BE111B459FAA899C" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Small personal wireless service facility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small personal wireless service facility</term> has the meaning given such term in subparagraph (G) of section 332(c)(7) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/332">47 U.S.C. 332(c)(7)</external-xref>), as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA71B7C16AA72486998FE5A3429C3E497" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and each territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC21670BC5B204BC095E66F6A9F751BB3"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Utility facility</header><text>The term <term>utility facility</term> means any privately, publicly, or cooperatively owned line, facility, or system for producing, transmitting, or distributing power, electricity, light, heat, gas, oil, crude products, water, steam, waste, storm water not connected with highway drainage, or any other similar commodity, including any fire or police signal system or street lighting system, that directly or indirectly serves the public.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H57E971B3FCE547199A105A54DB25F9E5"><enum>IV</enum><header>Other Matters</header><section id="H1C2C5FEE74E8452780FBCB8218B6AE25"><enum>401.</enum><header>Timely consideration of applications for Federal easements, rights-of-way, and leases</header><subsection id="H65B71304FA284A1BAA65C33A33B6979E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6409(b)(3) of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H54203B4B46B34ACDB5F5F329B5C8AF9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>an executive agency receives a duly filed application</quote> and inserting <quote>an application is submitted to an executive agency</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65CD172E5C9E4E50A398CEB0AFC7B283"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA22BF655ADC5425D9643725B0D0C5CAF" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><subparagraph id="H7FE66F49A55B41B4AA4B8FF2610BAE9D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Deemed granted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an executive agency fails to grant or deny an application under subparagraph (A) within the timeframe under such subparagraph, the application shall be deemed granted on the day after the last day of such timeframe.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8028B36A17584FE2A39E6F59047CD006"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Tolling due to incompleteness</header><clause id="H824D2C7727254A209DE5F4C6D250A6D6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial application incomplete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, not later than 30 days after the date on which an applicant submits to an executive agency an application under subparagraph (A), the executive agency provides to the applicant a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the application, the timeframe described in subparagraph (A) is tolled with respect to the application until the date on which the applicant submits to the executive agency a supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="HFCF2E40012B54DB0AFA23E7D2196875D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supplemental submission incomplete</header><text>If, not later than 10 days after the date on which an applicant submits to an executive agency a supplemental submission in response to a written notice described in clause (iii), the executive agency provides to the applicant a written notice described in clause (iii) with respect to the supplemental submission, the timeframe under subparagraph (A) is further tolled until the date on which the applicant submits to the executive agency a subsequent supplemental submission in response to the notice.</text></clause><clause id="HA56E37868DEB422D86A9ACF7796AEC78"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Written notice described</header><text>The written notice described in this clause is, with respect to an application under subparagraph (A) or a supplemental submission described in clause (i) or (ii) submitted to an executive agency by an applicant, a written notice from the executive agency to the applicant—</text><subclause id="HF956A9E8FDB647C4B5404BE5A7365DEF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>stating that all of the information (including any form or other document) required by the executive agency to be submitted for the application to be considered complete has not been submitted;</text></subclause><subclause id="H388F1C2D5B9644F0B79ED6B2E411BAFA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identifying the information described in subclause (I) that was not submitted; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA36A414DFD9D4B05BEE11338252E57DF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>including a citation to a specific provision of a publicly available rule, regulation, or standard issued by the executive agency requiring that such information be submitted with such an application.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBCF2D8A5C89F4E25BD9D456CA08EBBFF"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Limitation on subsequent written notice</header><text>If a written notice provided by an executive agency to an applicant under clause (ii) with respect to a supplemental submission identifies as not having been submitted any information that was not identified as not having been submitted in the prior written notice under this subparagraph in response to which the supplemental submission was submitted, the subsequent written notice shall be treated as not having been provided to the applicant.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF9BD6D79A43483C99119D848B1A5AFC"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Tolling by mutual agreement</header><text>The timeframe under subparagraph (A) may be tolled once, for a period of not more than 30 days, by mutual agreement between the executive agency and the applicant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DD55488FD494D63B1E89DC5BD43FAC8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(H)</enum><header>When application considered submitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this paragraph, an application shall be considered submitted to an executive agency on the date on which the applicant takes the first procedural step within the control of the applicant to submit such application in accordance with the procedures established by the executive agency for the review and approval of such an application.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC094115E6A9744CB8E0C2687F2750274"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to any application under subsection (b) of section 6409 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1455">47 U.S.C. 1455</external-xref>) that is submitted (as determined under subsection (b)(3)(H) of such section) to an executive agency (as defined in subsection (d) of such section) on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD71822106B094E0BA77282CFAAA0B811"><enum>402.</enum><header>Report on fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 60102 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1702">47 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8E33A5089B204EBB975FCB036F8BD0EC" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00"><subsection id="HF20E1F4BAF28481885CC2252CF9892F6"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Report on fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress a report—</text><paragraph id="H2BCB182E886F43CF8FF2CAB081B7A1A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detailing the fees charged by each eligible entity (or any political subdivision thereof)—</text><subparagraph id="HC10D8805560745B5B881DCC171E0BF80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to consider a request for authorization to place, construct, or modify, using (in whole or in part) grant funds received under this section, infrastructure for the provision of broadband service; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFC9262A6F6645F793B4F8012038A717"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to use a right-of-way or infrastructure in a right-of-way owned or managed by the entity or political subdivision for the placement, construction, or modification, using (in whole or in part) grant funds received under this section, of infrastructure for the provision of broadband service; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCF45318424948FDBF4CA293049B9159"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that identifies, with respect to any fee detailed pursuant to paragraph (1), any such fee that is not—</text><subparagraph id="H2BE17FFDDB2C44A2A6E167AA0C6B5134"><enum>(A)</enum><text>competitively neutral, technology neutral, and nondiscriminatory;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12D115049CBB42B99C17F8F477A5E411"><enum>(B)</enum><text>established in advance and publicly disclosed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09AFC836CD324F86854937BDB89AF801"><enum>(C)</enum><text>calculated—</text><clause id="HF6840CF73C714C0098B18BBB038654F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>based on actual and direct costs, such as costs for—</text><subclause id="HB2E0DADFDF70497BB544EC542C5518A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>review and processing of requests; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H928F3D46F520499FB7E9BA6A9E3398D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>repairs and replacement of—</text><item id="H4F7E5648D99B4E2BAA6BF973FD8EC829"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>components and materials directly resulting from and affected by the placement, construction, or modification (including the installation or improvement) of infrastructure for the provision of broadband service; or</text></item><item id="H69A3F72AFABB4E3ABF54C64BFC282CBC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>equipment that facilitates the placement, construction, or modification (including the installation or improvement) of such infrastructure; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H1C9CC0B2DAC2443485DB4B439BD1C89D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using, for purposes of clause (i), only costs that are objectively reasonable; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFFC7A5D05274D469F86E4B9EB73D54C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>described to a requesting party in a manner that distinguishes between—</text><clause id="H7A7C5AEC203C4EA393445BBACCA51D24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>nonrecurring fees and recurring fees; and</text></clause><clause id="HD626A31D0B664966B09E863E247C679A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the use of infrastructure on which infrastructure for the provision of broadband service is already located and infrastructure on which there is no infrastructure for the provision of broadband service as of the date on which the request is submitted to the eligible entity or political subdivision.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to streamline Federal, State, and local permitting and regulatory reviews to expedite the deployment of communications facilities, and for other purposes.</quote>.</official-title-amendment><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HIF00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name> with amendments</action-desc><action-date>April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

