<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEL26359-XG5-21-9K6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>107 S4369 IS: Absentee and Mail Voter Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4369</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S270">Mr. Schumer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S275">Ms. Cantwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S359">Mr. Heinrich</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S229">Mrs. Murray</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S422">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S247">Mr. Wyden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S436">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSRA00">Committee on Rules and Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To repeal an executive order relating to Federal elections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id1244937391334ae4b0409ea110cd0878" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Absentee and Mail Voter Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="ide8875d1864844054aff65c3cbbf71664"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="id954476eee52f40738960ae2d2779ae50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Article 1, section 4 of the Constitution of the United States clearly demonstrates that the power to make or alter any regulations regarding the time, place, and manner of elections lies with Congress and the States, not with the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbfb827c8a2954cf588c645137b470327"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On May 20, 1993, President William J. Clinton signed the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/31">Public Law 103–31</external-xref>), which was passed with bipartisan support.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id85632d98b22741b782e6412c9914b641"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On October 29, 2002, President George W. Bush signed the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/252">Public Law 107–252</external-xref>), which was passed on an overwhelmingly bipartisan basis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddc62a081cbc04efeae35ff156a898816"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Help America Vote Act of 2002 established the Election Assistance Commission, an independent and evenly divided bipartisan agency to assist States with new standards and improve election administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id102bbf1cb5004121961560ff364cce6f"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Neither the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 nor the Help America Vote Act of 2002 provide any authority for any of the actions directed by Executive Order 14399 (91 Fed. Reg. 17125) to create State citizenship lists for Federal election purposes based on unreliable Federal databases or to bar the Postal Service from delivering mail ballots unless States use lists provided to them or approved by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9edf89d3a2e64177a8d946130b48fa88"> <enum>(6)</enum> <text>Pennsylvania and New Jersey enacted some of the earliest laws to allow voting away from home in 1813 and 1815 in the context of the War of 1812 and many States granted absentee voting for military service members in 1864 during the Civil War. In the early 20th century, States such as Virginia, Indiana, and Wisconsin enacted absentee voting for several reasons. In 1924, President Calvin Coolidge and First Lady Grace Coolidge voted by mail according to Massachusetts absentee voting procedures from Washington, DC.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="idd45628075eca491fa99d34ab0d1b3e74"><enum>(7)</enum><text>All 50 States, the District of Columbia, and territories allow absentee voting. As of March 22, 2026—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idef3b8bbc64314ba1838445630f6eb3d6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">28 States (Alaska, Arizona, Florida, Georgia, Idaho, Illinois, Iowa, Kansas, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Michigan, Minnesota, Montana, Nebraska, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, North Carolina, North Dakota, Ohio, Oklahoma, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, South Dakota, Virginia, Wisconsin, and Wyoming) offer no-excuse absentee voting; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8bcfd08cdaca497da129739bd663e7f8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">8 States (California, Colorado, Hawaii, Nevada, Oregon, Utah, Vermont, and Washington) and the District of Columbia provide universal vote-by-mail.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id89f97fbeeee14475b39283731e2eb943"> <enum>(8)</enum> <text>More than 28,000,000 Americans voted by mail or absentee ballot in 2016, over 66,000,000 in 2020 during the COVID–19 pandemic, and over 48,000,000 Americans voted by mail in the 2024 general election. President Donald Trump has voted by mail on at least three occasions by his own admission, including in New York in 2018, Florida in 2020, and again in Florida in 2026.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="ida6ad4cccd2bb4ce89ac1b37875c46e0c"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Vote by mail has been used successfully and securely by members of the United States military for many decades and throughout major conflicts. Hundreds of thousands of members of the United States military and United States citizens living abroad relied on mail-in ballots to cast their vote in 2024 and the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20301">52 U.S.C. 20301 et seq.</external-xref>) requires all 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the territories of American Samoa, Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands to permit covered voters to register to vote absentee, and requires the Federal Government to expedite transmission of completed ballots.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id063395b535834bb4a1501eab5e700f3f" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The United States Postal Service is an independent establishment governed by a bipartisan Board of Governors which has the power to appoint the Postmaster General and exercise postal power, and cannot regulate or refuse to carry State-issued mail ballot envelopes at the direction of the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3f6dfd116ebd49408e301f6db00d9948" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Postal Service delivered nearly 100,000,000 ballots for the November 2024 general election and took extraordinary measures to ensure timely delivery of election mail in 2024 and will need to take action in the 2026 election cycle to again ensure timely delivery of election mail, including State-issued mail ballot envelopes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id918a70b2bef74d0495ea456936c3de6f"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Executive Order 14399 (91 Fed. Reg. 17125), issued by President Donald J. Trump on March 31, 2026, entitled <quote>Ensuring Citizenship Verification and Integrity in Federal Elections</quote>, greatly exceeds the authority of the Executive branch, is illegal and unconstitutional, and would disenfranchise tens of millions of American voters.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id629a8637723545bb96901236cffe34cd"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of Executive Order</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaf77c73f1a57434b8f00f89017c77686"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14399 (91 Fed. Reg. 17125) shall have no force or effect.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idecff225fce6644eb885598f99ef0cd50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds for similar orders</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd78fe05af2d5440c9b5bbe5f2e105b68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out Executive Order 14399 (91 Fed. Reg. 17125) or any similar order.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id30b6b8c7f1dc45039e13316eea04db8c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Postal service</header><text>The United States Postal Service may not use any funds, including funds available under section 2003 or 2011 of title 39, United States Code, to implement, administer, enforce, or carry out such Executive order or any similar order.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id5fc8ffa180044c8da26daaee265fa0c9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds with respect to certain other activities</header><subsection id="id12b4e8694fb848b8a893f6bea9a71ea2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National voter registration database</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be used by the Department of Homeland Security, the Social Security Administration, the Department of Justice, or any other agency—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id63389cd785f948b799f636405eebb5e0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to create a national voter registration database or a national citizenship database for Federal election purposes;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ccb5daf1fe34c418b92450a00fbe2bb"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to use existing databases or systems to compile citizenship lists for Federal election purposes; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc6eda04ac5164f49a2da3ab85aee66e1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide for the national collection of State voter registration lists or citizenship lists for Federal election purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9e080976af0f402a92f9a65f7f61dd48"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Mail-In and absentee ballots</header> <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="id835f98d3890d4966a080bfc3c2b11731">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no Federal funds may be used by the Department of Commerce or any other agency—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id1a2cc6b482b34227a0540654fa37058d">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for any purpose relating to the regulation of mail-in and absentee ballots in Federal elections; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="idd274cd3bd2a24014a8033bf858379a26">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>to determine the eligibility of a voter to cast a ballot through the mail in Federal elections; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
          id="idff621f923e5740a68228ed241a3592f1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the United States Postal Service may not use any funds, including funds available under section 2003 or 2011 of title 39, United States Code—</text>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="id04aa2a0a76f5452a80afe4de26c6de41">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to regulate the mailability of mail-in and absentee ballots in Federal elections; or</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
            id="idc700e35b27c44db98133bd0f3a001fec">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to determine the eligibility of a voter to cast a ballot through the mail in Federal elections.</text>
          </subparagraph>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="ided91072d7e0048679b541fcadef0b4c1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Compelling production of State voter registration lists</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be used by the Department of Justice to bring or continue a civil action against any State to compel the production of statewide voter registration lists under section 303 of the Civil Rights Act of 1960 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20703">52 U.S.C. 20703</external-xref>), section 303 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21083">52 U.S.C. 21083</external-xref>), or any other Federal law.</text></subsection><subsection id="id18e8ad15c83946a9a635ac2d6c43a169"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sharing of voter registration lists</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id80e2177b8ac9475ca01119b5e51d2bbf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in section 8 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20507">52 U.S.C. 20507</external-xref>), section 401 of the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/21111">52 U.S.C. 21111</external-xref>), or any other provision of law shall be construed to grant any authority to share statewide voter registration lists between any two Federal agencies, or to conduct data matching activities with any such registration lists using any system of records.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida894cb6d6e6648a3a743d2f8ba0f1af4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition of funds</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea9e747f2a2d471bae41dc21ec99bd93"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used by any agency for any activity described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f200516d12847d59878aa00c1d5dc04"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Postal service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Postal Service may not use any funds, including funds available under section 2003 or 2011 of title 39, United States Code, to carry out any activity described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcd88298bb9a64c0081810e6696ba2ce9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the terms <term>agency</term> and <term>system of records</term> have the meaning given those terms under section 552a of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

