<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H389922F778FD4487A5FAB8E9443F40D6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7988 IH: Safe Passage to the World Cup Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7988</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260318">March 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001229">Mrs. McIver</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that no Federal funds made available to the Department of Homeland Security or Department of Justice may be used to carry out any civil immigration enforcement activity on public transit or at public transit hubs from June 11, 2026, through July 19, 2026, in any metropolitan statistical area hosting a 2026 F&#233;d&#233;ration Internationale de Football Association World Cup match or Fan Festival, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBE3A362BBAA2409CAA04FF8E945EEF3E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0A6B56EC349A4F9B816ECBA45BD02AA0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Passage to the World Cup Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6969D8DCC7E041A7AD56519B5CA17DED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on use of funds</header> <subsection id="HDA0DB04AABD94F8999440F02402758EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds made available to the Department of Homeland Security or Department of Justice may be used, except under exigent circumstances, to carry out any civil immigration enforcement activity under the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)) on public transit or at public transit hubs from June 11, 2026, through July 19, 2026, in any metropolitan statistical area (as such term is defined in section 2001 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/601">6 U.S.C. 601</external-xref>)) hosting a 2026 Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) World Cup match or FIFA Fan Festival.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A2E0B655DE549999A4259A9E3CBDC4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exigent circumstances defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>exigent circumstances</quote> means a situation involving any of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA76E049F2D7D4618A7727F0F9B65D8C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The imminent risk of death, violence, or physical harm to a person, including in the case of terrorism (as such term is defined in section 2 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC91321240E80481DAE93A62A94F6B729"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The imminent risk to the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H787E413089C448549AEFBA21AED2B6F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The immediate arrest or hot pursuit of an individual presenting an imminent risk to public safety, including relating to death, violence, or physical harm to a person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36F42AE16F0949469BAF85F0C6BBDD71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The imminent risk of destruction of evidence that is material to an ongoing criminal case.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

