<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA93728B40E2540A8BF42A7185363A640" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6033 IH: Strengthening Transparent Reporting to Improve Veteran Equality Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6033</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to each report on certain disparities that affect the receipt of certain benefits administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H25712C61A30D492DB63C266B53504AD4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D51662F4B414FCBBF83DBAAC5493CEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Transparent Reporting to Improve Veteran Equality Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STRIVE Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H37B6520D337F4ABCBCA43A2E49B8AF07"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header> <subsection id="H2D6B8FB7A8A84DE980901D732BCDE2F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H5ED763230D534424A393520A1A9F2444"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to an internal report of the Department of Defense, Black members of the Armed Forces are more likely than White members to be the subject of—</text> <subparagraph id="HF3567E7CE6BE4C61A17180FC561D30B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an administrative action, including an investigation into alleged misconduct;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F0284B53AAC4E2FA410816EA671AE1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonjudicial punishment; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC12C35661C574BE3AC1BC636EB5E2AA3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a trial by court-martial.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E4811D7307649CFBD799066EEC7C3C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Certain administrative actions, nonjudicial punishments, and court-martial sentences may adversely affect the eligibility of a former member of the Armed Forces to receive disability benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H453D5AD302244619A042544DF91622C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the report titled <quote>VA Disability Benefits: Actions Needed to Further Examine Racial and Ethnic Disparities in Compensation</quote> (GAO–23–106097), published on July 26, 2023—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4F793EBEF2E14F11BF579844740A8B03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Black, non-Hispanic applicants for such benefits experience the lowest rate of approval for such benefits compared to applicants of other races or ethnicities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1948940907CE42A3AE905B8AA59DB1F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Black, non-Hispanic applicant is 14 percent less likely to be approved for such benefits than a White, non-Hispanic applicant; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H995EBA7BED894758B28E8848F1C6C35E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rates of approval for such benefits for Black, male applicants are between 3 and 22 percent lower than the rates of approval for applicants of other races or genders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA4136003F38C40358DCDA7C0A3F03CB1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Female former members of the Armed Forces are less likely to apply for such benefits than male former members.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8BCC7589DD634A3F8A542028356D38BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H906C7C49AEFA45679FB1E59DEEA2B5E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each former member of the Armed Forces made heroic sacrifices while serving in the Armed Forces, such as risking the life of the former member, to preserve the freedom of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D8C3F4FA33B4884AA66892C6640265C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the collection and publication by the Secretary of accurate data regarding the race, ethnicity, and gender of all applicants for, and recipients of, disability benefits administered by the Secretary would enable the Secretary and Congress to identify and address any disparity based on the race, ethnicity, or gender of a former member of the Armed Forces, with respect to the receipt of such benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3F0ECBB6960A403D9D1953421BFAE53C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports on racial, ethnic, and gender disparities with respect to disability benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HA0A93DA251E74457BC9F498E80F84F3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following elements:</text> 
<paragraph id="H31EE2505D11D4F2DA960FC7362373380"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Statistics for the 15-year period immediately prior to the date of the enactment of this Act that describe—</text> <subparagraph id="HF77BB64D98D145A0A804992B27669A35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the characterization of discharge or dismissal of each former member of the Armed Forces who separated from the Armed Forces during such period, disaggregated by the race, ethnicity, and gender of the former member; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1CA5C869ECE945F29E67BCEB575BB9E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of such former members, disaggregated by the race, ethnicity, and gender of each such former member, who—</text> <clause id="H7722C384B2F5425982F770F33906F8C9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requested review of the characterization of discharge or dismissal by an appropriate board;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD3D02D900CF442AF9946C8064F3012D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received review of the characterization of discharge or dismissal by an appropriate board;</text></clause> <clause id="HE679A434BB724F3392CD12051AE1D499"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>received a change to the characterization of discharge or dismissal as a result of a decision by an appropriate board;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1133917A4A1E45FA813210233D81BB1F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>applied for disability benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text></clause> <clause id="H8DB477CC29D347FB9F99FA18399DB1BA"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applied for and received such benefits; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB77F19BC99DB437EA06A8692EF13ABAD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applied for and were denied such benefits for reason of characterization of discharge or dismissal.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1FAEC02832404FB6824168806BD7D976"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The determination of the Comptroller General whether there is a disparity based on the race, ethnicity, or gender of a former member, with respect to the receipt of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE4333FF4D3CA49868530227D8871DAC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review of the characterization of discharge or dismissal by an appropriate board; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5444B742D45843508CE83F5A2670F4CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a change to the characterization of discharge or dismissal as a result of a decision by an appropriate board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31EC970592A04F31871F47412C223D1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessment of the Comptroller General whether there is a relationship between—</text> <subparagraph id="HF5F845516A124E80911162A4CDFA07F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any disparity determined under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB84CD12D6BF94D659DB895C373B3DF29"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any disparity determined by the Comptroller General in the covered report, with respect to disability benefits administered by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB49925E6DD334E9B9E0CF764BFC71EC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Secretary of Veterans Affairs: reports; plan; implementation</header> <paragraph id="HEEEA23391BA34B179038A010A1391CFE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 365 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives, and make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Veterans Affairs, a report that includes the following elements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H20982D1E9B3F4EC0ADB60360583BB289"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of any specific actions taken or processes implemented by the Secretary to address the limitations identified by the Comptroller General in the covered report, with respect to the collection and availability of data regarding each racial and ethnic group to which a former member of the Armed Forces belongs.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6E7652E9CDE140B69ED688A06319A2C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification by the Secretary, based on information in the covered report, of every significant cause of a racial, ethnic, or gender disparity with respect to disability benefits administered by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85188DCB4032451CA2B7CD13CD839A19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The three-year plan of the Secretary to address each significant cause identified under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EE40C9311964BC6ADD2B161615914D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation of plan; annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3773DAADF0BF466CB28CDFA85E69FC5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement the plan under paragraph (1)(C) not later than one day after the submission of the report under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEBA945ED95904CBAA3A0B1F2974728BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annually for each year during which the Secretary is carrying out such plan, make available on a publicly accessible website of the Department a report summarizing, for the period covered by the report, the actions of the Secretary pursuant to such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7ECBE493EF364ADD8B141590F4AA2D68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HAE7D4838CBE445CB85B4B627E819AC0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate board</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC599014E194845CCB271D02494BF65F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a board for the correction of military records under section 1552 of title 10, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5428094753CD4E04A94E6F96A2506A6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a board of review under section 1553 of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A1775F443C64C9DB2223D42A286057E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HAE9A788DE574464DB19051A6EAF92EF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H003FCAC870AE40BE93EBBD991D48B696"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B56CA7D059F44AF912C5CE2DCA3CDD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H717D018C26B148919C2AAD24268770D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D1C1DECFE584A32852F675504643DD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered report</term> means the report titled <quote>VA Disability Benefits: Actions Needed to Further Examine Racial and Ethnic Disparities in Compensation</quote> (GAO–23–106097), published on July 26, 2023.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

