<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0386D7EA78F841D485795E5AC0D94180" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9175 IH: Tax Clarity for Mining and Staking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9175</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260608">June 8, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide rules for taxation of income relating to the mining and staking of digital assets, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5A26DB0B712345D2AA1204AC31EDD958" style="OLC"><section id="H5AAD86315D24406383E8E85E7726DA6F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; etc</header><subsection id="H7ABFDE74395E4C44A648A65A08AF105D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tax Clarity for Mining and Staking Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H62CA248A02E34FAF93BE0E7D27D435B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise expressly provided, whenever in this Act an amendment or repeal is expressed in terms of an amendment to, or repeal of, a section or other provision, the reference shall be considered to be made to a section or other provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAA3EE34B74F344158C7313960AE22CDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H5AAD86315D24406383E8E85E7726DA6F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; etc.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HACBEE65FB1164030A033F90BB53E6626" level="section">Sec. 2. Treatment of certain digital assets received in connection with the validation of digital asset transactions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE2FDF795CD1446DF8F0BB5DF5179AB3C" level="section">Sec. 3. Investment trusts engaged in digital asset staking.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H545CF09938714C0C991E3AF858982FBF" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HACBEE65FB1164030A033F90BB53E6626"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of certain digital assets received in connection with the validation of digital asset transactions</header><subsection id="H3F98375370694003945DCC01AE8021AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> is amended by inserting after subchapter V the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE38A3092598144CBBF66DFC79E7A6478" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subchapter id="H0744E0C6310B45A9BFA79124135DE636"><enum>W</enum><header>Newly minted digital assets received in connection with the validation of digital asset transactions</header><toc container-level="subchapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H0744E0C6310B45A9BFA79124135DE636" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H87E128C25A8144F9A565991430A4615D" level="section">Sec. 1400W-1. Current inclusions in gross income; costs not capitalized.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3B7ADDC86A1F432EBD93E2C652EF4638" level="section">Sec. 1400W-2. Election to defer inclusion of income and capitalize costs of qualified newly minted digital assets.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD0E97D84415048529396A6D50B178B3C" level="section">Sec. 1400W-3. Definitions; regulations.</toc-entry></toc><section id="H87E128C25A8144F9A565991430A4615D"><enum>1400W-1.</enum><header>Current inclusions in gross income; costs not capitalized</header><subsection id="HE8B2565638FF419E89CDAF0622B4CBBC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the acquisition of any newly minted digital asset—</text><paragraph id="HB718F05A17194AB0A7EA629C461EB289"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the fair market value of such asset shall be included in the taxpayer’s gross income as ordinary income as of the time of such acquisition, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAB873A0714A46E69D4F538F57D5D340"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount included in gross income under paragraph (1) shall be properly taken into account in determining the taxpayer’s basis in such asset.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B3D5C81B64440818EF0AAFD4DC5BE77" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acquisition costs not capitalized</header><paragraph id="H94929D2283754648924EB536565F72AF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of this title (other than paragraph (2) and section 1400W-2), specified acquisition costs shall be treated as an expense which is not chargeable to capital account.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC294A30D9A964C179D7303CFF86C1F3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority for exception to conform with taxpayer’s applicable financial statement</header><text>The Secretary may issue regulations or other guidance which allow specified acquisition costs to be chargeable to capital account if such treatment would be consistent with the treatment of such costs for purposes of the applicable financial statement (as defined in section 451(b)(3)) of the taxpayer.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3B7ADDC86A1F432EBD93E2C652EF4638"><enum>1400W-2.</enum><header>Election to defer inclusion of income and capitalize costs of qualified newly minted digital assets</header><subsection id="HDA89A529ED364BA793672AA49F417554"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 1400W-1, in the case of any taxpayer for any taxable year to which an election under subsection (e) applies—</text><paragraph id="H9BDA72CABB4F4A8E858EF502F982A615"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all qualified newly minted digital assets acquired by such taxpayer during such taxable year shall not be included in the taxpayer’s gross income by reason of such acquisition, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22FC1ADB4C334F39A34895B85843785D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specified acquisition costs paid or incurred during such taxable year shall be chargeable to capital account with respect to qualified newly minted digital assets in accordance with the rules provided in subsection (c) (and no deduction shall otherwise be allowed under this subtitle with respect to such costs).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68A45516A3D142518BBF079E5F222178"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recognition and character of gain or loss on disposition</header><paragraph id="H863A409A6C784E638C5310D0A543E036"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a disposition of any qualified newly minted digital asset—</text><subparagraph id="H5399F9EC5B774522B5DB40636BB4B468"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any gain on such disposition shall be—</text><clause id="H1388199C321641A2BD8AD13342C1210B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>recognized notwithstanding any other provision of this subtitle, and</text></clause><clause id="H42B1D6A60E364CF986E630E50225E6EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>treated as gain from the disposition of property which is not a capital asset, and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCD053912B15421A93265FDAF708F9FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any loss on such disposition shall be treated as loss from the disposition of property which is not a capital asset to the extent that such loss exceeds the portion of the basis of such property that is not attributable to specified acquisition costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE6BA8B78CE7403E9B2F5A9D26FC2277" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for certain nonrecognition transactions</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text><subparagraph id="H333FB645F61146CF891ECD32E75A4F85" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any disposition to which section 1058 applies, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H505F294AC3224FA6B75066CD48CBCED5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent provided by the Secretary, any disposition which is a nonrecognition transaction described in subchapter C or K.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H507341DBFC834012858D0A1F99042465" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule for determining carryover basis</header><text>In the case of any disposition of a qualified newly minted digital asset with respect to which gain is recognized by the transferor under paragraph (1), if the basis of such asset in the hands of the transferee is determined by reference to the basis of such asset in the hands of the transferor, proper adjustments shall be made in the determination of basis to take into account such gain.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA892BE97FA64E119B0E8E86BB5EBE56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capitalization of specified acquisition costs</header><paragraph id="H74B1691654FD46299448E089916DEF3F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the Secretary shall provide rules for the proper allocation of specified acquisition costs among qualified newly minted digital assets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H484AADDC13FD460494AC37D39133BC1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cessation of activities</header><text>The rules provided under paragraph (1) shall include rules that provide for the proper deduction of specified acquisition costs which are not otherwise allocated to qualified newly minted digital assets pursuant to such rules because the taxpayer indefinitely ceases all activities related to the validation of digital assets (including staking and mining).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEA86A63B0374FAC8490BEE29CD1B756"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Qualified newly minted digital asset</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H71819C2621DA4CC9A71D36C8571141D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>qualified newly minted digital assets</quote> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any taxable year, any newly minted digital asset (determined without regard to subparagraph (B) of section 1400W-3(a)(1)) acquired by such taxpayer during such taxable year if—</text><subparagraph id="H1DBA1DD3F2A54190A7DE59D6FE707D90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the election under subsection (e) applies to such taxpayer for such taxable year, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70EAC4366CC04837A61178AF3DE483C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the taxpayer—</text><clause id="HB02BCB1A5A6641AB84882242579F752E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of any such newly minted digital asset issued in connection with a validation of digital asset transactions which was not supported by the staking of digital assets—</text><subclause id="H7E90F9C9BB2147A8B1CD049D418D35C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is the person who validated such digital asset transactions, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9BA0492CF09647D2B910769CCF58CF61"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is the first owner of such newly minted digital asset, or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD618AC3415144ED88DF580B35ADA9CB3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of any such newly minted digital asset issued in connection with a validation of digital asset transactions which was supported by the staking of digital assets—</text><subclause id="HA0CEC477181F49B19217496361E0A7E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is the person who holds the digital assets that were so staked, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3C5FB6D1D6E5425AA6DB8B05399D0609"><enum>(II)</enum><text>either is the first owner of such newly minted digital asset or acquired such newly minted digital asset promptly after such newly minted digital asset was issued. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0D1FC16132C48F597A9DFD85548C747" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lessee treated as holder</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(B)(ii)(I), if a digital asset is lent to any person, such person (and not the person lending such asset) shall be treated as holding such asset.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC52E4DA8AA9E4C3C816EE5700F26650A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Election</header><paragraph id="HDC9103E8A9C8429E9EA97904C6D0040C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An election under this section shall apply for the taxable year for which it is made and for each taxable year thereafter unless revoked with the consent of the Secretary. Such election shall be made at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA51F596FF3B40A99CE6E74EACE3B7F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application to partnerships and S corporations</header><text>In the case of any partnership or S corporation, the election under this section shall be made at the partnership or S corporation level.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68ED05B8E36242A6B8E07FDA1D3C88D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment as change in method of accounting</header><text>A taxpayer making an election under this section shall be treated for purposes of section 481 as making a change in method of accounting which is initiated by the taxpayer and made with the consent of the Secretary. Such change shall be applied only on a cut-off basis, and no adjustments shall be made under section 481(a). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98251277FADA4A69B6D8A45100800BF7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Controlled foreign corporations and passive foreign investment corporations ineligible</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to—</text><paragraph id="H474A4BE46782452A88F1562E4E9306CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any controlled foreign corporation or any passive foreign investment company (as defined in section 1297),</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACBBC3CCC110442AA79F918DBA2BCF96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H345FD24BBA4B40EC918775D6100138D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any foreign trust, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41DD084BFED24E368BBC612B842FDDFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any partnership in which one or more controlled foreign corporations, passive foreign investment companies (as so defined), or foreign trusts are partners in such partnership, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0C4FFDC2674972A2AB9A350066E4AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the extent provided by the Secretary, any partnership or trust if one or more entities described in paragraph (2)(B) are indirectly partners in such partnership or direct or indirect beneficiaries of such trust.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB2FF454CB9143849489C2145A6271D7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Treatment of certain grantor trusts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations or other guidance issued by the Secretary under section 1400W-3(c) may include regulations or other guidance providing rules for the application of this section with respect to digital assets owned through a widely traded fixed investment trust, including regulations or other guidance—</text><paragraph id="HAE517A6B059E4156B54696326ACD70DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifying information reporting requirements or requiring additional information reporting with respect to newly minted digital assets acquired through such a trust,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC40D6FC282AF4200B468BD95BDC4D847"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing reasonable methods for brokers (or any other person required to report information with respect to such a trust) to determine and report the portion of the interest in such a trust that results from the acquisition of newly minted digital assets during a taxpayer’s holding period,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9078894101E416DB9946A71A98CDBA4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>requiring owners of interests in such a trust to notify the broker (or any other person required to report information with respect to such a trust) whether an election has been made under subsection (e),</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99C47AB8F74840FA8EF29966A03E9F86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing rules for the appropriate allocation of basis to the portion of the interest in such a trust that is attributable to the acquisition of newly minted digital assets, including by requiring the allocation of any basis (other than specified acquisition costs required to be capitalized under this section) to a taxpayer’s other interests in such a trust,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2441F5A01BA42339CD9150C471342D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing rules to reduce administrative and compliance burdens by providing for aggregation, approximation, or other reasonable methods to compute and report gain attributable to newly minted digital assets acquired through such a trust, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DEA6A74D77842C9AE4AA997117A6EFE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>defining the widely traded fixed investment trusts to which the regulations or other guidance under this subsection applies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD0E97D84415048529396A6D50B178B3C"><enum>1400W-3.</enum><header>Definitions; special rules; regulations</header><subsection id="H5F523050D6C44356AFDCD16E43833DF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subchapter—</text><paragraph id="HEF24CCF24B6C47FFB76CE6E7CCCA8052" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Newly minted digital asset</header><subparagraph id="H55995A8B28664E66A4A7B9A1C8BB9BC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>newly minted digital asset</quote> means any digital asset that is issued in connection with the validation of digital asset transactions (including digital asset validation supporting activities) and that (prior to such issuance) was not owned by any person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72D688351E8040ECAFBC0ED8999C8D84"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination of treatment as newly minted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A digital asset shall not be treated as a newly minted digital asset at any time after the disposition of such asset by the first owner of such asset.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE431106A2DB34A029E7BCA3C3D627CFC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authorization of reasonable methods of determination</header><clause id="H4DF04AFEE67B4E0BA03D0E00A53B8B68"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided pursuant to clause (ii), a taxpayer may use any reasonable method to determine whether a digital asset acquired by the taxpayer is a newly minted digital asset.</text></clause><clause id="HE014DDF21AD74F7BB40E9B76C90FB135"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authority of Secretary to identify methods</header><text> The Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate specifying methods that are, or are not, reasonable for purposes of clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EED749B83B84E528CD0160B9BE05F8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specified acquisition costs</header><subparagraph id="H3D646AEEE3FC4A74873B7E682619427A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>specified acquisition costs</quote> means any amount paid or incurred in connection with validating any digital asset transaction if, at the time such amount is paid or incurred there is a reasonable possibility that the taxpayer will acquire a newly minted digital asset in connection with such validation. Such term shall not include any amount unless such amount would (without regard to this subchapter) be either allowable as a deduction or chargeable to capital account.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DA3C721853548F198AC6C8391DEF269"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain costs</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>amount paid or incurred in connection with validating any digital asset transaction</quote> includes any amount paid or incurred in connection with the activity of validating, or attempting to validate, any digital asset transaction, including—</text><clause id="HD2C44527AF434F73ADD7BD078BB9FA68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the direct costs of such activity,</text></clause><clause id="H9CD14FF99C23431C8EAC75914F9CA4E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indirect costs allocable to such activity,</text></clause><clause id="HB0EB58F15C2B4767AFCF93362A7A64D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fees paid or incurred to another party to carry out such activity, and</text></clause><clause id="HA23C1E844AEA4789A84E7DA8EF71E09C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>interest costs allocable to such activity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD35199C9C50D436EBEBAB39074B235BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of this subchapter—</text><paragraph id="HC5BC2EFAD54C469582C444A28724C976"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acquire</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person shall be treated as acquiring a newly minted digital asset in any case where such person comes to possess such asset and without regard to the manner in which such person comes to possess such asset.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9FF70C7C8447465ABCCB1ECBE2BC1651" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification that certain transfers are treated as dispositions</header><text>The following shall not fail to be treated as a disposition for purposes of this subchapter:</text><subparagraph id="H7495639F15524CA89DC9BA06DCE54C22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The distribution of any digital asset from a trust to a beneficiary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33EE13CEC11A4CAB8C5A562B2B8D0BC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The transfer of any digital asset from a decedent (whether or not incident to the decedent’s death).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDBF8C34DAA08473C8DCD0BB862AA41AE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subchapter, including to prevent the abuse of the provisions of this subchapter.</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8987C88642774C99BD5D5212F955B972"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of sourcing rules for digital assets acquired in connection with validating digital asset transactions</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/863">Section 863</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H33912D77CB1A4EE79F55975A5498194D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HADB467382D8D410F8459E00D4FEAE35C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Treatment of digital assets acquired in connection with validating digital asset transactions</header><paragraph id="HF5F18963F2E14E20A69924F6026C9451"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Income on acquisition</header><text>Income from the acquisition of any digital asset received in connection with the validation of digital asset transactions (including digital asset validation supporting activities) shall be sourced—</text><subparagraph id="H5CDE61084EA0433E9BBBB6A0AE514081"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the United States if the taxpayer is a United States resident at the time of acquisition, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CFD44F287A540C68B22CFFED9BC4C87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outside the United States if the taxpayer is a nonresident at the time of acquisition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D3CB4DE7715412BBDAD101AAB3901A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain deferred income recognized on disposition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Income described in section 1400W-2(b) shall be sourced—</text><subparagraph id="HC680818E364A4B67B5BCDCFE9F996714"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the United States if the taxpayer is a United States resident at the time of disposition, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0118FCC8341C4BA28708B785C3C615D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outside the United States if the taxpayer is a nonresident at the time of disposition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB25545E8783543A38FA094829CAB2AD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of branches</header><subparagraph id="H6C821D6FA5114DB7B654E7E32214B9C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Foreign branches</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a United States person with a qualified business unit (as defined in section 989(a)) in a foreign country, income described in paragraph (1) or (2) that constitute business profits attributable to such unit shall be sourced outside the United States. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H499FB985D29F4F5497F3051DD09F1247"><enum>(B)</enum><header>U.S. branches</header><text>In the case of a person that is not a United States person and that maintains an office or other fixed place of business in the United States, income described in paragraph (1) or (2) attributable to such office or other fixed place of business shall be sourced in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B828FCC682F43FEAFF9F8FB7FFE7DEA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Attribution</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Secretary may issue such regulations or other guidance as the Secretary determines necessary or appropriate for purposes of determining the amount of business profits attributable to a qualified business unit or office or other fixed place of business.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6230DC1026E54DCCBB39559B892265FF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of partnerships</header><text>In the case of a partnership, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary in regulations or other guidance, this subsection shall be applied at the partner level.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92E251EE88D0404D9E83E2A39F7171CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States resident; nonresident</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the terms <quote>United States resident</quote> and <quote>nonresident</quote> have the meaning given such terms, respectively, in section 865(g)(1), determined after application of section 865(g)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H892838440613489398AF03FFCFB48E3A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules relating to partnerships that hold newly minted digital assets</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/751">Section 751(c)</external-xref> is amended in the flush language at the end—</text><paragraph id="HEA27369FC21442E7B0E5108788A173F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and an oil, gas, or geothermal property (described in section 1254)</quote> and inserting <quote>an oil, gas or geothermal property (described in section 1254), and qualified newly minted digital assets (as defined in section 1400W-2(d))</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H463A701DFC4E4B3DA1822130B2230B31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or 1254(a)</quote> and inserting <quote>1254(a), or 1400W-2(b)(1)(A)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A358606DDB546A6A7DF6144C3F761EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination with deduction for qualified business income</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/199A">Section 199A(c)(3)(B)</external-xref> is amended by redesignating clause (vii) as clause (x) and inserting after clause (vi) the following new clauses:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB7D40CD131DC4355ABB462C8B2B9E77E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HFCB05A45FCE84E13AF6FB301FA24DDD8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any item of gain or loss on the disposition of any newly minted digital asset (as defined in section 1400W-3(a)(1)).</text></clause><clause id="H138FC3DC5DDB4D05A87171BCF23DA387"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Any item of income includible in gross income under section 1400W-1(a)(1).</text></clause><clause id="H81509F9346114D25806519EEE6BC5708"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any item of gain realized under subsection (a) or (b) of section 751 by reason of the references in section 751(c) to <quote>qualified newly minted digital assets (as defined in section 1400W-2(d)</quote> and to <quote>1400W-2(b)(1)(A)</quote>. </text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD1C568F3BC5440DFA60D5234ADCCABDD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of subchapters for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> is amended by inserting after the item relating to subchapter V the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2D3F23E1E2A844A5928AEC68BFF4CF81" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HE38A3092598144CBBF66DFC79E7A6478" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H0744E0C6310B45A9BFA79124135DE636" level="subchapter">Subchapter W—Newly minted digital assets received in connection with validating digital asset transactions</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF0681D4D2CD245A199131430849F4942"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to assets acquired in taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B7322FC681B44D4B65477E1FCFFDE11"><enum>(g)</enum><header>No inference with respect to proper treatment of newly minted digital assets to which the amendments made by this section do not apply</header><text>Nothing in this section (or any amendment made by this section) shall be construed to create any inference with respect to the proper application of any provision of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to any newly minted digital asset (as defined 1400W-3 of such Code, as added by this section) acquired in any taxable year beginning on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE2FDF795CD1446DF8F0BB5DF5179AB3C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Investment trusts engaged in digital asset staking</header><subsection id="H1880D17CBBCC48FA8510FE895135738F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7701(p), as added by section 4 of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2C71FF11B2FB4DEFB9D78A28B42A47FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H77C11F460DDC4504B28A6D013EFD0E4C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Status of trusts engaged in digital asset staking</header><subparagraph id="HCC5D63743DBF4B6E8C2F4A230044208A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity or arrangement shall not fail to be treated as a trust for purposes of this title solely by reason of the power of the trustee of such entity or under such arrangement to—</text><clause id="HFF5B496C998B4B2182B7F56899670657"><enum>(i)</enum><text>engage in staking digital assets held by the trust,</text></clause><clause id="H48FCB8C5C1AE49A6A768F115DC504C5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retain or distribute digital assets received in connection with such staking,</text></clause><clause id="HCAD584443109497AA6548290466A2D7B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>determine which digital assets held by the trust to use in staking, </text></clause><clause id="H12E9FD0BAF274E9F95B965791355A9D5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to the extent that any digital assets held by the trust are committed to staking, take measures necessary or appropriate to ensure that the trust has sufficient liquidity to make distributions in redemption of interests in the trust, including by purchasing the right to borrow money or digital assets to make such distributions, and</text></clause><clause id="H962225BD31D646D8A4B3DF4A2D73F379"><enum>(v)</enum><text>perform acts related to the exercise of the powers described in the preceding clauses of this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F478AADD5624AA69BD0CB3B05C5F24B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Not to apply to validating trade or business</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply in the case of an entity or arrangement engaged in the active conduct of a trade or business of validating digital asset transactions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E4DFF828D704DE59ABEB88C637030CB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HAF9B68FCDFAF4E759CD00BB4B70DE008"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The heading for section 7701(p), as added by section 4 of this Act, is amended by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and special rules</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Definitions</header-in-text></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0C7CA95B858042A89EA5D63813882E0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H545CF09938714C0C991E3AF858982FBF" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/7701">Section 7701</external-xref> is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD671FBD35A014EB1BD62FD5728118F1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (p) as subsection (q), and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H634309517A51474EBA6C3581214F7FF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (o) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79934DA6B13246CFB733247D272C551C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H191D6F7C71594B67A435097A651DD067"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Definitions related to digital assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this title—</text><paragraph id="H91694AD8246745AF868302FF1AC5FE2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital asset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>digital asset</quote> means, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger or any similar technology as specified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70751095EA3E44FC88BA8B0AD3B37C90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital asset transaction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>digital asset transaction</quote> means any transfer of a digital asset recorded on the cryptographically secured distributed ledger (or similar technology) referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A136C1F083C4E1A8F8E62315F4719AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Digital asset validation supporting activities</header><text>The term <quote>digital asset validation supporting activities</quote> means staking, mining, or similar activities in support of the validation of digital asset transactions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79BCE4C8623845E589121BFEBDD77321"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Validation</header><text>The term <quote>validate</quote>, and any derivative of such term (including <quote>validation</quote>), when used in connection with a digital asset transaction, includes the processes of proposing transactions for validation and verifying the validation of transactions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H502A837E897943579B2EC1163F16EB55"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Staking</header><text>The term <quote>staking</quote>, when used in connection with a digital asset, means—</text><subparagraph id="HBBA6F3FD46C6445B911839345EF59989"><enum>(A)</enum><text>making such asset available in support of the validation of digital asset transactions, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66CCFE340D294E2AA56FE018658A3477"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any substantially similar activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48EC7DE7CBD64CDCB599805A2159437F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Mining</header><text>The term <quote>mining</quote>, when used in connection with a digital asset, means—</text><subparagraph id="H02593327FB1E48D58DA7B6923540DB08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performing computations, or making available computing power, in support of the validation of digital asset transactions, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDF89E50071D4A7389ED79ECDCDA32A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any substantially similar activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

