<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDD23854012A1489F8915D4E64BBB6076" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6407 IH: RCORP Authorization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6407</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to maintain the Rural Communities Opioid Response Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBDC9C8D3B5DE477B85C58BED8ACEB331" style="OLC"><section id="H8816C3059A2A4C3BB086CE0DDBA52AF5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>RCORP Authorization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H148A836B4B164BFBA94F632E4EB0AF4E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rural Communities Opioid Response Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart I of part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 330A–2 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254c-1b">42 U.S.C. 254c–1b</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8D939B5D680A47C9BB94DDC2488C23B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE4F1EF0C0B4B495BA717815F67E66813"><enum>330A–3.</enum><header>Rural Communities Opioid Response Program</header><subsection id="H87A7CFFC99F44B1BA186B15A6D111102"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>), shall maintain a program to be known as the Rural Communities Opioid Response Program to establish and expand prevention, treatment, and recovery services in rural areas (as defined by the Secretary) for substance use disorders (including opioid use disorder), related behavioral health conditions, and other related public health issues.</text></subsection><subsection id="H27CE3B7E7BD544B2ADF013429B050BF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants and cooperative agreements</header><paragraph id="HA604AC15D7A74D358984EF0E71CDE367"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program under this section, the Administrator may award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2CB3BE194114C90B09A453B018BCBAD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant or cooperative agreement under this section may use funds received through such grant or cooperative agreement to—</text><subparagraph id="HB9C5E62F555A4C23AE70010915D46E8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct planning activities to strengthen the capacity of cross-sector networks and improve coordination of resources and care involving substance use disorder;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95D323F481E747D783A62B794A254F51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and implement evidence-based and sustainable delivery models to provide direct prevention, treatment, and recovery services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCE9A635326348B19E3E0D5F53BF7A81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>respond to new and emerging public health issues involving substance use disorder;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B80FF926EE644D69B88C7F891063595"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide targeted technical assistance or evaluation activities with respect to grants or cooperative agreements awarded under this section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE116D4E0945449A89A0A78D9B985713"><enum>(E)</enum><text>engage in such other activities as the Secretary may determine appropriate to carry out the program under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EC0363B7A574B42837A95EE6844F9B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibited use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that is awarded a grant or cooperative agreement under this section may not use funds provided through such grant or cooperative agreement for the acquisition or improvement of real property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C4729C3FA0C42519428ECBEDCC84532"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an entity shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HC9CFD87E5691478BB046C81CA9EAA9CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84AC21041755458B82FAA9E09F9FA9F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as such terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACD7C1E107004E3EA1E7902BC6B92B3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State office of rural health; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1FA4499E5BC47B5B47B7CA6034E6F3A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other domestic entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB098FAD8DB4844538FA5C6E27507E9B5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To seek a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require, including a description of how the rural population in the local community or region to be served will be involved in the development and ongoing operations of such activities, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CA8680FA91E4A21A4C850A81E592F66"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>The Administrator may not award a grant or cooperative agreement under this section for a period of more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54C71B07103E4A1CADCE425FB955EA2B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Administrator may fully fund a grant or cooperative agreement made under this section at the time of the award.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA65E6AB85D1841108AA7AD1F73963C55"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $165,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

