<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3B6DDA26482E4EB19CFDB6FF96ADDC1B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8703 IH: To designate the facility of the Federal Aviation Administration located at Yakima Air Terminal in Yakima, Washington, as the “Roy A. Rutherford Air Traffic Control Tower”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8703</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260507">May 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the facility of the Federal Aviation Administration located at Yakima Air Terminal in Yakima, Washington, as the <quote>Roy A. Rutherford Air Traffic Control Tower</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD3A8D478DAA542E28D496C73A06E82B0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9DC4502767974F1D9B7A0E63F1AF90C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The air traffic control tower located at Yakima Air Terminal in Yakima, Washington, and any successor air traffic control tower at that location, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Roy A. Rutherford Air Traffic Control Tower</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE8D8ED83C34B4016A3A78C649F6137EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the air traffic control tower referred to in section 1 shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Roy A. Rutherford Air Traffic Control Tower</quote>.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

