<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H01F426ADAE574EC093E4E9CDBA288D69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6516 IH: To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to identify individuals dually enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP and an Exchange.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6516</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251209">December 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to identify individuals dually enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP and an Exchange.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3B5ADE3CF9BC4099A5234CD02DEEB401" style="OLC"><section id="H7F226EE014CC4AEBBD7FC233992B1C58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Identification of dual Medicaid or CHIP and Exchange enrollments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1311(c) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H21C2A010E16D4865AE19E9011E5DF2E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB3740080F10A44ADA92F6DBAFE21B73D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Identification of dual Medicaid and Exchange enrollments</header><subparagraph id="H2EB81826EB51424C9D17B6A353BC7028" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, establish a program under which, on a recurring basis, but not less frequently than quarterly, the information of each individual enrolled in a qualified health plan through an Exchange is compared through the Public Assistance Reporting Information System (PARIS) facilitated by the Secretary (or any successor system) with the information of each individual enrolled in a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX of the Social Security Act, or a State child health plan under title XXI of such Act (or a waiver of such plan), for purposes of identifying individuals enrolled in both such a qualified health plan and such a State plan (or waiver) or State child health plan (or waiver).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE8896EA8C194EAA9584F52F66A17A02" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary shall take such actions as the Secretary determines appropriate (such as the notification of applicable Exchanges and the Secretary of the Treasury) to ensure that no individual identified under the program established under <internal-xref idref="H2EB81826EB51424C9D17B6A353BC7028" legis-path="(8)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> is receiving premium tax credits under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or cost sharing reductions under section 1402.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

