<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF111421E3BD74BE2BC5351A05D719A00" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8494 IH: To prohibit the Department of Homeland Security from entering into, modifying, extending, or renewing, any contract or intergovernmental service agreement to establish or operate any new immigration detention model, including the use of warehouses, modular facilities, soft-sided structures, tent systems, and processing centers.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260423">April 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000617">Mrs. Ramirez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001234">Ms. Morrison</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Department of Homeland Security from entering into, modifying, extending, or renewing, any contract or intergovernmental service agreement to establish or operate any new immigration detention model, including the use of warehouses, modular facilities, soft-sided structures, tent systems, and processing centers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDA17CC6E116E4A8EB4A9C794168A738E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3E678F7A28884CD4AFCAA05365FC56E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on new immigration models</header> 
<subsection id="HDE177B7D04C44FB493FAE786B03A0003"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="H516888F4ED76442787B8DE6713131E87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security, acting through U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, has announced plans to spend approximately $38,300,000,000 to acquire and retrofit warehouses and industrial facilities into large-scale immigration detention centers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H308AA6038B824A3DA04AB30C9B226507"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Such planned expansion includes the use of warehouses, modular facilities, soft-sided structures, tent systems, processing centers, or other alternative detention facility models.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H806025EC91B642AE8257A1A4C7BE37CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The facilities that the Department of Homeland Security is attempting to develop are similar to facilities used to incarcerate about 120,000 people of Japanese descent, as well as many others, in internment camps in the United States from 1942 through 1946, a grave violation of human rights and a dark chapter in our history.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BE75890095147328625124FD509218E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Immigration detention has detrimental and long-lasting impacts on individuals detained, their families, and their communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C25CCCF83BF465B85AF34DD52B62463"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Decades of documentation have proven that, across the immigration detention system, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement subjects people to violations of their basic rights and unconscionable conditions, including medical neglect, overcrowding, cruel and unusual conditions of confinement, and rampant transfers that disappear people deeper into the detention system, sowing confusion and cutting people off from their loved ones and support networks.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H402DFA60063F45D2950C770956F35E93"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Deaths in immigration detention facilities have occurred under the supervision of the Department of Homeland Security, including 33 reported deaths in 2025 and 13 deaths so far in 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC63ED2E72F604966B55E6880C1D2EDF5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The expansion of immigration facilities adversely harms surrounding communities through increased surveillance, infrastructure strain, environmental impact, and diversion of local resources.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9B339184090442DBF584888D9C10C13"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The expansion, creation, or repurposing of buildings as detention facilities diverts critical resources such as water and electricity away from the local communities, could cut off local tax revenue, and forecloses other economic opportunities for local communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF271381A2146439980CABB00B0E52853"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Facilities not originally constructed for the purposes of detaining or processing individuals drastically lack appropriate infrastructure, including sewage, sanitation, and water systems necessary to protect public health and would further exacerbate the unacceptable conditions named above.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50423B3123A542F0919BFAC516752619"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Congress has the authority to condition and prohibit the use of Federal funds and facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5EFB4614D37A48C88A9523D79E286250"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on new immigration models</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a covered agency may not—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBE85AEA6E91E465BAE94AA87D8A36CBF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish or implement any new immigration detention model; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E79290B59614E70A605280DAA657779"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish, operate, expand, convert, or renovate any warehouse, industrial facility, tent, soft-sided structure, modular unit, or similar building or structure for the purposes of housing, processing, or detaining individuals under civil immigration authority.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H817A899A7F34406591F56D5CD9931367"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H0559C8A04DFF46FDA578FDF2C46CC5C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the amounts made available before the date of the enactment of this Act for any fiscal year or otherwise made available to any covered agency may be obligated or expended to establish, construct, renovate, expand, or operate any new immigration detention model, including any warehouse, industrial facility, tent, soft-sided structure, modular unit, or similar building or structure, whether directly operated by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or by another governmental or nongovernmental contractor.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FAE59B54BB64709BD3F74C619C6D23F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on transfer</header><text>None of the amounts made available before the date of the enactment of this Act, may be reprogrammed or transferred for the purposes of operating or constructing immigration detention facilities, processing facilities, holding facilities, or non-traditional facilities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93BA781B50034D9ABD4D342E8EEE1EDF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>Amounts obligated to operate new immigration detention models, including any warehouse, industrial facility, tent, soft-sided structure, modular unit, or similar building or structure shall be transferred to needed services such as affordable health care and housing.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5CABBB00B861450E89F0079225550B25" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6B81E4E4FB8D42C6B44E077163C329A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <term>covered agency</term> means the Department of Homeland Security, including U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, and any component thereof.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74F6A08E6FE34F34956D11C487CFC23E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5B4D8C7A8D0402AAB20DE7EF5826EED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Detention facility</header><text>The term <term>detention facility</term> means any facility, building, or structure used to hold, process, house, or detain individuals pursuant to civil immigration authority.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H644C5990536C47F38BA4010D0B8F5A5F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expand</header><text>The term <term>expand</term> includes constructing, acquiring, leasing, retrofitting, modifying, renovating, or increasing the bed capacity of a detention facility.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2FB6F21D6BA4D7FB528C3A65A4B1A79"><enum>(5)</enum><header>New immigration model</header><text>The term <term>new immigration model</term> means any newly created, rebranded, temporary, emergency, or alternative detention framework that results in immigration detention.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8681C9EF7B834D03A07F3DF2797D2702"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

