<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H841EC2478EA245A0A32400FF5864CE15" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 998 IH: Commending President Trump, his administration, and the brave men and women of the Armed Forces, Intelligence Community, and Justice Department for the remarkable success of “Operation Absolute Resolve”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 998</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260114">January 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001051">Mr. Carter of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001099">Mr. Haridopolos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000177">Mr. Onder</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001137">Mr. Crank</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001129">Mr. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000475">Mr. Finstad</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001095">Mr. Hunt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000379">Mr. Alford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commending President Trump, his administration, and the brave men and women of the Armed Forces, Intelligence Community, and Justice Department for the remarkable success of <quote>Operation Absolute Resolve</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 3, 2026, President Donald J. Trump demonstrated extraordinary political courage by authorizing <quote>Operation Absolute Resolve</quote> to apprehend the dictator Nicolás Maduro and dismantle the command structure of the Cártel de los Soles;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Nicolás Maduro is a fugitive from justice, charged by the Department of Justice with—</text><paragraph id="H8CC72A010D2649F785949BE53B137824"><enum>(1)</enum><text>narcoterrorism conspiracy (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960a">21 U.S.C. 960a</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3FA4AB5BC1840BBA86088280D002D08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conspiracy to import cocaine (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/963">21 U.S.C. 963</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E25BD1F9D6B4E3B9AA210D7D0905672"><enum>(3)</enum><text>possession of machine guns and destructive devices (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/924">18 U.S.C. 924(c)(1)(B)(ii)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BC8D26DD2264FCCA089B0402B3001E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conspiracy to possess machine guns and destructive devices (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/924">18 U.S.C. 924(o)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas his co-conspirator and wife, Cilia Flores, was also extradited to the United States and is charged with—</text><paragraph id="HE0A7A50B669B461BAB5873B872A203FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>narcoterrorism conspiracy (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960a">21 U.S.C. 960a</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E5E19C27C94FF993B9750F7C1622A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conspiracy to import cocaine (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/963">21 U.S.C. 963</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H348324AE15F44B83BA16AB3EA1AD72EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conspiracy to possess machine guns (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/924">18 U.S.C. 924(o)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Maduro regime systematically dismantled Venezuela’s democratic institutions, beginning with the usurpation of the National Assembly in 2015, the creation of an illegitimate Constituent Assembly in 2017, and the staging of a fraudulent reelection in 2018 that was declared illegitimate by over 50 nations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2024, the regime finalized its transition to full authoritarianism when its controlled Supreme Court ratified a 15-year ban on the leading opposition candidate, María Corina Machado;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas to maintain his grip on power, the Maduro regime carried out thousands of extrajudicial killings, tortured political opponents, and terrorized the Venezuelan people, fueling the largest displacement crisis in the history of the Western Hemisphere;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Venezuela, under Maduro’s direction, provided safe harbor to foreign terrorist organizations and transnational criminal groups, allowing them to weaponize migration and flood the United States with tons of lethal narcotics; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas these state-sponsored drug trafficking operations have directly fueled the drug overdose epidemic, contributing to the deaths of tens of thousands of Americans annually: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H35A216FA544841B79D66EA3829AE43E1"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H438C9A9805CB4903968F378AEED0D6B5"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="HA7E66B1967AF45B8846258C56FCB5313"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applauds the courageous decision by commander in chief President Donald J. Trump, for his bold determination to confront the Maduro dictatorship directly, ending years of malaise and reasserting America in the Western Hemisphere;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1182B5C1319240FBB3B8486086621359"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">salutes the extraordinary bravery, professionalism, and operational effectiveness of the United States Armed Forces, the Intelligence Community, and law enforcement whose personnel successfully executed the mission to apprehend Nicolás Maduro and dismantle the command structure of the Cártel de los Soles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ED4C133CA704E22ADCD50A853F01DFD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expresses its profound gratitude to the families of the servicemembers involved, acknowledging the sacrifices made to ensure the safety of the American homeland from the threat of state-sponsored narcoterrorism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC51A55AB77F041B189346C6CAE3FD205"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirms the Monroe Doctrine and its modern version, the Trump Corollary, as the base of Western Hemispheric security declaring the United States will not tolerate the foreign military bases, intelligence assets, or proxy forces by our adversaries in the Americas;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF033F7F1268C44F4BD2EE97E28B0EDC4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recognizes that dismantling the Maduro regime is a critical national security imperative to stop the state-sponsored flow of drugs that have flooded American communities and directly contributed to the drug overdose epidemic that claims tens of thousands of American lives annually; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED7C4170BCFD48FC8E3CFBBD1452D392"><enum>(6)</enum><text>stands in solidarity with the people of Venezuela and supports a rapid, constitutional transition to free and fair elections to restore the democratic institutions dismantled by the Maduro dictatorship.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

