<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" slc-id="S1-ERN25829-VMY-G7-519"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 513 ATS: Designating November 22, 2025, as National Adoption Day and November 2025 as National Adoption Month to promote national awareness of adoption and the children awaiting families, celebrating children and families involved in adoption, and encouraging the people of the United States to secure safety, permanency, and well-being for all children. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 513</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S343">Mr. Boozman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S266">Mr. Crapo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S395">Mrs. Hyde-Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S378">Mr. Lankford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S389">Mr. Kennedy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S318">Mr. Wicker</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating November 22, 2025, as National Adoption Day and November 2025 as National Adoption Month to promote national awareness of adoption and the children awaiting families, celebrating children and families involved in adoption, and encouraging the people of the United States to secure safety, permanency, and well-being for all children. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas there are millions of unparented children in the world, including 328,947 children in the foster care system in the United States, approximately 70,421 of whom have a permanency plan of adoption as of September 30, 2024, according to the Children's Bureau of the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas many waiting children wait nearly 3 years in foster care before adoption;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, for many unparented children, the wait for a loving family, in which the children are nurtured, comforted, and protected, seems endless;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in 2023, 15,590 children were at risk of aging out of foster care by reaching adulthood without being placed in a permanent home;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, every day, loving and nurturing families are strengthened and expanded when committed and dedicated individuals make an important difference in the life of a child through adoption;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, while 1 in 3 adults in the United States have considered adoption, a majority of individuals in the United States have misperceptions about the process of adopting children from foster care and the children who are eligible for adoption;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas family reunification, kinship care, and domestic and intercountry adoption promote greater permanency and stability for children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Children’s Bureau, an office of the Administration for Children and Families within the Department of Health and Human Services, supports programs, research, and monitoring to help eliminate barriers to adoption and find permanent families for children;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas National Adoption Day is a collective national effort to find permanent, loving families for children in the foster care system;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since the first National Adoption Day in 2000, more than 85,000 children have joined permanent families on National Adoption Day;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the President traditionally issues an annual proclamation to declare the month of November as National Adoption Month, and the President has proclaimed November 2025 as National Adoption Month; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Saturday before Thanksgiving has been recognized as National Adoption Day since at least 2000, and in 2025, the Saturday before Thanksgiving is November 22: Now, therefore, be it </text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="S1"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id678b3d1ee8e5409dac8bb8f59434e5b8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates November 22, 2025, as National Adoption Day and November 2025 as National Adoption Month;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddb17321bbde94d7ea6928d68b7ad002b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes that every child should have a permanent and loving family; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6ea88b1b9f214e2dad3f1ad9e8cbad6a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages the people of the United States to consider adoption during the month of November and throughout the year. </text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

