<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE1145252D4604C21BB6A85E7A00F2012" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8725 IH: Survivor Tax Filing Simplification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8725</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to establish the Survivor Tax Portal, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBC7D1BB047B242BF8A64BB5832CC68DF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H463329226E124CDE964CBA48AB1EE407" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Survivor Tax Filing Simplification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HDC7C9DC16F5A4D21BFB44CF9D242AD94"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Survivor Tax Portal</header> 
<subsection id="H8F54B9C957D94855BF4A1410DAC29D7D">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), in consultation with the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration, shall establish an online portal (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Survivor Tax Portal</quote>) for the purpose of assisting surviving spouses and duly-appointed executors of estates of decedents in the preparation and filing of returns of tax.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBC922064F90D4F529E5BBCBE6707CF8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Features</header><text>The Survivor Tax Portal shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8F28B4D1875446B7AB4F0F3C3C33933B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide clear guidance, including through checklists, pre-populated forms, and status updates, on the preparation and filing of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8AB27FBA919542FD9A8DABA0DE99D1B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>estate tax returns with respect to decedents,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H653D8FA9636446E5B9CD0AB954134567"><enum>(B)</enum><text>joint returns under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6013">section 6013(a)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5321A34E90174D2FB38170AA9D0C8D38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>returns of tax by surviving spouses (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/2">section 2(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986),</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDB737E2BEB141F2B229B645507449CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow for the secure uploading of legal documents,</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2A207715AAC46FF80405CC71AFC89F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>integrate relevant death information maintained by the Social Security Administration,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55ED7CB0FFA44DA7AFF4C8DAE73F7C1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate adequate safeguards, in accordance with Federal law, to protect the confidentiality of any personal information, including through an identity verification system to ensure authorized access to such portal, and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB2154D18273845D68D31C8C89A98E7E8"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include such other features as the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), in consultation with the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration, determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B5B072AF89048E9B9FDD91886D26294"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Instructional guide</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall publish, and thereafter annually update, on the Survivor Tax Portal and on a publicly accessible internet website of the Internal Revenue Service, a one-page instructional guide regarding the use of, and the filing options offered on, such portal. The Commissioner of the Social Security Administration shall attach such instructional guide to any Form SSA–1099, Social Security Benefit Statement, issued following such publication.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0B0D53646BBF4083B55FDFEB72E05E1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Performance goals</header><text>Not later than 12 months following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall issue performance goals with respect to the operation and administration of the Survivor Tax Portal, including performance goals for the resolution of taxpayer inquiries on such portal within 45 days of the receipt thereof.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H14DC9DB2C6E140ABBA5853F299C92A09"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), in consultation with the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration, shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H562757EC89C849EEAE73A964371FD4D2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of grant program for recordkeeping and reporting of death information</header> 
<subsection id="H1D4BBB9713724E87B9026ECC75882170"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), in consultation with the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration, shall establish a grant program to assist States in the recordkeeping, and reporting to the Social Security Administration, of death information. In issuing such grants, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall prioritize States whose recordkeeping and reporting activities increase the efficiency of the Survivor Tax Portal established under section 2(a).</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H9239970B606E417B816CEF830871F6A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate), in consultation with the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration, shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

