<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9BB479DE02A449269A725589FB7E03A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6252 IH: Food Assurance and Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6252</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with the Director of the Census Bureau, to maintain an interagency food security measurement program to coordinate the annual collection, analysis, and reporting of data on food insecurity and hunger.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC51A17E5F45C4634B88D3B514A4478C5" style="OLC"><section id="HFD7087712BC942BFAC95A4F11E78DF25" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Food Assurance and Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H70A9AB4065A14F07BE14194BEE14FD2C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Interagency food security measurement program</header><subsection id="H2F10027C0C744CC49F7CA1F3DDE441A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interagency food security measurement program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture, in coordination with the Director of the Census Bureau, shall establish and maintain an interagency food security measurement program to coordinate the annual collection, analysis, and reporting of data on food insecurity and hunger.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA6F4FC493B5449E2AE0D49F576DBC077"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H16B7A9088525410BA1AD21505710D5AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Population Survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Current Population Survey conducted by the Bureau of the Census shall include a food security supplement consistent with the questionnaire issued in 2023 that includes the questions described in paragraph (3) for the years 2026 through 2028 and continuing thereafter with questions substantially similar to those described in paragraph (3) with any amendments to the questions predicated upon robust testing, and thorough review, public input, and Office of Management and Budget clearance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5466A92D24F940A3BE1A669678FD6D39"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agriculture annual reports</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall, with respect to the annual report issued pursuant to subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H45B36ED2B67B420BBA304BA523AC7BEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the findings related to the questions described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBCD383272DF40588842D0932D6DB286"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the report publicly available on the website of the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H455562D8CAC44AEE93F6DAE7D9E51ED2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>submit such report to Congress.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4DBC918016C46A587E8108F20AA33A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Questions described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The questions described in this paragraph are as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H1611394A0FD1408CBFF6902CF4F2D2C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Was the answer often, sometimes, or never true for you in the last 12 months for each of the following:</text><clause id="H209F49C0D5EF4313874C152E4A44DD80"><enum>(i)</enum><text>We worried whether our food would run out before we got money to buy more.</text></clause><clause id="HD0245D7BC5444C888158173864E96A05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The food that we bought just didn’t last and we didn’t have money to get more.</text></clause><clause id="H1A6C20BED3294C0BA7E41A499A977C0D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>We couldn’t afford to eat balanced meals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F733E4ACB854002AB7FB9DBBBC0E9B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the last 12 months, did you or other adults in the household ever cut the size of your meals or skip meals because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE3C4C069142400093D72559B8E6ACBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the answer is yes with respect to subparagraph (B), how often did this happen—almost every month, some months but not every month, or in only 1 or 2 months?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F1EF15D8F814AE78E643AA87819C12C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>In the last 12 months, did you ever eat less than you felt you should because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3A2590626CB48F0BD3728C141D99E17"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In the last 12 months, were you ever hungry, but didn’t eat, because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0501874DDCBB49F7A97E59A0B3E457A6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>In the last 12 months, did you lose weight because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22E39C45FF46403DB782A365633FF88D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>In the last 12 months, did you or other adults in your household ever not eat for a whole day because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCED321180749444698A8B655E4B7FE12"><enum>(H)</enum><text>If the answer is yes to subparagraph (G), how often did this happen—almost every month, some months but not every month, or in only 1 or 2 months?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF69751CA68D40678DEC55C15AEBBB60"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a household that includes children ages 0 to 17, the following additional questions:</text><clause id="H16F5E23881E34FE1BD1F00D9C31E1845"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Was the answer often, sometimes, or never true for you in the last 12 months for each of the following:</text><subclause id="HF8AA08741C804CE98D900DAB46385FF3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">We relied on only a few kinds of low-cost food to feed our children because we were running out of money to buy food.</text></subclause><subclause id="H733E0D8E2C3341B19FC36E9C6238747E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">We couldn’t feed our children a balanced meal, because we couldn’t afford that.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5299CC6C9F954199B8541435BE510C50"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The children were not eating enough because there wasn’t enough money for food.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCCD95FA431414DE9B23E80C6DA4A8DFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the last 12 months, did you ever cut the size of any of the children’s meals because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></clause><clause id="HCF9A2F14C71E41499D0336B9030654D9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the last 12 months, were the children ever hungry because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></clause><clause id="H334A55487012469DAB022988D2DE5883"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the last 12 months, did any of the children ever skip a meal because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></clause><clause id="H0458D341214440DCBCE746E4000FA702"><enum>(v)</enum><text>If the answer is yes to clause (iv), how often did this happen—almost every month, some months but not every month, or in only 1 or 2 months?</text></clause><clause id="H46A0805B4B634135B81B32B41F13D1E9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>In the last 12 months, did any of the children ever not eat for a whole day because there wasn’t enough money for food?</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8B2ECEA3D6F4419919A6D47E8CE41BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="HBF5BBA959DCB466B9630F90BC464CC63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B93B24097614F0EB751731B79E78906"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer</header><text>Of the funds appropriated under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide funding for the costs incurred by the Census Bureau in conducting the annual food security supplement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

