<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26117-6DL-P4-TCK"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3683 IS: Stop Excessive Force in Immigration Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3683</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260115">January 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S432">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish clear standards, training requirements, and reporting relating to immigration enforcement personnel.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H0867448CE07F4DBAB13FD8D7E6F9445D"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB7F13B2662D24B1C82E1ED73278B2D27"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Excessive Force in Immigration Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H50771CBBAB6C490D9E516636E7F63879"><enum>2.</enum><header>Enforcement standards</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter 9 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1351">8 U.S.C. 1351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 287 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B387DFA96D8497EAF8F98EF23CEF991"><section id="H247C047688BD4859B34893FC6DE7DB55"><enum>287A.</enum><header>Federal immigration enforcement</header><subsection id="H1543FD4665FB4779BE7CE5DAC93AEF25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of force</header><paragraph id="H93228882680C4F0ABD87336197DD58FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of non-deadly force standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All Federal immigration enforcement personnel may only use non-deadly force if—</text><subparagraph id="HE004A9DE084B460FB8D8A5B0261200C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no reasonably effective, safe, and feasible alternative appears to exist to bring an unlawful situation safely and effectively under control, after taking into account relevant factors, such as age, injury, disability, and size of the subject;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C72292A86FC4546A7F848BC0AD9046C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all reasonable efforts are made to de-escalate tensions prior to using force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id700e12da2b324f00a9c1edd1dfe10e06"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the level of force used is proportional to the seriousness of the actual or threatened resistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E7F4FB06EC44346A324FC58BBE0E238"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the risk of injury to a third person is minimized while using non-deadly force.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8E591BA67A744E75B64DA9F13A1B76EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of deadly force standard</header><text>Any use of deadly force by Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall conform to the Department of Justice Policy on the Use of Deadly Force and Prohibited Restraint Techniques set forth in section 1–16.200 of the Justice Manual.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8a6d6561646841dc8d8957d8fd044cd3"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reasonableness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reasonableness of a particular use of force shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1aeb6a0040244e0903c59d7f2dbb055"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be judged from the perspective of a reasonable officer on the scene; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0e01828e61a340ac9264e7de22bc9918"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider that law enforcement personnel are often forced to make split-second decisions about the amount of force necessary in a particular situation in circumstances that are tense, uncertain, and rapidly evolving.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H25AC59BD0AB84D27B61545AC4C90B567"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Retreat</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida0a3d72f942544d2963cffe87b7bf261"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph, the term <term>retreat</term> does not mean tactical repositioning or other de-escalation tactics.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91998a4045d746e1aebed846e62be5f0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel who make or attempt to make an arrest—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf0da202322244ea296204c215b0fc0a3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">need not retreat or desist from their efforts by reason of the resistance or threatened resistance of the person being arrested; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4d98909264464dff867d9b0f0476fa87"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be deemed an aggressor or lose the right to self-defense by the use of force when no reasonably effective, safe, and feasible alternative appears to exist, as determined under paragraph (1)(A), to effect an arrest, prevent escape, or overcome resistance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80D9804AF9DF4F0DA4D934D91DB3555E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Affirmative duty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel have an affirmative duty—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd89c7791e0934ca9b5525c970b9c8008"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to intervene to prevent or stop, as appropriate, any other Federal immigration enforcement personnel from engaging in excessive force or any other use of force that violates the Constitution of the United States, this Act or any other Federal law, or applicable policies regarding the reasonable use of force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8150da3d2c6b428c949743607dfefdff"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after witnessing the excessive use of force to report such action to their chain of command or the Department of Homeland Security’s Office of the Inspector General; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f5a34f295a64d858d64d26a937062b5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to recognize and act upon their duty to request and render medical aid, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E57B9E9BCDD4D3BB783F9AD9CECEF9A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Masks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel may not wear masks or face coverings unless a supervisory officer provides written approval for such use because—</text><subparagraph id="HB3BBCF02AB224351BAAD12250A8565D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the target of their enforcement activity poses a national security threat;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD014E624D984D60A9A7DA5C9736C7CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is a high likelihood that such personnel need to maintain anonymity for future covert operations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64744FF55CB943488D1112FD3A119BAC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">masks are necessary to protect such personnel’s physical health from environmental hazards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D4218ACD0AA4FE79CD5FF2E166D5F32"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Identification</header><subparagraph id="H0722E89E655649788A5B805D35C99379"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall wear a uniform or other identification clearly displaying the name of their agency or other indication that they are Federal immigration enforcement personnel unless—</text><clause id="H5FC03281E934464C9BB98232123F09B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the target of their enforcement activity poses a public safety threat or a national security threat;</text></clause><clause id="H46A970417A8748AAB14CA6AE4F6875FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not wearing such identification is necessary to safely carry out the enforcement activity; and</text></clause><clause id="H876745ACD5CF48539041C3FCFD45DC59"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such personnel receive prior written approval to not wear such identification from a supervisory officer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H117CA4EF58B44E589FDC9D959C14D668"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>All uniforms of Federal immigration enforcement personnel may not exhibit the term <quote>Police</quote> or any other identifier that may result in such personnel being misidentified as local police officers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A6BDA871C56475290D46644CDE92E10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Restricted equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel are prohibited from using or being equipped with noise flash diversionary devices (also known as flashbangs), rubber bullets, pepper balls, and tear gas unless such personnel—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7aec61827da14b5a8d64cded2c23cd63"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are trained and certified for the use of the specified equipment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED7E5CBEC0BB444EB3233A15AA501959"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are carrying out an immigration enforcement operation that involves—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0832116581f04bfcb9496976354207b5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the arrest of a person who—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc529b39c36134f378fafcdfc3f9db3db"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in the presence or view of such personnel; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id13310110681642339ad371b85881e632"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is entering or attempting to enter the United States in violation of any law; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F6FC553F29C480BBDC6BFEA73BC9245"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an enforcement target who is presenting a public safety threat or a national security threat; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5ade9e321bbd4d45ae8ad99c2ea69686"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to circumstances described in paragraph (2)(B), have completed a tactical action plan (or a contingent tactical action plan in the event such personnel unexpectedly encounter their target and do not have sufficient time to seek additional approval without jeopardizing their ability to apprehend the target) that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1d505c9e4b8943acb0b5e3840dba9227"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been approved by their supervisor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc02a0be685214853b910fb82a17a0ccb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">outlines the equipment they expect to use in the operation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id91d88f6c11074c5fbcbc983f58a8a217"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides justification for the need for such equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEFD487144AD4A3FB933B7BD71DAF522"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Backup team</header><paragraph id="H4B1643DA238A401B8EC5BF26490917E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any operation that does not qualify for an exception under subsection (b) may maintain a trained and certified backup team equipped with restricted non-deadly equipment that could be deployed whenever the safety of the primary Federal immigration enforcement personnel or others is at risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1AF5F6EA326499A997467E4571759FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>First amendment activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The safety of Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall not be determined to be at risk solely due to lawful protest or other activities protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAFC51A34BED4B0EB5C7ADEAE73FE9D6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Investigations</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide17f5ab90131437f9f17bb3f7809d362"><enum>(1)</enum><header>By Federal authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties and the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security and the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall investigate and, if necessary, discipline Federal immigration enforcement personnel, within their primary jurisdiction, who violate the requirements under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46ca0f616c094b87a62b7f7c66b615da"><enum>(2)</enum><header>By state or local authorities</header><text>The Department of Homeland Security and the Department of Justice should allow State and local authorities to investigate violations of law relating to any excessive use of force by Federal immigration enforcement personnel that results in death or serious bodily injury.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF801CAA12A024544A01BA621D41B91C9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Body and vehicle camera requirements</header><paragraph id="HF0D522BB57884C4C9959600CCAAD6C8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Stop Excessive Force in Immigration Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop and disseminate a Department-wide directive requiring the use of—</text><subparagraph id="HAE5F587A89324D80A83A262B7907BDB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">body worn cameras by all Federal immigration enforcement personnel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66F26CE2DF4747ECB2AB6E797DB83287"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dashboard cameras for all vehicles being used in Federal immigration enforcement operations and associated recording protocols.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E6C5E360A854EEF8927DA0959F1DD1B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Principles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the directive required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H3ABCE5E6C054409280444C2C7858B4D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">benchmarks for implementing the use of body worn cameras by Federal immigration enforcement personnel and dashboard cameras for vehicles being used for Federal immigration enforcement operations to conform with a standard that cameras are on by default and may only be turned off in certain circumstances;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB599AE578F1404F8CC55170453BF0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training requirements, procedures, and best practices for the use of body worn cameras and dashboard cameras; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA852AD6E52CC4E42B36A9086D8E476B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">plans to publicize the directive and the requirements under this section to ensure Federal immigration enforcement personnel and other impacted individuals are notified of the directive and policies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF63BE00B5564E50B3F4BC804FE09748"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The directive required under paragraph (1) shall not apply to any Federal immigration enforcement personnel who operate in a location where the Secretary of Homeland Security carries out redundant video monitoring or video surveillance that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id899b9acf03ee4ac198a47418545938a0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is maintained in good working order; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5e7c99775fd7470b80b4169e659f94eb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides video footage of a quality that is the same or better than that which would be captured by a body worn camera or a dashboard camera.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9734EC23CF54EE8A380A2D0108711AC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Retention of footage</header><subparagraph id="H52071AA4D0164AD38A5B27000875EC7B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), video footage from body worn cameras and dashboard cameras shall be retained by the Department of Homeland Security for 1 year after the date on which it was recorded and then permanently deleted.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBE9745402C34B5D9ACFFDC7681E97B8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional retention requirements</header><text>Notwithstanding the retention and deletion requirements under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HF1B4535FEB9441FF8583FAD856526D4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the video footage referred to in subparagraph (A) shall be automatically retained for not less than 3 years if the video footage captures an interaction or event involving—</text><subclause id="H26E451A016514299B61F7F250FAD0985"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any use of force; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HC10A2B0685B549E0BCB110AE22732415"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an encounter involving a registered complaint by a subject of the video footage;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1CE05F41BC2E4225AF30C5DA7118E23F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such video footage shall be retained for not less than 3 years if a longer retention period is voluntarily requested by—</text><subclause id="H1B4B0273CC234BE398E62D3492275EBF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal immigration enforcement personnel whose body cameras recorded the video footage if such personnel reasonably assert—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0ce141ecec734789be8c2be60443879a"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the video footage has evidentiary or exculpatory value in an ongoing investigation; or</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8d3473e517a04f59a660dc458aba1ba0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">they are subjects of the video footage and they reasonably assert the video footage has evidentiary or exculpatory value;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HE7730815CBA845E5A96BFD70B7075E80"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any superior officer of the Federal immigration enforcement personnel whose body cameras recorded the video footage or who are subjects of the video footage if the superior officer reasonably asserts the video footage has evidentiary or exculpatory value;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E540C174C9A40DF99B294FD9E68996E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any uniformed law enforcement officer if the video footage is being retained solely and exclusively for law enforcement training purposes;</text></subclause><subclause id="H00BAA93BC5F84442A78330C73DBC7FDB"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any member of the public who is a subject of the video footage;</text></subclause><subclause id="H73103E568AFB425B9D3EEBB5075D339D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>any parent or legal guardian of a minor who is a subject of the video footage; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H8D8F49CE2196480D9A72084181709E2B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a spouse, next of kin, or legally authorized designee of a deceased person who is a subject of the video footage; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA92B6070461C4D8698C190367A40B220"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">video footage may not be discarded until the conclusion of any investigation or lawsuit to which such video footage is relevant.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05B557D53C324D0C9E223FD3FC9D0A8F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Right to inspect</header><text>During the retention periods described in paragraph (4), the right to inspect, but not retain or in any matter alter, the body camera footage shall be given to—</text><subparagraph id="H7F846CC2AA6B45919117A13B0C72CB31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any individual who is a subject of body camera video footage and his or her designated legal counsel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H659349B7530D4CB9AC77102F9A2DCB32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any parent of a minor who is a subject of the body camera video footage and his or her designated legal counsel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B7A26E60D624E479FB1025944A5734E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the spouse, next of kin, or legally authorized designee of a deceased subject of body camera video footage and his or her designated legal counsel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0B47A11BFE54D94A804263B85ADDC6B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel whose body camera recorded the video footage and their designated legal counsel, subject to the limitations and restrictions under this subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3F2DF32674649E5A9EC0EE677F99D82"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the superior officers of the personnel whose body cameras recorded the video footage, subject to the limitations and restrictions under this subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE36D9E1A2E5482BA7F4991288CD82C7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any defense counsel who claims, pursuant to a written affidavit, to have a reasonable basis for believing a video may contain evidence that exculpates his or her client;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5417E66CC8BA496CB2A5F6B4C69190AE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any Member of Congress representing the district in which the operation in the video took place; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H264C6312BCB04922870ACA2C3ED08EED"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Member of Congress who sits on a congressional committee with jurisdiction over the operation depicted in such video footage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2389490C0AAA4894BAE58882D7097ECB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall receive training, not less frequently than annually, on use of force policies and related legal updates, including training—</text><paragraph id="HA4093A7912504034B2A54D5F37DCFC6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that reinforces the appropriate exercise of discretion and judgment in using non-deadly and deadly force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1BABC53AF3E4223B3FAEE8AEE9964BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that provides techniques for the use of and reinforce the importance of de-escalation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC709EC29EC2428297237C2A6D9255C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on compliance with the protections contained in the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States for journalists, protesters, and those who assemble;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2795CCA36164403866E14B58807E46A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>on compliance with the protections contained in the Fourth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States against unreasonable searches and seizures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CF861DDAB374A70BA5D0E044E72F8B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>that reinforces the illegality of determining immigration enforcement targets primarily based on race;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA15B5E08924EAFA861FF2DCF3D3A6F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that reinforces the affirmative duty of Federal immigration enforcement personnel—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbbde35600e7b4328aaf7a6ceec9997b9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to intervene to prevent or stop, as appropriate, any fellow officer from engaging in excessive force or any other use of force that violates the Constitution of the United States, any Federal law, or any applicable policy on the reasonable use of force; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF47EBFCE6CF44A84B03F162E77ED88A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to request and render medical aid, as appropriate, whenever needed; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48C92FEAA93A424097DE51E914F4DE7B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on documenting and keeping records of practice for immigration enforcement operations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E5B0C760F0E45CDBCFA5C5480D631A7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Requiring notification for local law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall notify local law enforcement of impending operations in their respective jurisdictions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H755D9392FF064508A6B3B0449945330E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>DHS reporting requirements</header><text>Beginning not later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Stop Excessive Force in Immigration Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to Congress semiannual reports regarding the criteria Federal immigration enforcement personnel use to determine whether an immigrant poses a public safety threat or a national security threat, including—</text><paragraph id="H809D24EBBA3C41C0BA7DF6802ADB8270"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report detailing instances where deadly or non-deadly force was used, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id668729948ecd4fbeb5c12f554bb319f7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the level of public safety or national security threat posed by the target;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfd5d5ddfb7194613a60f27483eda7f7d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reason deadly or non-deadly force was administered;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6127a8d5ed454eceb09f904905e61954"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific instances where deadly or non-deadly force was improperly administered; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1aba678104074f5dad864d7d3e370a0b"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the measures the Department of Homeland Security took to ensure accountability for the improper use of deadly or non-deadly force;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA1C6A3057604B7BA5ADEAF587FDD12D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report detailing instances of assaults against Federal immigration enforcement personnel, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id401043294ab64c3cb1f8b4ad841566dc"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of personnel involved in immigration enforcement operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbc317264e3204c61b1b05c1a91a4a54f"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of assaults against Federal immigration enforcement personnel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8c0264ece37a47a5a35e4a632c054ddc"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details regarding the severity of such assaults;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5D5698B1C974DEE9E2D94EBC9E43227"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a classified report detailing instances in which Federal immigration enforcement personnel operated without identification; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H119BC4E91B7C425F942DD4349137C213"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report regarding the frequency of Federal immigration enforcement personnel using facial coverings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H12737936E67849A898A463E0DF46E302"><enum>(i)</enum><header>DOJ reporting requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall submit a semiannual report to Congress that describes—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id4ab489e39d184f1d9b6ed5f4acf46470"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and circumstances of incidents of individuals falsely impersonating Federal immigration enforcement personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="idc99e1cd57d45431b9cf5bf768895fb95"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public safety impact of such incidents; and</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="id885e364975c04615a3abcfed54380777"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the Department of Justice is combating such impersonations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7C62B2F18584D498F1B8A0007C83309"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Databases</header><paragraph id="H4712DC7CCA034F9BBBDDC5AE5C39C1F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training and certification database</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id55cc474845e04080a6d6bbe62546c176"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall maintain a database that—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5a4c9d27d72140919d05a4d4483833f7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies all Federal immigration enforcement personnel who have completed all necessary training and certification requirements for using the equipment that is restricted under subsection (b); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebffb10a98b644cbbad59d1fb7afe6c4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is accessible to the supervisors of such personnel.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB63F5785BB894BE9A9FB076F98B9BEE7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Supervisors of Federal immigration enforcement personnel shall be held accountable if—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2dbab79881a54a569b7f9f0a8abce5ae"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any such personnel use equipment restricted under subsection (b) without receiving the necessary training and certification; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3f7b4c1310234097b384592d089f2b9c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">they improperly approve the use of such equipment by subordinate Federal immigration enforcement personnel.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H9E72A6459D2F4DB2B90EBD1946AC74C7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports database</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf35439df6a4f4860b394e6e0708d5055"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall create a searchable database that includes all reports generated by Federal immigration enforcement personnel, including—</text><clause commented="no" id="HB1CF0B07BA754722AB1570778B105D17"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of force incident reporting system, which shall contain records for all deployments of force by such personnel;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD8DD0265098D4AAFB8C984FC1A27EAA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>significant incident reports, which shall contain records for all operational anomalies or escalations involving such personnel; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H19219395AB224349AD28A05477C852DD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reports involving alleged violations of civil rights or civil liberties, which shall contain records of all allegations of abuse or misconduct by such personnel.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8DD588321E4C4610B70A0A0C190E8F27"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><clause id="H4C136BA73A8A4F17AF4FBFE90D525A20"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Unredacted availability</header><text>Entries from the database created pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be accessible by—</text><subclause id="HE5E6E30D1F604379878383AC9F5FC9F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any Member of Congress representing the district in which the reported incident occurred; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HED436D6F44C24BA3A7ADE42E90DA5612"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any Member of Congress who sits on a congressional committee with jurisdiction over the personnel who are the subjects of such entries.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6AE2C0FF41DD47B2800E859298A1F8B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Redacted availability</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall make available to the public a version of the database created pursuant to subparagraph (A) that redacts any sensitive, personal information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC466F0139F3447FCB90F7474F828445B"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE861AA6FEC884A72A55AFFEB2A19C916"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal immigration enforcement personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal immigration enforcement personnel</term> includes any immigration agent or officer who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1094335d4ff4edf87ae28b46a599a16"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is using the authority to conduct arrests or enforcement actions under section 236 or 287; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idffc8e239d06f43e589e8ee0525b5bf8d"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides support to the personnel who are conducting an enforcement action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB4397236C0B4AA2AC6D5F625BC43085"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National security threat</header><text>The term <term>national security threat</term> means any threat posed by transnational criminal organizations, cartels, human trafficking organizations, foreign terrorist organizations, and gangs with a demonstrated international reach, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70E75CAC6B19403C9C58DE62157B6F7C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public safety threat</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public safety threat</term> means an imminent and substantial threat to the safety of others posed by an individual, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H9C92CC9F778149A4A2E05FB2E38A3508"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, or in the amendments made by this Act, may be construed—</text><paragraph id="HA2B862BA14CE4F0A9770411105D073CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide Federal immigration enforcement personnel additional authority to exercise excessive or deadly force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A13E57DA64B4A96819071FDFA9DEDDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent Federal immigration enforcement personnel from taking action necessary to ensure the safety of themselves, other personnel, or bystanders; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47218ACC9B144A0B9B724FD600011317"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require State or local law enforcement to assist or to be involved in Federal immigration enforcement activities.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

