<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26G20-3Y5-RK-5KD"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4858 IS: Alaska National Guard Rural Community Revival Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4858</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S383">Mr. Sullivan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide for a National Guard Rural Revival and Modernization Plan.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alaska National Guard Rural Community Revival Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id11e828accfe44854a3b87e3fae490425"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Guard rural community revival</header><subsection id="id12e7f6147bdb4db2999f17eb1db6d069"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy and implementation plan required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army, in coordination with the Chief of the National Guard Bureau, shall develop a comprehensive strategy and roadmap to optimize Army National Guard readiness, force posture, and infrastructure in remote or isolated areas to include the Arctic. The strategy shall take into consideration the posture and plans of the United States Northern Command as well as Golden Dome for America in the assessment and development of the strategy, to ensure infrastructure investments meet homeland defense requirements and maximize operational effectiveness. The strategy shall be known as the <quote>Army National Guard Rural Revival and Modernization Plan</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Plan</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id2d854c9e1dec43139e966d803fe8e413"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements of the Plan</header><text>The Plan required under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following:</text><paragraph id="id74f67b1242e34fe79197d42d8a07db5a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Infrastructure review</header><text>A comprehensive audit and assessment of all National Guard armories, readiness centers, training support centers, and ranges within remote or isolated areas. The audit should include an assessment of necessary facilities improvements and include a plan for—</text><subparagraph id="ida8dcdb815b8948658311f5a1e70d9725"><enum>(A)</enum><text>joint-force and extreme-cold-weather tactical training, including integrated survival, mobility, logistics, and combat operations specific to degraded and contested Arctic environments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb9e4864894494f9d9623fa09e29d7592"><enum>(B)</enum><text>forward-operating logistical hubs, cold-weather equipment staging, and intra-theater supply-chain distribution points;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id757f4cfe6f15422889434d0de65d543b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>emergency management, disaster response, and homeland defense staging zones; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id93bc9a310927429dbb7fd7727416d279"><enum>(D)</enum><text>communications nodes and remote command-and-control capabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0697dcde0a5b436e87e302af58964755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>End-strength and billet optimization strategy</header><text>A feasible plan to address and fill critically vacant, unassigned, or under-strength National Guard billets within the designated regions to meet increasing operational tempo (OPTEMPO). The optimization plan shall include—</text><subparagraph id="id00849e123feb468993ac02531cad0604"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of recruitment and retention barriers unique to rural, isolated, or high-cost geographic areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id139f5953a9d04cccb90a91fa795fac4d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a targeted marketing, recruitment, and localized incentives framework, including specialized remote duty allowances, signing bonuses, and educational stipends, designed to source personnel directly from local and rural communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb503ab02baa453f808f32d4884c85e7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a potential rotational assignment framework to temporarily bridge immediate operational readiness gaps while permanent personnel pipelines are materialized to include associated funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16b01d59c49b43168f7c1b95ef5c3f10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Dual-use center modernization blueprint</header><text>A comprehensive capitalization and modernization plan for existing multi-mission, dual-use facilities. The blueprint shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd4c562a4bc94455a9d8ef554c349ff20"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify specific structural and technological upgrades necessary to sustain prolonged, multi-domain operations in austere environments, predicated on a comprehensive cyber-resilience and vulnerability assessment of the existing operational technology at installations and facilities, with an emphasis on—</text><clause id="ide85cec5005e946c78fdba937aa9a68b7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grid resilience, microgrid integration, and continuous primary power capabilities under extreme environmental degradation;</text></clause><clause id="id3c019c95697e4afca758ab5ebbb1a9cd"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communications modernization, including secure tactical satellite integration and redundant high-latitude network systems;</text></clause><clause id="id23ee7e46c56748bebf566f843a9af066"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>hangar, maintenance bay, and cold-storage runway and housing upgrades to handle modern tactical, rotary-wing, and autonomous aerial platforms, and personnel; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76602a9fdf92467591cb3d34805e731d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dual-use airfield infrastructure reutilization and expansion of existing runways to accommodate modern military and civilian aircraft; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id31a06622063c4ac0a97a739d77d5ab1d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure all proposed command and control (C2) and facility infrastructure is engineered to operate seamlessly within Denied, Degraded, Intermittent, or Limited environments, incorporating resilient closed and restricted network architectures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id87dccc1b10f9402799dcff5fa0627316"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Commingling and private-Sector leveraging planning framework</header> <text>In developing the facility expansion and modernization elements of the Plan, the Secretary of the Army shall evaluate and identify opportunities to leverage enhanced use lease (EUL) authorities or enter into public-private partnerships. The Plan shall—</text>
        <paragraph id="idb9043cd988b74a37ae3f16e524e6a723">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>include specific strategies to co-locate dual-use commercial, community, or telecommunications infrastructure within National Guard footprints to lower Federal infrastructure cost premiums and enhance installation resilience; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="idaded4f03f7c1478cbc6d4862d5d8520a">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>establish or clarify statutory data-sharing authorities and indemnification for the rapid exchange of cyber threat intelligence, risk assessments, and incident response data between the Department of Defense and the co-located commercial entities.</text>
        </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id500c7c789f9e4573a7ce8905eb1f4bfd" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Direct funding and minor construction threshold recommendations</header><text>The Plan shall include an assessment of funding mechanisms and potential legislative adjustments required to execute the infrastructure developments, conversions, and modifications identified under the Plan, including an evaluation of how the Secretary may utilize funds available for unspecified minor military construction under section 2805 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="ide6abc364bf2c40a6a142bcbea59e14ce"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Congressional briefings and reporting</header><paragraph id="idd37ee6aef2fb45d4ac7f21b8fe049fa1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial briefing</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Army and the Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall provide an interim briefing to the congressional defense committees on the initial findings of the armory audit and the initial personnel recruitment milestones.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3ef0ea323be34417aceee682ca90e76c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Concurrently with the submission of the President’s budget request for the upcoming fiscal year following the completion of the Plan, the Secretary of the Army shall submit to the congressional defense committees a formal report detailing the finalized strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id24d23f0ab7a54a1b82b41987db46988d"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees defined</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

