<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2AE720EFE6A4E749C906589584BF30E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8283 IH: Deterring American AI Model Theft Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8283</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent foreign adversaries from threatening the national security of the United States by extracting key technical features of closed-source, American-owned artificial intelligence models, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7E1F9C89BD2F467286F4DDBCE5A19EF0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA0DB9374D2F84F838EEA0DA06091C758" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Deterring American AI Model Theft Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H51162338769F4F16BFF5A6C2B000EFAE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDE21570B16D943FD808864F703A1D47A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>artificial intelligence (AI) models owned by United States private sector companies are essential for advancing United States economic and national security interests;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3EE19C4D86F4E0DB8D8CD1786E32EB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>many of the most advanced AI models owned by United States companies are <quote>closed-source models</quote> whose unique technical characteristics are not openly shared or published;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD21F4D707DFD4A1D9455DA17EFBBB315"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the unauthorized acquisition of model capabilities, such as model weights, model architectures, and other technical characteristics of closed-source AI models by entities of concern through model extraction attacks represents a threat to the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States, as well as the intellectual property rights and economic competitiveness of United States companies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7807CE95CA8743BF80A0F8F9BCA6F155"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Government, in cooperation with private owners of closed-source AI models, should take steps to identify, punish, and deter model extraction attacks on the protected capabilities of closed-source models by entities of concern;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9D60D158EE04850957CC3AA118588A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">model extraction attacks against American closed-source AI models allow foreign adversaries a short cut to acquiring advanced AI capabilities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE37DAF22F99F4A81A1BE1AC734B9B7A2"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized model training practices that adhere to the terms of service or are otherwise consistent with contractual terms set by the owners of closed-source AI models are a legitimate research method that play an important role in AI research and are fundamentally distinct from model extraction attacks defined in this Act.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H9861126AED5D40F995F6C062939342DD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H04277614205843ADA6CF2EC9B0567F43"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC4EACA81436E4867B07E95CB325A7896"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6E7B1E165EA4E98A097F7762AD2857B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs in the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H102D1C19075D48E1A07E23D38933CF80"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Closed-source AI model</header><text>The term <term>closed-source AI model</term> means any artificial intelligence model with the following characteristics:</text> <subparagraph id="H976E434AE18F498BB6BE6828638BC4B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proprietary key technical information such as underlying model weights that are necessary to reproduce and independently recreate the model that are not willingly shared with third parties or otherwise made publicly available by the owner of the model.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6EF61AA55D724B0696CEE627900A5F07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Access and use governed by terms of service or contractual agreements that are established by the owner of the model.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE0EC9D50D2E44708419ACE68F5903F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access that is provided via an Application Program Interface (API) or other consumer-facing, owner-controlled interfaces without enabling third parties to obtain, modify, or host the closed-source AI model on their own data servers or other technology unless specifically authorized by the owner of the closed-source AI model.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4440B6F9447C427393C815F981C6681E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B326A594157441EB04F1D352BE5D3EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China, including the Hong Kong and Macau Special Administrative Regions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF66B903FC6C64D3DAAADDAC3688E5E5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Russian Federation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H153B154C096549AC8DA74B3C95FBEF78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other foreign country—</text> 
<clause id="HC896A76B66BA46A6BE89F56A1AB1BFE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>listed in Country Group D:5 under Supplement No. 1 to part 740 of the Export Administration Regulations, as published on January 1, 2026, that is designated by the Secretary of State as a country of concern for purposes of this section and for which notice of such designation has been published in the Federal Register; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9286C96D7C174524B322391232DCB619"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designated by the Secretary of State pursuant to the assessment described in subsection (b) or (e) of section 4 of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEC8985F3C5B1499DB54C8018F370F804"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Entity of concern</header><text>The term <term>entity of concern</term> means any foreign person or entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD15F852CFA3C41A6BC912FEBD661F578"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located or headquartered in, or the ultimate parent company of which is headquartered in, a country of concern;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H560C975A14474AD8937A870C1FC2B2EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is operating under the direction or control of any entity located or headquartered in, or the ultimate parent company of which is headquartered in, a country of concern; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H16700E73F7624BF88C3A70E0838FA84C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is conducting or attempting to conduct a model extraction attack against closed-source AI models owned by United States persons and outside of authorized model training practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45FA12BABE1C44E692709E53F97C6F06"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Export</header><text>The term <term>export</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1742(3) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF3333D4FB4D4312A3F9A0A88DD9E222"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EEDD1600B8A47779E1A9CDC7EFA09F0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Fraudulent account network provider</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDDB99A4721D64E1E8DC856D46523CA6C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fraudulent account network provider</term> means any foreign entity that knowingly and intentionally creates, obtains, maintains, sells, brokers, or otherwise provides access to accounts that allow entities of concern to access closed-source AI models that they would otherwise be prohibited from accessing due to location restrictions in the terms of service or contractual agreements created by the owner of the closed-source AI model.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA57748DCDDE2415E96C2945ECF7A6289"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity that creates or transmits location information to enable persons within countries of concern to access the internet for purposes of freedom of expression is not considered, on the basis of this activity alone, a fraudulent account network provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EB46B8AA89E46B9B59B1D16FB61C59E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Good</header><text>The term <term>good</term> has the meaning given that term in section 16 of the Export Administration Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-appendix" parsable-cite="usc-appendix/50/2415">50 U.S.C. App. 2415</external-xref>)(as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7BE094BBFC934B089AC71A417AF2DD16"><enum>(9)</enum><header>In-country transfer</header><text>The term <term>in-country transfer</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1742(6) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3D8F8D65E40417BAF33F9CB2E4B0530"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Item</header><text>The term <term>item</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1742(7) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801(7)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCAABFD9E74D046A7A9A5F6DADC02AEB6"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Model extraction attack</header> <subparagraph id="HF9A11F7B6B8041529C3189D24DFF689B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>model extraction attack</term> means the unauthorized extracting of a closed-source AI model’s capabilities to replicate, develop, train, or improve another AI model, where such querying—</text> 
<clause id="HD4AFCF20F4D448B49CC0FFBB3F7945E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>circumvents technical, contractual, or other access controls, identity verification requirements, or geographic access restrictions implemented by the model’s owner;</text></clause> <clause id="HA95436AC00D340DA8D20E037F46B73FB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is conducted through fraudulent, misrepresented, or unauthorized credentials; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEDE2F864B48C4DAC9C0BA8226CECF8C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>violates the terms, conditions, or restrictions governing access to or use of the model, as established by the owner or authorized provider, that specifically prohibit the use of model outputs or interactions to replicate, develop, train, or improve another AI model.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H63C26A13E92846C3B4D2A3F20D3B3768"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inference of purpose</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the purpose of querying may be inferred from the totality of circumstances, including—</text> 
<clause id="H583BA5387C5B4803B6451D3500330666"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the volume, structure, pattern, coordination, or timing of the querying activity;</text></clause> <clause id="HA8F58AB6F0FE4B6F9287F694963CF79D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the concentration of queries on specific model capabilities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE404C384219A4082BF3661BE06D7032A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the use of multiple accounts in a coordinated matter; or</text></clause> <clause id="H9F64EDB66C354354B6C17F29E97FE11C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the correlation of querying activity within the development timeline of another AI model.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE0CAA81C40643DFB2620A58F157EFB8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Model training activities conducted in compliance with the terms, conditions, and restrictions governing access to and use of the closed-source AI model, or otherwise conducted within a permitted exception or the express authorization of the owner of the closed-source AI model, are not model extraction attacks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3477E8906E6C4E3FAA2779A365978C8D"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Operating Committee for Export Policy</header><text>The term <term>Operating Committee for Export Policy</term> means the Operating Committee for Export Policy referred to in section 1763(c) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4822">50 U.S.C. 4822(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2BB65D9422B43999139E41ECA2CAF15"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Owner</header><text>The term <term>owner</term> means, with respect to a closed-source AI model, the person or entity that—</text> <subparagraph id="HF229C1FFA4524D7291A2A1A10517769D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>holds intellectual property rights (including trade secret, copyright, patent, or other proprietary rights), contractual rights, or a combination thereof, sufficient to authorize or restrict third-party access to, use of, extraction from, or reproduction of such closed-source AI model, or any version, instance, or deployment thereof, whether such rights were obtained through development, acquisition, assignment, license, or otherwise; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F3709FE408E4DC4BF81A7C9FD04831F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a United States person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81A4E01DA6DC46278E71793E4C182F9B"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Reexport</header><text>The term <term>reexport</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1742(9) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801(9)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H094B94A3E4C241B9899571BAA4D8C2B4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Assessment of model extraction attacks and fraudulent account network providers</header> 
<subsection id="HF6F10611372241FAA48D566817EFFBA6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall complete an assessment to determine—</text> <paragraph id="HF2AEF683ECAF442197A7D49ABC2524BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which, if any, entities of concern have conducted or are currently conducting model extraction attacks against closed-source AI models owned by United States entities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D85BF37592F446ABFD6233AD6846286"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which, if any, entities of concern are fraudulent account network providers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H025EBB5968BB4914AD396B7FC6059E41"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Matters To be included</header> <text>The assessment required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text>
                <paragraph id="H77F5B0170D3B43D0A884FF05878EF609">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>A determination of which entities of concern—</text> <subparagraph id="HF4F2513313AA4D86A45C06446D3F3AC3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>have either previously or are currently engaging in model extraction attacks; or</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H7763E91479A74A489C923C6EBD550148">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>are fraudulent account network providers.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5842D51D2731439D8258BEB24BBAD178"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination of which, if any, countries model extraction attacks have originated from and where fraudulent account network providers exist.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H8CEFA501355449738F1D146328445658">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of which, if any, agencies or instrumentalities of governments of countries of concern have provided or are providing material assistance to entities identified pursuant to paragraph (1).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HF73EE3D965C147E19FCFE3DCA870CB1A">
                    <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text>An analysis of the methods employed by entities of concern identified pursuant to paragraph (1), including—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H0BE0DE9AF7734109AE341EBC924428B5">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>the role of fraudulent account network providers in model extraction attacks, including, to the extent possible, the physical location of fraudulent account network provider offices and data centers; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H506DB890B4434CCDA3364B4395445CDA">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a determination, to the extent possible, of the number of attempted model extraction attacks that occurred in the previous two calendar years from the date on which the Secretary of State begins the assessment pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H6D6CBEA8FB964C1DBAFCA9D1002C1457">
                    <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text>An examination of the strengths and weaknesses of various detection approaches that can be used to determine whether a model extraction attack has occurred or is occurring.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H2A86415D8FE94DBC839F90AAEEBC3637">
                    <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the economic and national security consequences of successful model extraction attacks by entities of concern that occurred in the previous two calendar years from the date on which the Secretary of State begins the assessment pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HB4A5935857D649DFB687B297B836F299">
                    <enum>(7)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Steps detailing how the United States Government is assisting owners of closed-source AI models that have been the target or victim of model extraction attacks in detecting model extraction attacks, deterring future model extraction attacks, and punishing entities of concern that engage in model extraction attacks or are fraudulent account network providers.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HCABD819742094035B5D974D907C9ED3B">
                    <enum>(8)</enum>
 <text>A diplomatic strategy to leverage United States allies and partners in detecting and preventing model extraction attacks by entities of concern.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA252C06881BF4915A1B5A4DBA6FBC09D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the assessment required by subsection (a), the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall consult with owners of closed-source AI models that have been the targets or victims of model extraction attacks, whose participation in this consultation shall be voluntary, other companies, academic experts, industry fora, and other appropriate entities to—</text> <paragraph id="HEE68E0997CA94B9CB6C9472F593A7D3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify patterns of attacker behavior and methods to better inform United States Government and private sector efforts to detect model extraction attacks;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4625FEA0A3B145F08393D4E475A34CA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop best practices for defending against model extraction attacks; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51397AE035404D358327A1C1198BAEC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop best practices for identifying fraudulent account network provider activities that facilitate model extraction attacks.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFAA5106E6E694A96A4B7699D306927FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HEAA7D5D2C93D4E6BB51414E08F5A893A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 210 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains the findings of the assessment. The Secretary of Commerce shall, annually for 3 years, submit to the appropriate congressional committees an updated report with any additional entities of concern identified pursuant to subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBB379F58547400788E2725E6E416EF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4DDA6F970C1C4A1FB15D4CE5249361A1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Routine assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall routinely assess for—</text> <paragraph id="H5B55519B18CE4D59A93F026A2EA2B6B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">model extraction attacks directed against owners of closed-source AI models that occur after the date of completion of the assessment required by this section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBD82C56521A44D59B5FAE8C3EB23FCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fraudulent account network providers that facilitate model extraction attacks after the date of completion of the assessment required by this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6149479C27BC4978929C69BC4399F6A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any material changes related to other matters specified in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H11CD8E226416493596F6B7FE42109512"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Industry coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall establish an information sharing mechanism that allows owners of closed-source AI models to voluntarily, quickly, and confidentially share information about model extraction attacks and fraudulent account network providers with the Department of Commerce.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HBD6DB39BFED0437097383381E66A936B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>AI model extraction attackers list</header> <paragraph id="HE49A5E9C3E6C4EFEA357FC82FAEBC5F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5F259594643D40B59B45E4FE622048D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a list, to be known as the <quote>AI Model Extraction Attackers List</quote>, that displays information about specific individuals and entities of concern, that the assessment required by subsection (a) and routine assessment described in subsection (e) identify as having conducted or directed model extraction attacks in the past year; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7A53C55282CE40DE8A2B521DBC7C188C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish such list on a publicly available website of the Department of State for up to 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A398E108CD644EFB23764AAF5C45946"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of confidential information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may not, in publishing the list required by paragraph (1) on a publicly available website of the Department of State, disclose confidential information provided by owners of closed-source AI models without the express permission of said owner.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H560117D860B648A9B07A05FA21ECDACB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Public guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 210 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall publish a report comprising of best practices to detect, prevent, and respond to model extraction attacks.</text> 
<paragraph id="HF0592AF23E2A43CCB9AD7C68645ED49D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be publicly available.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD09D28438ABA45D4B879D20B0E7B2317"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protection of confidential information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making the report required by this subsection publicly available, the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the Operating Committee for Export Policy, shall not disclose confidential information provided by owners of closed-source AI models without the express permission of said owner.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7B30C3499436410CA7FE0A8EABA9DA34"><enum>5.</enum><header>Deterring model extraction attacks and fraudulent account network providers</header> 
<subsection id="HD6205DDD1C9B48299D78551EFE5894A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Addition consideration for Entity List</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 210 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security, in coordination with each agency that is a member of the End-User Review Committee, shall make a determination by majority vote of the Committee on whether entities identified as having conducted model extraction attacks or having facilitated them via fraudulent account networks after the date of the completion of the assessment required under section 4 of this Act (identified pursuant to subsection (e) of such section), or any affiliate of such entity (to be determined by ownership of 50 percent or more in the aggregate, directly or indirectly), should be added to the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce under Supplement No. 4 to part 744 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulations.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HD3F08BA592D54E7293D93CE1320109DE" commented="no"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Sanctions described</header> <paragraph id="H3566C148BE3C40709FE969B44959F9EF" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Secretary of State, may, pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of entities of concern identified pursuant to subsections (b)(1) and (e) of section 4 if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H1391D57ECB494810BBBE213354DAFB5D" commented="no">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Exceptions</header>
                    <subparagraph id="H558063C0BAEA477585EF18AB9252C915">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
                        <header>Exception to comply with international obligations</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions under this subsection shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H7DE6CDE734BB47FABBE599C9FD384F9D">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
                        <header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian
                            assistance</header>
 <text>Sanctions under this subsection may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text>
                        <clause id="H3DD4767A98FC42EE811AE2C980D376CD">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="H99518C3A92074EA9AE291929C7E30604">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text> </clause> <clause id="H35C4F0A880EB42339B1133B055245F57"> <enum>(iii)</enum> <text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance; or</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HDEEF0E9CAC83486FB575EADB3CB5B28C">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H04DA184A538E4966ADB22E5D5062CEEF">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
                        <header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security
                            activities</header>
 <text>Sanctions under this subsection shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="HBD5A8854F4974F67A894BD8FA0FD8681" commented="no">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <header>Penalties</header>
 <text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this subsection or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

