<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09A1809B5F1B41ABB4413A215967AB99" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6906 IH: Protecting Patients from Rehab Fraud Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress>
 <session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6906</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000619">Mr. Rulli</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Attorney General and the Comptroller General of the United States to submit to Congress reports on the drug addiction treatment and recovery industry.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H840B1A7279CA436DA4A8E6EF22DC63DA" style="OLC"><section id="H18D1659BB01D49DB9543E27857F12A68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Patients from Rehab Fraud Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H305D732F51B94468B53720B805436423"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on the drug addiction treatment and recovery industry</header><subsection id="H18D720CAAFCC4710ADF02D58573EB2D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>DOJ report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the drug addiction treatment and recovery industry. Such report shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H72FFF2341C0C47BA852B9DE05EAE634B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The prevalence of entities using illegal tactics to entice individuals to enter a rehabilitation facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9823A29E39C245B3A7ABE2A80F5BA06A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The prevalence of insurance fraud in plans offered through an Exchange established under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act relating to individuals housed in such facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC48D009E1E16465284861B3D6FE5A20D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The practice of brokers encouraging patients to commit insurance fraud to enroll in high-cost out-of-network insurance plans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FB7230A95BD44C5BF7CF6696B9DFEA6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prevalence of drug use and trafficking within these facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AB83B13BB4047F781F55BC21B11646D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The practice of <quote>patient dumping,</quote> also known as <quote>curbing,</quote> by which patients are removed from a facility and abandoned once their insurer no longer pays the facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C51BC31405E4F679EB868909ECF6014"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prevalence of patients being dumped in places other than the original location they came from to attend such a facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA16CFBCAE0A54622980DB07A6DA45C1A"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any research on the prevalence of homelessness and relapse among individuals who are dumped.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A3259B76D774173BFFFA39F561E0A02"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Recommendations for Congress to crack down on illegal practices and false dealing in the rehabilitation industry and protect prospective patients seeking rehabilitation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H649AED760ED24CB2891C93AEBFE7C031"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the drug addiction treatment and recovery industry. Such report shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HE50ACC5EB84344D48AB75DB934965B97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The actions currently being undertaken by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and other Federal actors to curb the type of insurance fraud described in subsection (a)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5451B7CDD23481EB0CB0E4D53D06117"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The actions currently being undertaken by States to curb this type of insurance fraud.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFDDB62B329E44DF8F4243FC44129686"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent and effectiveness of Federal expenditures for rehabilitation facilities to date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE41126E85A84A96B3FDF7DA453B8597"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations for Congress to crack down on illegal practices and false dealing in the rehabilitation industry and protect prospective patients seeking rehabilitation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

