<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB35FE58B790B40A183A90340502983C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6806 IH: Antisemitism Response and Prevention Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6806</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251217">December 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001318">Ms. Balint</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to establish within the Department of Justice the Office of the National Coordinator to Counter Antisemitism, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H38B2704221BA46C49ED60A30F78C3ECB" style="OLC"><section id="H23CC9B5196674C15B1F4F0DB3D20F31A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Antisemitism Response and Prevention Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H11B64ED4EB424C738E3FC238536DF0E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF571DE17313341D3A242D5CB25D119F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Antisemitic incidents in the United States have reached historic levels, with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) documenting 1,938 antisemitic incidents in 2024, representing a 73 percent increase from 2022 and the highest number recorded since the FBI began tracking hate crimes in 1991, with Jews—comprising only 2 percent of the United States population—accounting for 69 percent of all religion-based hate crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H655A567D576E44E6860A66B2AA662398"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Following the October 7, 2023, Hamas attacks on Israel, multiple tracking organizations documented a 360 to 388 percent increase in antisemitic incidents during the 3-month period from October 7, 2023, to January 7, 2024, with FBI Director Christopher Wray testifying that antisemitism has reached <quote>historic levels</quote> in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29D4B5AB1B4F48D68F6B01CF87C44FC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Academic research has documented severe deterioration of campus climates for Jewish students, with Brandeis University finding hostility rates approximately twice as high as 2016 baseline measurements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5CAEABC6494E2BAEEC545139D48F9C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The May 2023 United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism represented a landmark, gold-standard, and comprehensive approach to addressing antisemitism, developed with extensive input from Jewish institutions and individuals across the political spectrum, emphasizing that combating antisemitism requires protecting democratic institutions, civil liberties, and coalition-building across diverse communities, and establishing coordination mechanisms across over 30 Federal agencies. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H627520BDE2FF4125BC31717695F8BE5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Despite the real and documented crisis of antisemitism, there has been a systematic pattern of weaponizing antisemitism accusations by the Trump Administration to pursue ideological and partisan political objectives unrelated to protecting Jewish communities from discrimination and hatred, including attacks on educational institutions for political disagreements, suppression of constitutionally protected speech, and enforcement of ideological conformity. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA5F1A2310EA49A782BD87717FC5F105"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Department of Education has launched investigations into approximately 60 institutions of higher education, not primarily to protect Jewish students from discrimination, but to use the false premise of antisemitism accusations as pretext for forcing the elimination of academic programs related to diversity and Middle Eastern studies, threatening to withdraw Federal funding to compel ideological conformity, and undermining the autonomy and academic freedom of such institutions, with common patterns including lack of due process, conflation of criticism of Israeli government policies with antisemitism, and targeting of protected speech and academic inquiry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB67B67187D0A4C66AD245DBB35D28BE7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Trump administration has inappropriately appropriated the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance (IHRA) definition of antisemitism as a tool for immigration enforcement and deportation proceedings, applying a non-legally binding educational tool in punitive legal contexts for which it was never intended, with the Department of Homeland Security announcing in April 2025 that it would screen social media activity for antisemitism using the IHRA definition to guide determinations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C2A5BE85A3C4F7388B71195FC313372"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Multiple documented cases demonstrate the systematic targeting of students and legal residents for deportation based solely on their pro-Palestinian activism, including peaceful protests, academic inquiry, and political organizing, with every case that has reached Federal court resulting in release orders and findings of likely constitutional violations, including Federal judges ruling that the Trump administration is in continued violation of the First Amendment to the Constitution by detaining individuals for protected speech.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5D7910E15A946ED8B405876442F1978"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Trump administration has sought to tie nonprofit security grants, which fund critical houses of worship and religious community center security measures (including synagogues and Jewish Community Centers), to compliance with administration positions on immigration enforcement and diversity policies, with the Department of Homeland Security imposing conditions in April 2025 mandating that recipients cooperate with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement officials and prohibiting any programs that <quote>advance or promote DEI</quote>, effectively holding Jewish community safety hostage to unrelated political objectives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FF249BBA31046F8944BB135D37E7EB0"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Federal judges have blocked enforcement of these conditions through permanent injunctions in multiple jurisdictions, ruling that conditions were <quote>arbitrary and capricious</quote> and <quote>unconstitutional</quote>, with nearly 70 religious organizations and over 120 faith leaders signing a letter rejecting these conditions and stating they are <quote>unified in refusing to capitulate to conditions that would require us to sacrifice the safety and dignity of our community members</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19ABD6BA1F3F431D824CA413BE455916"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Heritage Foundation's <quote>Project Esther: A National Strategy to Combat Antisemitism</quote>, released on October 7, 2024, has served as a blueprint for the administration's antisemitism policies, but rather than genuinely combating antisemitism, it weaponizes accusations of antisemitism to pursue partisan political objectives, including dismantling diversity programs, suppressing pro-Palestinian advocacy, defunding educational institutions, attacking nonprofit organizations, and undermining academic freedom.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68924953879048E9BA00C8E63926D859"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The New York Times investigation published in May 2025 found that <quote>the second Trump administration had called for or acted upon more than half of Project Esther's proposals</quote>, with Heritage Foundation officials stating there are <quote>clear parallels</quote> between their recommendations and administration actions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD761B66DB064418A51FC957D6F9D42D"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Project Esther’s development was led by predominantly Christian nationalist individuals with minimal Jewish organizational support, is tied to Christian Zionism theology and beliefs that Jewish presence in the Holy Land will precipitate End Times, and focuses exclusively on left-wing critics of Israel while ignoring antisemitism from white supremacists and other far-right groups, making no mention of Proud Boys, white supremacist militias, neo-Nazi groups, the Charlottesville violence, the Pittsburgh synagogue shooting, or other far-right antisemitic violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H835F4679A0DB4C5BA84D3B3506DACD7F"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Effective antisemitism prevention and response requires comprehensive, evidence-based approaches that strengthen rather than undermine democratic institutions, with research and experience demonstrating that approaches are most effective when they address antisemitism as connected to other forms of hatred and extremism, strengthen democratic institutions and civil liberties, build broad coalitions across diverse communities, focus enforcement on clear cases of discrimination while protecting political expression, and invest in education and prevention rather than relying solely on punitive measures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7653AA97FA4C4FCFBA8AC5309C7EC5ED"><enum>(15)</enum><text>History demonstrates that Jewish communities are safest in robust democracies with strong civil liberties, equal protection under the law, and inclusive pluralistic cultures, and most vulnerable when these democratic foundations are eroded, and that weaponizing antisemitism for partisan political purposes not only fails to protect Jewish communities but actively breeds more antisemitism by associating Jewish safety with the suppression of civil liberties and the targeting of political dissent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H002AFBE039064248BEB5A5D7C047106A"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Congress has a responsibility to ensure that Federal efforts to combat antisemitism are effective, evidence-based, and consistent with democratic values, and to prevent the weaponization of antisemitism concerns for ulterior political objectives, requiring substantial Federal investment in education initiatives, civil rights enforcement, community security programs, and other evidence-based approaches to combating antisemitism and related forms of extremism and hate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA31D18102800409BA62AB36A960EBC5F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy and sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H2D08E993103F4ED88456B721278E7080"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H576DD05BA14E4D8992B0195903D53C83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to raise awareness and educate the United States public about the history of Jewish Americans and antisemitism in all of its forms and various manifestations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H481C2D11D06042C8B67DF35FDCF99A34"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to use all available authorities to oppose antisemitism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8640570005D484C91327823C277FB9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not to use the fight against antisemitism as grounds or motive to pursue ulterior political agendas, including attacks on educational institutions for alleged political disagreements, suppression of constitutionally protected speech, or enforcement of ideological conformity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD339978BB9264966BDB06DEB4593F676"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to ensure that all Federal antisemitism policies and programs are developed with meaningful input from diverse Jewish communities and are consistent with democratic values;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H046E9BBB8D2344489A01FFA848A00AA0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to address antisemitism as connected to other forms of hatred and extremism through coalition-building and comprehensive prevention efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF09AD02925E47F6B7C0428A5F717AF7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to protect the autonomy and academic freedom of educational institutions while ensuring vigorous enforcement of civil rights protections against actual discrimination and harassment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDCE634F63A14F7BBA5069558F35B33E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H1D656C58818E440CBC4357CBD4AEF8CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as articulated in the Biden Administration’s May 2023 United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism there are several definitions of antisemitism which serve as valuable tools to raise awareness and increase understanding of antisemitism, including the non-legally binding definitions of antisemitism adopted in 2016 by the 31 member states of the International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance, the Nexus Document, and other such efforts; and all of the definitions are valuable tools to raise awareness and increase understanding of antisemitism, and should be utilized by Federal, State, and local agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BBD64E50C284891937B93A42A004ED1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the definitions are non-legally binding educational tools and should not be applied in punitive legal contexts, including immigration enforcement, deportation proceedings, or criminal prosecutions, for which they were never intended;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAB3F76168624CF398546731E792E038"><enum>(3)</enum><text>criticism of Israeli government policies, when not motivated by or expressed through antisemitic tropes or discrimination against Jews, is a form of political speech protected by the First Amendment and does not constitute antisemitism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H430B68643AB749C7A3521B0791F939F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>combating antisemitism requires protecting rather than undermining democratic institutions, civil liberties, academic freedom, and the rights of all communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C976B4938C842E3AE85F052CA82DBF8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the weaponization of antisemitism accusations to pursue partisan political agendas undermines genuine efforts to protect Jewish communities and breeds additional antisemitism.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD2698D24990F440EA3DE89BB5B5ECB7D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of a title VI coordinator and duties</header><subsection id="HAAF50E192887436FAE47EECA5946A2AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HDAE1EBDDF6B44C66AD5998566E0B94AC" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H6F70CE1CEB1E41CDB2510722CCC47528"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will—</text><subparagraph id="H66667C0B7D5344FD925DE09BD17D9470"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate at least 1 employee to coordinate institutional compliance with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), including investigation of any complaint alleging—</text><clause id="HDB0E3F0CF27E4A329FB6A1D103349D6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>noncompliance with such title; or</text></clause><clause id="H1828140F47F844AFBF29EEE1CA3C21FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any actions prohibited by such title; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H306E5BC20AC14B2787B1B0F0ECD9D0DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct a public awareness campaign, directly or through a contract with a nonprofit organization that specializes in public awareness communications, that—</text><clause id="HC4E7BABCCBA742978B9E8512035083AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is updated annually and is provided to students, faculty, and staff of the institution, including physical posting in one or more high traffic public places at the institution, such as a student center, and digital posting on one or more high traffic web pages of the institution, such as a student services web page; </text></clause><clause id="H8B11FED2DBB3475EB4A358F2A7A58A43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes appealing visual and auditory elements; and</text></clause><clause id="HD34996DA8DFF44E4B03CB7A4252A1082"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilizes methods and materials necessary to maximize student accessibility to the campaign;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA980FD664504A6093C90133A282F1AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>annually submit a report to the Secretary, and make such report publicly available on the website of the institution (subject to <internal-xref idref="HAA4CF77FC61C443980D2DB801A5EF853" legis-path="(30)(C)(ii)">clause (ii)</internal-xref>), that—</text><clause id="HEEA7829050594C74A4DBE07A4E371693"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes all complaints described in <internal-xref idref="H66667C0B7D5344FD925DE09BD17D9470" legis-path="(30)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> and all public awareness campaign efforts made under <internal-xref idref="H306E5BC20AC14B2787B1B0F0ECD9D0DB" legis-path="(30)(B)">subparagraph (B)</internal-xref>;</text></clause><clause id="HAA4CF77FC61C443980D2DB801A5EF853"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the version of the report made available to the public, may include redacted information with respect to the names, contact information, or identifying information of victims or minors involved in complaints described in <internal-xref idref="H66667C0B7D5344FD925DE09BD17D9470" legis-path="(30)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>; and</text></clause><clause id="HFEB659BC51F14C128D5BB36C8A89F31F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to the version of the report submitted to the Secretary, may not included any redacted information;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28F8168A62764FD3AB21410133975F7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide annual notice to students, faculty, and staff of—</text><clause id="H55EAFDE758E44777BA642CE64F6FE2F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, email address, office address, and telephone number of the employee designated under <internal-xref idref="H66667C0B7D5344FD925DE09BD17D9470" legis-path="(30)(A)">subparagraph (A) </internal-xref>to coordinate compliance with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H995F7596868B49CFBDF71D00C0E2D7B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the publically available report under <internal-xref idref="HEA980FD664504A6093C90133A282F1AD" legis-path="(30)(C)">subparagraph (C)</internal-xref>;</text></clause><clause id="H84CF3002A39340A2A01EB8A673DBED4D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the enforcement policies of the institution with respect to such title VI; and</text></clause><clause id="H55A4743874754A32B6314BDF7CC5A0FC" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the institutional procedures for reporting and investigating complaints under such title VI; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4267023FEA80493792AC828F73863667" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in carrying out this paragraph, take such steps as may be necessary to distinguish between discrimination and harassment prohibited by title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>) and political expression protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB587A35AED6742FE9217B9D825BB5612"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in the amendment made by this section shall be construed to require an institution of higher education to restrict constitutionally protected speech or academic inquiry, or to enforce ideological conformity. </text></subsection></section><section id="HAC21BF513A0E4BF18048DFEC8738B77A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education</header><subsection id="HE5DC44DFA7994A8DBCBE3C0702803549"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each of the fiscal years 2027 through 2032, there is authorized to be appropriated $280,000,000 to the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education, as established under section 203 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3413">20 U.S.C. 3413</external-xref>), to carry out the activities authorized by such section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4408A08A25F545CBA6AB81F3BEE2FCAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification on regional offices</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of Education shall issue a certification that—</text><paragraph id="HF93A481803CE4854BAEA7F2E99173989"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all regional offices of the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education that were closed, consolidated, or transferred on or after January 20, 2025, and before the date of enactment of this Act, have been reopened and remain open, and that such offices maintain adequate staffing to handle the volume of civil rights complaints received and to provide technical assistance to institutions of higher education with respect to civil rights complaints; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7E4B0969C804231AE6467437BE1C54E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no regional offices of such Office for Civil Rights were closed, consolidated, or transferred on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6FE9FCCAA4549CD87139783AE1F0ABA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H659EB0776B474343B3FC43F8488D7750"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>If the Secretary of Education does not issue a complete and timely certification required under <internal-xref idref="H4408A08A25F545CBA6AB81F3BEE2FCAF" legis-path="5.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall, not later than 30 days after the date on which such certification was due, submit a report to the appropriate Congressional committees that identifies any regional office described in paragraph (1) or (2) of <internal-xref idref="H4408A08A25F545CBA6AB81F3BEE2FCAF" legis-path="5.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref> that has not been reopened, and provide justification for the failure to reopen such regional office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19F79A8105CB40A3A8884061865D8581"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Any report required by this subsection shall be unclassified.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4453A5E05C37483792F61301A63C7E8F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate Congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Education and Workforce, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEB89CDC197C44A1A95266B765794A5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Monthly congressional briefing</header><paragraph id="HB73A252541CB467A89A4CCF014A59129"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>For the period beginning on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date that is 1 year after such date of enactment, the Assistant Secretary for the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education shall give a monthly briefing to Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="HB5DA1F645ED04B3B8B431B7907353DB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides the number of complaints that the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education has received in the previous month regarding discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin in violation of title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>), disaggregated by the basis of discrimination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD438C9C480114C548A4F95E4EB9FE126"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describes how the Office for Civil Rights has addressed, or plans to address, such complaints, and any investigations that have been opened in response to such complaints; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD0E26FDCA604F9FA9131C812746049E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides data about the length of time that such complaints remain open after being received by the Office for Civil Rights.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5DAA33F26F3416E912750392D4E32F4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 48 hours before each briefing required under <internal-xref idref="HB73A252541CB467A89A4CCF014A59129" legis-path="5.(d)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>, the Assistant Secretary for the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education shall provide a written report to Congress that contains the information that will be presented at the briefing, in a manner that protects personally identifiable information in accordance with applicable privacy laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DBED7E0F0A046C599B6EFB9D8FB3824"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no action shall be taken by the President, the Secretary of Education, or any officer of the Executive Branch to transfer the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Education, as established under section 203 of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3413">20 U.S.C. 3413</external-xref>), from the Department of Education to any other agency, organization, or reporting structure, or to close or consolidate such Office, without express statutory authorization enacted after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC365D224147145BBBC86DFEFA35BB261"><enum>6.</enum><header>Office of the National Coordinator to Counter Antisemitism</header><subsection id="HECB768B8292047B8B56419E2EF08CB2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish within the Department of Justice the Office of the National Coordinator to Counter Antisemitism (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HABA4044B3BE84E74994527C0D233144D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><paragraph id="HD20C394B0A2445FBBD94B9F27F38DEB4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Office shall be headed by the National Coordinator to Counter Antisemitism (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Coordinator</quote>), who shall—</text><subparagraph id="H114E201A1E7341E3B6905F1CAE833828"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appointed by the Attorney General;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H614429EA01F2431DAFF567112EFB3496"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve for a 4-year term of office; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8097D498B7F9419FBC3D255D49535032"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be eligible for reappointment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3915B473B0024D249FD09B563BEDB665"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Position classification</header><text>The position of the Coordinator may not be a position in the excepted service or filled by a noncareer appointee, and shall be filled by an individual who is not a political appointee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD34F72A52A81476591731ACE1FBDD1AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on assignment of other duties</header><text>The individual serving in the position of Coordinator shall not have, or be assigned, duties in addition to the duties of the position of Coordinator as described under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25A02789E6D1461EA112185E7397E377"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of the Coordinator</header><text>The Coordinator shall—</text><paragraph id="HB47D4C3A1BEB41C88A6C0FD45607C90E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve as the principal advisor to the Attorney General on countering domestic antisemitism; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H929FE9E974DE43DCB18755DA2BB2D847"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate Federal efforts to counter antisemitism, including ongoing and multi-year implementation of the United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism, across the relevant agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19C70E314EA14B39AE920783E6C7F9C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that Federal efforts to counter antisemitism are evidence-based, consistent with democratic values, and developed with meaningful input from diverse Jewish communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB0CBF5F93EF4FDDB283B133528C32ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct, for a period of 10 years beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, a biennial review of the implementation of Federal efforts to counter antisemitism, including—</text><subparagraph id="H076468648E5548ADB5136ED165BE5AEC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of such efforts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H475C3DCDDF8549CEB567582E14334B88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for changes to such efforts, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFED4B641C2674D90898DF3CE841EE39C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>review the internal and external antisemitism training and resource programs of the relevant agencies and ensure that such programs include training and resources to assist relevant agencies in understanding, deterring, and educating the public about antisemitism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H846231D9CCDB4B6AAA4B640EF6C5C69D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>coordinate with organizations, including community-based organizations, civil rights groups, and Jewish institutions, engaged in antisemitism prevention and response; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC363F3F1DCB4B93BE5791DB9892A385"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure that all antisemitism prevention efforts are coordinated with broader programs to address extremism, hate crimes, and conspiracy theory proliferation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36776B23E0EC488F8410D2D89C47EC27"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Division personnel</header><text>The Coordinator may appoint personnel to positions within the Office as the Coordinator determines necessary. Each position within the Office of the Coordinator shall be filled by an individual who is not a political appointee.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA96338D469594321BE2C99C1FFA241C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Political appointee</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>political appointee</quote> means an individual occupying—</text><paragraph id="H84D0D765BE6A457889204E07C6500DB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE26894081ACB4D149C875C9D9DFA31FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a noncareer position in the Senior Executive Service, as described under section 3132(a)(7) of that title;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5128C9FB3044E2A8777C03673F887EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39D97F7855EE4C13B5D0D5631352203D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a position which has been excepted from the competitive service by reason of its confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H889ACAD9B2FB4F5AB90BCFDFF8127761"><enum>7.</enum><header>Hate Crime Reporting Center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1 of the Hate Crime Statistics Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/41305">34 U.S.C. 41305</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5ACCDADE15894C1CBC45C19F13D57A34" style="OLC"><subsection id="HEA396BA0F9C2466CA141E9271D794D2F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Hate Crime Reporting Center</header><paragraph id="HB7C549B44C7C4661A2DC735E1C87A0B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation shall establish and maintain within the Civil Rights Unit of the Federal Bureau of Investigation the Hate Crime Reporting Center (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the <quote>HCRC</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E726AA2DB9A43B5B22A54C10FC09240"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordinator and staff</header><subparagraph id="H639F0002D15E4A788B923C41513EF6D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><clause id="H28D2741FFA924577A6AA7E5C5A6270DE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The HCRC shall be headed by the Coordinator of Hate Crimes Reporting (hereinafter in this section referred to as the <quote>Coordinator</quote>), appointed by the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation from among persons who have substantial experience in monitoring and combating hate crimes. In considering applicants for the position of Coordinator, the Director shall consider persons employed outside Government as well as Government employees.</text></clause><clause id="HB987C9B0C6A24A7292530EEFEB2C4421"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Duties of the coordinator</header><text>The Coordinator shall—</text><subclause id="HDD7CA91F1C1C48149C59E80C94F06DD5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as the principal advisor to the Attorney General and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation on hate crime reporting in the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE145F6F78D524B3EB5720AD05FEC40BE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>coordinate all Federal efforts to gather and determine incidents of hate crimes in the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H18B3D870E8104B30A398F2B535029E9E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>ensure hate crime data collection and reporting is comprehensive, accurate, and publicly accessible.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBF59A7991D49471EBCC98712E47E7F8A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Term and removal</header><text>The Coordinator shall serve for a 6-year term of office, and shall be eligible for reappointment. The Coordinator shall not be subject to removal during the term of office, except for cause established in accordance with law.</text></clause><clause id="H739C6A747E2E45CC9376449B4EE181B6"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Position classification</header><text>The position of the Coordinator may not be a position in the excepted service or filled by a noncareer appointee, and shall be filled by an individual who is not a political appointee.</text></clause><clause id="HA10ABB9DE44740E0A59395E992347426"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Direction and control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (iii), the Coordinator shall be free from the direction and control of any person other than the Attorney General and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></clause><clause id="H719F858EDCA94FAEA7DF963AA0B32E5A"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Prohibition on delegation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation may not delegate to any other officer or employee of the Department, other than the Deputy Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Deputy Attorney General, the authority of the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation with respect to the HCRC.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2819F43711E42AB9CF7F61C952FF65F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Coordinator shall appoint such employees as are necessary for the administration of the HCRC. An employee of the HCRC shall have no duties other than those that are necessary to carry out this subsection. Each position of the HCRC shall be filled by an individual who is not a political appointee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E158A8343FE4851B53C9A390F65FC7F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Political appointee</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>political appointee</quote> means an individual occupying—</text><clause id="HAD567472ED064F429F611865B5A5623F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text></clause><clause id="H9F5B1284EE534A028EBB4FF98AC6C882"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a noncareer position in the Senior Executive Service, as described under section 3132(a)(7) of title 5;</text></clause><clause id="H948550E86CCC4A4B9F3FCCF8A7DBD5C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text></clause><clause id="H8A16488E493342448039C3FD783714A4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a position which has been excepted from the competitive service by reason of its confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C6B2F821D7248D5A6BFA2D9E0E02428"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mission of the HCRC shall be to strive to record, track, index, report, and publish data related to every hate crime committed in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD28CAF46414604B48B9409EB2ADADA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Methods</header><subparagraph id="H22B9C41C87D2464CB8C3D6903599819E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Public awareness campaign</header><text>The HCRC shall conduct a national public awareness campaign, which—</text><clause id="HE6C3E16F14F746E398E244BFA30555E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may—</text><subclause id="H2AF8373FF2854FA385BFF506EE31E739"><enum>(I)</enum><text>include appealing visual and auditory elements;</text></subclause><subclause id="H02FAC66946924F9C9306D15FB6862FD8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>be updated annually; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2775A619646D4B76914EAF64FD4E755A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>be distributed to law enforcement agencies for—</text><item id="H15E0299C123A49C0B2E64B8932B689C4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>physical posting in 1 or more high traffic public places, such as community centers, billboards, and police stations;</text></item><item id="HCCE32B8B7D6543FF83347E12C94015E0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>digital posting on 1 or more high traffic web pages; and</text></item><item id="HF84C4E8EAEF74042A5DD8682DB1DE7C6"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>advertisements on television and radio; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HB7434FAEB1D14D99ADF45E573382FC08"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall—</text><subclause id="H2953C755C95D4288981230F37531FBB6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>use such methods and materials as are necessary to maximize accessibility; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H59FFC12296054301B06DD278293F578B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make special efforts to reach out to all communities targeted by hate crimes, including through culturally appropriate and multilingual methods.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61CCE55E328549979BCFAF87526DAE65"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contracting with nonprofits</header><text>The HCRC may carry out this subsection directly or through a contract with a nonprofit organization that specializes in public awareness communications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CD1F0454846419D894CAA729810ED35"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Media and online monitoring</header><text>The HCRC shall employ researchers to closely monitor all media reports and online platforms pertinent to hate crimes in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA00ADA1BA27E4E749DC0D5F51917AD19"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>The HCRC may establish partnerships with national community organizations with chapters across the country in order to build trust and to create additional reporting streams to receive credible reports of hate crimes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC688FE7FA364E3AA124E2F86182D3C4"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The HCRC shall receive information from the Uniform Crime Reporting Program of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and shall have access to all data submitted to the Federal Bureau of Investigation under such program as to make its own independent determinations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H43EB6E0F42B54480B5377406498AB946"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C116C712EDC4AED8AAF5131F1C07925"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Publication of findings</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the effective date of this subsection, and annually thereafter, the HCRC shall publicly publish and disseminate the number of hate crimes the HCRC recorded in the previous year, including a breakdowns by State and by class targeted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55A013DF329F48C1A6D288DD0C3EF202"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subparagraph id="H0697FAD437284AAA8388369786E08B79"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Report on hate crimes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 180 days after the effective date of this subsection, and every 90 days thereafter, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, in consultation with the Coordinator, shall submit to Congress a report detailing the hate crimes the HCRC has recorded for that reporting period, including information such as location, targeted class, and any related law enforcement action. The report shall be unclassified but may contain a classified annex.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB84C741599D34AF2853F44A5EBA1BB1B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report on activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date that is 180 days after the effective date of this subsection, and every 180 days thereafter for a period of 5 years, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, in consultation with the Coordinator, shall submit to Congress a report detailing the activities of the HCRC for that reporting period, including as described in paragraphs (1), (3), and (5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3FD1AC5DB6431D99B80DFF45003DE6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Hate crime</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>hate crime</quote> means a crime described in subsection (b)(1). </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD449D971C3B243C2A079074DDAC7EECA"><enum>8.</enum><header>Nonprofit Security Grant Program</header><subsection id="HBE4AE8BB6C484041BFB65868B10A0E66"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Duties and prohibitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 2009 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609a">6 U.S.C. 609a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7D650D3E0890438397CBCFBBF95A057A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Period of performance</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Duties and prohibitions</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8F76EAC219B43C7A8EFCE223B53C1BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6D14778C69474F018D3D9FD9C1D970ED" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HEF59878A73174902A269BC0821E1C9E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Period of performance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H29962512DD4149E28243BEFE005B79D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H118B8AA8433045FEBB94E0204A371B2E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H92C250EE36C2493599113E5FD85756A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sufficient personnel and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall ensure there are sufficient personnel and resources in the Federal Emergency Management Agency to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1D15179FF0D4763A00BF1399D6F4D9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Neither the Administrator nor a State may impose as a condition of receiving a grant under this section a restriction on the policies or practices of an eligible nonprofit organization described in subsection (b) that are related to any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF07E2BF7DD1E4D7A92ADF5FD3B6CA679"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Diversity, equity, and inclusion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1ECBBEF8728249C6AB7109557D6D8ACE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Immigration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37927812F6AF4EC599DF46500BE22BEF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Security other than physical security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4BD1A627E6F431D8FE0ECA3E75BA61E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A political position or affiliation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC56AE3340E604C48861464A8BA9DD910" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Political advocacy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58033A35709C4FD79822AC703E91078A" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A protected status or characteristic.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF6BE7B7C6EA4B1B83215D23FA0E70A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (e) of section 2009 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609a">6 U.S.C. 609a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFCBC131DBBB64677B44BCBE14E191A7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>2028</quote> and inserting <quote>2032</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CC43F47E69947E48BB276AF180403BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB4FBD57007BC4BE38F993CF2415EAE7B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H0A30CF6C78804B4B8E2F43D401DDD55B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each recipient of a grant under this section, the following:</text><subparagraph id="H464797DB12D8463B85CF5092A2CF2639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The name of such recipient.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8EB5F99A932450A9A7E1F8B06E1B6A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount of such grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C196506309F439190130692B3A2A1B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The expenditure by such recipient of such amount not retained under subsection (c)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE73FDEAB0FB9488A8F443E68FFD7E4C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (8); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC83B641E894743DB99284EF922F3960E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF113C47FCA5D463FA2048E8D3254032F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H3D0E25497AF6486290CFF9A4EB1DA38B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of applicants for grants under this section to which the Administrator did not make such a grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9FAF50171464E308517E2E362AAE708"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of such grants made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCA2E252C4544C54B0C280C3D3288371"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The range of amounts for such grants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36630ECA82B64E8790FC9DD6B97B2CE4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The average amount of such a grant.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7034247C58F4D3582743C2AC94381E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Subsection (i) of such section is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9F4F6B008D28469F886DF017C2FF6D88" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H58A3146B354E47D883E22F55F8FC4C27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A4D0A09C80E4A04ACB74D2C30662853"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and moving such clauses, as so redesignated, two ems to the right;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD0CCC88D12749FD92B9C68CE59AAD32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>appropriated $360,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028</quote> and inserting </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H75009D52FFCE469D9B78A3545BBD3B87"><text>appropriated—</text><subparagraph id="HF4AE4001B7C14FBD940633A84CEB3E2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$360,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4C6DEC0B19B42AAA6A0ABE59B9AE0B0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAB5921944A3346EDACD42283381470F0"><subparagraph id="H7BFDB4B0E12D44C4B553E1C7F8377052"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032 to carry out this section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAA647ADD20C49D6ABE234F94F9587E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>2028</quote> and inserting <quote>2026</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6FDF045843F4B689E91C98FD555867C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public awareness campaign</header><paragraph id="HD1E9A1AD82624E84ADE8F7586744EEDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall carry out a public awareness campaign (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Campaign</quote>) to inform at-risk communities of the Nonprofit Security Grant Program under section 2009 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609a">6 U.S.C. 609a</external-xref>) (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H345D320DFB7741F6B30DA262238F7285"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Components</header><text>As part of the Campaign, the Administrator shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="H1F977F747DD540C8908DCB24C23EB01E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Conduct targeted outreach to eligible nonprofit organizations described in subsection (b) of section 2009 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609a">6 U.S.C. 609a</external-xref>) that serve at-risk communities, including Jewish communities, religious minorities, and other communities vulnerable to hate crimes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7E4FAA7B43149DBA33874D6F97A7C4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provide technical assistance to such organizations that seek grants under the Program, including such organizations that may lack expertise in submitting an application for such a grant.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53722A803B074A8EB446D2651739D19B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Develop and distribute multilingual educational materials about eligibility, application processes, and available security enhancements under the Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8216E7EBD9D47A2BEF75AEB510DFA79"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Host informational sessions, webinars, and workshops in diverse communities across the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADD97E15DED04193A7D0D826E089065B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Partner with national and local community organizations to maximize reach to underserved and at-risk communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9005BECF5E94D81BEDC3AA098FF7AD9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Use multiple media platforms, including digital, print, radio, and television, with culturally appropriate messaging.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F5565EF25E248B9947727DD6992282F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032 to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H353BA6800A9547E69F70ABF2250F0E88"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><subsection id="H89E879D7EA9342BD8F1F39CD9DD883EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on extremist ideologies</header><paragraph id="HD5C7293433CD4FB4B4DE4055CD6D3423"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the propagation of extremist ideologies in public institutions and law enforcement organizations, including prisons and law enforcement units.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50C1171B989F4A5999E1B0A2DC71E5CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of the report described under this subsection, the term the <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H76749763EB40454E848E87827A6F20B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC17AACF2149A4E8AB8F00777A9549EC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9DEA3C71BC5428AB2F7D09BE3B7D4E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Classified annex</header><text>The report shall be unclassified but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H040A05F5D6294CAEBC5051F1E405A8B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on domestic terrorism</header><paragraph id="H30BFA97F2124462FA4026DA7AD40D2B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigations, and the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report—</text><subparagraph id="HC629861CC61D4D62B6C3CBEE50BBE10F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessing the scope of the threat of domestic terrorism in the United States as of the date of the report; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB8828D3ACAB41F5BA8F2576D1FB8535"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reporting on any actions taken during the reporting period to combat such threat.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4210241895284922983E45A91262071D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>For the purposes of the report described under this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H34B52E1CB39A4FE09343BA4F242C8492"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Homeland Security and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F59ACE83AA44B8AA93E6A7C67697FFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary, the Committee on Homeland Security &amp; Governmental Affairs, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CD136559124422EA8C620C44206A6FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Classified annex</header><text>The report shall be unclassified but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF5EC08409A1D43F784741A35CFEABFFE"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H92A7481B189E40168BD36F1F72240E74" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antisemitism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>antisemitism</quote> has the meaning given such term in the third paragraph of page 13 of the United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3408D0DB125946698414DA7FDAEC9A31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relevant agency</header><text>The term <quote>relevant agency</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H166FE4FDFF664FFABE1959D60FF1A5DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Domestic Policy Council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D3E3416F83D49249A52FE71D15E182F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9561C1C1E41448639D8A93F3D43A96C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office of the Special Envoy to Monitor and Combat Antisemitism of the Department of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25ABF0D71C2A4976A4FADE4D366074EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04F324CBA8C441D6B97C7B2423DD02EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6599C27E8BB44A18E7C25C8FD45F354"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53C20C7C6B554D0F9FE8D9E313BD66DB"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Department of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1171D473D51C4FB3B2C2315EE5932D5B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the National Counterterrorism Center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DC0A47CFB6B47208CCC6B4679831DEA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the United States Holocaust Memorial Museum;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CF6DC109FC6400B968F2A4EE0F8C0C3"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H946DFBEB9EEE44AAA42E7CCD34F60318"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE675219699D240B18367196FC78E23A0"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Small Business Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4CC168B7F7A480B940E6BAF131EFE4C"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEABFB38B7F6A40229C168B8A285A4A63"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC14FF745937469EA32858BF8F2FFA25"><enum>(O)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8688A8313C3847C68863505E811E6311"><enum>(P)</enum><text>the Corporation for National and Community Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9001E18A22F439987B4F0432EAAF7FB"><enum>(Q)</enum><text>the National Endowment for the Arts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBF3B56E68284D7981F88D4931270431"><enum>(R)</enum><text>the National Endowment for the Humanities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60FB59F2C54145768DEA672573B424A1"><enum>(S)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD42037BB97E34DF189BC8BBF60C6C7F8"><enum>(T)</enum><text>the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H468FADEE26FA47E79B339870C510BA67"><enum>(U)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF183730C3A646359EE2D6CF92345B3B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Department of the Treasury;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF672925260FC458EB99C3B849C9DF582"><enum>(W)</enum><text>the Office of the Director of National Intelligence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC74684014F6E4C7EA6C302DED12499B6"><enum>(X)</enum><text>the Institute of Museum and Library Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB98312CC28EA47C7AB478AA23BF443E1"><enum>(Y)</enum><text>the Office of Personnel Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31189A0E3BB7433A830C3FCF18DED321"><enum>(Z)</enum><text>the United States Mission to the United Nations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79AB5041E15E4A80B7440EF89EC0FEE6"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the General Services Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H678CC48C39824A50871EB8441DD828EA"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9E01E267CD94AC28A62C35BE55F83C3"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>the Department of Labor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0866CFFDA4174FD3962DB4383AB42CC9"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC394A5E57CD84584842507E536FD1FBC"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>the Smithsonian Institution; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B5E156288C846E4BCF655345E755739"><enum>(FF)</enum><text>the Office of Faith-Based and Neighborhood Partnerships of the White House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H310AA7D0477146A8B5A6C452298731C1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism</quote> means the document entitled <quote>The U.S. National Strategy to Counter Antisemitism</quote> and published by the White House on May 25, 2023.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

