<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA208E34619E49E38FC03CAAC36C4857" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6185 IH: Targeting Environmental and Climate Recklessness Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6185</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the imposition of sanctions with respect to significant actions that exacerbate climate change, to reinforce comprehensive efforts to limit global average temperature rise, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4845A77BA1FC43F0ABB63201A2BB675C" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC2A4A47ABD92487D916AA52B79DD3E90"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Targeting Environmental and Climate Recklessness Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H837B08FB31DD47AC8E8618B752AB5EA4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HD92405E71A7F4B058587B33EA931EB62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Climate change is imposing significant damage on communities in the United States and abroad in the form of severe weather events, wildfires, heat waves, droughts, flooding, ocean acidification, and other threats to public health and safety. Scientists expect those effects to grow in frequency and intensity in the coming decades, jeopardizing the jobs, health, and safety of the people of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39A2A38F6F374BE783A6D023BF513E3B"> <enum>(2)</enum> <text>Collectively, the international community needs to limit global warming to under 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels in order to avoid the most catastrophic effects of climate change. In 2024, average temperatures passed the 1.5-degree threshold for the first time. With sustained 1.5-degree warming, scientists expect the United States to experience a sharp rise in annual heat-related deaths, longer and more destructive wildfire seasons, more frequent and severe droughts, reduced crop yields, more multibillion-dollar flood disasters, increased high-tide flooding in coastal areas, more days with unhealthy air quality, and longer tick and mosquito seasons, among other effects. Low-income communities and communities of color will experience the worst effects.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="HC64A354A5F4E4D37B16CD9C8529B6C31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The adverse impacts of climate change will increase exponentially as warming continues. Under the current trajectory, the world will experience warming that exceeds 3 degrees Celsius by the end of the century. At 3 degrees of warming, scientists expect dangerous conditions in the United States where outdoor work is unsafe for many months of the year, farmers struggle to keep livestock and grow crops, power grids become overloaded, water becomes scarce during summer months, poor air quality leads to widespread health problems, severe wildfires and droughts become more common, major flooding events occur on a regular basis, mosquito- and tick-borne illnesses spread further, and some coastal areas become submerged.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8115FC718A9C496695D4B73F7AAC7351"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Climate change is also expected to pose a significant challenge to the international community’s shared vision of fulfilling the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6201A038B87549DAB41F6A4105362F2A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To avert catastrophe, the United States and every country on Earth will need to make drastic reforms to global economic systems to reduce greenhouse gas emissions, reduce deforestation, and adapt to unavoidable changes in the climate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15550DAB24DC474CA9F9633DE7FCCA96"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Internationally, economic actors continue to pursue activities, such as development of new coal-fired power plants and deforestation, that contribute to dangerous levels of greenhouse gas emissions and the destruction of carbon sinks. In addition to carrying a significant climate risk, many of those activities are associated with serious human rights abuses, acts of corruption, and environmental injustice against Indigenous communities, communities of color, and other communities that have historically faced marginalization and discrimination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80DC09C1EE5C42E48EED4ADD8B7047DA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Illegal deforestation is a significant driver of the destruction of the Amazon rainforest. Criminal networks with the capacity to coordinate large-scale extraction, processing, and sale of timber deploy armed personnel to protect their interests. Those criminal networks regularly attack and threaten members of Indigenous communities, other environmental defenders, and enforcement officials. Perpetrators of such violence are rarely brought to justice. Numerous studies show that transnational criminal organizations no longer limit themselves only to drug trafficking but diversify their operations to include natural resource crimes, among other activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE60C0BFA10854BB2A83C6F8E144325FE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The goals articulated in the Paris Agreement depend on collective action involving the entire international community. Progress made by one economic actor can be reduced or cancelled out if another economic actor emits significant greenhouse gas emissions into the Earth’s atmosphere or destroys important carbon sinks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91C6D968467A4F94BE88E7982947D6FA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 2025, President Donald J. Trump withdrew the United States from the Paris Agreement and attacked climate change-related activities across the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FD88559E213453C8E93CFD23695A762"><enum>(10)</enum><text>President Trump's decision to ignore climate change has provided the People's Republic of China with a strategic opportunity to make significant competitive gains in preparing for a new economic order in a world that has warmed by 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A70578D7CE84FED9B375BCFCF019033"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the first year of President Trump's second term, the United States experienced one of its costliest years on record for wildfires and storms, record-breaking heat waves, and severe flooding—all disasters that were linked to climate change.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85CDD8B8706A4232AD58192BFBF23AAF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The United States Government has developed and implements targeted measures to restrict access to the United States financial system for specific individuals and entities whose actions threaten or run counter to United States national interests. While the United States has not yet used such measures for climate-related activities alone, the United States Government has deployed such measures in response to terrorism, proliferation of weapons of mass destruction, transnational organized crime, narcotics trafficking, malicious cyber-enabled activity, wildlife trafficking, serious human rights abuses, and acts of corruption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA2F7646B444EECB74E30CD598A54EC"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The United States should take action to address the urgency of the climate crisis and hold actors responsible for environmental and climate harm.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA606D0B817F648D2A90CFC5E84A913B5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on a comprehensive approach to addressing climate change</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H4D0A784666E7463B935F307F01B3176C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the targeted measures described in this Act are only one component of the comprehensive approach needed to address climate change and mitigate its effects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB6F7456EF9F4DA397AD847AD009E85A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Government must ensure through law and regulation that entities in the United States are not engaged in or complicit in any of the egregious behaviors for which foreign persons may be targeted under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57BC194295A344C09C226AE0AC8C345D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Government should continue to make progress toward scaling international climate finance to more than $11,000,000,000 annually and promote international efforts to support climate change adaptation and mitigation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0001CED67924A53B51882DFA3BF4D0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States Government must work proactively with foreign governments, including by offering positive incentives, to address climate change and to promote economic development in ways that do not needlessly increase carbon emissions, deforestation, or the risk of corruption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE080461E407C4D51B801514E0D1DE2DE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the targeted measures described in this Act should be employed if engagement has failed to prevent significant actions that exacerbate climate change and deforestation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF738E9D2E1D4AE8BB49A75278DA1902"><enum>(6)</enum><text>given broad international support for countering climate change, the Secretary of State should encourage the governments of other countries to implement targeted measures that are similar to the provisions of this Act, and the Secretary of the Treasury should support implementation of such measures, in order to increase the effectiveness of actions taken by the United States to combat significant actions that exacerbate climate change, including related corruption and human rights violations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC3FCF4DF0D4C4331A1A9EF2D1DFCEE53"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy on application of Global Magnitsky sanctions to environment-linked corruption and human rights abuses</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABB0C667FFCF472F9C3844CCCBB4D790"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to consider use of applicable authorities described in Executive Order 13818 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking the property of persons involved in serious human rights abuse or corruption) in relation to activities described in section 5(b), including for acts of corruption and serious human rights abuses against individuals described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H373E35723E4C4F54B56B334C72941927"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text>An individual described in this subsection is an individual who—</text><paragraph id="HD495CA03BFE143BCA891D32C9A115C6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advocates for the protection of the environment, public health, Indigenous rights, or community land rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0CA42C899FE419AA6F1A660BB79967A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>investigates, exposes, or raises awareness of harm or corruption related to natural resource use; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60947ECABD19428B84C719FEF86FE76C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is obliged to leave the individual’s habitual home due, in whole or in part, to sudden or progressive change in the environment—</text><subparagraph id="H582E0E38ED73491594F1AF421F5E6FEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>caused by human activities or attributable to climate change; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7945DC1DB2F34A4382A722805ABC24FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that adversely affects the individual’s life or living conditions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBB06254226C245BA85596BED697215AF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to significant actions that exacerbate climate change, deforestation, or harm to environmental defenders</header><subsection id="H35AADAC6D3E3416CA52D4FAAEF1E4997"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the President should employ the authorities provided by this section to prioritize action against, and deterrence of, egregious behaviors that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA43039620EF24861B1C3EF61F40FF29F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undermine efforts to limit the increase in global average temperature to 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE41F3BC2A1E14A618E0F610AC71D2D35"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contribute to deforestation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA15EE86701A242AA88408030E239C7AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">present specific harm to environmental defenders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED8204E23350499182662558B6F30774"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose one or more of the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to any foreign person the President determines, based on credible information—</text><paragraph id="HD7C1EC48746B4AB2BDAEDB8D6F52B05D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>knowingly, recklessly, or willfully engages in an activity in a foreign country that causes, or is likely to cause, greenhouse gas emissions that are not in line with scientifically established pathways to help avoid a sustained increase in the Earth’s temperature of more than 1.5 degrees Celsius above pre-industrial levels, as determined by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, including any action that significantly undermines, as a result of timing, magnitude, or corruption, projects for the adoption in the country of high-efficiency, low-carbon, or renewable energy technology or infrastructure, including the construction of low-efficiency fossil fuel power plants;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CB04C7A9EC7451BBC01F6D6221ABF32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engages in an activity in a foreign country that causes, or is likely to cause, illegal deforestation or loss of natural carbon sinks, including—</text><subparagraph id="H8631C8B3CC754CCAB655381EFB07810E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishment of incentives for, or promotion of, knowingly conducting deforestation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2887A63F8FDD4CA78B542D2DE80D9FC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engagement in, or failure to combat, illegal logging, mining, or ranching;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6F16ECFEDBD420BAD2061AECF8C6E74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>knowingly engages in an activity in a foreign country that misrepresents the environmental impact of a project, investment, or product, including misrepresenting the amount of greenhouse gas emissions associated with the project, investment, or product, in the context of—</text><subparagraph id="HF94C3279F0B94B1C834EBCF188E889DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessments conducted by multilateral organizations, national governments, or investors; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE14F3501228B4090A00DC1435207C6CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public efforts to gain market advantage based on purported environmental advantages of a product;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAAF5BE4EBFD041FFBA0E6F4DAE370425"><enum>(4)</enum><text>engages in an activity in a foreign country that causes, or is likely to cause, limitations on or circumvention of opposition to deforestation or projects described in paragraph (1) by individuals seeking to protect the environment, public health, or community land rights, including actions that encourage impunity for those perpetrating physical threats or violence against such individuals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4089429248824299A04F6F02FBB4A732"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is otherwise responsible for or complicit in an activity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4), including a government official who approves or implements policies or acts that serve to promote such an activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80DCDA82DA9045E58E1C33502A5D5CAA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>has acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, any foreign person in a matter relating to an activity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4), including for or on behalf of a government official described in paragraph (5);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94A876A7C3D0424EBA42325E080E6942"><enum>(7)</enum><text>has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, an activity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0032229FD83A4B7896B899F1296E1992"><enum>(8)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by a foreign person that engages an activity described in any of paragraphs (1) through (4) or is described in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42ABE5DEE25C459383950BD00A15549F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions that may be imposed with respect to a foreign person under subsection (b) are the following:</text><paragraph id="H47FBD7C642024708B3F1DAC954D9B518"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Inadmissibility to united states</header><text>In the case of a foreign person who is an individual—</text><subparagraph id="HAB0546D9C56C49E0BAB8FE4A41A968EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ineligibility to receive a visa to travel to the United States or to be admitted to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE1DFF50AD454CA3A0E9B90ED07EC0C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the individual has been issued a visa or other documentation, revocation, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), of the visa or other documentation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96A9F134B7874216860D16A666984597"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><subparagraph id="H00625E66A14A404F9ACF1F97B20F28CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The blocking, in accordance with the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), of all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5F6029776CA4A8FA727FF92E87985A2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inapplicability of national emergency requirement</header><text>The requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>) shall not apply for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC368D47EA5624E87B7CA948C318278C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other sanctions options</header><text>Any of the sanctions described in section 235 of the Countering America's Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9529">22 U.S.C. 9529</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B23A359B7D3459E9F062504BE267D58"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration of certain information in imposing sanctions</header><text>In determining whether to impose sanctions under subsection (b), the President shall consider—</text><paragraph id="H96D9850501814561AF3FC5C1CB2FCA96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information provided jointly by the chairperson and ranking member of each of the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H648A0CC64E21439ABCB696A7EDADD035"><enum>(2)</enum><text>credible information obtained by other countries and nongovernmental organizations that monitor environmental harm or violations of human rights.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF99115FDA984ABE9EF3C8BA2D25CC5B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="HCE5A9AAECAB849E0BB326364FBF09538"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intelligence and law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H7E0986D2406A4CE2AFC07A5750694E1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9390F3757CC49E096030EBC0AE5394C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any authorized intelligence or law enforcement activities of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H494F7E84C92D4D6BBAB1D7D6B00BF862"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with united nations headquarters agreement</header><text>This section shall not apply with respect to the admission of an individual to the United States if the admission of the individual is necessary to comply with United States obligations under the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, under the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967, or under other international obligations of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E8C10CB38B444FF9C6858662209845B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subparagraph id="H7FBF3984539345C8B05BB13ADC239B35"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authority to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property under this section shall not include the authority to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7213446B6FA4D91823C1B37952F83EE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8196A49896BF4AFA8E68C31AD3312AF4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="H80355DCDA68A407C9D353C7B21A98AD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC07A2470B0F44017A375EDADB02DF33B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5D22AB84BB044C197C99714509620FB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEFD7C075428C4C7EA631A989C9098FE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0868B37A3D0F4572963D5AABA53298E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Environment and Public Works and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85AA39393EEF4BC9B54FE5CAD9192335"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B29F9BB7EC545B2932FFEB04CD54A3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Carbon sink</header><text>The term <term>carbon sink</term> means a feature or process that absorbs more carbon from the atmosphere than it releases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02CA627FDEE64821900A550D5741CD1B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deforestation</header><text>The term <term>deforestation</term> means the conversion of forest to other land use, whether human-induced or not, that results in—</text><subparagraph id="H91A4310B19DB4284AA3686674EC83E71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>permanent reduction of the tree canopy to less than a minimum 10 percent threshold; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A01865A40264CD5AF611F7FC4249038"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the conversion of areas of forest to agriculture, pasture, water reservoirs, mining, or urban areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFB7D8EA6509D458D9DE6C026444CA02C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1BBF51E477654DE4953A6E7E696C6A6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a person has actual knowledge of the facts; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB92797AD6DFC4B6AAAA1EB7A27A6686A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a reasonable person acting in the circumstances and exercising reasonable care would have that knowledge.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H088670BE21BE4DEB954E1CACFDB22E60"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D33591EE2BB477683138F1C70EEE357"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recklessly</header><text>The term <term>recklessly</term>, with respect to conduct, means that a person displays a deliberate indifference or conscious disregard to the consequences of the conduct.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA940C5984C3D4CADA06A5353568FCFAB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8402E6D736E746A2A9D6ECB75F9B0153"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65E7E0E9D688439CBD18C45C37217DC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H81562E0EE04B438094DB096596BB5044"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Willfully</header><text>The term <term>willfully</term>, with respect to conduct, means a person has knowledge—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8C95ACF77E074A3FA20DF7577350243C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the facts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74B996597EE54185A2C92F6AA157AB72"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the conduct was subject to sanctions under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4B567B4F54C24B0CA9887A8596516CBA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Additional resources for the Office of Foreign Assets Control</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Treasury such sums as may be necessary to support the targeting by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of persons under this Act and to enhance the ability of that Office to target persons for the imposition of sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/10101">22 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section></legis-body></bill>

