<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25192-C7S-6Y-KMH"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 579 ATS: Affirming the importance of the Social Security program to the people of the United States and expressing the sense of the Senate that Social Security must be preserved, protected, and strengthened for current and future generations.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 579</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260108" legis-day="20260107">January 8 (legislative day, January 7), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to </action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Affirming the importance of the Social Security program to the people of the United States and expressing the sense of the Senate that Social Security must be preserved, protected, and strengthened for current and future generations.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, on August 14, 1935, President Franklin D. Roosevelt signed the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/301">42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) into law, establishing a foundational commitment by the United States to provide economic security for its senior citizens;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Social Security program has served as the cornerstone of retirement security for generations of individuals in the United States, providing vital retirement, disability, and survivor benefits to millions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Social Security program has successfully paid scheduled benefits throughout its 90-year history, delivering on the promise earned by workers in the United States and their families through a lifetime of contributions;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Social Security program remains the primary source of income for millions of seniors, individuals with disabilities, and surviving family members, and its continued strength is vital to the economic well-being of the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Social Security program faces significant long-term financial challenges that require thoughtful and responsible action to ensure its continued stability and effectiveness;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas preserving and strengthening the Social Security program is a bipartisan responsibility that requires cooperation and leadership from policymakers; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas increased public awareness, education, and dialogue are essential to ensure that the Social Security program remains strong and solvent for current and future generations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="idcd5268592b1e460c9db943b16d3fa3a4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms its bipartisan commitment to preserving and protecting the Social Security program for current and future generations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id23102be9961d4262b7b1975893b3aad0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affirms that an automatic, across-the-board cut in benefits would disrupt the retirement security of tens of millions of people in the United States and must be avoided; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id074947acc5424526b5b7cb9845da5875"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls upon Members of Congress to work in a bipartisan manner to develop and enact legislation that ensures the long-term solvency of the Social Security program and protects seniors, individuals with disabilities, and families in the United States for generations to come.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

