<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7228154A83B84D01BBE099218B7336DC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6358 IH: Veteran Education Empowerment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6358</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize and improve a grant program to assist institutions of higher education in establishing, maintaining, improving, and operating Student Veteran Centers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1EAF6E0065D64161B3EA690CD7718109" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H482192D96F1C4EBCA321493EF0054A3E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Education Empowerment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7AF922D28A714B25861B1E675AC43393"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H3EC189FF196D463690B40938F36A36D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Almost 1,000,000 veterans attend institutions of higher education each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF55599FF5C2E4544BA683FB2DE051FC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Veterans face unique challenges in transitioning from the battlefield to the classroom and eventually to the workforce, including age differences, family obligations, significant time away from academic life, and service-related disabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F6BE40C89464501B72696696F7734D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Studies have found that student veterans can feel lonely and vulnerable on campus and that connecting student veterans can effectively ease this isolation by bringing together new student veterans with those who have already successfully navigated the first few semesters of college.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47BA47328CE54D75973CE4F232F2C7D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Student Veteran Centers are recognized as an institutional best practice by Student Veterans of America.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57606352F8DD45C1A7FA6F4A66116BEB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Department of Education included as one of its 8 Keys to Veterans’ Success that colleges and universities should <quote>coordinate and centralize campus efforts for all veterans, together with the creation of a designated space for them</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE241A7B1A3564F2898945A8D27C048F5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Budget constraints often make it difficult or impossible for institutions of higher education to dedicate space to veteran offices, lounges, or student centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H702DFD581EB84BCAB029F9C300EF65F3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The 110th Congress authorized the funding of Student Veteran Centers through the Centers of Excellence for Veteran Student Success under part T of title VIII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161t">20 U.S.C. 1161t</external-xref>). Congress has appropriated funding for this program in subsequent years.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H205EA8D681444A2C9C657956297D153D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program to establish, maintain, and improve Student Veteran Centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part T of title VIII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161t">20 U.S.C. 1161t</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF76D0002035249BE9EC7769BD79813AA"><part id="HF464A4ADAF094CEC900DF56BD8755DB0"><enum>T</enum><header>Grants for Student Veteran Centers</header><section id="H0FD75D70DE94422EB0B994342A3DC441"><enum>873.</enum><header>Grants for Student Veteran Centers</header><subsection id="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations under <internal-xref idref="H3D5AD1EE888B43AAA58EE095069CFF41" legis-path="873.(h)">subsection (h)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall award grants to institutions of higher education or consortia of institutions of higher education to assist in the establishment, maintenance, improvement, and operation of Student Veteran Centers.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB9E45E6FA6C41ACBA4DF4BA0020E978"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><paragraph id="H24FE6B285924449D9A795D7AE3FA7B94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An institution or consortium seeking a grant under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H315D909454EA4587B4B50EC88B6F7C23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> to an institution or a consortium if the institution or consortium meets each of the following criteria:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H44D9C8CE8AB3470E88278A9042BD7577"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium enrolls in undergraduate or graduate courses—</text><clause commented="no" id="HEFDF5A16F9AC411B9509F6366A05C33A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a significant number of student veterans, members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty, or members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H605979AB8EEB4E9FA1E35F39CAB3028B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a significant percentage of student veterans, members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty, or members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces,</text></clause></subparagraph><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="paragraph" indent="subparagraph">as measured by comparing, for the most recent academic year for which data are available, the number or percentage of student veterans, members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty, and members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces who are enrolled in undergraduate or graduate courses at the institution or consortium, with the average number or percentage of student veterans, members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty, and members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces who were enrolled in undergraduate or graduate courses at comparable institutions or consortia of institutions.</continuation-text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFF5E0F46AF464E08B66284A658F4E11E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The institution or consortium presents a sustainability plan to demonstrate that the Student Veteran Center will be maintained and will continue to operate after the grant period has ended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4DD0D2CDD084509BE6F535D6B575023"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In awarding grants under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall provide the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC7042D98BC194D3E889E3257697842EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Priority consideration to institutions or consortia that meet one or more of the following criteria:</text><clause id="H0A94EC6C2C464008B039E480CD39D44C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The institution or consortium is located in a region or community that has a significant population of veterans.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF34070347DD447798F5CF3549DDDF0D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium considers the need to serve student veterans at a wide range of institutions of higher education, including the need to provide equitable distribution of grants to institutions of various sizes, geographic locations, and institutions in urban and rural areas.</text></clause><clause id="H24ABD6D789274E5FB97BC7D40AF79DBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium carries out programs or activities that assist veterans in the local community, and the spouses or partners and children of student veterans.</text></clause><clause id="H99F5BDEF75D44183BD0FF661CA6FEF11"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium partners in its veteran-specific programming with nonprofit veteran service organizations, local workforce development organizations, or other institutions of higher education.</text></clause><clause id="H131CE0594BC844C2ABA5AA7903C29067"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium commits to hiring a staff at the Student Veteran Center that includes veterans (including student veteran volunteers and student veterans participating in a Federal work-study program under part C of title IV, a work-study program administered by the Secretary of Veteran Affairs, or a State work-study program).</text></clause><clause id="HD662333F16B14DDB839EEB84F0B8E765"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium commits to providing an orientation for student veterans that—</text><subclause id="HE7CB090FB9DC4528A154FC1A6469F262"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is separate from the new student orientation provided by the institution or consortium; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD6BFBB2053F14092A2F2463EDFAA5E86"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides student veterans with information on the benefits and resources available to such students at or through the institution or consortium.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H46A03A18AEE04F91AB454C245CF7528D"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium commits to using a portion of the grant received under this section to develop or maintain a student veteran retention program carried out by the Student Veteran Center.</text></clause><clause id="HF4C7EB7923EE46089510A9696EFF29F4"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution or consortium commits to providing mental health counseling to its student veterans (and the spouses or partners and children of such students).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CD7BCFBDAD048629203ECD9263ABEAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Equitable distribution of such grants to institutions or consortia of various sizes, geographic locations, and in urban and rural areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF36D50E228F94955A2330287F507247A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H761323D4C0B846AAB709CF04B773997D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An institution or consortium that is awarded a grant under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall use such grant to establish, maintain, improve, or operate a Student Veteran Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33CFD077E32C4953BE2C4DE881658480"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other allowable uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution or consortium receiving a grant under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> may use a portion of such grant to carry out supportive instruction services for student veterans, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF9D14DD9AC1A4628A5917EB9502E8D17"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance with special admissions and transfer of credit from previous postsecondary education or experience; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE3E3D772F8643BD9F8FBCF8B1E0E103"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other support services the institution or consortium determines to be necessary to ensure the success of student veterans in achieving education and career goals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C99CACA3D87476EA2D86BA78994DAC7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amounts awarded</header><paragraph id="H2D15D5F9D72A45BAA0B1DD2208A4317D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Each grant awarded under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> shall be for a 4-year period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC1D91CF28484D648A1094171DA64EEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Total amount of grant and schedule</header><text>Each grant awarded under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> may not exceed a total of $500,000. The Secretary shall disburse to an institution or consortium the amount awarded under the grant in such amounts and at such times during the grant period as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B8B03677CCC4BA6BBACAE62E60F85BD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>From the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, and not later than 3 years after the date on which the first grant is awarded under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the grant program established under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, including—</text><paragraph id="H7CC87F38D0F140BCA74BE6DB2CD9F4D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of grants awarded;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9244AD3858F846E7A573542ECA96F543"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the institutions of higher education and consortia that have received grants;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H899D36C6017243AD8E93689CDC45EE57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to each such institution of higher education and consortium—</text><subparagraph id="HE4A01BB3C969493EB2596CB0D8E807CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amounts awarded;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B8AC2E86E5542E997B2920888BEB126"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how such institution or consortium used such amounts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFDBBE66EDB741488F3444920BCCBEE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the demographics of student veterans (and spouses or partners and children of such students) to whom services were offered as a result of the award, including students who are women and belong to minority groups;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18AC49E0C0D0410BBA92F4779F45F058"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of student veterans (and spouses or partners and children of such students) to whom services were offered as a result of the award, and a description of the services that were offered and provided; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6E09DC0A710446DA8861A4B945438C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>data enumerating whether the use of the amounts awarded helped student veterans at the institution or consortium toward completion of a degree, certificate, or credential;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD42B48481D4A89BA7D9BD095B8E872"><enum>(4)</enum><text>best practices for student veteran success, identified by reviewing data provided by institutions and consortia that received a grant under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DF7745CE16B4F74AF91F9BFB3807A78"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a determination by the Secretary with respect to whether the grant program under this section should be extended or expanded.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C63467347614566ACF301D864647217"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Department of Education best practices website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations under <internal-xref idref="H3D5AD1EE888B43AAA58EE095069CFF41" legis-path="873.(h)">subsection (h)</internal-xref> and not later than 3 years after the date on which the first grant is awarded under <internal-xref idref="HE42E60EB0581496697E8B1D4B77EFBAD" legis-path="873.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, the Secretary shall develop and implement a website for Student Veteran Centers at institutions of higher education, which details best practices for serving student veterans at institutions of higher education.</text></subsection><subsection id="H959E89CB809A4A99A535697EB5865604"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD16514982D4246638230AE60B411771D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E01AA009E6D4480B8758A103A81F2BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student Veteran Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Student Veteran Center</term> means a dedicated space on a campus of an institution of higher education that provides students who are veterans, members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty, or members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces with the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6EBEAF0521AF4AA9BBBE65C42C2C29CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A lounge or meeting space for such student veterans (and the spouses or partners and children of such students), and veterans in the community.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCB1B46961D84FEBBFFD1FF9BE981B94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A centralized office for student veteran services that—</text><clause id="H45F486A2E86D4AB09FC480047C44618A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a single point of contact to coordinate comprehensive support services for student veterans;</text></clause><clause id="H0D0BA6DC47094A1A89DF5F16DB8B545B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is staffed by trained employees and volunteers, which includes veterans and at least one full-time employee or volunteer who is trained as a veterans’ benefits counselor;</text></clause><clause id="HBFBAB6C5904944E48A7E35223EEC8DC4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides student veterans with assistance relating to—</text><subclause id="H15AB5EBB96B043AD9BEB87372603BB1F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transitioning from the military to student life;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0C311C8BBAB943498DC8E7AEEDB4942E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>transitioning from the military to the civilian workforce;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC6A8F1A32CAB49C993931580AEB03FCD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>networking with other student veterans and veterans in the community;</text></subclause><subclause id="H76C938D7F0274F9FAC486F1293E30A59"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>understanding and obtaining benefits provided by the institution of higher education, Federal Government, and State for which such students may be eligible;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB1CF95CBCCB84033887C441877DF08F6"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">understanding how to succeed in the institution of higher education, including by understanding academic policies, the course selection process, and institutional policies and practices related to the transfer of academic credits; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H46DA829EDD8F4C3DABD189D960C6A93D"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">understanding disability-related rights and protections under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) and section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3E36A5F97D364B87983C39CF8E7933D0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provides comprehensive academic and tutoring services for student veterans, including peer-to-peer tutoring and academic mentorship.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D5AD1EE888B43AAA58EE095069CFF41"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2026 and each of the 7 succeeding fiscal years.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

