<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1EC607C536EF4652B91B3F87CD5A0BEA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6430 IH: Junk Fee Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6430</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit and eliminate excessive, hidden, and unnecessary fees imposed on consumers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H00E20C4B336A49C7828E55D3A495B4B1" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HBC3E9D5FE5D148F69CA2DBCAA8B79041"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Junk Fee Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H39735744BDF0478C975EAC16B97BD23B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protecting consumers from excessive and hidden fees</header><subsection id="H197A23F616C1443191C54ECA22B2F311"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Protecting consumers from hidden fees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1289496A837244B3B8A94C945434207E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered entity shall clearly and conspicuously display, in each advertisement and when a price is first shown to a consumer, the total price of the good or service provided by the covered entity, including any mandatory fees a consumer would incur during the purchase of the good or service and any mandatory government charge related to such purchase.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9DB291F72614312B94B62622D6A1F31"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Price consistency</header><text>A covered entity shall ensure that any mandatory fee incurred by a consumer during the purchase process does not change from that advertised to the consumer.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99FBAD583CBD40A78FC8038ED21C977D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Excessive fees</header><text>A covered entity shall not impose on a consumer or advertise any mandatory fees that are excessive or deceptive for any good or service offered by the covered entity.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2D7CF758DA44F3A86FC9C9564813BB3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ticket holdbacks</header><text>If a good or service provided by a covered entity is a ticket to a sporting event, theater, musical performance, or other live performance that an audience watches as the live performance occurs, the covered entity shall, not less than 72 hours prior to the first public sale or presale of such ticket, clearly and conspicuously disclose to the public, including at the point of sale, the total number of tickets offered for sale by the covered entity or available for the given event.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE018B65244EA4CDDB459CCBD3FEE522D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Protecting refunds</header><text>A covered entity shall clearly and conspicuously disclose any guarantee or refund policy prior to the completion of a transaction by the consumer and, in the event of a refund, provide a refund in the amount of the total cost of the ticket including any mandatory fees.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB41960F646D349219AEA89ACEF5ECBEC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Speculative ticketing</header><text>If a covered entity does not possess a ticket at the time of the sale, it shall provide to the consumer—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82C350427002426A8832CB623596A3B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a clear and conspicuous notice that the covered entity does not possess the ticket; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC5FC949A1AA4525BC3B73D449B87F8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a full refund if the covered entity cannot provide the ticket advertised to the consumer in a timely manner prior to the event.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H482650C72A7941D4AF285F20A277A555"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking on excessive and hidden fees</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission may promulgate rules in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, regarding the disclosure and imposition of mandatory or deceptive fees, including any such fee not described in subsections (a) through (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA4685F7AFB949BDAB2566D45BACCDB0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Excessive fees</header><text>In considering whether a mandatory fee is excessive, the Federal Trade Commission or court shall take into consideration—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H926EEC7202AD4BDB95AC789177BC11DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the fee is reasonable and proportional to the cost of the good or service provided by the covered entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF07FD4C36EC4383A968D22928063536"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the reason for which the covered entity charges such fee; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9342F011E974F7B90939058EF6C9CF5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other factors determined appropriate by the Federal Trade Commission or the court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB03F4C0235643788118C22A5FB4EF76"><enum>(h)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EE4D13377F140638C02F1E508D1F987"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement by the Commission</header><subparagraph id="H2AFF086FAEE84D678B8761E2530C033A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBFAED83C3BC40AD91CC01E4A9222FF4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><clause id="H35642A8C197E4660A125733E10D48FBF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></clause><clause id="H931CDE5B27E24F3EAE73B09F39172F8F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HF723189538C84335A7D8B8A2E7F0D2AD"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Federal Trade Commission under any other provision of law.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9075B19800AA427CADB25DFBDCF253D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header><subparagraph id="H11803A96B7F74A4F9A24879550C667E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that a covered entity has violated or is violating this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder that affects the residents of that State, the State, as parens patriae, may bring a civil action in any appropriate district court of the United States, to—</text><clause id="HCB056B461CDA4FF0BDB03CBFCA5DC144"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enjoin any further violation by the covered entity;</text></clause><clause id="HACF2B26CF90243C586F84BB76AFE23AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enforce compliance with this section or such regulation;</text></clause><clause id="H369585737AC54FFA9960A407C35B90D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obtain other remedies permitted under State law; and</text></clause><clause id="H0BA1804CFFD24625B20F9F2B231A7CD0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDECBAD4606A4206AD67D62C11F83582"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The attorney general of a State shall provide prior written notice of any action under subparagraph (A) to the Commission and provide the Commission with a copy of the complaint in the action, except in any case in which such prior notice is not feasible, in which case the attorney general shall serve such notice immediately upon instituting such action.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ED56E0316E4432E999A6187421E6599"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Intervention by the Commission</header><text>Upon receiving notice under subparagraph (B), the Commission shall have the right—</text><clause id="H4E208AEB502343AB9A97690A62EB9607"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to intervene in the action;</text></clause><clause id="H88367A7D4DF84A8B8799A9DD3E7A5AAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon so intervening, to be heard on all matters arising therein; and</text></clause><clause id="H59777D406E014C06A1D589A8A6AF92B6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to file petitions for appeal.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25334C83B00B4F99B249767AB4D699D3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text>If the Commission has instituted a civil action for violation of this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder, no attorney general of a State, or official or agency of a State, may bring a separate action under subparagraph (A) during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for any violation of this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder that is alleged in the complaint. An attorney general of a State, or official or agency of a State, may join a civil action for a violation of this section or a regulation promulgated thereunder filed by the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98E89B5B4CE444268E8710923EB80124"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing a civil action under subparagraph (A), nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the chief law enforcement officer or official or agency of a State, from exercising the powers conferred on such chief law enforcement officer or official or agency of a State, by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, administer oaths or affirmations, or compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H237AFDD3051C4F6ABACF607101CFA4DB"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39C9D78817994D84A8584C6C99F5DA42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB97BCBCF553A4167BDC79B53B44D5A63"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered entity</term> means—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97ACA8F97F3C405EBC31EC6DE2A6F59C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a provider of short-term lodging or an online platform that allows for the booking of short-term lodging;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69B84CEC3AF5445DA8B00F5D041FDC07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a provider of a ticketing service that sells tickets for an event or retains the authority to otherwise distribute tickets for such event, whether as a primary seller of tickets or in the secondary marketplace for ticket sales; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0ED40BA551247788A722AC6680F538F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other entity determined appropriate by the Commission through a rulemaking in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA648F5E916854669940AA57E3CBA1A83"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Short-term lodging</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0D233D5F9684B0D9E56D866B907E4D6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in clause (ii), the term <term>short-term lodging</term> means any lodging that is offered for an occupancy of less than 6 months or temporary sleeping accommodations at a hotel, motel, inn, short-term rental, vacation rental, or other place of lodging.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4828061DE2214EE99F7A4ED442D73093"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>short-term lodging</term> shall not include an accommodation of 6 months or more through a landlord-tenant relationship.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0A49E261CDA4D1BA87F209259C73440"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deceptive fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deceptive fee</term> includes—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F24737105664C10AD4C057E2D0591AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any fee for which the nature, purpose, amount, or refundability of such fee is misrepresented; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC89B35D14B984B0ABFBE6C6D83A1081B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any mandatory fee misrepresented as an optional fee that a consumer must opt out of.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7BFD98FBF6849E2BB080B9B6429ED61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mandatory fee</header><text>The term <term>mandatory fee</term> includes—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H955FED32CFC74E8F8F7ADB186DF1F62A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any fee or surcharge that a consumer is required to pay to purchase a good or service being advertised;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF87DFC7D07D47B59F76AB4C8D6909C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a fee or surcharge that is not reasonably avoidable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA67717D78A04443C80EE05CC83EDE554"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fee or surcharge for a good or service that a reasonable consumer would not expect to be included with the purchase of the good or service being advertised; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A89940C19A74E66AE6CB83C31965B9D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other fee or surcharge determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H5F4667028B3B4AE8BC6F9457AE8041A9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Communications service fees</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9EBE855F85BB4347A47631CBCA8671F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ending early termination fees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1738E25321F34009916D835783ED29C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>A provider of a covered service may not charge a fee to, or impose a requirement that is excessive or unreasonable on, a consumer for the termination of a covered service before the end of any period specified in any agreement between the provider and the consumer.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F8B17FAB2D744AE82C771C570EB28C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ending excess billing cycle charges</header><text>After termination of a covered service, the provider of the covered service shall provide to the consumer a prorated credit or rebate for the remaining days in the billing cycle.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F6E6FAC45AE413894246646A10204E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Device purchase and return</header><text>This subsection does not prevent a provider of a covered service from charging a consumer for—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93B45D92ACE64761969C8F94F080B51B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of rental or loan equipment that is not returned to the provider within a reasonable period of time; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3200521783F45E5961C28643609AF83"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the outstanding cost of a purchased device.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6957B0B32D4141CCA4A2246571202681"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Communications Commission may promulgate regulations to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1D7AD456BB24BB3A0E6631A5C782619"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Truth in billing and advertising</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H74ECD4789E8947B0BCC98C7684C023C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aggregate price transparency in billing</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H38FBF4C5CC864FA98741B59CA38B0A2D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A provider of a covered service shall state an aggregate price for the covered service through a single, clear, easy-to-understand, and accurate line item on the bill of a consumer, including a bill for a legacy or grandfathered covered service plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF7DB075CC614EA88623F8B2147891B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure of end date of introductory or temporary price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A provider of a covered service shall state, on the bill of each consumer paying an introductory or temporary price, the date on which the introductory or temporary price ends by disclosing—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8779277CD6C0437FA0E444635566F7D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71079529B79C4AD985E6F6FF0A5F72B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the period during which the discounted price will be charged; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3338FB92350340C8890D4C0E20CCA520"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the period will end, resulting in a price change for the covered service; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H745818A173E14524AD614BD5663BC14D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the post-promotion rate not later than—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B2FAD65D2284DE48F3CDC3E80282EAF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">60 days before the date on which the introductory or temporary price ends; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6F2BC45B02845BA88D2208B29E4B122"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">30 days before such date.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H502AB0F6D8FB4C769324B8179028CB5A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Itemization</header><text>A provider of a covered service may state an itemized explanation of the elements that compose the aggregate price required by subparagraph (A) on the bill of a consumer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFFC76FDBC674705931BF5785BFBCA47" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aggregate price transparency for promotional materials</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE2910E1A3402435DA433F4993BEACDA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A provider of a covered service that communicates a price for the covered service in promotional materials shall state an aggregate price for the covered service and, at the option of the provider of the covered service, an itemized explanation of the elements of such price in a clear, easy-to-understand, and accurate manner.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B9EB1A238A94EDFBA035CA66146F048"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosure of location-dependent pricing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the aggregate price described in subparagraph (A) fluctuates based on service location, the provider of a covered service shall state where and how a consumer may obtain the location-specific aggregate price, such as electronically or by contacting a customer service or sales representative.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD98E7047CEA5464E8CCA35B10ADAF314"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disclosure of temporary aggregate pricing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If part or all of the aggregate price described in subparagraph (A) is temporary, a provider of a covered service shall state the post-promotion rate, the date on which the post-promotion rate was calculated, and the period for which each rate applies in the promotional materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23420A3D021347F19E9F2433112C0C88"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Itemization</header><text>A provider of a covered service may state an itemized explanation of the elements that compose the aggregate price required by subparagraph (A) in the promotional materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3838A9D4ABE549D890C9225DF5F21404"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements under this paragraph shall not apply to the marketing of legacy or grandfathered covered service plans that are not generally available to new customers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F0D4BE3BB004837B614526079FF9437"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking on mandatory fees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21628556CCFD401A928152A231768EA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Initial rulemaking proceeding</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Communications Commission shall commence a rulemaking proceeding—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BBF79F8CB64404181E5959060BF6211"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to consider whether and how the Federal Communications Commission should—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0EDC29DED2A4318A5939FBFFA03A1E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require the disclosure of mandatory fees with respect to a covered service; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC46F1060AAD14E76990A23F97B88EAB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>prohibit the imposition of mandatory fees with respect to a covered service, in particular any such fee that a consumer would reasonably assume to be included in the advertised price of such service; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2F8F81A8B82479786E3D1706953B119" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in which the Federal Communications Commission may promulgate regulations to implement the requirements or prohibitions described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01729BB3ECD94193B4E57EDABD826D71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent study or regulations</header><text>Any time after the completion of the rulemaking proceeding required under paragraph (1), the Federal Communications Commission may conduct a study or promulgate regulations regarding mandatory fees with respect to covered services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8BC77B92A4542869B4C0EA93620FB0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="HCADCDB52BE874267895B2E4C9F84318E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A violation of this section or a regulation promulgated under this section shall be treated as a violation of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) or a regulation promulgated under that Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A7E343DD3B84C5CB22E6007D1E1265C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manner of enforcement</header><text>The Federal Communications Commission shall enforce this section and the regulations promulgated under this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC79ABCB3213049D7A13466FDB2964AC4"><enum>(e)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8E7AF45A92DB409FA2BA7BBA4FEC3DAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered service</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4955DE6C70654F04868061002DDB3DC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H58F384EAB856467D81EE31F519DD19B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">broadband internet access service (as defined in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation));</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83A3E0BA160C4C89987D482A1DD0FD90"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>voice service (as defined in section 227(e)(8) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/227">47 U.S.C. 227(e)(8)</external-xref>));</text>
                        </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD97102260549432FA0646BD340E68BB3">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">commercial mobile service (as defined in section 332(d) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/332">47 U.S.C. 332(d)</external-xref>));</text>
 </clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D36758AAFB54940828D3F0E60DB7F25"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>commercial mobile data service (as defined in section 6001 of the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1401">47 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>)); or</text></clause><clause id="H03722075B7674783A18A6833F0B07171"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a service provided by a multichannel video programming distributor (as defined in section 602 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/522">47 U.S.C. 522</external-xref>)), to the extent that such distributor is acting as a multichannel video programming distributor; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9CA2AFE3C2B4790B3E9BB5DE9578209"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any other service offered or provided as part of a bundle or package with any service described in clauses (i) through (v) of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD001B54B8860427581B18A5873D09FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mandatory fee</header><text>The term <term>mandatory fee</term> includes—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD50ED85734249279B1E4466DD9416F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any fee or surcharge that a consumer is required to pay to purchase a covered service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67F440C2059347898AB3B6E6A4A4DFB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any fee or surcharge that is not reasonably avoidable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB77BA69D1E8F4A609C909BF5A1F86F5C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fee or surcharge for a good or service that a reasonable consumer would not expect to be included with the purchase of the good or service being advertised; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECE5AF5AD4224793AA12C511831BF527"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other fee or surcharge determined appropriate by the Federal Communications Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DAEDF1450E7422794CF0C4BFA60E017" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Promotional material</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>promotional material</term> includes video programming in which a provider of a covered service advertises or markets a covered service to consumers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCE5E940596CB4B92A93DC10D91CAF508"><enum>4.</enum><header>Air carrier ancillary fee transparency</header><subsection id="HA6AF01F8CB2543DC9FCD7CF914F2C5FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Section 41708 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HE7FF45D5E7D149CA94BE9A5C64146E7D" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA7E0A07F0B26470EB51B60E307E23C6B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Ancillary fees</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H673C3AA530A4418693463A6B617CCBE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Quarterly reports</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0FB9A4226434EA4A96E9DFA36BDEE63"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Secretary shall require any air carrier or foreign air carrier operating in the United States to file with the Secretary a report for each quarter of the fiscal year on the total revenue such air carrier or foreign air carrier earned from ancillary fees (as defined in paragraph (2)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCD64881786D42C499FF2569ECE95BF3"><enum>(B)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Contents</header><text>A quarterly report filed by an air carrier or foreign air carrier under subparagraph (A) shall include, at a minimum, the following information:</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D5BF367B41D45AE8141C5FD8B456EAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The revenue received from ancillary fees during the reporting period, provided in an exact dollar amount, including—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE28ECE69A89844C2BB460FC3970194D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount received;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFCA74708A6D34AA7A01E2E09546B3142"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total amount disaggregated by each critical ancillary service provided; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62B2136BCE534D27AB31E08E68299DC8"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the total amount disaggregated by class of service.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26C73DBFEB0A44AAA4E3A3E65BF1851E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The manner in which the air carrier or foreign air carrier collects ancillary fees, including whether the fee for a critical ancillary service is included in the base fare price or charged to the consumer through another method.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6A02B15F59354DDAA199B9CFCF07BD32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The average dollar amount charged to a consumer for each critical ancillary service provided.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8B83ECFC9EB4F8E857BD8412E7E5310"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Publication</header><text>Notwithstanding section 329(b)(1)(A), the Secretary shall compile the information provided in the quarterly reports filed pursuant to subparagraph (A) in a single quarterly report (which shall include a comparison of the total revenue received from ancillary fees by each air carrier or foreign air carrier) and publish such report on the internet website of the Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE667BF1BF6D44CBDAD8B1D31456E3099"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF66EEE052C274F82AEDFE0CB6655A4FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ancillary fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ancillary fees</term> means any fee charged, through a direct payment or other form of compensation, by an air carrier or foreign air carrier for the provision of—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65DB5BA8756F45EA8F51DB2DC476AB9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a critical ancillary service; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83C59EA7B2604EEABECAB7605E575021"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other service not subject to taxation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4261">section 4261</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1A23AE4D437417493CB5292E165654E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Critical ancillary service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>critical ancillary service</term> means, with respect to an air carrier or foreign air carrier, any supplemental service provided by the air carrier or foreign air carrier that is critical to the purchasing decision of a consumer, including—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BA65C2FB804401DB0894DC3332B59ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transporting checked or carry-on baggage;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H987D62B5E8804B90B4723A2BBA5C4DAB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifying or canceling a reservation;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF2F9CB13DBE4446B9F4A4A325B2396B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">selecting or otherwise indicating a preference for seating on an aircraft; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F5255A087EB446EAB63030C79F3A7B2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other service determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5B58B5F6EA2E4564AF4678F60CA4ECB0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Record requirements</header><text>Section 41709(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>(including information regarding the source of revenue and whether such money was received from a base fare price or from an ancillary fee (as defined in section 41708(d))</quote> after <quote>receipts and expenditures of money</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

