<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4DA5F0CABE8B4084B4AE206D6EF5F30D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7405 IH: Rail and Highway Transmission Planning Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7405</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study on using highway rights-of-way and rail rights-of-way as locations on which to construct high-voltage transmission infrastructure, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF35E755AADAA445F8EF164B86AB1F98E" style="OLC"><section id="H6440AB3779234A88A29CBADC726FAE62" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rail and Highway Transmission Planning Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2D905A12EAA946E892D8B626886E9029"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress; Purpose</header><subsection id="HEE4B14F0E9734ACD9635676C074828C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that transportation rights-of-way, including highway and rail rights-of-way, should be utilized in ways that serve the public interest, including accommodating new electric transmission infrastructure.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5E8DD151C6AA4BB3979E87297D6A3459"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to accelerate the development of high-voltage transmission infrastructure by identifying opportunities to co-locate such projects within existing transportation rights-of-way, with the goal of alleviating energy capacity constraints and delivering more affordable, reliable electricity for consumers.</text></subsection></section><section id="H14CC12621D0C41EEB8C6CD09B6ED46A4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on placing high-voltage transmission infrastructure on rail and highway rights-of-ways</header><subsection id="H726AD940234F456094FB5A4E9947CEEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and each director of a National Laboratory determined relevant by the Secretary of Energy, shall conduct a study evaluating the potential benefits and challenges of using covered rights-of-way as locations on which to construct high-voltage transmission infrastructure.</text></subsection><subsection id="H486AC19964DC4BC7BA5DC784DA7B52AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>In carrying out the study under subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy shall—</text><paragraph id="HDCFE5529D0F54A97A9D6F01A00F29101"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a review of projects completed or being carried out to develop high-voltage electric transmission infrastructure on a covered right-of-way in the United States, including an assessment of any challenges with respect to safety, engineering, property rights, or other matters encountered while carrying out such projects and how each such challenge was addressed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H816156251F8D46A8BE218920E4D15BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>based on the results of the review under paragraph (1), determine best practices with respect to the planning, permitting, financing, and developing of high-voltage electric transmission infrastructure on a covered right-of-way;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9837F877CCE9466AB219D6E3AFCD148E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">generate, or consolidate from available sources, data on covered rights-of-way to evaluate the technical feasibility of building high-voltage transmission lines on each such covered right-of-way;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H406AA5921D394867B86BC243EF8BF600"><enum>(4)</enum><text>using data generated or consolidated under paragraph (3), identify each covered right-of-way suitable for the construction of high-voltage transmission lines considering—</text><subparagraph id="HFA5D2107AACE40B582C3D3F5CEFE4D23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to the geographic region of each covered right-of-way evaluated, the need for transmission infrastructure to alleviate energy transmission capacity constraints or congestion in the geographic region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF9785F489E84F7AA9C35DFA6E5CC8E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the technical feasibility of building high-voltage transmission lines on each such covered right-of-way; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B0D54F0B5D24B6496D53E3EA15778D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other considerations determined appropriate by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAD1E9CF567B447D97CF4D394C8C4389"><enum>(5)</enum><text>with respect to each covered right-of-way identified under paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H3582391ADD4440B8AB7A196376995823"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the suitability of various high-voltage transmission configurations, accounting for the infrastructure needs of each such configuration, including—</text><clause id="H85A04AC30CA340EF8382A2BDA900BD39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high-voltage alternating current;</text></clause><clause id="H0418D31560C74724A57726E4CC0DD85C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>high-voltage direct current;</text></clause><clause id="H4DE1C23647D34519A2ECBCAB90676B56"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>point-to-point high-voltage direct current;</text></clause><clause id="H10F82BCDD66140088E128322B76BE974"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>multi-terminal bi-directional high-voltage direct current systems;</text></clause><clause id="HEEA098E1266D4B3FA92088313DCA3ACE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>overhead lines;</text></clause><clause id="HB89C2E83DD9646D1A19FC22FF658EDC2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>underground lines; and</text></clause><clause id="HF313E66D803C4BAD882F05A4B4CA3F50"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>any other relevant configuration, as determined by the Secretary;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H981F5139C9FD42EB8555F74198128D46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and examine any potential challenges unique to transmission development in the covered right-of-way;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0289F4530474C8197A760613F1EE294"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determine the costs and benefits of constructing high-voltage transmission infrastructure in the covered right-of-way, including any cost or time savings expected to be realized with respect to land acquisition or obtaining any requisite permits, and compare such costs and benefits to the average costs and benefits of constructing similar high-voltage transmission infrastructure on lands that are not a covered right-of-way;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA72026255C3E4FD99AD202F6B6E0D36F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identify—</text><clause id="H95BF9AD72F084330962A51D7602CF78C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any potential funding mechanisms and financing opportunities available for entities to use for the construction of high-voltage transmission infrastructure on the right-of-way; and</text></clause><clause id="H10DC584D3F0E4D3FBE666FA15156F1DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any potential financial benefits for stakeholders in such construction, including owners of property abutting the right-of-way or otherwise implicated by the construction; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF39F9B04AFF4B83B7808AE86B20B43E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>analyze how, if at all, the construction of high-voltage transmission infrastructure on the covered right-of-way is likely to support improvements in grid reliability, streamline the interconnection queue, increase energy transmission capacity, contribute to reduced energy costs for energy consumers, and improve highway or rail safety and efficiency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A62088B53AF418B983CD5F3453692F1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>evaluate the effects, if any, of constructing and operating high-voltage transmission lines on covered rights-of-way on the environment, railroad operations, and communities near the right-of-way, including—</text><subparagraph id="H0FF9411D2CB44BB9B49CA5FCD1AB1078"><enum>(A)</enum><text>electromagnetic interference with rail safety, rail signaling equipment, and rail communication equipment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDA03A9D699142F0A892F5BB1754AD33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the potential for safety or operational interference while performing maintenance, rehabilitation work, or expansion of transportation infrastructure on covered rights-of-way;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5532761D15C46F290F0E5CA175C0225"><enum>(7)</enum><text>develop—</text><subparagraph id="H5A82F576252249C38254578E96EED141"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an interagency action plan with respect to the construction and operation of high-voltage transmission lines on covered rights-of-way; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA62AB48E897B422083628661F7457B05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for use facilitating the construction of high-voltage transmission infrastructure on a covered right-of-way, resources for use by—</text><clause id="H52E0112DDE5B4493A932DEB2AB9D881C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal, State, and local governmental agencies; and</text></clause><clause id="H832DE87AFD3F40D5AEDCBF177E92350D"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>utilities, railroad carriers, and other relevant stakeholders, as identified by the Secretary; and</text>
 </clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H314F3D14FCC34EA4AA615E0FA5BDB842"><enum>(8)</enum><text>consult utilities, railroad carriers, and any relevant stakeholders, as identified by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BDDC018FB044BEDB3DEA63DFB292195"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><paragraph id="H265693B3171A4FBB81C1A52D4D2B774A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rolling publication of study elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as is practicable after each element of the study described in subsection (b) is complete, the Secretary shall publish the results of the element and any data developed or consolidated in the completion of the element.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3B00EA2B9E6470B820DECBAF51AD66D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC8CEF074DF2B4DF89984538C9A59E47D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report detailing the results of the study under subsection (a), including all data underpinning such results, which shall be presented in a machine-readable format; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18D660D1D01646719FAAA9CEFA006B88" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish such report and such data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA4E0813D0A40F8ADAF209B426B2A13"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>All information, data, and reports published pursuant to this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H3A2ED3100C584A88BA4866AC09C1AA79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be published on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Energy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A9F5684BEB74FBCA8B4E0783FBC981B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be published with redactions of any data the publication of which the Secretary determine poses a national security risk.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD2CC9708B054513B02560603BC80378"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H01926206ED2B4F4AA0D798071DD13C50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered right-of-way</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered right-of-way</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8D3F8D8D757743AAB24D081A11507B48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a highway right-of-way, including a right-of-way of a State highway and a right-of-way of the National Highway System; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H481549AFE8DE43E580C19F532B8A55D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a rail right-of-way, including a right-of-way of an abandoned railroad.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCFDAB636BD644ADA952CFC73C4852AE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Highway; National Highway System</header><text>The terms <term>highway</term> and <term>National Highway System</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 101 of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A98292A8FB417A93D4B3EFB2C12A10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H508DA7B87BDD433590BB88027528B2F6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Railroad carrier</header><text>The term <term>railroad carrier</term> has the meaning given such term in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

