<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9BFED554A154C4E85E203F9C7D19823" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6200 IH: Eliminating Start-Stop Engine Nuisance Technologies that Impair Automobile Life Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6200</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation to repeal or rescind certain actions, initiatives, policies, and regulations related to engine idle start-stop technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC197DB6D34854C9BBB19D51F75622769" style="OLC"><section id="H18051FF3FE9F443AA01AEB381556008F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Eliminating Start-Stop Engine Nuisance Technologies that Impair Automobile Life Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ESSENTIAL Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA2CF3BEF9D6B48B18711A65B1057C13F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of certain actions, initiatives, policies, and regulations related to engine idle start-stop technology</header><subsection id="H15ACFAC4AA4842F8B205E89735072A0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (except subsection (b)), the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation—</text><paragraph id="H6CD9FA1B8A1547A0A3C3E31617570B4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, repeal or rescind any action, initiative, policy, or regulation of the Environmental Protection Agency or the Department of Transportation that is specifically designed to encourage, incentivize, promote, or require manufacturers of vehicles (including cars and trucks) to install or equip any such vehicle with engine idle start-stop technology; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H291AFF72DD0B45DAB795E8D6DAB5784E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not issue, take, or enforce any action, initiative, policy, or regulation that is similar to an action, initiative, policy, or regulation that is repealed or rescinded under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C69FA92C4D74BAEB31D9AD0E4DE77D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation may not repeal or rescind any action, initiative, policy, or regulation if, at the determination of the Administrator or the Secretary, the repeal or rescission would result in increased risk of carbon monoxide poisoning.</text></subsection><subsection id="H47478589F4F34B51BF94421355975FE4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H76C0A8F3878D4DABACEDEFD3A8CFF324"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation shall jointly submit to Congress a report that outlines how the Administrator and the Secretary are carrying out subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48E76D563DA848DE8DF5CDA676AD568B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Secretary of Transportation shall jointly submit to Congress a report that outlines how the Administrator and the Secretary carried out subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA40169A475124A7480A09FB3899018FE"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Engine idle start-Stop technology defined</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>engine idle start-stop technology</term> means any technology which enables a vehicle to automatically turn off the engine when the vehicle comes to a rest and restarts the engine when the driver applies pressure to the accelerator or releases the brake.</text>
      </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

