<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H43C45EA7CB9D40879D0BD833C70658C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8888 IH: Ending Passenger Rail Forced Arbitration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260519">May 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to prohibit Amtrak from including mandatory arbitration clauses in contracts of carriage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H43050B8BE0AB41A4968DC7E0E219C75C" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC40A03689533470DA9DEC7BE72982D7C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Passenger Rail Forced Arbitration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H4ED688206A7C4F60BF8F90B35A0A20B6"><enum>2.</enum><header>No validity or enforceability of arbitration agreements for consumer and civil rights disputes</header> <subsection id="HC64C97DAFF2C4531BE9B4B2E86A52FB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/243">Chapter 243</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E3E937E1B1443D09181A435F095A4A6">
<section id="H6684112E451341A2A106096A9C96D0F8"><enum>24324.</enum><header>Prohibition on mandatory arbitration</header>
<subsection id="H91869398E1F34641ABB746F8B2CBBC2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of this section are—</text> <paragraph id="H1C94BE1138D64692B1F0D813004D1C04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prohibit predispute arbitration agreements that force arbitration of consumer and civil rights disputes between Amtrak and customers of Amtrak; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7FBD1007E6634C08AC2E0F7FB313C0D5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prohibit agreements and practices that interfere with the right of customers to participate in a joint, class, or collective action related to consumer and civil rights disputes between Amtrak and customers of Amtrak.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7B67770CD87C43609794886DF412F6D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H303FEA9EA7F544F5BBA1E1F1EF48EBBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amtrak</header><text>The term <term>Amtrak</term> means the National Railroad Passenger Corporation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9397418B0E304687A58310B2A112A592"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil rights dispute</header><text>The term <term>civil rights dispute</term> means a dispute—</text>
<subparagraph id="H061B58CF3D8C495799FB1B99EA97DC8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>arising from an alleged violation of—</text> <clause id="HAE3530A7252340CAB984D3A0F6BB2F16"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Constitution of the United States or the constitution of a State; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H8079734A34354D5FA5B48B4FC92F2CBE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any Federal, State, or local law that prohibits discrimination on the basis of—</text> <subclause id="H93A6C727B6CE4FA7A1A8A1D5D47AA101"><enum>(I)</enum><text>race, sex, age, gender identity, sexual orientation, disability, religion, or national origin; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H911FCE15A1DD4C04B82DFA218B7564AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any legally protected status in education, employment, credit, housing, public accommodations and facilities, voting, veterans and servicemembers, health care, or a program funded or conducted by the Federal Government or a State government, including any law referred to or described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/62">section 62(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, including parts of such law not explicitly referenced in such section that relate to protecting individuals on any such basis; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA28F69D4F5044E9F90D268D4BBF0BB11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in which at least 1 party alleging a violation described in subparagraph (A) consists of 1 or more customers (or their authorized representative), including 1 or more individuals seeking certification as a class under rule 23 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure or a comparable rule or provision of State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9BE0B0B5320A49378C3497ADD9A3E294"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consumer dispute</header><text>The term <term>consumer dispute</term> means any dispute, including all claims related to personal injuries, between Amtrak and 1 or more customers who seek or acquire—</text> <subparagraph id="H00D33DEDA9094F508CB552D55A910131"><enum>(A)</enum><text>services and accommodations provided by Amtrak; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5E114041B4604911AC98B41B893048D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carriage on Amtrak trains and equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC9E5DA552EE49A18596F3B3599E53E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Customer</header><text>The term <term>customer</term> means any individual, except for an employee of Amtrak and without regard to whether the individual is a minor or paid for the transportation, who seeks or acquires—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8D309E347A0347C1AEDE9ABD756EA66C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>services and accommodations provided by Amtrak; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA69D0D7BC6A4BB4B99CFFDD66AD1008"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carriage on Amtrak trains and equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7B76F16016914DC1A4727C20F9289964"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Predispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <term>predispute arbitration agreement</term> means an agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE65A20B7415049C4A18E48DD1DEBB08B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Predispute joint-action waiver</header><text>The term <term>predispute joint-action waiver</term> means an agreement, whether or not part of a predispute arbitration agreement, which would prohibit, or waive the right of, 1 of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of the making of the agreement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6EAE4CCACDDE4136BBEE0C5E7B87C76F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rail passenger carrier</header><text>The term <term>rail passenger carrier</term> means a rail carrier providing—</text> <subparagraph id="H91DA05A8D24D4D07B26598DE26169A98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>intercity rail passenger transportation (as such term is defined in section 24102); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC710D6DF9C7A40D7A88F035AD14EEEAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interstate or intrastate high-speed rail (as such term is defined in section 26105) transportation, excluding a tourist, historic, scenic, or excursion rail carrier.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H48C3AF2BEDC04E2AB5F97813227AD593"><enum>(c)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="HC0FB160FDF3F416EA8A21AFF381D72B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All predispute arbitration agreements and predispute joint-action waivers shall be invalid and unenforceable with respect to a consumer or civil rights dispute between Amtrak (in its capacity as a rail passenger carrier) and a customer of Amtrak.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0FC8F15DB1724029B82A84A4D6810E8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header>
<subparagraph id="H6371E0CF1A0844FCB3FE6CC88191A966"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A determination of whether this section applies to a particular dispute shall be made in accordance with Federal law.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA86B302800040DA9872C4E76AD980D5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authority of court</header><text>The applicability of this section to an agreement to arbitrate and the validity and enforceability of an agreement to which this section applies shall be determined by a court, rather than by an arbitrator, regardless of whether—</text>
<clause id="H64D5FE371AD04A74A576269F9F1916FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the party resisting arbitration challenges the arbitration agreement specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement; and</text></clause> <clause id="H541FDD2143524F11881BEE7F30CB8F57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the agreement purports to delegate such determinations to an arbitrator.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5FE2F89752F44D51A8E78761789CB739"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to apply to a predispute arbitration agreement or joint-action waiver invoked in connection with any dispute subject to the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H12A4CABFBCA642DDA116DADD8D15BD1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)—</text>
<paragraph id="H551334599D19466FAA16E49D8567DBD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB5B747CB83549F6A0521587F56FE6DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall apply with respect to any dispute or claim that arises or accrues on or after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H684FF9D015C54AD7A4E0ACC01817A321"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/243">chapter 243</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD725C3E610054898B051A41850BFA296"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">24324. Prohibition on mandatory arbitration.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

