<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H870D758226554C67809CB044EFA13815" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9330 IH: Earned Wage Access Consumer Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9330</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260618">June 18, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To regulate the business of offering and providing earned wage access services to consumers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFAEB2FF7EEAA423F9691AF022C3EDEF0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE606B201BB4A478EA6626CD6C4B8A9B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Earned Wage Access Consumer Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7032603991CC4D58AC37C6AC4ED59D8A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Earned wage access services</header> <subsection id="H41F057642F1941AC810BE70BEFDB0EF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of earned wage access services</header> <paragraph id="HF255DC18A0EE4579BC8AA9414345E94E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No-cost option required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an earned wage access provider offers a consumer the option to receive earned wages in exchange for a fee, such earned wage access provider shall also offer such consumer the option to obtain the same amount of earned wages at no cost to the consumer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C00DC61A24E400FBF32570C2E3D0A5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required disclosures</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6CFD787D79004392BD469BF37EF887EE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Disclosures preceding agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each earned wage access provider shall disclose the following before entering into an agreement with a consumer:</text> <clause id="H618F172238AB458F979939DC3186E080"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any limits on access to the earned wages a consumer may request from such provider, including—</text> 
<subclause id="H4E03B7809AB04599BBB0747E12CCDBEA"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any limits on the amount of earned wages a consumer may request from the provider each day, pay period, or other time period;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4782A627CD8445ACB6AF299498B2958D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any limits on the frequency or number of disbursements of earned wages a consumer may request from the provider each day, pay period, or other time period;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H62F644039ED443B893E48422B632805C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any limits on the amount of earned wages a consumer may request from the provider that are based on a determination by the provider of the ratio between the amount of earned wages requested by the consumer and the total wages earned by the consumer, and how such determination is made.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9E47FD58E7B64C2A9A583E7E22F82C26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any fees that such provider may apply, and the amount of such fees.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9217FC8502F94135A21B19599D402033"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A clear and conspicuous description of how the consumer may obtain earned wages without paying a fee or tip.</text></clause> <clause id="H7CC28D91ECB540AD94020C834E820BA1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An overview of such provider’s use of tips that describes—</text> 
<subclause id="H315C6E91DEFB462E828BF77DF0875718"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether such provider will accept tips from the consumer and in what amounts; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA51882ED45AA4FC8A6968E2877D6EB0B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whether such provider will suggest the consumer provide tips and in what amounts.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7AC1C6BDBC24FDE906A87D3C00B48C3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disclosures preceding disbursement of earned wages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each earned wage access provider shall disclose the following in a clear and conspicuous manner after approving any request from a consumer for access to earned wages but before disbursing such earned wages to such consumer:</text> <clause id="HEE151FDB21F94D4F8F3130E70AB47083"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The account number such provider has assigned to the consumer, if applicable.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9130EC14B25042B2803DD6ABDF8528E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of earned wages that will be provided to the consumer by such provider.</text></clause> <clause id="HB1E6F080FA8641E09F85ACC1FD9C693D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total amount of any fees applied by such provider for such transaction.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE339E5AC3894CF8A46359687D5C48BA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of any tips the consumer has chosen to provide for such transaction.</text></clause> <clause id="HDEC5A06CDFB84C55A80988D8F048F2A8" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount that such provider expects to receive as payment after disbursing the earned wages, the date on which such provider expects to receive such amount or a description of when such provider expects to receive such amount, and the manner in which such provider expects to receive such amount.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBCC890BEDAC2494DA326BE1D937391C2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional disclosures relating to fees and tips</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each earned wage access provider who, during a calendar year, has disbursed earned wages and received a fee or tip from a consumer shall provide the consumer ongoing access to the following disclosures:</text> <clause id="H5A5E446419DA499EA13ED0D576BE1565"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total amount of fees and tips that the consumer has already paid in the then-current pay period.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4CFDC8721A0F40EFA601429F5BE0984F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The total amount of fees and tips that the consumer has already paid in the calendar year-to-date.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H093828F9783C436AA3510C216CF49937"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional disclosures relating to tips</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an earned wage access provider solicits, charges, or receives a tip from a consumer, such provider—</text> 
<clause id="H5463D5F450764635A077DE639864F3A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall clearly and conspicuously disclose to the consumer, before the provider commences the transaction to which the tip is related, that such tip—</text> <subclause id="HD91ED41C91634FE7A511F25B2719DAC0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is voluntary;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE42898CCE59142B3BF9993D03F509C45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is not a requirement for receiving earned wage access services; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4164998E5B614916812EDE7B806A6694"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will not impact—</text> 
<item id="H3C485B1D8DC94C4DBA3A848F36C9B127"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount of such earned wages;</text></item> <item id="H6D2591B2106046F1934A200A1B830A02"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the frequency with which such earned wages are disbursed to such consumer; or</text></item> 
<item id="H188489277D744441932D18E19B84FEF5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the consumer’s eligibility to use the provider’s earned wage access services; and</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5906A639701D4866AFDC4C2E2C59CDA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not state that such tip will benefit any specific individual or group of individuals other than the provider itself, unless the statement is true.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEC28B41C9434A7991B49F53A2BC6454"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Changes to terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each earned wage access provider shall notify each consumer with which such earned wage access provider has entered an agreement to offer earned wage access services of any material changes to the terms and conditions of service used by such provider not less than—</text> <clause id="H84F4C2C3F6354DF4B899AA49742597C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>30 days before such material changes take effect; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H26211409875A4021BDC35AA103C65261"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a shorter amount of time before such material changes take effect, if the consumer has consented to such shorter amount of time.</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H17C0595F72404EB58D67A8D77D46484E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cancellation of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an earned wage access provider makes earned wage access services available to a consumer on a recurring basis, such earned wage access provider—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCF100BAC6FD84FAFAB1CABBD1500E6B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall allow such consumer to discontinue such services if such consumer provides notice to such earned wage access provider that such consumer desires to discontinue such services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92CFDD3A610549FD8D8DB95E5C21F741"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not impose any financial penalty or cancellation charge on such consumer as a result of any discontinuation of services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0C54DB5A1A14F6CBF13DB251D19CFBB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dispute process required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each earned wage access provider shall develop and implement policies and procedures to respond to questions and complaints from consumers relating to—</text> <subparagraph id="H6832B0D1742341DFACFF12CF05C10F9F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unauthorized disbursement of earned wages;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B2663FBEED94499879EA493072FA43B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disbursement of earned wages in an incorrect amount;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F4425AD8D35444C9845AC0B1E84F089"><enum>(C)</enum><text>disbursed earned wages that were not received; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5962F51513A046419EE41CCA493BD50C" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payment of disbursed earned wages that was not received or was made in an incorrect amount; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20C26A22571E4642BB1183ACA8D17371"><enum>(E)</enum><text>fees or tips that were not authorized or were made in an incorrect amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC38AA44C4BEE4E328B1543928554FD7D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compelling payment for disbursed earned wages</header> 
<subparagraph id="H20202D3457DC49CFB700D09EDD846FBB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An earned wage access provider may not seek payment for earned wages disbursed by such provider to a consumer, including such disbursed earned wages, or any related fees or tips, by—</text> <clause id="H4DDB335926A04DCAA598E7D0759598BF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>filing a civil suit against the consumer;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFCF70D6693A64D21BDCC7D373593A928" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">initiating arbitration proceedings against the consumer; </text></clause> <clause id="HEC64B2D5CF6F44EFB4733DAEFB70D404" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">using the services of a debt collector (as such term is defined in section 803 of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act) to collect amounts from the consumer; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAC22C02600F24963A6ED423B5DD01739" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">selling expected payment to a third-party debt buyer for purposes of debt collection from the consumer.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB759AB71C2F946349BB5EE77609C273D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply if an earned wage access provider is seeking payment for earned wages disbursed to a consumer based on information provided by the consumer that the consumer knew was false.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67FFDBF8BF1F4A83AF77B5B2F4D128CF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reimbursement required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an earned wage access provider seeks payment of disbursed earned wages, a fee, or a tip directly from a deposit account of a consumer, on a date earlier than, or in an amount different from, what was disclosed at the time of authorization and such attempt triggers an overdraft fee or non-sufficient funds fee from the consumer’s financial institution (as defined in section 509 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act), the earned wage access provider shall reimburse such consumer for such fee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF128BF33E3B4475A782B154E6B2370D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Additional limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An earned wage access provider may not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H636E72A5C34642BABFDD4D8B3A403FC6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share any fees or tips that were received from or charged to a consumer for earned wage access services with the employer of such consumer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE20046F20CF45028209FB8223FD8CDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accept payment of disbursed earned wages, fees, or tips from a consumer through a credit card of the consumer, unless such credit card is provided to the consumer as a part of the earned wage access service;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8FD9C191F4AE4AB6B3631A8B6D8FDB92" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require a consumer to pay a late fee, deferral fee, interest, or any other penalty or charge as a result of a failure by the consumer to pay disbursed earned wages, fees, or tips requested or applied by such provider; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H821CC373BDAA447DAF69CA9413BD39F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">furnish information to a consumer reporting agency (as defined in section 603 of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681a">15 U.S.C. 1681a</external-xref>)) about a consumer’s earned wage access services activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8B20096E39EB413CAE2B5501407B64ED"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Disclosure to employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An earned wage access provider may disclose to an employer with which such provider has a contract relating to earned wage access services the date and amount of a consumer’s earned wage access transactions associated with the earned wage access services. Subject to applicable privacy laws, a provider may disclose information necessary to perform under a contract with an employer relating to additional products or services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H068630B7A71C40F9848C6CD095407237"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Non-discrimination</header> <subparagraph id="H20643EFCEDEA4D95A75C5898B77CCF59"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any earned wage access provider to discriminate against any consumer on the basis of race, color, religion, national origin, sex (including on the basis of pregnancy, childbirth, or related medical conditions), marital status, or age when offering earned wage access services.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5612B164548C475D837D93C46B88D744"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this paragraph—</text> <clause id="HD9DD4195EA8E440FA9AC3CD6C6820EC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>race</term>, <term>color</term>, <term>religion</term>, <term>national origin</term>, <term>sex</term>, <term>marital status</term>, and <term>age</term> have the same meaning, respectively, as used in section 701 of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691">15 U.S.C. 1691</external-xref>) and rules issued thereunder; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H46594789C4204163BCC25A9E35CA5D51"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <term>pregnancy</term>, <term>childbirth</term>, and <term>related medical conditions</term> have the same meaning, respectively, as used in section 701(k) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e(k)</external-xref>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE90DD7AA4CB24A02B42B04774F052F03"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Consumer data protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each earned wage access provider shall be deemed a <quote>financial institution</quote> for purposes of subtitle A of title V of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1FB9D64DF224BCDB82D5A88791C3EC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relation to State laws</header> 
<paragraph id="HE004F7C612734E70AB974524176F607B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preservation of State law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), nothing in this Act may be construed as annulling, altering, affecting, or exempting any person from complying with any State law, except to the extent that a State law is inconsistent with the provisions of this Act, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDE2BCB9DC624AB4BD847D855B474AE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No State or political subdivision thereof may impose, maintain, or enforce any laws, constitutions, statutes, regulations, orders, or interpretations with respect to earned wage access services that comply with this Act that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4F03E2A1C40A482D98B891B300325976"><enum>(A)</enum><text>treat such services as credit, a loan, debt, or a substantially similar product or service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H60689A77D4A949FBA5E25825383C32D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>treat a provider of such services as a creditor, lender, or provider of a substantially similar product or service; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE439EAC1ED8849219F0107C8C947885E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits or substantially restricts the offering or provision of earned wage access services that comply with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC58E15C9256842549D7AED3BC471E3EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to preempt, displace, or limit the authority of a State or political subdivision thereof to enforce laws of general applicability, including laws relating to fraud, deceit, unfair or deceptive acts or practices, contracts, property, or taxation.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0366495BFCCC47608237424CF31D3A3E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Bureau shall issue such rules as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H76993CE2F80A4F499B0EFCD85F1BF186"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Earned wage access services provided in compliance with this Act, and any fees or tips received in connection with such services, may not be considered credit, a loan, debt, an obligation, liability, or consumer credit, and a person providing such services shall not be considered a creditor or lender, and such fees or tips shall not be considered interest or a finance charge, under Federal law.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9F2D39D2CED4BCB8356AB5189E6ED6D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HBE27B858E8A44667A5A5C1C2254C344A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Bureau</term> means the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B089235B9BD4ED2A83D65714AAF92BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consumer</header><text>The term <term>consumer</term> means a natural person. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H681F91C47A3E4DD8B16961F463AA0496"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Earned wages</header> <subparagraph id="H782C9D974CB8408A8C1D5F405E312288"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>earned wages</term> means salary, wages, compensation, or other income that a consumer or an employer has represented and that an earned wage access provider has reasonably determined have been earned or have accrued to the benefit of the consumer in exchange for the services provided by the consumer, but that have not yet been paid to the consumer by an employer.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3E796ED495B421FAD07BDFBA67A3529"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Services provided</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Services provided by the consumer include any services provided—</text> <clause id="H501FB04966BF4CF3BD35B832F53CAEB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on an hourly, project-based, piecework, salaried, or other basis; or </text></clause> 
<clause id="HA4AB2D539AC64AC9ADDEB27AB8C59F57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when the consumer is acting as a contractor of the employer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B23A6F5639A435A85F62FCE6329300B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Earned Wage Access Provider</header> <subparagraph id="H530DE206BC3249879300EE87D038EDFC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>earned wage access provider</term> means a person who provides earned wage access services to consumers.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF4A3CB0B61FF449A80DF354BB3DEDE2E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>earned wage access provider</term> does not include— </text> <clause id="H1BF1E497F0344EA58933DA0BBD77C801"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a person who is not obligated to provide access to earned wages as part of an earned wage access service;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEA484C455395420781BE335BF19254AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an employer that offers a portion of salary, wages, or compensation earned by a consumer directly to such consumer prior to a normally scheduled pay date or as such wages are accrued, irrespective of any scheduled periodic pay cycle;</text></clause> <clause id="H9FAB10FE8FA9433B98880F80CD2424AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a financial institution (as defined in section 509 of the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act) that permits a consumer to access amounts associated with an electronic fund transfer from the consumer’s employer or a payroll services vendor of the employer for which the financial institution has received information but which has not yet settled; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6EC2FA7AF3524C71B0B5B5A9D45C12C7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a payroll service vendor in its capacity as a facilitator of wage payments to a consumer by an employer, exclusive of any earned wage access services that such vendor may provide.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48232F2C073A42F385558EFFE9350E17"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Earned wage access services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>earned wage access services</term> means the delivery of earned wages to a consumer based on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2D081CD16DA748B68841247A4D14D0FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employment, income, or attendance data obtained directly or indirectly from the employer of such consumer or a payroll service vendor, or other vendors, contracted by the employer of such consumer; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1D1C5BDF48AF4E73B3414216C9B10310"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representations made by the consumer and the reasonable determination of the earned wages of such consumer by an earned wage access provider, based on information made available or accessible to the provider by the consumer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3EBB4B917924155B399FFF6A8B8F1AE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Employer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>employer</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H31E8BA8BBF9E43859938A2C08BC29A37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a person who employs a consumer, or any other person who is contractually obligated to pay a consumer salary, wages, compensation, or other income in exchange for services provided to the person or on the person’s behalf; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H132BCC3A8F9047A19BB66B908BD2FC32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="H0B7E4063253D424390AAA51AC193748E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a customer of a person; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H19417F050E32489C87A73141F369170D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a person whose obligation to pay salary, wages, compensation, or other income to a consumer is not based on the services provided for or on behalf of that person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79DE052085A5454884F3AED43C7A43A8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fee</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D269DF2D5874BDE919011BDB4F02CFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fee for delivery, or expedited delivery, of proceeds to a consumer; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2DF685EE89BD481D8C0A1BF73C055510"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a subscription, participation, or membership fee for earned wage access services or a group of services that includes earned wage access services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7C0D41E618DE43A2B3043965EEFB30F6" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Payroll service vendor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>payroll service vendor</term> means a vendor contracted directly or indirectly by an employer to facilitate payment of employee wages in accordance with Federal, State, and local law, including the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938, or to provide or verify employment, income, or attendance data. </text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HD412B44F76914DCC89F9A4E7BE238F77" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tip</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>tip</term> means any gratuity, donation, or other voluntary payment that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD1923E1048FD4F2F9BECDE7F455CB715"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made by a consumer to an earned wage access provider;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3C59395C7FD436DAF91399B3D5233ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provided gratuitously and without any consequence for nonpayment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0B2A1D870DAE4C5AB4DDD75D5E3299F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not subject to negotiation, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F6D4583B25C4E61AE6E988ADFFB6A5D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in an amount determined by the consumer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H998944EC9F5D422696B725847B510542"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="HA77C20B2FE1D4948A3D796EFABD526EC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> <subsection id="H5D836EBFDE4C4565A140FE4526173B6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1002 of the Consumer Financial Protection Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/5481">12 U.S.C. 5481</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H599039C34F7F4891B5C23BC54BEA276F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (12)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4AC9BBECC1354244A7308CA17AF8BF3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (Q), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC6688BE31F79436A9F5A880A91F45FC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (R), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0D1616DCB994CD0971D6580128A029E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H689E464CC7BA43E6B2FD0964C85FDE12" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H16415B0A7AD2459BAB20604C563C840D"><enum>(S)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Earned Wage Access Consumer Protection Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B214B5CE9B649BBAC2907045EBB4B05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (15)(A)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBD0DB3280F9F4BAF9E08B0F4F6587826"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating clauses (x) and (xi) as clauses (xi) and (xii), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C56CB6C7D374A7BBCFD9B5B2888A2D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (ix) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF7EC684E3E534E68B8CF83228CF7242F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="H603099467DDA4F7DAB6E0FCA682AE734"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing earned wage access services, as defined in section 2 of the Earned Wage Access Consumer Protection Act;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB135E9DBE7D645C586C3023E0B4361AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Truth in Lending Act</header><text>Section 103 of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1602">15 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA6CF576C93034E04BAB14EC153A86223"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (f), by striking <quote>defer its payment</quote> and inserting <quote>defer its payment, but does not include earned wage access services as defined in the Earned Wage Access Consumer Protection Act.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2343955DDF084AE1A03E179EF141FE5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The term creditor does not include earned wage access providers as such term is defined in the Earned Wage Access Consumer Protection Act.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

