<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB735D68059A84D1D8C1A58487EBEC57A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6942 IH: Nick Shirley Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6942</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260106">January 6, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional Gold Medal to Nick Shirley, in recognition of exemplary investigative journalism that uncovered waste, fraud, and abuse perpetrated against American taxpayers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C6D5C69DDFC441C99195BE2DD916622" style="OLC"><section id="HC69944C56B3447A690EF853884354A0F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nick Shirley Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H43FA219D9D844AE28B53F343CEFCC1AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="H2174DE22E8B2433F9A9A3797D33BE420"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On December 26, 2025, Nick Shirley posted a 42-minute investigative post on X uncovering mass fraud in the Minnesota Somali population against U.S. taxpayers. Nick Shirley stated on X: <quote>Here is the full 42 minutes of my crew and I exposing Minnesota fraud, this might be my most important work yet. We uncovered over $110,000,000 in ONE day. Like it and share it around like wildfire! Its time to hold these corrupt politicians and fraudsters accountable We ALL work way too hard and pay too much in taxes for this to be happening, the fraud must be stopped.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8CFA266DF3E4913A1409B28B20B239D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Due to exemplary investigative journalism preformed by Nick Shirley, Federal funding to fraudulent businesses in Minnesota has been halted by President Trump.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC8EEAB6A961D4D86ABA28E7F073D68F5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that Nick Shirley showed bravery, integrity, and dedication to the principles of the U.S. Constitution during the uncovering of historic levels of fraud, waste, and abuse under Governor Tim Walz and therefore deserves the Congressional Gold Medal.</text></section><section id="HE3BE5FAA15D747C1999F70C15F3BC435"><enum>4.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="HB10D854876114F11B9E9B30D5A509122"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Presentation Authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the presentation, on behalf of the Congress, of a gold medal of appropriate design to Nick Shirley, in recognition of exemplary investigative journalism that uncovered waste, fraud, and abuse perpetrated against American taxpayers.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAEF75A3F3F55490BAA006D82E7EC64D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the presentation referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike a gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAD72B982314543C98201C630C8040455"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that the United States Mint should expedite production of the gold medal under this Act, so that the heroic and protective actions of Daniel Penny on May 1, 2023, in New York can be recognized and honored in a timely manner.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA62EC67021A0455D8EFD6365F87E055B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck pursuant to section 4, at a price sufficient to cover the cost thereof, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H967A6A0B68A047F3AF88BD037BD0A8B4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="HF0129FECD4C24BD6A7621FF40C4C3C1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>The medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFAE4A52189894BA8853A3E58E2F0E8E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4FEACF3B23204BE4928CD2F65C1EB814"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="HEAD7816E6E874952A5F4E377A745C34B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBCA189FE5C6241E285CD5425F736D660"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 5 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

