<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H880080D529FE42AB8E80C643BEE6C182" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 921 IH: Recognizing the 30th anniversary of the Dayton Peace Accords.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 921</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251202">December 2, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the 30th anniversary of the Dayton Peace Accords.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, December 14, 2025, marks the General Framework Agreement for Peace in Bosnia and Herzegovina (commonly referred to as the <quote>Dayton Peace Accords</quote>), which ended the Bosnian War and brought peace to Bosnia and Herzegovina;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas widespread and systematic ethnic cleansing and concentration camps were used as a tool of war against Bosnian Muslim men, women, and children, culminating in the July 1995 genocide at Srebrenica, where over 8,000 Muslim men and teenagers were detained and killed;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (referred to in this preamble as <quote>NATO</quote>), led by the United States, initiated airstrikes against Bosnian Serbs to stop grave human rights abuses, which led to ceasefire negotiations and the peace accords;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas negotiations began on November 1, 1995, in Dayton, Ohio, culminating in a historic peace agreement which was signed on December 14, 1995, to halt the conflict and bring peace to the region;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, despite seemingly insurmountable differences in opinions, the negotiations succeeded due to dedicated foreign service professionals, a common yearning for a peaceful resolution, and an outpouring of support from the global community;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the General Framework Agreement for Peace in Bosnia and Herzegovina, also known as the Dayton Peace Accords, laid the groundwork for NATO and European Union (referred to in this preamble as <quote>EU</quote>) stabilization missions over the past 30 years, which have allowed the citizens of Bosnia and Herzegovina to live peacefully and prosper;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Dayton Literary Peace Prize, established in 2006, remains the only literary peace prize awarded in the United States and recognizes the power of the written word to promote peace, and after the death of Ambassador Holbrooke in 2011, the Lifetime Achievement Award was renamed the Richard C. Holbrooke Distinguished Achievement Award;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the peace negotiations were strongly supported by the City of Dayton, Ohio, its leaders, and the broader community, which created strong relationships between all parties involved in the negotiations, including a sister city relationship between Dayton and Sarajevo;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the United States Government reaffirms support for Bosnia and Herzegovina’s sovereignty and upholds the commitment to equality for all ethnicities according to the General Framework Agreement for Peace in Bosnia and Herzegovina;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas, since the signing of the Dayton Peace Accords, the Government and people of Bosnia and Herzegovina have been working in partnership with the international community towards building a peaceful and democratic society based on the rule of law, respect for human rights, and a free-market economy;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas EU opened accession negotiations with Bosnia and Herzegovina in March 2024;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the NATO Parliament Assembly held its 2025 Spring Session in Dayton, Ohio, to commemorate the 30th anniversary of the Dayton Peace Accords;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas NATO and Bosnia and Herzegovina agreed to an Individual Tailored Partnership Program in October 2025, strengthening NATO and Bosnia and Herzegovina’s strategic partnership and positioning Bosnia and Herzegovina closer to NATO membership status; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the United States hosts a diaspora of an estimated 350,000 individuals of Bosnian descent, large numbers of whom reside in St. Louis, Missouri, Chicago, Illinois, and Bowling Green, Kentucky: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H35DEC070FD574223B26D2F452B56F16B"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HDE71B47F773D4F00866E40AAC62BBE0D"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H4A4D180AE62A430AAC02FB5E9E785936"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms the joint United States and EU commitment to promote and protect human rights, democracy, and the rule of law in Bosnia and Herzegovina and around the world;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H10E8C7A7BE124EECBD0446D652B928B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the continued commitment of the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina to peace and cooperation 30 years after the Dayton Peace Accords;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D0FAF6F83E34DBB980B4311AE2EC4FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notes the efforts undertaken by the Government of Bosnia and Herzegovina toward NATO and EU membership, including measures to resolve its constitutional issues, strengthen its governing structures, and undertake necessary economic, rule of law, and judicial reforms;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2530E43A46D4A4392D51C9642D41970"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reiterates the continued importance of the Dayton Peace Accords as the basis of constitutional reform in Bosnia and Herzegovina and the promotion of political, economic, legal, and religious equality, which are also key requirements for EU accession;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFDDAC170BF042AEA82B1D2C5B4B4F41"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the Government of Bosnia and Herzegovina to continue to pursue constitutional reforms needed to reconcile the past and engage across ethnic and religious lines with empathy and respect to build a common future;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4171CD17319146BDB39E052BCAA91B08"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the Government of Bosnia and Herzegovina, through its respective leaders, to uphold the integrity of the tripartite presidency, strengthen its key institutions, and work to achieve an independent democracy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01811CE5D8FF46D4AB8C4F546F6909B2"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the United States Government to maintain support for the Office of the High Representative until members of the Peace Implementation Council reach a unanimous agreement that the presence of the Office of the High Representative is no longer necessary;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C1B7D342519432196511FC59E65B5E0"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urges the United States Government to work closely with Bosnia and Herzegovina and its bordering nations—especially those who are signatories of the Dayton Peace Accords—to support full implementation of the Stabilization and Association Agreement between the EU and the Balkan States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02FAF949446C43EEA9508BA7EAA7A865"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages continued regional cooperation to combat the malign influence of foreign actors, such as the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78E5907D53D149D9BD65309F335A3AD9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>recognizes the State of Ohio and the greater Dayton community for their role in fostering the Dayton Peace Accords, and for continuing to support diplomacy, security, and peace around the world; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88715164B3AF4DA396A7E06E8C9164DA"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">acknowledges the important contributions of the Bosnian-American diaspora in their communities throughout the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

