<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA139E56391174C8D87B32FB7ED2D45B4" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1334 IH: Reaffirming the Nation’s commitment to one Nation Under God in the Pledge of Allegiance.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1334</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001321">Mr. Barrett</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Reaffirming the Nation’s commitment to one Nation Under God in the Pledge of Allegiance.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas America’s Founding was rooted in the belief that every man, woman, and child is <quote>endowed by their Creator with certain unalienable Rights, that among these are Life, Liberty, and the pursuit of Happiness</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas references to God and divine providence have long been part of the Nation’s civic traditions, including in the Declaration of Independence;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Declaration of Independence was signed on July 4, 1776;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas President Abraham Lincoln first said the phrase <quote>Nation, under God,</quote> in the Gettysburg Address on November 19, 1863, at the dedication of the Soldiers’ National Cemetery;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the <quote>Pledge of Allegiance</quote> was written in 1892 by Francis Bellamy to express loyalty to the United States and its constitutional republic;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Congress formally recognized the Pledge of Allegiance on June 22, 1942, during World War II, as a symbol of national unity and patriotism;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas the Pledge of Allegiance became formally recognized in the Federal Flag Code (4 U.S.C. § 4—Pledge of allegiance to the flag);</text>
        </whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas Louis Charles Rabaut represented the 14th District of Michigan in the United States House of Representatives from 1935 to 1947 and 1949 to 1961;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on April 20, 1953, Louis Charles Rabaut of Michigan sponsored and introduced H.J.Res. 243, a resolution to include the words <quote>Under God</quote> in the Pledge to the Flag;</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas Louis Charles Rabaut of Michigan was inspired to sponsor H.J.Res. 243 to distinguish the United States from the Soviet Union, stating that, <quote>the unbridgeable gap between America and Communist Russia is a belief in Almighty God</quote>;</text>
        </whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas the words <quote>under God</quote> in the Pledge of Allegiance reflect the understanding that individual rights and liberties are derived from a higher and divine authority, and not from the government alone;</text>
        </whereas><whereas>
 <text>Whereas, on June 14, 1954, Congress passed and President Dwight D. Eisenhower signed H.J.Res. 243 that amended the Pledge of Allegiance to read: <quote>I pledge allegiance to the Flag of the United States of America and to the Republic for which it stands, one Nation under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all</quote>;</text>
 </whereas><whereas><text>Whereas millions of Americans voluntarily recite the Pledge of Allegiance each day in schools, civic ceremonies, public meetings, and patriotic observances across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the words <quote>under God</quote> in the Pledge of Allegiance continue to symbolize the humility of the Nation and the principle that governmental power is limited and accountable to enduring moral truths;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on January 1, 2026, Donald J. Trump, the President of the United States of America, proclaimed 2026 as a Year of Celebration and Rededication to the Nation’s Founding;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 4, 2026, the Nation will celebrate and commemorate the 250th anniversary of the signing of the Declaration of Independence, marking the United States of America’s Semiquincentennial; and</text></whereas><whereas> <text>Whereas, as part of America’s Semiquincentennial, on May 17, 2026, the <quote>Rededicate 250</quote> prayer event took place on the National Mall, led by President Trump and conservative religious leaders to mark America’s 250th anniversary as <quote>one nation under God</quote>: Now, therefore, be it</text>
 </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HFBA38A363DC1462EB8623D79A6699CED"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H293DEF54B3BF4E34B82A9F59722D9B7B"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H92F2263FCEEE4C63B9479389D2EF50FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reaffirms the Nation’s commitment to one Nation Under God in the Pledge of Allegiance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79E41B7D9FDD4093A25CE2567CA70E8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reaffirms the phrase <quote>one Nation under God</quote> has and will continue to serve as a unifying affirmation of the shared values of faith, liberty, equality, and justice that underpin the American constitutional system for generations to come.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

