<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7D58D4BA9AB44C28A5ABD09FCA3F7EDB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6177 IH: Grid Research and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6177</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modernize and standardize the manner in which information and data is reported to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H726AD1C82DF9450C8F6EBD7BAC0207AA" style="OLC"><section id="H3574D4EE14C842638F8879AD4D8DA0B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grid Research and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8F580C7C168E408185E091D306EAFCDB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modernization of reporting information and data under the Federal Power Act</header><subsection id="H64AF839F5E15422E8DDB6DC96DBC7570"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall, by rule, modernize and standardize the manner in which information and data are reported, by transmitting utilities and Transmission Organizations, to the Commission under the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/972">16 U.S.C. 972 et seq.</external-xref>) in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF839C908240A4FFFAA087D6DBB1E0F2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content of reports requirements</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Commission shall require the information and data that will be reported, as it applies to projects, existing assets, or systems owned or operated by a transmitting utility or Transmission Organization, to include the following:</text><paragraph id="H7379F60CAE504AA29AE6952B51927479" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Information and data relating to a project and the lifecycle of such project, including—</text><subparagraph id="HBD1E30E1643C42F9BE0FC0B2DAA613DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>project milestones, including proposed, approved, and actual in-service dates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2C10202902749088A1AD004259974B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>project classification information, including whether the project represents new construction, an upgrade, or a rebuild of existing infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AA6AF5F4A5A48869AC23A039446D5DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>major development history, including original construction and last major upgrade dates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AC03604A27244E09D7A08D796AA8476"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the location of any applicable project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7887048B17DE4B0C9ED7C1AA7D038024"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the project nameplate capacity, length, and voltage; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H830B2B44C9414673B555C3C4CA85DE5E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an identification of the applicable planning process through which the applicable project originated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E257DE7EB254380ACB576B36E5E9B4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The costs and economic justifications of a project, existing asset, or system owned or operated by a transmitting utility or Transmission Organization, as applicable, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB4B6D89BA746437898AAC4178F027188"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">original projected and actual final costs of all new projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53D6BE305EF249C2894EB6D8122B80CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">original projected and actual final costs of renewals and replacements of project works;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FDC409EFEA040FF936489BBDC4E9148"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">original projected and actual maintenance and operations expenses of the projects and existing assets on a current-year and five-year rolling average basis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3228729B605D415FB18D606AC051458B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cost allocation shares where applicable, including identification of entities responsible for shared investments in projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0B7C9306EAF4378A2E8540D418E5253"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cost-benefit analyses of projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE6ABD0EBB494B22A820C7E87E80155F"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the project was subject to a competitive solicitation process and, if applicable, the outcome of that process; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40A47C3F51D2460E927DC73FF9C45B67"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">classification of the project based on benefits provided, under the relevant transmission planning framework.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84FAEC35939243A69FCEEC71061E1421"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The capital structure and the rate of return of a project, existing asset, or system owned or operated by a transmitting utility or Tranmission Organization, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF6598203A7424244B3B0A822F50BE499"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the allowed return on equity, return on debt, and return on preferred stock;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AD3D2DCA56B4240B534D2553F5FE747"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the authorized or actual capital structure, including the percentage of debt, equity, and preferred stock used in ratemaking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H296BD544F6774D029793BE7E58F220D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the resulting overall weighted average rate of return;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD19DAD3AD8E4C93BED2AB0583250287"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Commission-approved incentive adders applied to the base return on equity, including rationale and duration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A5606ADC225416AA2733E2FF6849926"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where applicable, information necessary to assess potential double leveraging effects arising from a holding company structure, as defined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5A49369EB9A4E9E87AEAED5BC9465CF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For information and data relating to a system owned or operated by a transmitting utility or Transmission Organization, as applicable, congestion-related costs or the costs incurred by ratepayers, power supplies, or distribution customers as a result of transmission system constraints that prevent the dispatch of least-cost generation resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3FB9A5D236C4938BD9BEF880449859C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Technical and non-technical losses and inefficiencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8880DACF2E274225B103743A90528082"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A complete accounting of interconnection-related costs incurred by interconnection customers, transmitting utilities, or other entities, disaggregated by cost type and responsible party, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCA4C41B82A574B8DADDECC5C3563E302"><enum>(A)</enum><text>study fees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4575EC28BB1D40C288A50477FF3FA534"><enum>(B)</enum><text>milestones or reservation payments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE69F378E6DD4FE3A59CEB27AAD6F7CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>costs of local interconnection attachment facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26546699DD6349179A985A2F6342BA3F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>grid network upgrade costs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94E817F95CFC41B187C6D105B06CA263"><enum>(E)</enum><text>estimates of costs to a larger system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B5CF3E55CE340638C3BBA88B529FE32"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The projected and actual capacity and load of a system owned or operated by a transmitting utility or Transmission Organization and the projected and actual amount of energy delivered by such system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFF8EF88B85C49C9AE50B62E4B594675"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Information and data on the use of capital-efficient advanced technologies, including information on—</text><subparagraph id="H45E9C355082F4F9BB749D328B7D91C82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hourly usage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84597E95524A4D49BEEC2AA701B09DD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the location of the technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7826D9C1EFA64054A8524AF05DBEC823"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the types of technologies deployed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB1B3AE89B8448D4B4EFFB29E510C98B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Any additional metric the Commission determines necessary to improve ratepayer affordability and understanding of the transmission sector.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9684A245F9134C62B9FE3D202E25F10A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Content of interconnection reports</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Commission shall require a transmitting utility or Transmission Organization to report, no less than quarterly, to the Commission information and data on interconnection queues and details relating to interconnection study models used.</text></subsection><subsection id="HECBA1FCAFE594C2DA0D8A4D04277FDF4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Format of reports</header><paragraph id="H4FD39D5CE15246FE8AFA1E6FE1785B0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to subsection (a), the Commission shall ensure the completeness, accuracy, and accessibility of information and data reported to the Commission under the Federal Power Act, as the Commission determines necessary, by—</text><subparagraph id="H0C724A3CEABD478091F3C5EF2BA925C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing standardized reporting requirements that specify standards for describing and recording such information and data, and, if the Commission determines appropriate, providing templates or other tools to reduce administrative burden;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E48F488254A4FE9ABDED97D00C897E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing a format for such information and data to be submitted in a manner that is fully searchable and machine-readable;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DA8A1A91C0A4FD29DB9F4E9D38FF92E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requiring any form filed by a transmitting utility or a Transmission Organization contains no blank cells, unless clearly marked as exempt pursuant to paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0141758D345E4662983D7B91D3A029C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>requiring any projections required under subsection (a) are defined, including key assumptions, methodologies, and any other information that could influence the result of the projection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47D03A281DB24C0EABCD5C79DBEA66BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>requiring the information and data reported under this section are made available to the public through a single, user-friendly web interface that allows users to search, filter, and download the data in a machine-readable format.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H727EC6D5FB4245CAABD2DC358490CC23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><subparagraph id="H1C1DA1559C4E46E3A8B69FFEEE4AF4F0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A transmitting utility or a Transmission Organization may request an exemption from a requirement under paragraph (1) if such transmitting utility or Transmission Organization submits to the Commission a written statement explaining why such an exemption is needed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76840A0D203C4CB28EA07D9AA32D3C6E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The Commission may approve the request for an exemption if the Commission determines that the exemption is justified based on the written statement submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H730086DDCB574774A41B3654335F42E6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>FERC Form No. 1</header><paragraph id="HEADD1ACF4A554B7489930D74F75D266F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Commission issues a rule under subsection (a), the Commission shall review covered forms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D7728FF921B4804BB4C0A24666C0303"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Completeness</header><text>Upon reviewing covered forms under paragraph (1), if the Commission determines that a covered form is incomplete, the Commission shall require the relevant transmitting utility or Transmission Organization to file a revised FERC Form No. 1 in a manner that complies with the requirements of subsection (d) and the requirements under section 141.1 of title 18, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F0850B4CB904BC5AD12288527573EC6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered form defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>covered form</term> means a FERC Form No. 1 filed with the Commission by a transmitting utility or Transmission Organization during the 5-year period immediately preceding the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3FD26374C274F929376FD27F4B204F6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Modernization and centralization of FERC Form No. 1</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in collaboration with the Administrator, shall make all historical and future FERC Form No. 1 filings publicly available through the centralized data repository established under section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H72889227BDD04D73AB9962C9E983C146"><enum>3.</enum><header>Development of centralized data repository</header><subsection id="H2B1FE1AED83E472F86D05DCACE3F0168"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission, in collaboration with the Administrator, shall develop and maintain a searchable and publicly accessible data repository containing information and data the Commission determines necessary to carry out the requirements of the Federal Power Act and this Act, including information and data reported or filed by a transmitting utility or Transmission Organization—</text><paragraph id="HD943A4B161A042DE9328169DB4B8325A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in FERC Form Nos. 1, 1–F, 3–Q, 714, 715, and 730, including information or data from these forms reported prior to the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3BE161F62B844C38FF61997583F9532"><enum>(2)</enum><text>pursuant to the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96C10AE3C9154CE195B71521B03E6A32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>EIA expertise</header><text>In collaborating with the Commission under this section with respect to the data repository developed under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="HE91A2246B3DD4BAC99A1C17733527B15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and maintain schemas and metadata for Form No. 1 data consistent with section 3506(b)(6) of title 44, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39D9630AE65B46D5958E6CD4C57E32E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide user-friendly tools to explore, download, and analyze such data, including filtering by utility, year, region, and data category; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A7F90ACBF6048E68CAFE096E90A721F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure such data is accessible to the public in both bulk and disaggregated forms, with Application Programming Interfaces and visualization tools where feasible.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2738DEDC4AB4E40A161BF6B0FB981B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Commissioner shall ensure that the data repository developed and maintained under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H99487C9EDE1C486CA4366A21454FC52D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes the data in fully searchable and machine-readable format;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72B3E846254B4E0F9436ACACF2E6EB71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is capable of including high-quality data through schemas and accompanying metadata;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2CD0140A47A41C78FCE84494C35468B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensures consistent identification of data elements or assets that satisfy regulatory requirements for data, established by the Commission, as reflected in machine-readable metadata;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H607FA4AFC77F49669F661EEB0F9C3485"><enum>(4)</enum><text>uses standardized data formats across all Transmission Organizations and transmitting utilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC777069EB42D48BEB3E29C26CDEF1E8F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is used by Transmission Organizations and transmitting utilities to file reports required under the Federal Power Act and this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19D0ABD487504C8FB35EDC064C8478AD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enables uploading of reports filed under the Federal Power Act or this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED152F8249B04CD7AE9D7545271315B5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>is optimized for operability by Transmission Organizations and transmitting utilities to limit the administrative burden of, and ensure consistency in, such filings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD6C6779D7AF430EBACCD313DA2D7FC9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>includes interactive tools and visualization interfaces to allow users to explore trends in transmission buildout, interconnection timelines, and associated ratepayer costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4B3C8DA91D541C5BACDE001CD6A44BA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>incorporates Application Programming Interfaces or bulk download functionality to support third-party analysis and research; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H768549B392CF42648C8E4968C3480D91"><enum>(10)</enum><text>ensures that publicly accessible data is aligned with the security of guidelines for Critical Energy/Electric Infrastructure Information, and includes appropriate data anonymization and cybersecurity protections, based on Commission guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA2CE76C795514722885F15999EF96B65"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grid research and analytics</header><subsection id="H7E0E506881EC4B0992E33E92F6A21F6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research and policy analysis</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Commission, using standardized methodologies and anonymized queue data collected under this Act, shall conduct research and publish periodic reports on the following topics:</text><paragraph id="HB0AF192C2E19459A94B608B2C76A934E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Primary drivers of increased costs to ratepayers associated with transmission and interconnection, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3E9EE81BC9EC431A90821A8FD367E45C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transmission capital expenditures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC6EBDB9A3DE4F7A9979F91A0EDA1DAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interconnection-related upgrade costs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CD4489C3C234490A49DBC9698E1ADBA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>interconnection study delays;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H546DA2F3E83A4A29A47F8CAA820278FA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>regional variations in cost allocation methodologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H505A57F0FB3948ACB83B7A0851B6769F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>cost recovery practices by utilities and grid operators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA588270C9044B758948982F610D7242"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Value delivered to ratepayers from transmission and interconnection investments, including through—</text><subparagraph id="HC7AFDC8C78FC4F8B822B339AA9BE7524"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improvements to electric system reliability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H612C448EA0464FDBBEAB1190A1BBCA11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>avoided emissions or emissions reductions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06EB48DC60214632AB3D2A4A215AF8EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhancements to long-term system resilience and grid flexibility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC7CD461EB994D83B940F76239061E9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mechanisms to enhance ratepayer affordability, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC4421232A6DA4282A889F5F96CF8B4D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluation of performance-based regulation frameworks applied to transmission and interconnection-related investments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C6ECE1F21B64EBF883B2C68E2C5D8BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessment of alternative interconnection solutions such as grid-enhancing technologies, shared infrastructure models, or consolidated upgrades; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFC0EB47416841BF8813D43AC545025C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluation of demand-side interventions that reduce the need for costly transmission or interconnection investments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA359E8C49D064AC7BD66B9EBA4472FE0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Comparative scenario modeling of potential energy futures, to—</text><subparagraph id="H56A68B66B1774560A7713DDFD0D8EADC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify lowest-cost pathways to national grid expansion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A0CE44E3A834A25A78C63F8D1BA496E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess trade-offs among investment strategies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B81D279A74E4686BB59364CE5205C26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inform decision-making by utilities, regional planning entities, and Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF791853699D4940AC06D5F1534C1604"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Systemic cost impacts from interconnection inefficiencies, including analysis of how study delays, queue withdrawals, and increased construction periods contribute to higher system costs for ratepayers or generators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67A886D6EEF54F05AD8886170D4F97A3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Opportunities to increase system efficiency and unlock latent capacity through improved operational practices and deployment of advanced technologies, including—</text><subparagraph id="H86097D3779CA4AF182C829AA026DB340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessment of unused or underutilized grid capacity due to outdated planning assumptions or lack of dynamic optimization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0A06F8B167445D58F71E7CD9DFC7BCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluation of technologies such as dynamic line ratings, topology optimization, flexible interconnection, or flow control devices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADDD30155F50487ABB266A1EC47603AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>quantification of benefits to ratepayers and system operators from unlocking this capacity relative to traditional capital-intensive buildout.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5823B40307AA485F851386E8D7BE0859"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interconnection transparency and dashboard</header><paragraph id="H3DF8B549956D4526B90F6D6E8A377AF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, through one or more National Laboratories, develop, maintain, and continuously improve an Interconnection Data Dashboard (in this section referred to as the <quote>Dashboard</quote>) that presents real-time and historical information relevant to interconnection of generators, loads, and other utilities or transmission systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H619FDA4B562C44B7A9CD0A6F0F6D0E2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Dashboard shall provide public stakeholders, regulators, utilities, developers, and researchers with transparent, up-to-date insights into the effectiveness, efficiency, affordability, and reliability of interconnection processes across all transmission planning regions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF85C93E046A43288B47CDDF27A925BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data sources</header><text>The Dashboard shall incorporate data collected under section 3 of this Act and from FERC Form No. 1 filings, relevant Commission filings, publicly available interconnection queue data, and additional datasets, as determined appropriate by the Secretary or the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H362FD05D82544FA89A76E7DECA8EA16C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Capabilities</header><text>The Secretary shall develop the Dashboard to be able to—</text><subparagraph id="HF4711B59E2A74F7EB018C00AE5507D59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>present anonymized interconnection queue data, including application volumes, withdrawal rates, project timelines, and milestones;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3320FD5EBAE54480B8F829152AF29E32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide visualization of average and median interconnection study durations, disaggregated by region and project type;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8E3162752C74D9AA0279DA34E81C761"><enum>(C)</enum><text>show aggregated system upgrade costs, study backlogs, and queue performance metrics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E0191F3AFD24A78B680F7399EB7ED98"><enum>(D)</enum><text>allow filtering by geographic location (e.g., State, balancing authority, latitude/longitude coordinate), utility, fuel type, and project size;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6138AF3F79C84974B69F25AF8B242866"><enum>(E)</enum><text>present each interconnection project’s current development status, such as application submitted, study phase, approved, under construction, or in-service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H416366A68A9D4FBFBC8A383BE94FD43B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>display physical asset characteristics for each interconnection project and system segment, including nameplate generation capacity, peak load served, and conductor capacity ratings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H798BFE564EFB4285925CAB2D2BFC4808"><enum>(G)</enum><text>identify trends in queue reform outcomes, including impacts on throughput, delay reduction, and project completion rates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D69879F284A4A4083B619EA645A32A0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>support export of underlying data in machine-readable formats for public analysis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADBBA95C2094417E984D475024491738"><enum>(I)</enum><text>perform any other function the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B5E6696256F48EEBEC9278E83E32B5C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with National Laboratories and the Commission, shall publish annual reports summarizing findings from the Dashboard, based on data collected pursuant to section 3, without substituting for the more comprehensive cost-driver analysis required under subsection (a), including—</text><subparagraph id="H9374CAE77BD1433EBF687717E2287BDA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>interregional comparisons of queue efficiency and project success rates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CF931B3E77A40E6862B47F309E1B90B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>systemic drivers of delay or cost escalation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC815DDB97D5D423BBE1EF9CC08D3505E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>estimated ratepayer impacts associated with interconnection bottlenecks; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC73EC4D0645A45B68B5C2A81A379189B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations for improving interconnection transparency and system performance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA08C5C36A754307839C32F4BAE174F0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>The Dashboard shall be made available on a public website and designed for use by a broad range of users, including through visualizations, downloadable datasets, and API access, while maintaining protections for CEII.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6740801185E6403AAAFA2CD246DA7A04"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H1EA164D45222492A9717A39730FC65FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration of the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H147B0B1F41034CF19120A77C027E670E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF35B5AE3B8BA479FA7E6CBCFCC36CB75"><enum>(3)</enum><header>FERC Form no. 1</header><text>The term <term>FERC Form No. 1</term> means the Form of Annual Report for Major electric utilities, licensees, and others, designated as FERC Form No. 1 and prescribed under section 141.1 of title 18, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C94B6B2C5414C34A5468190D183E74E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Metadata</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>metadata</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3502 of title 44, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H243694B91065406DB2C430B09D10E8E3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Project</header><text>The term <term>project</term> refers exclusively to transmission infrastructure projects planned, proposed, or undertaken by the transmitting utility. This includes projects initiated through—</text><subparagraph id="H787B6771638A4D0CBD899619A29329BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regional or local transmission planning processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43335AFA77114560ADA493D40D450635"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interconnection studies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6481909A23BB4AC9A542FFCB77F88773"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reliability-driven upgrades; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC101F0F4813C415496172DE6BB19CAA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other applicable pathways as determined by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H038FD4EF7D414B289A5C3820FCB598D8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5820EA6ED4D4F918B84761FE1983486"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Federal Power Act terms</header><text>The terms <term>transmitting utility</term>, and <term>Transmission Organization</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

