<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BAACF803EE04300AB95D81BA580531B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9271 IH: Governors’ Right to Inspect Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9271</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize sitting Governors to conduct health and safety oversight inspections of immigration detention facilities located within their states, and to establish a reporting mechanism to Congress on conditions found therein.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H68F391DDA48043AD9E386599A01EFEFD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC08B9565745249049460DC9F784CA887" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Governors’ Right to Inspect Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H1831A45CEEE648659A497BE2E3E63A98"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header> <subsection id="H2B5AB567A2014DBA92638F05E26A7076"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7ED4A0F38D8B47EB8C3FB88E4F661460">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The United States detains over 70,000 individuals in immigration detention facilities at any given time—the highest number in at least two decades—in facilities operated both directly by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) and by private contractors under Federal contract.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC0611444C2D4BBF92911A5117A875A8">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>Nearly 50 individuals have died in ICE custody since the start of 2025, the highest death toll in at least twenty years, raising urgent concerns about the adequacy of medical care and conditions of confinement across the Federal detention system.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H492D3ABC1CB2479184F26515BB492858">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>Credible reports from detainees, attorneys, and elected officials at Delaney Hall detention center in Newark, New Jersey—a privately operated, 1,000-bed facility run by GEO Group under Federal contract—have documented overcrowding, spoiled food, lack of medical access, and inadequate sanitation, resulting in a hunger and labor strike by approximately 300 detainees in May 2026.</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H052D397E9513474E8DEC23E7B8064A17"><enum>(4)</enum><text>New Jersey Governor Mikie Sherrill, exercising her responsibility as the chief executive of the State of New Jersey to protect the health and welfare of individuals within her state’s borders, sought to conduct an in-person oversight visit of Delaney Hall on May 25, 2026, and was denied entry. The Governor stated that the denial of access itself was evidence of serious concern about conditions inside the facility.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H520D8977F1DE453093395F5409E7FA5B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Governors, as the chief executives of the states in which detention facilities are sited, bear direct public health responsibilities for their residents and have a constitutional and civic interest in ensuring that facilities within their states meet basic health and safety standards.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H290FF937681147FFA463519A022088AC">
          <enum>(6)</enum>
 <text>Governors are uniquely well-positioned to conduct independent, on-the-ground health and safety oversight and to communicate findings directly to Congress, supplementing—and where necessary, compensating for gaps in—existing Federal inspection programs.</text>
        </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3C2C76C60C974D0D8A32F78CE846534D">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Purpose</header>
 <text>The purpose of this Act is solely to authorize health and safety oversight—not to grant Governors any authority to interfere with Federal immigration enforcement operations, detainee custody determinations, or removal proceedings.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="H1821244B8C074B9D93120F1D1A3A5647"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HBB0373C331EE4011B9A5711502DD3C00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>authorized oversight official</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF01E1CFD72F94D0ABACB2B35E6B92E28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Governor of any State in which a covered facility is located; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H531837F738984FC4839217D736A62C95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any State public health or safety official designated in writing by a Governor solely for purposes of conducting inspections under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H633F9AED624648A39518429FDB476B7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered facility</term> means any facility located within the United States that is used for the detention of individuals in the custody of the Secretary, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA3F77BC5D9041DF8C3565C8636935DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilities owned or operated directly by ICE;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA04FE640A4A45B7AAACD1189E94014C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilities owned or operated by a private entity pursuant to a contract with the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17E836C9E9494968BCD09A6DCA30F538"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any detention facility of a State or unit of local government pursuant to an intergovernmental service agreement with the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H45C454C849274E2791E451D1B7D2CC1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>health and safety inspection</term> means a visit to a covered facility for the purpose of observing and documenting physical conditions at the covered facility as such conditions relate to the health, safety, and humane treatment of detained individuals, including sanitation, medical care access, food quality, water access, sleeping conditions, temperature, ventilation, and emergency safety systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F20EBDE186248138E186E0A864865F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>ICE</term> means U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64ED7E893F0D4F369B8C6903FE8C0DA9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H299DE32E1C7844A8AC6C83B093F22698"><enum>4.</enum><header>Right of access for health and safety oversight</header> <subsection id="H30EADD0822F44208A6AAAD05FE1302CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law or policy, no funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary may be used to prevent an authorized oversight official from entering a covered facility for the purpose of conducting a health and safety inspection.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H940289F5FB72405CACDF9CF826F92463"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of access</header><text>An authorized oversight official conducting a health and safety inspection shall have the right to—</text> <paragraph id="H90DC5F3048A341E0951B6AB8D23F44E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access all areas of the covered facility where detainees are housed, fed, provided medical care, or otherwise held;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0AFE8CD5BA243E19C4711D6D34AC48E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>speak privately with detainees, on a voluntary basis, regarding health and safety conditions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C55879ADBBE429081342DDCCD3C4C38"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review health and safety records of detainees, including food preparation logs, medical treatment records (in aggregate and consistent with applicable privacy laws), and facility maintenance records; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H04CFE468C7CA4CD09213FED7E2F01469"><enum>(4)</enum><text>document physical conditions at the covered facility through written notes and photography, subject to reasonable security protocols established by the Secretary pursuant to section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC092E8C3D41146328F61BB7801EA0A5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No interference with enforcement operations</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to authorize any authorized oversight official to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H96385A2B255F409498BDA86AEFCD63C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>direct, halt, delay, or otherwise interfere with any ICE enforcement action, custody determination, removal proceeding, or transfer of detainees;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F68B5E2993849E9A972D5EFC63B6E76"><enum>(2)</enum><text>release or order the release of any detained individual;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8B4449F40F8487BBBC6CA545725BF60">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>direct Federal employees or contractors in the performance of their duties;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H39E94C60FDA54B1B8F0C85785EEF3865"><enum>(4)</enum><text>access classified law enforcement information or sensitive law enforcement information unrelated to health and safety conditions; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26F4D4537D274B40AA8459FE495AAB7B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>engage in access for any purpose other than civilian health and safety oversight.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2E2ED05D22F64033B8542B6DECCD46AC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Notice requirements</header> <subsection id="HFB8C264A4A52491DA8A118024FB9E63E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Governor access</header><text>The Governor of a State may conduct a health and safety inspection without prior notice.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB54313A90C1B44A683D194547AFAE124"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designated State officials</header><text>An authorized oversight official shall provide advance notice to the Secretary not less than 24 hours before conducting a health and safety inspection. Notice shall be provided in writing to both the facility operator and to the ICE Field Office Director with jurisdiction over the facility.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE47D4626FD724FE6A30001A98ADAD10C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Facility obligations and security protocols</header> <subsection id="H82F2544A8E6048D7A98F423948B6A337"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Duty To cooperate</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The operator of a covered facility shall cooperate with a health and safety inspection.</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HABEBD9D1E08044FB98E0892E7C056FC9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reasonable security protocols</header><text>Not later than 90 days after enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall by rule establish reasonable security protocols governing health and safety inspections, which may include—</text> <paragraph id="H146C647E044D4F42A1BFE4C3CA172F2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prohibition on weapons within the facility;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD8E76C58B8874FD0B6BAB1AC29125E96"><enum>(2)</enum><text>escort of authorized oversight officials by facility staff;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EDB898E537C4704B56A803F4F4679C9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restrictions on photography in areas posing genuine security risks, provided such restrictions are narrowly tailored and do not prevent documentation of health and safety conditions; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48BA81453C6C4EBAAE09E6FAB91E8E4A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prohibition on disclosure of information that could compromise the identity or safety of undercover personnel.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">Security protocols shall not be designed or applied in a manner that effectively prevents or significantly impairs the conduct of a health and safety inspection.</continuation-text></subsection></section> <section id="H4D724ED92C934488989F8970D233B885"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting to congress</header> <subsection id="HECE36A67BE5940EE98BAD64D709F70A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Optional reports by Governors</header><text>Following any health and safety inspection of a covered facility in a State, the Governor of that State may submit a written report to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H234DE8420E18491E9BE149B46754A3B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H969DD9D1C44047F0A8DF41576D694625"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBA136162C3914501A0FB62A3EDBF6E51"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3138E8D758E3414983906D303F64ECFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6CC4B9383DE7440EBB0082E8EB8BC83F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9EA77F27D5D14EFEABC4123311C31198"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C9D6D135A944BCF91E168A33B6A2622"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any Member of Congress representing the district or State in which the facility is located.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8018D074C6CB4C07847E21B2A49C9C74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of report</header><text>A report submitted under this section may include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF9E680F60DBE4A59B70842C17C563ABB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, location, and operator of the covered facility inspected;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7917A2E9D0E247B194871513D52AEAEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date and duration of the health and safety inspection;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3A16F9E760349918AA6632AAC5391B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>observations regarding health and safety conditions, including any deficiencies observed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92F105C1638A4142800832CF181651DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for corrective action; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H687FB1C17D52415582FF04335504A4E9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any response or explanation provided by facility operators during or after the inspection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE4D573471F5B47199339E6D31A1B074E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>DHS response</header><text>Upon receipt of any report submitted under this section, the relevant congressional committees may transmit the report to the Secretary of Homeland Security. The Secretary shall have 60 days to provide a written response addressing any deficiencies identified in the report and any corrective actions taken or planned.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE72C1A9C0D8140EF8636BAEE5FC3B72A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>Reports submitted under this section, and any response of the Secretary thereto, shall be made publicly available on the website of the Secretary, subject to redaction of any information that would compromise facility security or individual privacy.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1CD1EBA6B306432096991F223084991E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Enforcement and remedies</header> <subsection id="H9E03466739D647838BEC19B5DFC3F0A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil Action</header><text>An authorized oversight official who is denied access to a covered facility in violation of this Act may bring a civil action in the U.S. district court for the district in which the facility is located for—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC5594B4863D846B0869FC5EF20AF15AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">declaratory relief affirming the right of access;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H042104B68CFB4F65A4D7F6F329A6C35A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">injunctive relief ordering access to the facility; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA05D3DBA41142CF855BB95303131E74"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other relief as the court deems appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5A7683E19FA346CCAE15C94445B6AF6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No private right of action for detainees</header><text>Nothing in this Act creates a private right of action for any detained individual.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF9E9EB05E3B94AC389A4F14A2676FC68"><enum>9.</enum><header>Relationship to existing law</header> 
<subsection id="H658D1F2CBD1B4D44AF57BCF4852C13FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Supplemental authority</header><text>The access granted to authorized oversight officials under this Act is supplemental to, and does not limit, any rights existing under—</text> <paragraph id="H8336A6FAE6124345BD2ACAA0FE6A6F7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any State law providing health and safety inspection authority over private detention facilities; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91CD9B8CCC124E54B50C50AD9884731C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any existing intergovernmental agreement between a State or locality and the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H954ECFBDA1A0493C92BE736E563059DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal supremacy</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to permit a Governor or their designee to enforce State law within a covered facility in a manner that conflicts with Federal law or that interferes with Federal immigration enforcement operations.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0DDCCA583B1142E4847851BF31DFB1FD"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to implement the requirements of this Act, including the establishment of security protocols under section 6 and the maintenance of a public reporting portal under section 7(d).</text></section> <section id="H748FCDAA6301460EAE1E7F3B79A375AE"><enum>11.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date this is 180 days after the date of enactment.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

