<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEB50398F71064AEBAFF10D799791B9EA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9120 IH: To require the Postal Service to implement recommendations from the Inspector General of the United States Postal Service for improving identification and notification of undelivered and partially delivered routes, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9120</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Postal Service to implement recommendations from the Inspector General of the United States Postal Service for improving identification and notification of undelivered and partially delivered routes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7D7D38B9CB3F4C799210045DA383EF59" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0405FFD8B6B742E8870CDE897B6ED886" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Postal service required to implement certain recommendations of the Inspector General</header> 
<subsection id="H41BA36D3233D432AA91B732216D053EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service shall review and, to the extent practicable, implement the recommendations of the Inspector General of the United States Postal Service with respect to undelivered and partially delivered routes contained in the report set forth by the Inspector General entitled <quote>Delivery Operations—Undelivered and Partially Delivered Routes</quote> (Report Number 21–262–R23) and dated December 16, 2022.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3BA1771C280C40378D7D4F1BB0CD1677"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Postal Service shall implement the recommendations described in subsection (a) not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

