<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26380-8GH-GM-V20"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4295 IS: Stop Support for United Nations Relief and Works Agency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4295</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260415" legis-day="20260414">April 15 (legislative day, April 14), 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S407">Mr. Hagerty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S344">Mr. Hoeven</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To prohibit aid that would benefit Hamas, to place restrictions on funding for United Nations entities that are led by countries that support terrorism, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H639899FAAB6943CC9D2EE971D9C312A7"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA7392CD0D423448C9A3ED1A0940ECB06"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Support for United Nations Relief and Works Agency Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Stop Support for UNRWA Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6C769B0DF70B44ED8ECA9BCBE3AA34A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition against United States contributions to UNRWA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States may not make any voluntary or involuntary contributions to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (referred to in this Act as <term>UNRWA</term>), to any successor or related entity to UNRWA, or to the regular budget of the United Nations for the support of UNRWA or such successor or related entity.</text></section><section id="id53a184738768474f9395467bd388ffad"><enum>3.</enum><header>Restrictions on United Nations delegations and organizations</header><subsection id="ida7a53521ab9e491cab9785b6250a4cff"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Restrictions on United States delegations</header><text>Federal funds may not be used to pay any expenses for any United States delegation to any specialized agency, body, or commission of the United Nations if such agency, body, or commission is chaired or presided over by a country, the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 1754(c) of the Export Reform Control Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)</external-xref>), has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</text></subsection><subsection id="idae65e98da87849f1afffe3fdbab45d79"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Restrictions on contributions</header> <text>Federal funds may not be used by the Secretary of State as a contribution to any organization, agency, commission, or program within the United Nations system if such organization, agency, commission, or program is chaired or presided over by a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 620A(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371(a)</external-xref>), section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>), section 1754(c) of the Export Reform Control Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)</external-xref>), or any other provision of law, is a government that has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</text>
            </subsection><subsection id="id5a7776f8adbe420fbfd59521daa306d4">
        <enum>(c)</enum>
        <header>Revocation of immunities</header>
 <text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no official, employee, or representative of UNRWA shall be entitled to any of the privileges, exemptions, or immunities otherwise provided under the International Organizations Immunities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/288">22 U.S.C. 288 et seq.</external-xref>) or under any other provision of law or Executive order.</text>
      </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

