<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB9DD398A59D54E258FFFECDEA212F8C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8287 IH: Semiconductor Controls Effectiveness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8287</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Assistant Secretary of State for Intelligence and Research to submit a comprehensive report on the impact and effectiveness of United States semiconductor export controls on the People&#8217;s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50E5A7AADB87452DA0F2DD4CE12E7DBE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1083B522B845425FB87BE11E6BD843B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Semiconductor Controls Effectiveness Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0115CDAAD7D94F91A050A2F6BA67966B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDC6E75AFD86C4FA3BECD2F6A7DC752FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>United States export controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and advanced integrated circuits are critical for United States national security and the Artificial Intelligence race with the People’s Republic of China (PRC);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EDA4B2F41574E0295995EB8D9DB98AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efficacy of export controls requires rigorous, data-driven evaluation and assessment; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H920184D4F2DD4C5F951778A81AA0EC20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>export controls on semiconductor manufacturing equipment and advanced integrated circuits to the PRC have impacted the PRC’s military modernization efforts, indigenous semiconductor industry, and advanced artificial intelligence development; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA16EAFAD1E3485CB2544B5DAC68DC1F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>given the stakes of the strategic and technology competition with the PRC, the American public benefits from public disclosure of the real-world data and impact analysis to understand the national security, foreign policy, and economic impact of specific export control policies.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFA87E260DA754AA6A038DEE7AC3FF47B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on impact and effectiveness of semiconductor and advanced computing export controls</header> 
<subsection id="H9E8C2592906F4C9E8A370B127A484158"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 360 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary of State for Intelligence and Research (in this section referred to as the <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote>), in coordination with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security and the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the impact and effectiveness of United States semiconductor export controls on the People’s Republic of China (PRC). </text></subsection> <subsection id="H98D04A8B625D4E60BDA5FC424AFCC04C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include a comprehensive inventory of all United States export controls concerning semiconductors and semiconductor manufacturing equipment (SME) destined for the PRC. For each such control, the report should detail the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC6B8E2D849234217A401BC3B0D68D18B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A short description of the control and when it was imposed. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55CAD1C325B0443EAD2CABFBCD95AF51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Whether the control constitutes a technology control, an end-use control, or an end-user control. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1DF7DEE338548029F34C3F04E950311"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Whether such control is unilateral in nature or has been implemented by any international partners and allies. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82138F10982C4FE499FFC8B2C00527E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An analysis, including quantitative data and evidence to the maximum extent practicable, on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC7D61E4773694445A6EA9773D48D5DFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the intended goal or stated purpose of the control when it was originally imposed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E10240D53944CCAA619FDC49742871B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact of the control on the PRC’s military, intelligence, and surveillance capabilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H904ABE2399604B48A496F6641F63DB0C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impact of the control on the PRC’s ability to develop, manufacture, and acquire advanced integrated circuits; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H130CA58CD138429199287CDF01D59353"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the impact of the control on the broader PRC indigenous semiconductor industry, its revenue, and global market share;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4914D5BC0A734A7891B127B89A547EA2">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>the impact of the control on PRC artificial intelligence capabilities, including, but not limited to, computing capacity, model usage, and data-processing capacity;</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H242113F8ADDC4D9389B9CBE39246C197">
                        <enum>(F)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of the control on the revenue and global market share of United States companies, and, if negatively impacted, whether that revenue went to companies headquartered in allied countries or to PRC companies; </text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0819E11DE01945618B1E72E143C6D1B0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the impact of the control on United States long-term technology leadership and global competitiveness; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7BF3018597024886946D5C8636D4932F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a determination as to whether the control has been and remains effective in achieving its stated national security objective. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4586BC207A3149C6AB1A7EC9A0167F40"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An analysis of whether the availability of comparable items, software, or technology from sources outside the United States has undermined the effectiveness of the control. In detailing such foreign availability, the Assistant Secretary shall include whether the foreign availability originates from within the PRC or from allies and partners of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEBFF6467CF17450E95421A2F04862F1E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall also identify—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2087B8ED9FB44664B27A9AAF92CAC8C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>controls that have been the most successful in constraining the PRC’s strategic capabilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E27FC1339B44573BB4546355A5ED1CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of controls, if any, that have failed to constrain the PRC and disproportionately harm United States industry without a corresponding advancement in United States national security and foreign policy, and the reason for why the control has failed to constrain the PRC;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6E3CAD358ED94EC29CF69EFA4BB224E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations on how to bolster cooperation with United States industry to enhance compliance with the controls and the overall effectiveness of controls; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDDE6687F12842E2ADC6D7F17621C171"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a set of recommendations to improve the efficacy of the export control regime, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1E79074D6C5746979B7BA7A08CAF23F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specific refinements to existing controls; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD58195363B6B4FEA84AD9F8136F79817"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methods for bolstering enforcement efforts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80E9EBD09FC349639E281FED1496F8A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for closing diversion loopholes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H220FB97E05614DC7AFA7CC3B7B29D0A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Stakeholder engagement</header><text>In carrying out the requirements under subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall engage relevant stakeholders to inform the assessment of United States export controls, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H153E24EF034343EC95F29A39CA11A87D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relevant Federal departments and agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H745B11FD1EDA421B8F9132477249962B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>private sector entities from the United States semiconductor, semiconductor manufacturing equipment, and advanced computing sectors; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2C9D46C7CA4B4E82A2AB6FAA79F4B263"><enum>(3)</enum><text>individuals from academic institutions, think tanks, and other research organizations with relevant expertise;</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA528729ADABC477390BEB88E84E2ED56"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form and posted on the Department’s website. The Assistant Secretary of State for Intelligence and Research may include a classified annex as appropriate. </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD11CD233D7964F7083DCD70E797C6252"><enum>4.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HC4DB00047B3D4B2096B6FF6D3E24E12F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DD2477356C44A42B34A1A78D4FBFE1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text> </paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

