<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H01FF3A863F1C4DC9AA7344C7E891DFE1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8043 IH: Vets Collections, Liquidity, and Efficiency Accountability for Reinvestment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8043</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001326">Ms. Bynum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the efficiency of the recovery and collection of revenue for the Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Care Collections Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAB75B945A67049879982A5C03697E54D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDB7FB8A5F1914A69B8613A9C47CC76FC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Vets Collections, Liquidity, and Efficiency Accountability for Reinvestment Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Vets CLEAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H165E46DB56EB4D5FB79DD41A65D2BE26"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provide flexibility and efficiency for collection of revenue for Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Care Collections Fund</header> <subsection id="H72E86729945C465C8F383899E25A0C5A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1729A of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4F3B7994E25E4972859BE30E7242B38D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HC7FF35551FF241C08174749366AF2D10" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HB5F5BA6E662B4787939CB90A999DD172"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Sections 3711 and 3729 through 3733 of title 31, to the extent that such recovery or collection is based on medical care, services, or medication provided or paid for under this chapter.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE0C113F15704EC6BAEE7902262269FC"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Amounts recovered or collected through administrative, legal, or judicial processes, including investigations and audits, to the extent that such recovery or collection is based on medical care, services, or medication provided or paid for under this chapter.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC01EFD065BC4DEEB4023312092F315E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c), (d), and (e) as subsections (d), (e), and (f), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B16AD642923438D91607ED0CECBCD15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="HAD1E7061401643B587AF092F5BEE7C37" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H0C55E017889146F98B04A151F0411A78"><enum>(c)</enum> <paragraph id="HEE23C87C8C4241C69BC9D817872B0F25" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds directed to the <quote>Medical Services</quote> account to reimburse such account for the costs of care provided under the following authorities may, at the discretion of the Secretary, be deposited in the Medical Care Collections Fund:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6E0BA6E7B57F444D851EDB5EDA7A2D9E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 1781 of this title.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D13F3D8ADCD41D489D4436DB84DC00D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 8111 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1916CAF323446E1A39BB23BF27A4457" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Secretary to deposit amounts into the Medical Care Collections Fund pursuant to this subsection shall expire on September 30, 2028.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1524C07B2E7F4F4793EE5E3175AECF4B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO reports</header><text>Such section is further amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H118B914BDA3B4DE5B554A083EF638019" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HF35587F0AA8D4C5CAAB5471F0BF8D13C"><enum>(g)</enum> 
<paragraph id="HB7E5CE213A9140FA8E5064AA29D0611D" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, and not less frequently than once every 180 days thereafter during period the authority under subsection (c) is effective, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on amounts deposited into the Medical Care Collections Fund under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF70CD2E4B0341C2A1B7A41A0886B9E3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3A34F8C6FA944CCC8FF9CA168CB86B62"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount of funds recovered or collected during the period covered by the report, disaggregated by source of recovery or collection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20DCCF9BCF824191804535D83D990A1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how such funds were expended by the Department, including the categories of medical care, services, staffing, or other purposes for which the funds were used.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

