<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF57CFEF9AAFE431EAC49CBCFFE283F1D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6659 IH: Critical Minerals Trade Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6659</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001236">Mr. Moore of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001239">Mr. McGuire</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish within the Office of the United States Trade Representative a Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA3F7E3BC39E341FE8EC43171D9352BF3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2D0ECEF6FEF24B47AAF364F11CA3AAE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Critical Minerals Trade Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HEF9BE4E88FF74F0485C3BC0371A237BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> <paragraph id="HB804431DDB6F453DBE62418132B086B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Critical minerals, including rare earth elements, are essential for national security and economic resilience.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5FC66F85C7D3495789336C5020D21B31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Processed critical minerals and their derivative products are key building blocks of the defense industrial base of the United States and integral to applications such as jet engines, missile guidance systems, advanced computing, radar systems, advanced optics, and secure communications equipment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58E091A79A314C3FABBDC32C4EC6023D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States remains heavily dependent on foreign sources of critical minerals which exposes the economy and defense sector to supply chain disruptions and economic coercion.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3A27C4DAC8746C7ABB562F3F7D9546B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Foreign producers of critical minerals have engaged in price manipulation, overcapacity, and arbitrary export restrictions, using their supply chain dominance as a tool for geopolitical and economic leverage over the United States.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HD12AA72800F64B53B711CB4259E0FA20"><enum>3.</enum><header>Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 141 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2171">19 U.S.C. 2171(b)</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3555406C9C3643B1B35850D6655AB963"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In subsection (b)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC99AF2F80F4F4AAEA1DCABEB64216B04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>one Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator,</quote> after <quote>one Chief Agricultural Negotiator,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C80EC270E924CAA888DE51DF8CA24A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator,</quote> after <quote>the Chief Agricultural Negotiator,</quote> each place it appears.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF9BCD52F39E438592AF0B768A925794"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In subsection (c), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H1A4C349182EF4C4DA9709AE2BA5051F9" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HCE50AFFCD38E4A19862579934FFBE7D6" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The principal functions of the Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator shall be to conduct trade negotiations regarding critical minerals, enforce trade agreements relating to United States critical minerals resources, take appropriate action to address the acts, policies, or practices of trade partners with respect to critical minerals, and lead the coordination of the Office’s critical minerals policy in consultation with the following individuals:</text> <subparagraph id="H1287B6B0EE4F4CA3BF1F295DFE4255CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of State or his designee.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4AB1C286A1C54664A48D68FCE6B673FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy or his designee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE534B6C49F446788C08432528A5A05E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior or his designee.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A37BD56D33D46118C2A8916F21033D6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other individual the United States Trade Representative determines appropriate.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H627769BB3DF0444BA9FCA844DAC552B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>By adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H600A75258BCC4E0C93782B340C50AA75" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H9F128AC71CC047E794060CEC1F6D5EA6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual report by Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator</header> 
<paragraph id="H89B29112843E4C79B1B567E4910E5FE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2026, and annually thereafter, the Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, and concurrently publish on a publicly available website of the United States Trade Representative, a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9EC31D7B0585421986983B2A72520607"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes in detail the results of a review with respect to the acts, policies, and practices relating to the trade in critical minerals in the preceding fiscal year of countries determined by such negotiator to—</text> 
<clause id="HA7FC64CBE0D14A6D8314B8B88AAE898F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have a significant trade relationship with the United States; or</text></clause> <clause id="H50C85137E7E24D9CB77292FFBDCB776A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pose a risk to the supply chains of the United States; and</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEA415F4449C451DA42C87E2B54CC190"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determines whether each such act, policy, or practice reviewed under subparagraph (A)—</text> <clause id="HE628BBD4CACE4641AF3A46AB96DE1049"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creates a supply chain vulnerability which would be detrimental to the United States defense, energy, and critical infrastructure sectors; or</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H33D4CC4B2EF64376A9C36BE53AAAE417"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">violates, is inconsistent with, or otherwise denies the United States of a benefit under a bilateral or multilateral trade agreement with such identified country; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H344332F321E44CABA98A5ED636F3FAE3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides an update for each plan previously submitted under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB86B1ED018664E1DB6A71DD5A9FC1917"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Response to adverse actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the submission of the report under paragraph (1), the Chief Critical Minerals Negotiator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan to respond to the findings of the report, including any action taken under title III of this Act, to each act, policy, or practice identified in such report that was determined under paragraph (1)(B) to violate, be inconsistent with, or otherwise deny to the United States a benefit under a bilateral or multilateral trade agreement with such identified country or create a supply chain vulnerability which would be detrimental to the United States defense, energy, and critical infrastructure sectors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCB5D7052170742E9A0B7903ED8A05AA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

