<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2945FED2E57545BF948578DD9B432C16" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9097 IH: American Manufacturing Revitalization Exchange Program Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9097</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260602">June 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a new educational exchange program to strengthen manufacturing workforce education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE20BC9FFCA3343F1A11E75CCEAEC65CD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H34C0C0CDF94C4EE4A3E51BCC54FF687F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Manufacturing Revitalization Exchange Program Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8C41AEB8328B46AD85E5C5FCBC55F3CF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDFCAD783DD58495AAE4ED2ADBD066487"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the manufacturing industry requires a skilled workforce across all educational and training levels, including skilled technicians, production workers, engineers, scientists, and laboratory personnel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8645F06DB7A04123A2DC422D7F541A20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States manufacturing sector faces significant challenges due to an aging workforce, labor shortages, difficulty recruiting and retaining skilled workers, and the long-term effects of offshoring;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H505D44589B514730B46CC50EEA5C5B83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in 1979, there were 19,600,000 workers in manufacturing, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD831F6F27694BDE8E66D0488E1E4D9D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by 2019, 6,700,000 jobs were lost, according to the Bureau of Labor Statistics;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FB6627851CE4774A5F8D3BF9F284C00"><enum>(5)</enum><text>according to the Manufacturing Institute, an affiliate of the National Association of Manufacturers, by 2033, the industry will require 3,800,000 additional workers, yet nearly half of these positions may remain unfilled;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0434D1A5D28B42C7A4C98CB7FD8F7C98"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">according to the Manufacturing Institute, the economic cost of these vacancies could total $1,000,000,000,000 by 2030;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE082AD08A6834DAF96C9F9637252FB83"><enum>(7)</enum><text>reshoring manufacturing has the potential to create millions of high-wage jobs, many of which do not require a four-year post-secondary degree but may include industry-recognized certificates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFAF5750E69CB47719F7C57E939E60F27" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>according to National Association of Manufacturers, foreign direct investment in United States manufacturing reached more than $2,400,000,000,000 in 2024, which has helped reshoring and job creation efforts with about 244,000 jobs in 2024 and, according to Manufacturers Alliance, 268,000 jobs in 2023;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9DDD8B379A4C4883B49A213E3793017F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>current manufacturing workers need ongoing training to keep pace with the expanding set of skills required for high-quality, technologically advanced jobs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF827849EB5E4AF88A1531D500C227EC"><enum>(10)</enum><text>aligning workforce development programs with industry needs is essential to foster the skills and competencies necessary for high-quality jobs in a globally competitive manufacturing sector;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71D322531C4D41C1A57E5AF7899B484B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>according to Apprenticeship USA, there were 97,500 registered apprentices in the advanced manufacturing industry in 2025, a 20 percent increase over the past 5 years; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2B0C60A28F640F3A9968158894F79F9"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the United States should collaborate with allied and partner nations to provide opportunities for work-based learning, apprenticeships, certification programs, cooperative education, and other initiatives to engage the future workforce at all educational and career levels.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF21BB93E2BB14EC5826A0BE4D3C78DB3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Manufacturing revitalization exchange program</header> 
<subsection id="HA4FFB6ED8C7E418888EBBC6BC3FB4BE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established an international exchange program to be known as the <quote>American Manufacturing Revitalization Exchange Program</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>), which shall be administered by the Assistant Secretary, in accordance with subsection (c), to increase manufacturing knowledge, training, experience, expertise, and workforce in the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF302690D85FF4421AFA468EDEB74D550"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Program are the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H48DB59921F9841BBA1C51F397DEFA56C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To advance the domestic and foreign policy priorities of the United States by promoting an international workforce exchange in manufacturing sectors, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H89104D05BC204E5D85628922693D2C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>robotics;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC374FDE02A2341B8A711B59C06F831C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>semiconductors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36F9D8823E064CE2B9F7E62D9DDC5B3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>aeronautics, including space operations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5E964C2EFB004A06B3FAECBBAF4CE1C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>additive manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D79A52C6AA74A5FB8C43C7B689CDB20"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ship building, including shipping manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4411EAD909AE466EA55D4C3CB7A84B97"><enum>(F)</enum><text>energy, including mining;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H950689F849FE432A8C2E64795CCCA7E2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>automotive; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H97B47C4327F842F3AE8B2769176E5B82"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other sector the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Commerce, identifies as strategically important or critical and would benefit from the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9F9336A99904B72BEEECA8EB9FA7462"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To send United States citizens from a trade or manufacturing background to manufacturing institutions, sectors, or companies in allied nations, and, in particular, in allied nations who have entered into trade agreements with the United States, to receive training in manufacturing skills.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FF6DDDDE3EE414BA30BBE741CC9BB34"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To build relations and to connect manufacturers in the United States with technical institutions and manufacturing entities in allied nations to share best practices for machine operations, assembly, management, and other skills and expertise related to manufacturing or supply chain security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2ADF54F2F10041D49344DF9EA2E8F7D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To assist in developing a robust and skilled manufacturing workforce in the United States that can support and fill the gaps within the United States manufacturing sectors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0CD862A2E3574231A4A22F46228A91CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To assist in expanding and modernizing the manufacturing labor force in the United States through increased workforce training and apprenticeship opportunities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECADDE761B0346268C5101288F498DC1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To reduce reliance on the foreign manufacturing industry for skilled labor, components, parts, processes, technology, and products related to national security and the manufacturing sectors and to enhance the competitiveness of the United States within the global manufacturing marketplace.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DFAC2899AB94E7C9C5F75AD4B60B961"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To facilitate innovation with respect to casting, molding, forming, machining, assembling, additive manufacturing, and other processes pertaining to manufacturing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0335BC2F8164465D8E1E16B3A4C3357F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Not to subsidize corporations by funding the workforce training of persons who are affiliated or have minority interest in a United States company that has subsidiaries in an allied country where the program will take place.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFA504F2C2D624766BEDD029B7DA2FD6A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration of Program</header> 
<paragraph id="HE9535A6657234DD1A5F2E7C36308AC2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prior consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, shall administer the Program after consultation with manufacturing industry leaders, Manufacturing USA, the Secretary of Commerce, the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Employment and Training, labor organizations, allied governments, and United States diplomatic and consular posts located in allied nations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95A7F0B5D46E48A097E154CD79BF85F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limit on number of participants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall select not more than 10 participants for the Program per year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE814C3FD184D4BECA6857A15937014C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Participant selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0F6E636CE5244D6ABE7062757FAD8B5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">select Program participants in accordance with the eligibility criteria under subsection (d) and in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Employment and Training, Manufacturing USA, and other manufacturing groups; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4048682B3C864999A9EA6DCF38717319"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure Program participants come from a wide range of backgrounds and manufacturing regions in the United States.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H05D69ABB3F864183918E5A796C4C5305"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Participant placement</header> <subparagraph id="H438F6CCACB0B4173BA7B5DBA504E9301"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, and United States diplomatic and consular posts located in allied nations, shall place Program participants in a manufacturing sector, institution, or company approved by the Assistant Secretary in an allied nation.</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0CD8535500634F27A4146FF7B2712ABE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the Assistant Secretary, in coordination with United States diplomatic and consular posts, Manufacturing USA, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, and other relevant Government agencies, shall conduct outreach to relevant manufacturing, workers, and workforce training organizations, as well as relevant manufacturing companies, higher education institutions, and to allied governments the Assistant Secretary determines are likely to produce a range of qualified applicants to be sent abroad.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H58F790B3BF384B0299F9E7FE97DD551D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Participant eligibility criteria</header> <paragraph id="H0893233D480248CFB42A902264CC7C09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mandatory requirements</header><text>Each Program participant shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2DBA573BBA7346D1A565FF8902B4EEAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have—</text> <clause id="HC1AB0411D81941539E9DB6281D1B3D0C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">worked as an apprentice in a Program-related manufacturing vocation, job, or field, as determined by the Assistant Secretary;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H22804C1F60C44B058C2686DB58CD7CC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completed a Program-related trade curriculum apprenticeship, or an equivalent apprenticeship, as determined by the Assistant Secretary in consultation with the Secretary of Labor; or</text></clause> <clause id="H1027795C251545CE905A92A569CBE8C6" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enrolled in at least a two-year or four-year higher education institution, trade manufacturing institution, or vocational school and completed necessary pre-requisite courses and training as determined by the Assistant Secretary;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE28CC7A5BF24446AA256BC5099976377"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be a United States citizen; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DD6BD999748406E83F80DFE248954A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrate proficiency in language skills or provide a plan to obtain the language skills necessary to participate in the Program with respect to the allied nation the participant will be placed in.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H551C1CF45EDA41798C2B09EE16DF7F07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting Program participants, the Assistant Secretary may consider a variety of factors, including whether participants—</text> <subparagraph id="H09A1D2A6513144788A8D4EC588DE4163"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have experience as a manager or supervisor in a field related to manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC88B8250D90C41FBB556D0ED54B6B537"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have experience as an instructor or trainer in a vocation or apprentice program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74A4CCD0C56B45B89A18950848F1F1CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hold a degree in a field related to manufacturing;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1BB5DA635B464456984C4350DB833BC8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are in a position at a training program overseen by a labor organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A98BB2C698F4CD58CD1C1D495361226"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have experience as an administrator in a higher education institution related to manufacturing; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDDC7F473C4A643B78C7E6FEDA271F617"><enum>(F)</enum><text>hold a faculty position in a higher education institution related to manufacturing.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H109C1835668A4A33B68C89D219DCE246"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Structure of program</header> <paragraph id="HB0621608B5B84DD89B74634D1738E603"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Work plan</header><text>To carry out the purposes described in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF1E85C946A4D452BB9620B0F82757213"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to Program participants, the Assistant Secretary shall, in coordination with United States diplomatic and consular posts in allied nations, Manufacturing USA, and other relevant Government agencies—</text> <clause id="HAD7A6C64BC474FEF9A8E8CAD9CA44999"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approve a work plan that identifies the target objectives for the participants, including specific duties and responsibilities relating to those objectives;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8919B8F4DC554CD38F0C0FDAEA39F516"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>approve the manufacturing sectors, companies, or institutions in allied nations in which the participants will conduct their workforce exchange;</text></clause> <clause id="H94771D4B260E4B9DA028B37574860CBB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordinate and be authorized to enter into agreements with the Secretary of Labor and other relevant Government agencies to provide credentials or recognition of on-the-job training for participants that align with manufacturing industry standards upon completion of the Program;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF6628D5EB2804BB7A14D0BD9896A9AAD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>ensure that the knowledge, skills, and processes acquired by the participant are documented, where practicable, through model-based work instructions, digital assembly documentation, other digital manufacturing knowledge capture platforms, or social media platforms, and disseminated in a public form to Manufacturing USA, manufacturing institutions, and employers upon the participant’s return; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB9382E8A593C41A8B48CEE468F222847"> <enum>(v)</enum> <text>find ways for students enrolled in a higher education institution or a vocational or apprenticeship program to receive course credit after participation, to the best extent possible; and</text>
            </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF64D7B7DF4F345DF8067FFC021CF919A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the participants shall—</text> <clause id="H3398FB80DCC946B7830D26F88B7E5A97"><enum>(i)</enum><text>participate in pre-travel orientation and information sessions to learn about their host allied nation, the format of the Program, and the work and training expected;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H76D1082CBA2A472CB44C3795E043A70A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>participate in advanced coursework, research projects, or practical training opportunities, offered by the host institution during completion of the Program;</text></clause> <clause id="H2BFD3E0FE13F47BD983A159698F07E34"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>engage with industry partners and skilled experts to gain hands-on experience with respect to best practices in the manufacturing industry;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF88B18ED7083422DB56E702153F4127C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>participate in research projects or practical training opportunities offered by the host institution during completion of the Program;</text></clause> <clause id="HA0E316BE9B7540D581AF7C126BFC72BC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>participate in professional development activities, such as conferences, workshops, trainings, and seminars, to expand knowledge of best practices in manufacturing;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2F5950EA0BB14D8E8C70A43516C34020"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>train with a professional skilled tradesperson who has specialized expertise related to a manufacturing sector;</text></clause> <clause id="HA185B86C1B4848989E6A64E9B316948E"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>record or track, to the best extent possible, their experiences and skills learned, to share with the Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs, Manufacturing USA, manufacturing institutions, and other relevant government entities;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBD3BE3424EFD47E6A939DFEB5F0BAA16"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>serve as a cultural and workforce ambassador of the United States, fostering mutual understanding with the host country’s manufacturing community;</text></clause> <clause id="HD07D91DB896F40AAA2CAFC21EAE184B3"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>participate in professional development activities, such as conferences, workshops, trainings, and seminars, to expand knowledge of global best practices in manufacturing;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB6D379D433AA4776812551A58A6DCB3E"><enum>(x)</enum><text>build and strengthen networks with international peers, skilled tradespersons, and industry professionals to facilitate ongoing collaboration and knowledge exchange;</text></clause> <clause id="HFBB3871E99D64BF7AF425725CF818185"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>receive, upon completion of the Program, industry recognized credentials, certificates, letters of completion, or equivalents, to mark the completion of training in the relevant skill or skills developed during the Program; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB70D479259494801AFEBEF5D777BD9E5"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>be recognized, upon completion of the Program, as alumni and, as such, be eligible to participate in applicable Department of State educational and cultural affairs alumni networks, activities, and professional development opportunities, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A093C5E69FF40A4B2BC8D63A99515FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Program periods shall be for a duration to be determined by the Assistant Secretary but may not be for a period longer than 12 months. A one-time renewal for a period not longer than 6 months may be granted by the Assistant Secretary in consultation with the relevant United States diplomatic and consular post and allied nation government.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE5D6F45AFF80431EA423235F8138271B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exchange award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall provide each Program participant with a stipend that is equal to the amount needed for the participant’s reasonable costs during the Program period, which may include—</text> <paragraph id="H0D046F7F2431466E94C008B4EF761CF0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>living expenses, including housing, basic food costs, and daily transportation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE9A270068A7E4FFF874D4EC93F6A6E67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>essential training materials;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA52831F4561D4F2CBCB8E950A39B0935"><enum>(3)</enum><text>mandatory visa application, immigration fees, and other essential pre-departure requirements;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H577A417A86454A7E919AF37E4401CD14"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relocation expenses including airline and rail for Program required travel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1A1A15AC53049D9815B69A48ADD0C37"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>in-country travel allowance essential to travel to manufacturing sites and institutions and Program related travels;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB05346809F3F4C18B28219D9A48773DD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>health care for participant and dependents;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2ABBC9CC97247A1A5A98E7FAA0A1104"><enum>(7)</enum><text>software licenses, digital training platforms, and digital tools necessary to participate in trainings and skills learning; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H17E5CB5A4881499FA8508BF6C0986F7D"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other reasonable related costs approved by the Assistant Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC2430F5650FD45539016F0FC80BF21DF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of completion of the Program by the initial cohort of participants, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report providing information on the implementation of the Program, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0EBA877FB6324C049A8476F8BA8947A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to Program participants—</text> <subparagraph id="H0445C816882447FCB47AAFDCF57351D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>background information, including—</text> 
<clause id="HE6E2934E0F0748E6873F8D2D837C663B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>qualifications;</text></clause> <clause id="HB8876CA0944D4F4FA0551481D5FDC722"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>geographical origins; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7A6DD79547484F9F86AB937CA0E4573B">
              <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other relevant information the Assistant Secretary determines necessary;</text>
            </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCD49BB9A282A44DCA65EAECB3A4623DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of participants;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D66B9A53C10416EB48A25E2E9035198"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the institutes, sectors, and companies the participants were placed with;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB982B6C9E4684D62B9389677983007A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the type of work training the participants engaged in;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3277D5019E144CD1AAE2AB3B1D7021E9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the types of cultural events and activities the participants engaged in;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF427DD416E11425481A1E037CA18E9AE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>feedback on the Program and lessons learned;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01D7BCC3FD8E461588522CD2341E5DAA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the jobs, vocations, or trades sought after or obtained after completing the Program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE8F13CCEE26F49A395764D266DAF547D">
            <enum>(H)</enum>
 <text>feedback from the host institution, industry, or company about the contributions of the participants;</text>
          </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FD27A18A28B4A85907E0153AA9E56DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of manufacturing or work placements selected and their relation to the development of United States region-specific specialties under the Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA821CEFA5BDF4083BC5643AE9F3F8F8A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan for factoring in the lessons learned and acquired skills-based knowledge into Program going forward;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FF24451169A41AC808BAEC334545126"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the total amount of funds used in support of the Program and efforts taken to maximize the efficiency and effectiveness of the funds used, including encouraging industry partnerships and support of the program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92DA048B714A451CB7934330439D3F84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any potential legislative recommendations to improve or enhance the Program to achieve the goals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE444B59E7CB7424CA88BA670B8573FAE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>post-Program information that includes—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA7E3EA76B2048A5A26125DAA72404EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the job, vocation, or trade the former participant has sought after or obtained; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A54EACA834C433594F97BED08C892A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a report from the host institution, industry, or company the participant found placement in, about the contributions of the participants;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C664E4C92C64423984524C79A9FAADB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of the digital tools, platforms, and methodologies used to capture and transfer manufacturing knowledge from host institutions to United States employers and training programs, and an assessment of their effectiveness; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8361D640DB7A41F3AA2AB6F6D53F5A37"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the total amount of funds used in support of the Program and efforts taken to maximize the efficiency and effectiveness of the funds used, including encouraging industry partnerships and support of the program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8F5F703B97984629AE13A581D7FDC629"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation coordination assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, is encouraged to enter into agreements with allied nations, and, in particular, in allied nations who have entered into trade agreements with the United States as well as corporate entities, and other appropriate organizations to create forms of assistance for the purposes of supporting and sustaining the development, implementation, administration the American Manufacturing Revitalization Program authorized under this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="HDEC0C97487E648F48F07E1611FF5014B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to engage in independent consultation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out section 3(a), the Assistant Secretary is authorized and encouraged to consult, as appropriate, with Manufacturing USA and other relevant manufacturing, technical, and workforce organizations to inform the identification and selection of other priority manufacturing sectors to cooperate with when carrying out the American Manufacturing Revitalization Program.</text></section> <section id="HA2912AB4A1274177BA8314D0B76DDD9C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study for future expansion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall conduct a study on how to expand and sustain the Program in the future so that it builds partnerships with private sector, manufacturing entities, the Department of Labor, the Department of Commerce, and labor organizations, which may be conducted in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Commerce, Manufacturing USA, relevant Government agencies, and labor organizations.</text></section> 
<section id="H561694FF116045F0A8AF46A7635710DD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, the requirements of this Act, and the American Manufacturing Revitalization Program established by this Act shall end on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> <section id="H2A195797AB2B460BB013502204912AF5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC1ACA83EF865459883FA42C28933A6F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Allied nation</header><text>The term <term>allied nation</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H50EE585EC4904EACA01D01632643A583"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text> 
<clause id="H03693D04119443DB8CBA09C9122295E2">
            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any country described in section 2350a(a)(2) of title 10, United States Code, with a large manufacturing industry that includes not less than one of the sectors described in subsection (b)(1); or</text>
          </clause> 
<clause id="H4C1F2C875D4C4D0BAE1A0C499A0DDB62"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other country the Assistant Secretary determines contains qualified manufacturing sectors; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62BD3E7911FA42BC82ADCF7C0F4BD732"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any nation identified as a <quote>covered nation</quote> in section 2533c(d)(2) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCADD976228D248E7A3CD71BB50B3DB92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote> means the Assistant Secretary for Educational and Cultural Affairs, who shall be responsible to the Secretary of State, acting through the Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H210F8ECBB63B41CAB5215C67E56551FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Labor organizations</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> is as defined in section 152(5) of title 29, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE86EE65124FB45C7951CD712057C5CE4">
        <enum>(4)</enum>
        <header>Manufacturing sector</header>
 <text>The term <term>manufacturing sector</term> means to engage in the mechanical, physical, or chemical transformation of materials, substances, or components into new products as defined by the North American Industry Classification System 31–33 of the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BFBEF4DD05649D48854CC5362091D78" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Manufacturing USA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Manufacturing USA</term> means the program established under section 34 of the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/278s">15 U.S.C. 278s</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> </section> </legis-body></bill>

