<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H34B25F524D524E1EAD95EC4AB2BB015B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9674 IH: United States Coast Guard Corrosion Control Assistance Team Pilot Program Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9674</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260714">July 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to establish a pilot program to provide corrosion prevention and control assistance to Coast Guard field units, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5B9C3A2FCDAF4558B5039B2098E35E3E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA6110843F87A448D9C0436076EE3A5B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States Coast Guard Corrosion Control Assistance Team Pilot Program Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3D609914E1184F24B3F1CC8AAD95A464"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of pilot program</header> <subsection id="HC651114BD9BD45B09B9591000131B701"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, acting through the Assistant Commandant for Acquisition, shall establish and carry out a pilot program, to be known as the <quote>United States Coast Guard Corrosion Control Assistance Team Pilot Program</quote>, to provide corrosion prevention and control assistance to Coast Guard field units.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF13D17BA53340148FCA30803474672B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program established under subsection (a), the Commandant shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAB417A2A94AE4C318830719842AFCD4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide on-site corrosion prevention and control technical advisory services and direct assistance to Coast Guard field units upon request;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAC35DB8DB234AF9B69C3984223FA04F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop and maintain a repository of corrosion prevention and control best practices and lessons learned applicable to Coast Guard maritime assets;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95E78B6DF15A487EA4A1B53E3AA1BA4C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess corrosion conditions and recommend corrective and preventive maintenance actions at Coast Guard units;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H64D0E78C8D694BB69A993CCDDB7775FA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support training and education of Coast Guard personnel in corrosion prevention and control techniques;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16F44A02BDB64260B91AE16487CD6D45"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinate with the Department of Defense Office of Corrosion Policy and Oversight and other relevant Federal agencies to leverage existing expertise, technical standards, and program data; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H67A6FA676B184A33B8086F40A3736CCE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>collect data and metrics necessary to assess the effectiveness of the pilot program and inform future programmatic decisions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD8E48581AEF64D67B2ACC93E2CC97E0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot program objectives</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program established under subsection (a), the Commandant shall specifically seek to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H17FC781527DF479B8B78226FCA90E658"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrate the feasibility and effectiveness of a Coast Guard-specific corrosion control assistance capability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C6839E85AAE4343813D421B4DD84290"><enum>(2)</enum><text>apply lessons learned from the Navy’s Corrosion Control Assistance Team program and other Department of Defense corrosion programs to the unique operational environment of the Coast Guard;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE0EF9EBC2E78499989F6AADD1D54BF72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>quantify the impact of corrosion prevention and control interventions on Coast Guard asset readiness and service life; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3027248B7F5B4B56B366DBC9EDB02688"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop recommendations related Coast Guard anti-corrosion prevention and control initiatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4CD328D5B0734A10AEFF31E5CE8D54F6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out the pilot program established under section 2, the Commandant may—</text> <paragraph id="H2144D0A9A8A04EB197FB0A716917A690"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procure equipment, tools, and materials necessary for corrosion assessment and control activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0327C18B11F42DAB43353512A618F7A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>train program personnel;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2298223CE78B48D1823A2CDA7A7E3D12"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contract with non-Federal entities for technical expertise and advisory services; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H251A4D95F7184887A06AD716A9B78FCA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop data systems and information management tools to support program operations.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HEE1BCC0F4B9B4C0CB578EC2C92895B3B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Organization and staffing</header> <subsection id="H944803C0F8984015AA78BF0D89ECF62A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Corrosion control assistance teams</header> <paragraph id="H1E5ECFD34A784EBC86B3939BB9591FB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program established under section 2, the Commandant shall establish not fewer than 2 Corrosion Control Assistance Teams consisting of qualified corrosion prevention and control specialists.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D35E36F225A41DB9261478D32B9B610"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Team composition</header><text>Each Corrosion Control Assistance Team shall consist of personnel with technical expertise in—</text> <subparagraph id="HB977805E364B42FABF3CBD8D5D2B3CBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>marine coatings and surface preparation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA4B01CE1AE4F4A1886617AADBBC43207"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cathodic protection systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E93B15F1B2A4D41BB9A070CACEA38EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coatings and corrosion control training;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1CD5211B2D304000BC1EA850F16C9D82"><enum>(D)</enum><text>corrosion control of C5I (Command and Control, Communications, Computers, Combat Systems, and Intelligence) systems;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB31B2E6AC8C94515B3173A662E0C66AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>corrosion engineering and failure analysis; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB74767D16613419D84CF0A0A56E246AE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>preventive maintenance program development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA41E68970F24C018DA7AC4B45AAC3C7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifications</header> <subparagraph id="H5C219AE960D34EC5BFABD28B71586747"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Corrosion Control Assistance Team shall possess relevant technical certifications, including corrosion control credentials from AMPP (including certified Coating Inspectors, Protective Coatings Specialists, Cathodic Protection Specialists, and Corrosion Specialists) and commensurate demonstrated expertise, as determined by the Commandant.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC6696D48B32C4964BC8F72865FAFFDD7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Accreditation</header><text>Firms performing the work should be AMPP QP 5 Accredited.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8F28BDA78F7B476D9FF87F2AAA40D6C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text>In establishing and staffing the pilot program, the Commandant may—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6E82C74972CE4DBCB7B518D38CA51A69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enter into memoranda of understanding with the Secretary of the Navy, the Secretary of the Army, or the Secretary of the Air Force to detail military or civilian personnel with corrosion prevention and control expertise to the pilot program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAFCC1FFF6B94ED1AFB29CC0B53A28AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contract with private sector entities possessing relevant technical expertise; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FEBF92069BB44DAA83CF32A6554B44D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>request technical support and subject matter expertise from the Department of Defense Office of Corrosion Policy and Oversight.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H0668D9E527EF454B902C9F101571107F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="H735317009965426F94452635B202B9C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date on which the pilot program commences operations, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives an interim report on the pilot program that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H559E55B35A044671AB4C5657F4214203"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of field unit visits conducted and services provided;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AA954F159634CCEBFBFB959AD795A42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>preliminary data on the impact of program activities on asset readiness and maintenance costs; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83FD9589C0B24E55B5661BB54E5AB439"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any significant challenges encountered in program implementation and proposed corrective actions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5DE42F98770F4605A60F8EADFEE2FE16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 90 days before the date on which the pilot program is scheduled to terminate under section 6, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a final report on the pilot program that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB0F3DC3BDCB84FECAE99F18E188DD6F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a comprehensive assessment of the effectiveness of the pilot program in achieving the objectives described in section 4(c);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C31300F27084CD99049986EF1BE55A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>quantified metrics on improvements in asset service life and operational readiness attributable to pilot program activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD623155012E9437487757D196431CC86"><enum>(3)</enum><text>lessons learned from the pilot program and from coordination with Department of Defense corrosion programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DF685E4FE5E424CB13959455FF79A68"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a detailed assessment of the feasibility and projected cost of a permanent, full-scale Coast Guard corrosion prevention and control program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83721E6AC777459580551F5FC7A42F91"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a recommendation from the Commandant on whether to establish such a permanent program, and if so, a proposed program structure, staffing plan, and funding requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9C5B00596ADF4ABF9A05840CC0A67AA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Commandant shall make each report required under this section publicly available on a publicly accessible website of the Coast Guard.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4FED2A953B9B40FA932AB4177C93B6FE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Duration of pilot program</header> 
<subsection id="HD8983B29FCB4485A80762F21D6DF576D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The pilot program shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date on which the pilot program commences operations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6464104ECC634235B3F17FA793C6B1D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Commandant may extend the pilot program for a period of not more than 2 additional years if the Commandant determines, and notifies the committees specified in section 5 not later than 180 days before the termination date, that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC06A3EE059344E94BB38284B5621F03D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the pilot program has demonstrated sufficient effectiveness to warrant continuation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEACD5145329D499395D2B6AAF4DE5D48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>additional time is needed to collect data necessary to make a final determination on the establishment of a permanent program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8D26DD1E3B4D448D9B68DD58A544D4A6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Consultation with Department of Defense</header> 
<subsection id="H73A97E6D96F14E9CA03F484D1AB16791"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the pilot program, the Commandant shall—</text> <paragraph id="H144255B563284D02BEC4D572F629C254"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish formal consultation mechanisms with the Office of Corrosion Policy and Oversight of the Department of Defense to access technical expertise, standards, and program data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5122BE4B0C3A4950A69A59FD35C05DE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seek to leverage, to the maximum extent practicable, existing Department of Defense corrosion prevention and control tools, processes, and best practices; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7ACD7972BAAF4B8AA2F045529503E17B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>where appropriate, develop Coast Guard-specific adaptations of Department of Defense corrosion prevention and control standards and processes.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA6C84337000D4344A2B0C4AD48A3D09A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Navy CCAT consultation</header><text>The Commandant shall specifically seek to—</text> <paragraph id="H9A5C4CF94F4941799BC3C0CAA212CDDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a formal review of the structure, operations, and outcomes of the Navy’s Corrosion Control Assistance Team program prior to standing up the first Coast Guard Corrosion Control Assistance Team under this Act;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H171F73D18C134DF18DE06269928E7248"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wherever practicable, adopt Navy Corrosion Control Assistance Team operational procedures and technical standards that are applicable to Coast Guard assets; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8248DE894134E1F8613EFAB0410DE1D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a formal information sharing mechanism with the Navy Corrosion Control Assistance Team program to facilitate ongoing exchange of lessons learned and best practices.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H325A037C70204E59898F4058B1FD7E79"><enum>8.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives an implementation plan for the pilot program that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H1A647233D31C40CAB3FE6CC1CBB4E402"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of the Coast Guard districts or units to be served during the initial phase of the pilot program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB88367772F5B4A8EBEC7AA85D4F6DDB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a proposed schedule for commencing pilot program operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H620599B0742049FAB84348BAF8713247"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a framework for measuring and reporting pilot program outcomes, including specific performance metrics; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDE26C2AB77044694BE694D3C0E742ACC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of planned consultation activities with the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

