<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD988FD724F1A482FBFD8E40B949E051E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8429 IH: Baby Food Safety Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8429</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260422">April 22, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001223">Mr. Magaziner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001223">Mrs. Sykes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure the safety of food and limit the presence of contaminants in infant and toddler food, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F8B4650DED44C9A89D3D5EA621FAB4C" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H17E8A85D56044BC5B66BCC997BE52B70"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Baby Food Safety Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H92472A9A488D42C78A63BDA3C8C0F1DC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of infant or toddler food</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23BC7630449648B6B8072C6A169E6173"> 
<subsection id="HA9914CDDF08F406999C6943CD9BF81CF"><enum>(tt)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>infant or toddler food</term> means food that purports to be, or is represented as being, for infants or children up to the age of 24 months. Such term does not include infant formula.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H85DE64B0D7714D19AD439C791430D4A0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Contaminants in food, including infant or toddler food</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA220BDFD0EF45A59BBE84D94D39DB39"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter IV of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/341">21 U.S.C. 341 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H133FD12CFEDF4CC1A46C81A2CE1DEB7D"> 
<section id="H642160DF19D1456582D6BB986234A0B1"><enum>425.</enum><header>Contaminants in food, including infant or toddler food</header> 
<subsection id="HD4C33D8B6444407881B565B6527050E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administrative orders for contaminants, including toxic elements, in food</header> 
<paragraph id="HD188CDD3EF4248CD9986811AA5EF0144"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<subparagraph id="H26368E47F5DE4043A09BD53617BBFC66"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required limits</header><text>The Secretary, by administrative order, shall establish limits on the toxic elements of lead, cadmium, mercury, and arsenic (or a species of any such toxic element) in—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8410FF4323DB4BE19F96324E5A0F63A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any infant or toddler food; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBD7ACFBA632043D1807BC7D24F2637DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>food predominantly composed of a fruit or vegetable puree or juice.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9725831E90114AC48EA61E8EBDED24C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional limits</header><text>If the Secretary determines appropriate upon review of relevant health data and other relevant available information, the Secretary, by administrative order, may—</text> 
<clause id="H6D58B0B5F08142228928441547063688"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish limits for contaminants, including toxic elements, in infant or toddler food, in addition to the limits for toxic elements described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause> <clause id="HCDA5E565461F42FFAC7D3EB35B6762E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>establish limits for contaminants, including toxic elements, in food predominantly composed of a fruit or vegetable puree or juice, in addition to the limits for toxic elements described in subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF0C9A80A20E478D8C68B4F95FCB08CC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>In establishing or revising any limit under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H137129249B3F42C78C1E7145A7D08A39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate relevant health data and assessments, data from State and local health departments, and other information the Secretary considers relevant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF09D1C5E75F04A6B9A5CFD7571DE90A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take into account relevant differences among food types, groups, and categories, as appropriate, including the extent to which the use of such substances cannot be avoided in the production of the applicable food and its ingredients, based on an evaluation of alternative ingredients, use of best manufacturing and agricultural practices, and full compliance with section 418; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08668E7578D1490995BEE7668E50B8C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding the requirements of subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code—</text> 
<clause id="H4BCD2772DCE6405D9C30C08E8ACAB0B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>publish any administrative order under paragraph (1) in the Federal Register following—</text> <subclause id="H6F2C51599D92471F8C6800D5F6BA0B73"><enum>(I)</enum><text>publication of a proposed order in the Federal Register; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H80C90FE4AE5D443EB4D27271A297532E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>consideration of comments to a public docket open for not fewer than 45 calendar days; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5CBBACBBA9904270B157E7D42C575AFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>set forth in any proposed or final administrative order under paragraph (1) a substantive summary of the valid scientific evidence concerning the proposed or final limit.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H138847F0158B4ED19E8B626341704E68"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Changes to limits</header><text>If the Secretary determines appropriate after review of relevant data and assessments and other available and relevant health information, the Secretary may revise any limit established under this subsection by administrative order published in the Federal Register in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD2EA327A8324E92AD8C8B78EA0593AF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timeframe for initial limits</header> <subparagraph id="H53DBCA2EE5A041259A664F71DD53E5F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Proposed orders</header><text>Subject to the requirements of paragraph (2), the Secretary shall issue proposed orders for limits under paragraph (1)(A) as follows:</text> 
<clause id="H1423B4CF6AA448358D7F96798807FE1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>For lead, not later than December 31, 2026.</text></clause> <clause id="H7CF7A866C1A5485E912F88959D6FD81A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>For arsenic, not later than December 31, 2026.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAB7F5A8E64824C91AC4348AA63DEB10A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For cadmium, not later than April 30, 2027.</text></clause> <clause id="HBBA79D25EA1443128C6680F0FECDC80E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>For mercury, not later than April 30, 2029.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6D5BAE4196B84A708D7B66BD74C9E376"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final orders</header><text>The Secretary shall issue each final administrative order for a limit established pursuant to subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) not later than 18 months after issuance of the respective proposed order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2ACF95126AC440F980339092EE1C37B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The limits established under this section shall represent the level at which the contaminant may render the infant or toddler food injurious to health. In determining such limits the Secretary shall take into account the extent to which the use of such substance cannot be avoided in the production of each such food and its ingredients, based on an evaluation of alternative ingredients, use of best manufacturing and agricultural practices, and compliance with section 418.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H46A9AB64B94B4F2B815B019E44A8876C" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Adulterated food</header><text>A food may be determined adulterated, at the final product form, under section 402(j), if such food bears or contains any contaminant (including any toxic element) in excess of a limit established under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B8E3F02C0FC4787B6077DE1625453A0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text>The Secretary shall review, not less frequently than every 4 years, the limits established under this subsection, taking into consideration relevant information and available data to consider whether such limits should be revised, following the procedure described in paragraph (2), in accordance with the criteria specified in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H979F21F9686B4EE6B373F7180F67CD98"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sampling and testing for toxic elements and contaminants in food, including infant and toddler food</header> 
<paragraph id="HF2FBC9E297C3432482622B145B51DBA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Baby Food Safety Act of 2026</short-title>, the owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility engaged in manufacturing or processing infant or toddler food, food predominantly composed of a fruit or vegetable puree or juice, or such other food as the Secretary may specify by regulation, for consumption in the United States, shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H56223F1B467541FDBEEAD0E5157EA71E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have a control program in place for toxic elements and contaminants subject to limits under subsection (a)(1);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5871205FC8D74436B60028C341C3FBA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collect representative samples of each such food in final product form in accordance with a sampling plan described in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D5EA512F80A44A5B2364CAF41E62757"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct testing of the samples collected from the final food product for toxic elements and contaminants, in accordance with a sampling plan described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB7ECA218F0F4F728767E7851B47DE11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for sampling and testing plan</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6526B41991BC4F1CB5B0D9DC35A35738"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility described in paragraph (1) shall—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B7F8F58A5DA496E8B837317D2EA6DBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prepare a written plan for all sampling and testing required under this subsection; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3616BF8A81B497FBC536B924C475BFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that all sampling and testing conducted under this subsection is conducted in accordance with the plan described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBEDBC474844241E2B6E7F3FA00D29F66"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sampling plan</header><text>A sampling and testing plan required by subparagraph (A) shall identify—</text> 
<clause id="H663BFD8AACCC4B33A9D5AE96AEB97E63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of sampling units and sample unit size based upon appropriate criteria for identifying, in a representative fashion, the levels of toxic elements and contaminants in each food;</text></clause> <clause id="H479545F13B6943F58FFB10F32C3C181A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one or more appropriate test methods and procedures to be used to analyze the samples; and</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82B05CEF405D451BAD1AE145669E8335"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>appropriate testing frequencies not less frequently than every quarter and whenever a significant change in the product or process necessitates such testing.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDC97709EFC64C7F970B1068F497A420"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Baby Food Safety Act of 2026</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue guidance to assist facilities described under paragraph (1) with developing sampling and testing plans. Such guidance shall address the standards for adequate and appropriate sampling and testing of each toxic element and contaminant as required by the Secretary, the minimum frequency at which samples should be tested for toxic elements and contaminants or specific species of toxic elements or contaminants, and standards for compliance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A020034AFC0401087EAD51946679C10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contaminants to be tested</header><text>In carrying out the sampling and testing under this subsection, the owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility described in paragraph (1) shall ensure that each sample is tested for levels of—</text> <subparagraph id="H52C30BA0937D4AA48533257C29ADF9E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>lead, cadmium, mercury, and arsenic; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H638AB4A17F83457EAA5CF52AD21A2FDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other contaminant that the Secretary may specify, in accordance with the sampling plan under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5B2D6B50E2854605847F1E7CD4E3C62A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foods to be tested</header><text>The sampling and testing conducted under this subsection shall be conducted for—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H97C7BF6F76CB4806A0D734E6ECD3C9F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">infant and toddler foods, in final product form;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H76DFD6852D644E55B3B8FFB1A6881CE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">foods predominantly composed of a fruit or vegetable puree or juice; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H457BC90B6338461AB8F9259AC8C81F1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other foods in final product form as the Secretary has specified, as appropriate for the protection of public health.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1E26798135224E6C9449D37AB8AC6155"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header> <subparagraph id="H418C2009CBAC4E349CA667E3BF01B83F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility described in paragraph (1) shall maintain, for not less than 2 years or the shelf life of each food product manufactured or processed by the facility, whichever is longer, records documenting the sampling plan and results of testing conducted under this subsection with respect to the food. The owner, operator, or agent in charge of such a facility shall make such records available for inspection and copying by the Secretary upon request by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B13FCF373524A80A185AA9853D7CDF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The records maintained as required under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text> <clause id="H73D5CA8A795B4B5D98CFDFB12DC5D402"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a detailed description of the foods sampled and tested;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H76C9BC437E01458D8C3BEA7A2184C622"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of samples and tests performed;</text></clause> <clause id="H0602C2E6FB3F4223A127F191661199D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the size and number of items in each sample unit;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE2460034EC44535A461600EEC910E4A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a copy of the sampling plan required under paragraph (2);</text></clause> <clause id="HCCD688ABED3048C2809FD13C90AB09AF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>identification of the entity conducting the sampling;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H404FFD261B614E41B7EF352728AFB9FA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>identification of the entity conducting the testing;</text></clause> <clause id="HB7E56C4C3D5E4028B0A7BBA52A859D88"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>identification of the analytical methods used to perform the sampling and testing;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68C63C2ACF2D4E51B813AB6CE65E4D27"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>analytical findings of the sampling and testing; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CFBBC94B5D34989B1C11D031339E896"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other data and information as the Secretary may require.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53154730116F44F0A4B2EDACF87E7FB2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The requirements of this paragraph shall apply to all records of sampling and testing conducted pursuant to this subsection, regardless of the findings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H610EE2DBFEB340A5B4EACDC9DD553866"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Laboratory accreditation</header><text>The owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility described in paragraph (1) shall ensure that testing required pursuant to this subsection is performed in accordance with international standards by a laboratory that—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3C844C76EE274106842688AD5821AC92"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is in compliance with the requirements regarding laboratory accreditation described in section 422; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8AF34F8495D4F72A414CF8A2C53FCE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the requirements described in subparagraph (A) do not apply to the laboratory, is accredited by an accreditation body that conforms to international accreditation standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43142D1AEA34456B8787714019A084E2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sampling and testing program</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement a sampling and testing program for infant and toddler food that is sufficient to—</text> <subparagraph id="H8048579828E3473B981BB397A842CAFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support the periodic review under subsection (a)(7) of limits on toxic elements in infant and toddler food; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAE69E98A0E0345E88210C9EE9313A9C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>independently verify that products are compliant with the limits proscribed pursuant to this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5C4243929D5745ABA316017489EF203A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Record availability</header> <paragraph id="HD5DA0F6E66104C5883F35473A694F18D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon request by the Secretary, the owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility described in subsection (b)(1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0045E7D0C7C6404FB17911765239598E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make all records required under this section available promptly to the Secretary for inspection and copying; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA00B991D05FB44A1A3529C2C33B83737"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide within a reasonable time an English translation of such records maintained in a language other than English.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1DF0809E00C4B27950590BC02AA7C43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Record availability</header><text>Any records that the Secretary may inspect under this section shall, upon the request of the Secretary, be provided to the Secretary by the owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility described in subsection (b)(1), in advance of or in lieu of an inspection, within a reasonable timeframe, within reasonable limits, and in a reasonable manner, and in either electronic or physical form, at the expense of such owner, operator, or agent. The Secretary’s request shall include a sufficient description of the records requested.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0294CD0506B84D2DA8A5EDB8CF6E02EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confirmation</header><text>Upon receipt of records requested under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary shall provide to the owner, operator, or agent described in paragraph (2) confirmation of the receipt.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7022F65D588A40DD8A44C185B722D5EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authority of the Secretary</header><text>Nothing in this subsection supplants the authority of the Secretary to conduct sampling, testing, or inspections otherwise permitted under this Act in order to ensure compliance with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H876625B6535C4178A0F71F0F322F7F6A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Delayed applicability</header><text>The requirements for sampling and testing under this section shall apply beginning on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H10CE1FF95340483EA22D2E46516D7948"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Importer requirements</header><text>Section 805(c)(4) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/384a">21 U.S.C. 384a(c)(4)</external-xref>) is amended, by inserting <quote>monitoring and verifying the accuracy of records described in section 425(b)</quote> after <quote>for shipments,</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D88633B99194D8BAA57CA24B5373411"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enforcement</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E8E5912F3A94494A875088570A24349"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Adulteration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 402 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/342">21 U.S.C. 342</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H08A6FB3D682D40CD84DB6D2710D82605"> 
<subsection id="HD403D39382AA43348516A99201A5FC17"><enum>(j)</enum><text>If it is an article of food in final product form that is an infant and toddler food, a food predominantly composed of a fruit or vegetable puree or juice, or such other food as the Secretary may specify and—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA53ACB2078CF4DF9ABB327F239F070E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such food bears or contains any toxic element or contaminant in excess of a limit established under section 425(a); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78D8046242194E69A42EAC24D9EE8AC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility that manufactures or processes the food is not in compliance with subsection (b) or (c) of section 425.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A296C69BF764B69A17CCEDAA00929EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibited act</header><text>Section 301 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA9F1AC702A2A450896D1F24862F0265C"> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC21606AD18A04E2DBFC66E147B8D7941"><enum>(jjj)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The failure of an owner, operator, or agent in charge of a facility that manufactures or processes food to comply with applicable requirements under subsection (b) or (c) of section 425.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H7A2BBD5A8C034B649AB297554154C313"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation of food traceability plan; study on inspections; reporting on inspections</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2D2EDA8CAC144171BA18CCF06D36DEB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Implementation plan</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, in coordination with the FDA Human Foods Program and the Center for Food Safety and Applied Nutrition, shall finalize an implementation plan for the Food and Drug Administration to achieve its goal of compliance, not later than January 20, 2027, with the rule issued by the Food and Drug Administration titled, <quote>Requirements for Additional Traceability Records for Certain Foods</quote> (87 Fed. Reg. 70910 (November 21, 2022)) (or any successor rule). Such plan shall include a description of—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4BEC97B546E4B67986F1ACC7E49F52F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any resource needs of the Food and Drug Administration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF7B9DF30E154BFC966E0E6808626F68"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategies for facilitating compliance with the rule; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C90819262A946DC9A6EB41E7F8B8FCA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detailed plans for communicating with and educating regulated entities, non-Federal regulatory partners, and regulatory staff of the Food and Drug Administration about the requirements under the rule.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA99FCA0E6272402BBBAA4BC5C89FE45F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study on inspections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3E1B197A802E44BB91A9D6A62980B76C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a study to—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5C004FF9F76473083C334AA28606E19"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine the annual number of facility inspections that is sufficient to determine that imported foods are held to the same safety standards as domestic food; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67E5582696A242F395DA8EA7D703926A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify whether such inspection targets are consistent with the targets in the most recent annual report regarding food conducted under section 1003(h) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/393">21 U.S.C. 393(h)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70D717F53543414EBC3C75803E2753BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report to Congress on the findings of such study, and, if applicable, any factors preventing the Secretary from meeting its goal for the number of inspections and a plan to ensure that such goal is met in the next 2 years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9FA594EF8B54400D9E9A92CC53A08C95"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report regarding food</header><text>Section 1003(h)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/393">21 U.S.C. 393(h)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DAC0A27389C4D4A90ACE42D69422652"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3DF46C74D8E412D9213C6AD542F24BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (F), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA4B5EF839032485AAD33B4E1A1CC7D27"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEFB7FCA5841141BD8C19AB09E8A63EAF"> 
<subparagraph id="H6A730480206843C7A27E36B2D0982C3C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the nature of domestic facility and foreign facility inspections described in subparagraph (C), the aggregate inspection findings of such inspections, and the compliance rate of foreign food importers with certification standards;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H277DBFDF66694D328404EC43419F0D46"><enum>5.</enum><header>Records for or in lieu of certain inspections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 704(a)(4) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/374">21 U.S.C. 374(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDEB81815801B41E695605210A72C654F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (D) as subparagraphs (C) through (E), respectively;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BC7B6D5658F4934850913D12BB4BC07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7577E7C1BF4D49C19199E70F9C06AB3F"> 
<subparagraph id="HAA8F3BEBA81B4ABF9AEBBF1D0E39FD8C" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H3124697465164C9194519F227CEA0BF7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any records or other information that the Secretary may remotely inspect or copy under authority of this Act from a person that owns or operates, or is an agent in charge of, an establishment that is engaged in any of the activities described in clause (ii) shall, upon the request of the Secretary, be provided to the Secretary by such person, in advance of, at the time of, or in the case in which an in-person inspection would be unsafe, in lieu of, an in-person, on-site inspection, within a reasonable timeframe, within reasonable limits, and in a reasonable manner, and in either electronic or physical form, at the expense of such person. The Secretary’s request shall include a sufficient description of the records or other information requested.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="H8C0C4235655B49E38A5FBD6E902C0672"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The activities described in this clause are records relating to—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57606864870F47C1865460986D9D9180"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufacturing, processing, sampling, testing, packing, transporting, distributing, receiving, holding, or importing of an article of food; or</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0C19C049B124FEF94C5BA95BE6C04DB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the distribution or use of animal feed bearing or containing a veterinary feed directive drug, or the issuance of a veterinary feed directive.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB03F66BE48B04E6F97A0CC1C2A3AE51E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA74296922054897AB869C174E83ABF5"> <subparagraph id="H14AF404F2C0F4E51B935F1046943B04E" indent="up2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Section 703 does not apply to records obtained or copied, or other information obtained or copied pursuant to a request made under this section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H554B2AA5CE3F4F91A7E49FF5178582A9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Mandatory recall authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 423(a) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/350l">21 U.S.C. 350l(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>animals,</quote> the following: <quote>or that an article of food is adulterated under paragraph (a)(1) or (j) of section 402,</quote>.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

