<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD0B942CCF8794D19A12197FB93AF177E" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1125 IH: Recognizing the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, commending a month of fasting and spiritual renewal, and extending best wishes to Muslims in the United States and across the globe for a joyous and meaningful observance of Eid al-Fitr.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1125</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260319">March 19, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001232">Mrs. McClain Delaney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001231">Ms. Simon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the Muslim holy month of Ramadan, commending a month of fasting and spiritual renewal, and extending best wishes to Muslims in the United States and across the globe for a joyous and meaningful observance of Eid al-Fitr.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Ramadan is the holy month of fasting and spiritual renewal for Muslims worldwide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas this month of sacrifice and contemplation began on February 17, 2026, based on the visual sightings of the crescent moon;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Muslims in the United States and around the world observe Ramadan by fasting, emphasizing self-discipline, worship, charity, and reading the Holy Quran to improve patience, humility, and spirituality;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Ramadan continued until the celebration of Eid al-Fitr;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas Eid al-Fitr begins each year with the sighting of the new moon, signifying a month-long end to fasting and reflection for all Muslim followers;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that there are approximately 2,000,000,000 Muslims worldwide;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas over 5,896 Muslims serve on active duty and over 2,300 Muslims serve as selected reserve personnel in the United States Armed Forces;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas there are over 200 elected officials who identify as Muslim;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that there are 2,200,000 Muslim voters in the United States;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Muslim population has been growing in the United States and today’s American Muslim population is a tapestry of ethnic, racial, linguistic, social, and economic groups;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas American Muslims have contributed to every part of society to make advancements in medicine, science, engineering, economics, sports, education, and the law; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the observance of the Muslim holy month of Ramadan has concluded with Eid al-Fitr, a 3-day celebration: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HE2F6ADDBE228467F927DDA681C248EFB"> 
<section id="H3232531AC57C4C09A9358C1136836B40" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H0E470710DCA04411933DFB37DC8374A8"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>demonstrates solidarity with and support for members of the community of Islam in the United States and throughout the world;</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBB7C94260A545AD917DA962398A112D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of the Islamic faith;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF21662763A747628DB0CBE93CBC9AA7"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text>observes, out of respect for Ramadan tradition, the Muslim holy month of fasting and spiritual renewal; and</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9830B812B2ED451EB4A90E92B0F5AEE0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>offers its best wishes to all Muslims celebrating Eid al-Fitr, the conclusion of Ramadan, while also expressing its deepest respect to Muslims in the United States and worldwide on this important occasion.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

