<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3F96126C83824E13ADB34AB053C9A7F7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6859 IH: Honest Oversight of Ticketed Dining and Onsite Grub Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000598">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to conduct a study on certain concession pricing practices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA70009544E4A475C9689F56328A2DE5C" style="OLC"><section id="HA658A93E5D864939B24D45DD925482A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may cited as the <quote><short-title>Honest Oversight of Ticketed Dining and Onsite Grub Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HOTDOG Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4A5FD16B79E3421CBA9B71264037DC10"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HCDFAE05E310A48DDABD8A398849B5E5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Many sports venues receive significant public investments through direct grants, State and local tax credits, economic development incentives, and tax-exempt bonds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04F7D81A966A42F7AE6E29756688B737"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2025, the cost of concessions at major sporting events and concerts are unaffordable for the average American family.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98D8B9DA7B7043D9BE3464A822115A41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>At Madison Square Garden, the average price of a beer is $16, more than twice the average in New York City, making it the third most expensive among NBA arenas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE3A97DDCB8C440292F4761A318B8152"><enum>(4)</enum><text>At Highmark Stadium, home of the Buffalo Bills, beer costs $10 on average, which is double the price fans would pay at a nearby bar across the street.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E67A4F516BD40DD86C9CD87F8CD49A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Fans across music concerts and professional sports, including the National Basketball Association, National Football League, National Hockey League, and Major League Baseball, face exorbitant concession prices in addition to already high-ticket costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD4C833221964F9CAA027964479E66A6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Street pricing, a model that aligns concession pricing inside a venue with prices for comparable items in surrounding communities, has been adopted by certain venues to make concessions more affordable, producing benefits for both businesses and consumers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2B8579FE16745DF97BE029E5C5C02A9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Fans and travelers attending events at venues supported by their tax dollars deserve clear, transparent, and fair pricing of food and beverage concessions.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H47DAB227C02D47CC8261E043D55A258A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on concession pricing practices</header><subsection id="HC2CF28144FCD478FAFFCFB10EA84BE39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall conduct a study with respect to concession pricing practices at a nationwide sample of covered venues that includes information relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="H9DC251BAF0734B17A5B2711CE8E241FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The price of food and drink items offered for sale by such venues.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H990800C1797C451E80FA1F22EF383D36" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A comparison between such prices and the price of the same or similar food and drink items offered for sale by the communities surrounding such venues, including bars and restaurants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5BF14586F24C6B805F4087CB34126E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Pricing practices at such venues, including the use of any of the following by such venues:</text><subparagraph id="H923429E546424BECB3D551B0072ACA1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Dynamic pricing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8679796469384590924A4158792F57AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Service fees.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26B2BFB0BCBF4F91A39C292113040165"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Promotions such as value deals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DCEC41DCA234A5D8A22AA5DFD5F34E5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The extent to which such venues disclose the price of food and drink items offered for sale by such venues prior to purchase, including by listing such prices online and disclosing such prices at the point of entry of such venues.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H159A4422E0AF41B8BAB516BF62C158A3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Consumer-friendly pricing policies that balance consumer access to affordable food and drink items with the cost of venue operations, including price caps on the price of such food and drink items and menu options for such food and drink items offered at a reduced price.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7450675ADB04692A4B7C4FDE0F6A3CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission shall submit to Congress a report that includes information relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="HF7ACAF4CBA074047858F567404F5BC19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D0955BF0D4F4115A67FC1B65E44F2F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for legislative, regulatory, and industry action with respect to improving affordability and transparency with respect to concession pricing practices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA54C78694F9348769F3E103A0F22DF91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5FEB5CDB3B5742D58C78B44CB9F5F592"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23225DAED20046758708D17572EDB844"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered venue</header><text>The term <quote>covered venue</quote> means a stadium or arena that—</text><subparagraph id="H53FCEFD33DBD43CFB0151E4B52952A31"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is used for a professional sports exhibition or game, a music concert, or any other comparable event (as determined by the Commission) for at least 5 days per year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35E5D96A686747C2B2B9416A6CEF6184" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was constructed or operated with funds from a public subsidy, including funds from a direct grant, a State or local tax credit, an economic development incentive, or a tax-exempt bond;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H025513D68A154014A31EE7B25E55FCB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requires ticketed entry for consumers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE16DEEA72484D27B091B5C9E5922C64"><enum>(D)</enum><text>offers food and drink items for sale to such consumers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D23FBF6715545898C046307D4A208AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

