<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD67C784753F54E4D9777A1252535190A" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-concurrent" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HCON 76 IH: Recognizing the visionary leadership of Chief Richard LaMunyon and the profound global impact of the Law Enforcement Torch Run for Special Olympics.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. CON. RES. 76</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</sponsor> submitted the following concurrent resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>CONCURRENT RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the visionary leadership of Chief Richard LaMunyon and the profound global impact of the Law Enforcement Torch Run for Special Olympics.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, in 1979, Wichita, Kansas, Police Chief Richard LaMunyon was invited to the Special Olympics Kansas State Summer Games;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chief LaMunyon witnessed firsthand the unique bond between athletes and law enforcement officers, having been moved by the <quote>tears of joy</quote> and excitement of a young athlete while presenting her with a medal;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas this interaction served as the <quote>spark</quote> for Chief LaMunyon to commit his department to supporting Special Olympics Kansas (SOKS);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chief LaMunyon sought to eliminate the financial burden on athletes and their families, who at the time were required to pay for dinner dance banquets;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in June 1981, Chief LaMunyon and his officers launched the first <quote>Flame of Hope</quote> run from Wichita City Hall to South High School, raising approximately $300 in its inaugural year;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Chief LaMunyon collaborated with Eunice Kennedy Shriver, the founder of Special Olympics, to ensure the athletes remained at the forefront of the mission;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, after witnessing the <quote>loud roar of support</quote> and positive interactions between hundreds of officers and athletes at the Kansas Summer Games, Eunice Kennedy Shriver gave her official blessing for what is now known as the Law Enforcement Torch Run (LETR);</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the LETR has grown from a local initiative in Wichita to the largest grassroots movement supporting Special Olympics worldwide;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the movement now spans all 50 States, all provinces of Canada, and over 25 other countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 150,000 law enforcement officers participate in LETR events annually; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since its inception in 1981, the movement has raised a total of $1,139,597,747 to support individuals with intellectual disabilities: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0F9CF9CC87054735934F59AE09B88A61"><section id="HE3BEEDD69CD446319067F7B8DE2FCB41" section-type="undesignated-section" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That Congress—</text><paragraph id="HC3CA59E871B343BBA0ABEC3F69270352"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Chief Richard LaMunyon for his visionary leadership in founding the Law Enforcement Torch Run;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD958B40E2E24645B8E9670489CE1E25"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends the 150,000 law enforcement officers who continue to carry the <quote>Flame of Hope</quote> and foster community inclusion; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DC121D4BF4B488D9312D7EFCBDDFAC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">celebrates the <quote>roaring flame of stability</quote> that the Law Enforcement Torch Run provides to the Special Olympics movement worldwide.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

