<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-HLA26139-HWJ-25-664"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 618 ATS: Recognizing the importance of career and technical education (“CTE”) educators and work-based learning coordinators in delivering high-quality CTE, preparing students for success in the workplace, the classroom, and in life, and supporting dynamic workforce pipelines that enable the United States to grow and lead in critical economic sectors. </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 618</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260226">February 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S384">Mr. Tillis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S354">Ms. Baldwin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S390">Mr. Van Hollen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S417">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S437">Mr. Justice</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing the importance of career and technical education (“CTE”) educators and work-based learning coordinators in delivering high-quality CTE, preparing students for success in the workplace, the classroom, and in life, and supporting dynamic workforce pipelines that enable the United States to grow and lead in critical economic sectors. </official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas students in classrooms across the United States today are the future leaders, innovators, and workers of tomorrow, and the future of American competitiveness and economic stability is predicated on a robust workforce prepared to meet the needs of critical sectors;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas career and technical education (<quote>CTE</quote>) educators work with secondary and post-secondary students—</text><paragraph id="id6e87cc3ce5b14576bb02725b8c111afc"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to explore career pathways; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5715129857c94002a881208b653e5b9f"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to teach academic, technical, and practical, sector-specific, hands-on skills across a wide-range of in-demand industries and occupations; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82dc6e379b604a5ba86001f6dfc299f8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop skills necessary for rewarding employment and success in life;</text></paragraph></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas work-based learning coordinators help build a bridge for students between the classroom and real workplace experience by collaborating with education systems, CTE programs, and industry partners to facilitate meaningful, age-appropriate work-based learning experiences for students that include internships, apprenticeships, and job shadowing;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas there are CTE programs in every State and territory, and there are approximately 12,000,000 students enrolled in CTE programs across the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the high school graduation rate for CTE concentrators is 97 percent, which is above the national average, and these students are more likely than others to be employed full time and have higher median annual earnings 8 years after graduation;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas without CTE educators providing support, instruction, and industry knowledge, and without the support of work-based learning coordinators, students would not be able to participate in and enjoy the benefits of CTE programs;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas student participation and interest in CTE programs remains consistent, yet there are persistent shortages of CTE educators, with school administrators reporting difficulty filling positions in CTE subjects 57 percent of the time, and retaining CTE educators in high-growth fields is challenging;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the 2025–2026 academic year, 25 States, the District of Columbia, and American Samoa reported CTE educator shortages;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 79 percent of high school students expressed an interest in work-based learning experiences, yet only 34 percent of high school students reported being aware of opportunities within their age group;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas work-based learning coordinators could help increase awareness of CTE programs among high school student and increase access to such opportunities; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the month of February is recognized as Career and Technical Education Month to celebrate the value, importance, and accomplishments of CTE programs, and there is no CTE without CTE educators: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id665871b7b04e4f2d89533c2f1ccdca7e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4eae43a63643423699e840a76154a89a"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the importance of career and technical education (<quote>CTE</quote>) educators and work-based learning coordinators in delivering high-quality CTE, preparing students for success in the workplace, the classroom, and in life, and supporting dynamic workforce pipelines that enable the United States to grow and lead in critical economic sectors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69a3ecfa9c0c47a2892f6fa0a429ee42"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that all students should have access to quality CTE and work-based learning opportunities that will help them succeed in the classroom, in the workplace, and throughout their lives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3107338467d4a4094349eb55a9ea643"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that the quality of CTE instruction depends upon the quality, preparedness, and availability of CTE educators and work-based learning coordinators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idce271c7715644d748fc071393f04e158"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that CTE educators, work-based learning coordinators, and educators of all academic subjects, deserve competitive wages, good employment benefits, and safe working conditions; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67b8b643f7fd4a21bd79ffaeaf22919f"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that improving the salaries, benefits, and working conditions of educators would help reduce persistent educator shortages; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc449b2651b8249a9a4f67e87af4548af"><enum>(2)</enum><text>commends CTE educators and work-based learning coordinators for their contributions and dedication.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

