<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H464887F2D80844DFB1FD28AB42EB4BD2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6268 IH: Lead Endangers Animals Daily Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6268</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Interior to prohibit the use of lead ammunition on United States Fish and Wildlife Service lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H45E98A10D84F4007A9DD4E0642160591" style="OLC"><section id="H57C8C689CA1B468EB47832CA27D0C9A5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lead Endangers Animals Daily Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LEAD Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAE609423B3EC444798E8CAB4D0351D09"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H2D2C9D61DEC64EECBBA191681F6D7C6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1991, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service required the use of nontoxic ammunition for all waterfowl hunting.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA5081DDF4CF4C5C80FB294C0EBDBE27"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research has shown that the presence of lead in the environment poses a threat to human and wildlife health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7210460427CD4778BC3DC582F869FD16"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Environmental Protection Agency has determined that lead is toxic to both humans and animals, and can negatively affect nearly every organ and system in the human body, including the heart, bones, intestines, kidneys, and reproductive and nervous systems. Lead exposure interferes with the development of the nervous system and is therefore particularly toxic to children, causing potentially permanent learning and behavioral disorders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB94D9FFA78384D06A3787E5E60D92FE3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lead is a potent neurotoxin, for which no safe exposure level exists for humans. The use of lead has been outlawed in and removed from paint, gasoline, children’s toys, and many other items to protect human health and wildlife.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA76085E8334F0C80A2862D52ECBF86"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wildlife, including federally listed threatened and endangered species, is at risk of lead toxicosis through the ingestion of lead ammunition, either directly by ingesting lead from spent ballistic materials while foraging, or indirectly by scavenging carcasses and viscera left by hunters. Lead may also pollute soil and water around outdoor shooting ranges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD62A0283DA45C99BBA5D2B54E95F78"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lead ammunition also endangers human food supplies. Dairy and beef cattle have developed lead poisoning after feeding in areas where spent lead ammunition has accumulated. Spent lead ammunition can also contaminate crops, vegetation, and waterways.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD316D1E77F4C402C882F4C346E0BFEDA"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Humans are at risk of lead toxicosis through the consumption of game meat harvested with lead ammunition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90DF8E02E8E64B5CA2D5E8EA9DE6E89C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alternatives to lead ammunition are readily available, and studies have shown that nonlead ammunition performs just as well as lead-based ammunition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E118C153D584CB4B6F566DC30118B99"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In January 2017, the outgoing Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service issued Director’s Order 219. In March 2017, the Principal Deputy Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service repealed this Order.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H28FCAEFBD9DD47AAB1CD435E16635F42"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nontoxic ammunition</header><subsection id="H61AC4115F2114EE2A17AF0230D83351E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), and not later than 1 year after enactment, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall issue final regulations prohibiting the discharge of any firearm using ammunition other than nonlead ammunition certified under subsection (b) on all lands and waters under the jurisdiction and control of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></subsection><subsection id="H93D14D03C0514902B0DF1B2DE29B32A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall, for the purposes of enforcing this section and in consultation with State and Tribal governments, establish and annually update a list of nonlead ammunition.</text></subsection><subsection id="H64E96F542E5642229F1795287C12C2F5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply to—</text><paragraph id="HF9590663191B4E9ABD2D900D622ACF3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Government official or agent carrying out a statutory duty unrelated to the management of wildlife;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B4CBA1BAC9249D0814AE8DEEE6CE145"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State, local, Tribal, or Federal law enforcement officer or the agent of such officer when carrying out a statutory duty; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAC1F3EBF57E4154975310A02414ECA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an active member of the United States military when carrying out official duties.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5444F5834698460FBAA902A78EE61985"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that knowingly violates subsection (a) may be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary of no more than $500 for the first violation. A second or subsequent violation shall be punishable by a fine of not less than $1,000 or more than $5,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBD0144EF16CE49C7B2E2CF61D1EDF08B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H6C004C80C1674787B0A9E31667C25B27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ammunition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>ammunition</term> means any bullet, ball, sabot, slug, buckshot, shot, pellet, or other projectile that is expelled from a firearm through a barrel by force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H723F92EEE670400EA03C95529CFAE4DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEC353163D0D4F7392BF68808F484900"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Explosive</header><text>The term <term>explosive</term> has the meaning given such term in section 844 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33E8E8D8F11C461580021BAC25BC84E0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text>The term <term>firearm</term> means any weapon which expels ammunition by the action of an explosive or compressed air.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE2CFB909648458B981AF6114D6C779F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nonlead ammunition</header><text>The term <term>nonlead ammunition</term> means ammunition in which there is no lead content, excluding the presence of trace amounts of lead.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BE1DA8157EA4237A2805438CC0A204E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69B10F59E15E4C90A999A499876A8A91"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Trace amounts</header><text>The term <term>trace amounts</term> means one percent or less by weight of the total weight of the ammunition.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

