<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H295C5490DDFC4123A3DD0EA5934401C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7271 IH: Evan Anzoo Memorial Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7271</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260127">January 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000400">Ms. Kamlager-Dove</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001238">Ms. McBride</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000176">Mr. Olszewski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000606">Mr. Latimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General to submit a report on the effects of the United States Agency for International Development stop work order, the discontinuation of USAID services, and the shuttering of USAID, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDCB88588C5AB46D683A0E1312F8157A5" style="OLC"><section id="H63831847F2B84F5BBDA7783B7562AE60" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Evan Anzoo Memorial Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H701566B186384685A5AF5F81385047F1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H9D19438FFCF547EE9446318DCCD8B2EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and make available on a public website, a report on the following:</text><paragraph id="HF920DCD88BE84CA5B80BC83F1FD6B252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An estimate of the number of deaths in 2025 due to the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) stop work order, discontinuation of USAID services, and shuttering of USAID.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BE4B74888D24F109081D2AEA0F269B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate of the number of anticipated future deaths over 5 years from the initial USAID stop work order, the discontinuation of USAID services, and shuttering of USAID due to the lack of access to services that USAID previously provided.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D67A1DCE36742DB943E19C04205E208"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination whether any of the following individuals died as a result of the initial USAID stop work order, the discontinuation of USAID services, or the shuttering of USAID:</text><subparagraph id="H5E8C757DE5144AF196855561E69E1DF0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evan Anzoo, 5, South Sudan, died after losing access to USAID-provided HIV/AIDs treatment.</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0B67DB4FFDF4671B30EB4C764D6DF34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Pe Kau Lau, 71, Thailand, died after losing access to USAID-provided oxygen supply.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FF9BB0C7CE24C74801E7EE61A2C176F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Jibia Tusifu, 10, Democratic Republic of Congo, died after losing access to USAID-provided malaria treatments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFD8850FFF2046F28A02F19729DD38C6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Daniella Kalenga, 8, Uganda, died after losing access to USAID-provided malaria treatments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A42C08119364E588A3100657F988519"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Suza Kenyaba, 5, Democratic Republic of Congo, died after losing access to USAID-provided malaria treatments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H408EFE2B55F84EFB99EB58A32FB69743"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Peter Donde, 10, South Sudan, died after losing access to USAID-provided HIV/AIDs treatment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7CDF1000A864B17BB06226A33DD1A49"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Achol Deng, 8, South Sudan, died after losing access to USAID-provided HIV/AIDs treatment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6137FB73F6CC45ED8E5DD22DE101873F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Gilbert Kayombo, 7, Democratic Republic of Congo, died after losing access to USAID-provided HIV/AIDs treatment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC3CEBB333974F54B5B709ABDD923AA1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Martha Juan, 25, South Sudan, died after losing access to USAID-provided antiretroviral drugs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84D9C756376E4CE3A60427FD629F8CBA"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Viola Kiden, 28, South Sudan, died after losing access to USAID-provided antiretroviral drugs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F7BBFCD0D4645A9A4BC46A2A9912563"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of the names of any other known individuals determined to have died as a result of initial USAID stop work order, the discontinuation of USAID services, or the shuttering of USAID.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCCE5123C26A84934A69C82352F7BB8A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interim update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall update the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate on the findings, as of the date of such update, of the Comptroller General with respect to the matters described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

