<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26048-LYY-4M-K9F"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S921 RS: Tyler’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 307</calendar><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 921</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20250310">March 10, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S429">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S413">Mr. Padilla</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S327">Mr. Warner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S391">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S419">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S426">Mr. Kim</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S412">Mr. Tuberville</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20260128">January 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S373">Mr. Cassidy</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue guidance on whether hospital emergency departments should implement fentanyl testing as a routine procedure for patients experiencing an overdose, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HD18158DB54E64D998F3D01E91BF6E2DF"><section section-type="section-one" id="H317CCC1C3FFE468B9DB056141A1C62F8" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Tyler’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7F7221D053DC48DA9B394D851218C4B4" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Testing for fentanyl in hospital emergency departments</header><subsection id="HF449514262EC4204B148EBDE03AE5682"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall complete a study to determine—</text><paragraph id="H25274B207E5D4F388463F2E50A01B31E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how frequently hospital emergency departments test for fentanyl (in addition to testing for other substances such as amphetamines, phencyclidine, cocaine, opiates, and marijuana) when a patient is experiencing an overdose;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE62081BEE1474623AF89E668300219B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the costs associated with such testing for fentanyl;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71C4396CD01745F5887DCEB11846A4A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the potential benefits and risks for patients receiving such testing for fentanyl; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0358402EB66E4846B76C46868FEB54D4"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how fentanyl testing in hospital emergency departments may impact the experience of the patient, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF55A01B3F87B4235A4B8B362A4DB7BC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protections for the confidentiality and privacy of the patient’s personal health information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB6380F3660A42A38E5FAFED8D43F731"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the patient-physician relationship.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE0735F6FEFDC428A9081DF3AD2D3F260"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 6 months after completion of the study under subsection (a), based on the results of such study, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue guidance on the following:</text><paragraph id="HE61B375700A14A31AB9E30199529CE37"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whether hospital emergency departments should implement fentanyl testing as a routine procedure for patients experiencing an overdose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AF1CC0CE41F4A1FA2BA9AEA63107E09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>How hospitals can ensure that clinicians in their hospital emergency departments are aware of which substances are being tested for in their routinely-administered drug tests, regardless of whether those tests screen for fentanyl.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FF47772AC9946A99983BB601E65EAC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How the administration of fentanyl testing in hospital emergency departments may affect the future risk of overdose and general health outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA346670E0CA44B496B685604B34E4F7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>hospital emergency department</term> means a hospital emergency department as such term is used in section 1867(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395dd">42 U.S.C. 1395dd(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="id08865628-df6b-428f-b10b-53620ce414cf" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Tyler’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idc3e80f2b8e9f4dc3bd7ebfdaa675c354" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSHR00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Testing for fentanyl in hospital emergency departments</header><subsection id="id38946a5889244ec192269ff6aff9a735"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and in coordination with other Federal departments, agencies, or stakeholders, as appropriate, shall complete a study to determine—</text><paragraph id="id86e45f83723842df8bbcbc330c8938c5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how frequently hospital emergency departments test for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances when a patient is experiencing an overdose, and test for other controlled substances related to such an overdose;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide2b9fcee7b9d446984c2f41f5ee62d86"><enum>(2)</enum><text>scenarios in which hospital emergency departments do not administer tests for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances when a patient is experiencing an overdose, or for other controlled substances related to such an overdose;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id63eca4cff2d746c1aa25b2e10cb600f3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the costs associated with such testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd4cc1ae891640bca271f5dfe5a6e4d3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the potential benefits and risks for patients receiving such testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide19df445e077495db8ae75c7335e21d3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>potential staff training needs to support testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida9f7b7bcb1f5422da0164014c1ae8de0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>how testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances in hospital emergency departments may impact the experience of the patient, including—</text><subparagraph id="id8d87b228329a40a68dba1987ba898a16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protections for the privacy and security of the patient’s protected health information (as defined in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations)) under part 160 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, and subparts C and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2d6204086cbd43dbb444226414971eac"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the patient-health care professional relationship; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5acbea8614fd40a8b13727894f92cc2d"><enum>(7)</enum><text>barriers that hospital emergency departments may encounter when trying to implement testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances and recommendations on how best to address those barriers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6654b5d964d04b1d85a544eddecefc77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 9 months after completion of the study under subsection (a), based on the results of such study, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and in coordination with other Federal departments, agencies, or stakeholders, as appropriate, shall issue guidance on the following:</text><paragraph id="id1e94020dbfa748b083398e8062afa0b5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whether hospital emergency departments should implement testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances as a routine procedure for patients experiencing an overdose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf94105b350494959bda69d0ef5f5539c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>How hospitals can ensure that health care professionals in their hospital emergency departments are aware of which substances are being tested for in their routinely-administered drug tests, regardless of whether those tests screen for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd5d21cd03023492db0af427d5159b2cd"><enum>(3)</enum><text>How the administration of testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances in hospital emergency departments may affect the future risk of overdose and health outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idec3b0ee91c424517a30be4fc1060118b"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Available Federal resources that can assist hospital emergency departments in implementing testing for fentanyl or fentanyl-related substances.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided2a1d5596054c29ad894f800585fee0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>hospital emergency department</term> means an emergency department of a hospital or an independent freestanding emergency department (as such terms are defined in section 2799A–1(a)(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-111">42 U.S.C. 300gg–111(a)(3)</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>January 28, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

