<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-OLL25A01-PCG-J2-D0J"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 S3482 IS: First Step Implementation Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3482</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251215">December 15, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To reform sentencing laws and correctional institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H92DE5D2E86634857957F0B3862A6CF71"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="id47605A5E9B674B9581440F4E1FB4912F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Step Implementation Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="idD35FE2F44E5040759975EAAD915295D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="S1">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id85c31253ece544f1a97e9838f4ac31f9">TITLE I—Sentencing reform</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idbd1a78e27b4247b1a110d65d122e2fff">Sec. 101. Application of First Step Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ide3ab6ddc27a24a4aa17c2b01006ccd56">Sec. 102. Modifying safety valve for drug offenses.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="id2106D10F0EAF4957AEB9AC094CDAA596">TITLE II—Corrections Reform</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="idad8acf425d9b47cfbb4206979935e0b5">Sec. 201. Parole for juveniles.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="ida0140e3c7e3d4a8fa8cdd3795f4948c7">Sec. 202. Juvenile sealing and expungement.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="id449a12e740944b0584b20cab1aa7899d">Sec. 203. Ensuring accuracy of Federal criminal records.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="id85c31253ece544f1a97e9838f4ac31f9"><enum>I</enum><header>Sentencing reform</header><section id="idbd1a78e27b4247b1a110d65d122e2fff"><enum>101.</enum><header>Application of First Step Act</header><subsection id="id1c0aae45ab1544c39c3e27744da516af"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="id6D3D3E850A484932A11A87459B5F4F5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered offense</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idD80B90C27638407F972D95953D63B1D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a violation of a Federal criminal statute, the statutory penalties for which were modified by section 401 or 403 of the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5220), that was committed on or before December 21, 2018; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0FB5F3D9ECD4454EB2D0812EA57BA58B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a violation of a Federal criminal statute, the statutory penalties for which are modified by subsection (b) of this section; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5659D8EF13E34112A861BF7A00F37C16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>serious violent felony</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9ACBA5E937FA4373B7D71FD5EB0A69B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments</header><paragraph id="id44DDDBA8F4174C21B8D4933D3A72FBAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="idB262CA0720144CFBAD6A826A9E97D0AA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act</header><text>Section 401(b) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="id51B9550C11FB48DA80BDE969737CC820"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="id540A25CD03054024B0C1C34BD9958B8B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>felony drug offense</quote> and inserting <quote>serious drug felony or serious violent felony</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="id54620679240B45AEBCBC91EABC41FC99"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>felony drug offense</quote> and inserting <quote>serious drug felony or serious violent felony</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id04D1BE15F5B94BB4B4997ECD36614DD9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)(ii), by striking <quote>felony drug offense</quote> and inserting <quote>serious drug felony or serious violent felony</quote>;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="idF5BF88F9F2F44C31964B0E45412CEF55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>felony drug offense</quote> and inserting <quote>serious drug felony or serious violent felony</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="id2C96CD9D815B48D29E6C39271C439F48"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>felony drug offense</quote> and inserting <quote>serious drug felony or serious violent felony</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9E01844402C84D9EBD96AF59A5F9E724"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Import and Export Act</header><text>Section 1010(b)(3) of the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/960">21 U.S.C. 960(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>felony drug offense</quote> and inserting <quote>serious drug felony or serious violent felony</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idE572C52EEA6C4B8C82F54449240B11D0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pending cases</header><text>This subsection, and the amendments made by this subsection, shall apply to any sentence imposed on or after the date of enactment of this Act, regardless of when the offense was committed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idff41b755d1904ce7a2975712308c29c7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Defendants previously sentenced</header><text>A court that imposed a sentence for a covered offense may, on motion of the defendant, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, the attorney for the Government, or the court, impose a reduced sentence as if sections 401 and 403 of the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5220) and the amendments made by subsection (b) of this section were in effect at the time the covered offense was committed if, after considering the factors set forth in section 3553(a) of title 18, United States Code, the nature and seriousness of the danger to any person, the community, or any crime victims, and the post-sentencing conduct of the defendant, the sentencing court finds a reduction is consistent with the amendments made by section 401 or 403 of the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5220) or with the amendments made by subsection (b) of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="id9259f54b0c7345bfbbf6d8c50add846b"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Crime victims</header><text>Any proceeding under this section shall be subject to section 3771 of title 18, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Crime Victims' Rights Act</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="ida316644b4735441fa3b9bd04736285c7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>For each motion filed under subsection (c), the Government shall conduct a particularized inquiry of the facts and circumstances of the original sentencing of the defendant in order to assess whether a reduction in sentence would be consistent with the First Step Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/391">Public Law 115–391</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5194) and the amendments made by that Act, including a review of any prior criminal conduct or any other relevant information from Federal, State, and local authorities.</text></subsection></section><section id="ide3ab6ddc27a24a4aa17c2b01006ccd56"><enum>102.</enum><header>Modifying safety valve for drug offenses</header><subsection id="id20c558f2b1ae4fa6b542bebff51e5e45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>Section 3553 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id73B878682D7E47799FAC0F01A61CF88D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB0B5875CEF9A41E499675DD79B5849C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9152766dbfc74acc8e4b48c8abd63efa"><subsection id="idde92694d10c74496873ce9eed0845ee2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Inadequacy of criminal history</header><paragraph id="id2f81af82eb874b07813b6be43b456d73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If subsection (f) does not apply to a defendant because the defendant does not meet the requirements described in subsection (f)(1) (relating to criminal history), the court may, upon prior notice to the Government, waive subsection (f)(1) if the court specifies in writing the specific reasons why reliable information indicates that excluding the defendant pursuant to subsection (f)(1) substantially overrepresents the seriousness of the defendant’s criminal history or the likelihood that the defendant will commit other crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id057f6b2c011d4de1b7496850d5e13e8a"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to any defendant who has been convicted of a serious drug felony or a serious violent felony, as those terms are defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="id2106D10F0EAF4957AEB9AC094CDAA596" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Corrections Reform</header><section id="idad8acf425d9b47cfbb4206979935e0b5"><enum>201.</enum><header>Parole for juveniles</header><subsection id="id43ee9c44b843436d902ee5e5cbb9ec53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">Chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/5032">section 5032</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id958ebd8127dc45dc9249324757e4cf27"><section id="idb5588e114c0e48f88e42ebed3db27383"><enum>5032A.</enum><header>Modification of an imposed term of imprisonment for violations of law committed prior to age 18</header><subsection id="id5a941c9dd9b945e48ef5a71660683898"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a court may reduce a term of imprisonment imposed upon a defendant convicted as an adult for an offense committed and completed before the defendant attained 18 years of age if—</text><paragraph id="id419699d343c2409a83d4afe8d815bbd6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant has served not less than 20 years in custody for the offense; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6e490bc3e314c7f9e877793eaad159b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the court finds, after considering the factors set forth in subsection (c), that the defendant is not a danger to the safety of any person or the community and that the interests of justice warrant a sentence modification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id135a7c3aa12044a1b2a91257abc065d2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Supervised release</header><text>Any defendant whose sentence is reduced pursuant to subsection (a) shall be ordered to serve a period of supervised release of not less than 5 years following release from imprisonment. The conditions of supervised release and any modification or revocation of the term of supervise release shall be in accordance with section 3583.</text></subsection><subsection id="id64336cec23ad4767bbd8bba29e8c7f03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Factors and information To be considered in determining whether To modify a term of imprisonment</header><text>The court, in determining whether to reduce a term of imprisonment pursuant to subsection (a), shall consider—</text><paragraph id="id7dc4086bddf54a46a49ee96d281e0d50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the factors described in section 3553(a), including the nature of the offense and the history and characteristics of the defendant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9733bcb3d1a24d029548a40fe87e7881"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the age of the defendant at the time of the offense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id59df7fbdfe3d475dae85827825e7f408"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a report and recommendation of the Bureau of Prisons, including information on whether the defendant has substantially complied with the rules of each institution in which the defendant has been confined and whether the defendant has completed any educational, vocational, or other prison program, where available;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id46bcef0e94034376bd0937eefc1c5a21"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a report and recommendation of the United States attorney for any district in which an offense for which the defendant is imprisoned was prosecuted;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf427bb863c2b4f21840a318e5f1c2aba"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether the defendant has demonstrated maturity, rehabilitation, and a fitness to reenter society sufficient to justify a sentence reduction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6acb26b32b8546e3a8320e834c7fb5b8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any statement, which may be presented orally or otherwise, by any victim of an offense for which the defendant is imprisoned or by a family member of the victim if the victim is deceased;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd2250a342e56418999ecfbe2bb66f57a"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any report from a physical, mental, or psychiatric examination of the defendant conducted by a licensed health care professional;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id197de7eb10764acba0ce52d767f3c559"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the family and community circumstances of the defendant at the time of the offense, including any history of abuse, trauma, or involvement in the child welfare system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3941f0c9bf3d40dc8d46a7fe0ad477d2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the extent of the role of the defendant in the offense and whether, and to what extent, an adult was involved in the offense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id72574324a59c4380b6833bda6dc9cca4"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the diminished culpability of juveniles as compared to that of adults, and the hallmark features of youth, including immaturity, impetuosity, and failure to appreciate risks and consequences, which counsel against sentencing juveniles to the otherwise applicable term of imprisonment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42d21580679f4d04a3aae4e7918dd95e"><enum>(11)</enum><text>any other information the court determines relevant to the decision of the court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id21f6a397134f4e45afa8bc7013134575"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on applications pursuant to this section</header><paragraph id="id1b15673fa30943e8bd8e516274eafc25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Second application</header><text>Not earlier than 5 years after the date on which an order entered by a court on an initial application under this section becomes final, a court shall entertain a second application by the same defendant under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e95576a000d493f84abb8d59e38de3e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final application</header><text>Not earlier than 5 years after the date on which an order entered by a court on a second application under paragraph (1) becomes final, a court shall entertain a final application by the same defendant under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idccef685e4c5f464abaa01e2d9468f4d7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A court may not entertain an application filed after an application filed under paragraph (2) by the same defendant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb10eea0f3754415fae226abb03641da0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Procedures</header><paragraph id="id220d2204e009475192b8291e760c9c91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Bureau of Prisons shall provide written notice of this section to—</text><subparagraph id="idbb24b4332045422c99d318d1043ab76c"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any defendant who has served not less than 19 years in prison for an offense committed and completed before the defendant attained 18 years of age for which the defendant was convicted as an adult; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id50bc9520aa8947cc8a0d7c5ca1c7015d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sentencing court, the United States attorney, and the Federal Public Defender or Executive Director of the Community Defender Organization for the judicial district in which the sentence described in subparagraph (A) was imposed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f8a634783414a68a32e5d689c3e8cae"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Crime victims' rights</header><text>Upon receiving notice under paragraph (1), the United States attorney shall provide any notifications required under section 3771.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id97b238b3e8cc467aa8a78c9d25fa117a"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="idb6316c2c201c4b2eaa1ca1b501f6c787"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An application for a sentence reduction under this section shall be filed as a motion to reduce the sentence of the defendant and may include affidavits or other written material.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida3f92380344343a290376f80a0b6b50d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>A motion to reduce a sentence under this section shall be filed with the sentencing court and a copy shall be served on the United States attorney for the judicial district in which the sentence was imposed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id65a93ae6e4c0440bb4704edcd7f52767"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expanding the record; hearing</header><subparagraph id="id1ecaac26fb9b415e8b63668bde03f0ec"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Expanding the record</header><text>After the filing of a motion to reduce a sentence under this section, the court may direct the parties to expand the record by submitting additional written materials relating to the motion.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8fa7a2615dcd4ebda7b3a1fab20071fd"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hearing</header><clause id="id8eb08e3d0b1d4ba29440f315f897b3c0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The court shall conduct a hearing on the motion, at which the defendant and counsel for the defendant shall be given the opportunity to be heard.</text></clause><clause id="ida7843b4722884b1b9858cb755aa80a12"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Evidence</header><text>In a hearing under this section, the court may allow parties to present evidence.</text></clause><clause id="id5a09cd17eb4d44398763dfe9ac111ceb"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Defendant’s presence</header><text>At a hearing under this section, the defendant shall be present unless the defendant waives the right to be present. The requirement under this clause may be satisfied by the defendant appearing by video teleconference.</text></clause><clause id="id40750e6b84384207a5a3f0dc172f8bb0"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Counsel</header><text>A defendant who is unable to obtain counsel is entitled to have counsel appointed to represent the defendant for proceedings under this section, including any appeal, unless the defendant waives the right to counsel.</text></clause><clause id="id9b655173190d4854a9dd55c84380d268"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The court shall state in open court, and file in writing, the reasons for granting or denying a motion under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2790419ed72e476194d497e55cb55403"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>The Government or the defendant may file a notice of appeal in the district court for review of a final order under this section. The time limit for filing such appeal shall be governed by rule 4(a) of the Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id32e7f38381334c5dba1bd7eba5f8899a"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Educational and rehabilitative programs</header><text>A defendant who is convicted and sentenced as an adult for an offense committed and completed before the defendant attained 18 years of age may not be deprived of any educational, training, or rehabilitative program that is otherwise available to the general prison population.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id70ae7dfbe0594229bc444d7d23d12373"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of sections</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/18/5032">section 5032</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id2e68e83e-79d2-4784-b0b6-4ec97c08f73b"><toc><toc-entry idref="idb5588e114c0e48f88e42ebed3db27383" level="section">5032A. Modification of an imposed term of imprisonment for violations of law committed prior to age 18.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idc8619970fb6c49d6be685624dc000104"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to any conviction entered before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="ida0140e3c7e3d4a8fa8cdd3795f4948c7"><enum>202.</enum><header>Juvenile sealing and expungement</header><subsection id="id7ea45feaaacf48078c3ab95bbcefc5c0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to—</text><paragraph id="id147f2f12701e47b3828059d755ea3897"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protect children and adults against damage stemming from their juvenile acts and subsequent juvenile delinquency records, including law enforcement, arrest, and court records; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id369fb54dfe784acf811119a2de6ffac9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prevent the unauthorized use or disclosure of confidential juvenile delinquency records and any potential employment, financial, psychological, or other harm that would result from such unauthorized use or disclosure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3e527b136c854a1b8819d0ffa2c3ac77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 5031 of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id08c7b564dd0e4467a578a692d5744b47"><section id="id6dba6a9e5ce14460bac94dd024ae4b21"><enum>5031.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter—</text><paragraph id="idce0dc5f1555642bb92c5003f8bad80b5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>adjudication</term> means a determination by a judge that a person committed an act of juvenile delinquency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5d9f0ba98c0d417fbf9411f44e7e437e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>conviction</term> means a judgment or disposition in criminal court against a person following a finding of guilt by a judge or jury;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7264610b5d0f4fdabac6d31069345dcf"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>destroy</term> means to render a file unreadable, whether paper, electronic, or otherwise stored, by shredding, pulverizing, pulping, incinerating, overwriting, reformatting the media, or other means;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee85061dbfcb41ceabbb876869b38dc6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>expunge</term> means to destroy a record and obliterate the name of the person to whom the record pertains from each official index or public record;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb260f6368330440197487c324fc5eba1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>expungement hearing</term> means a hearing held under section 5045(b)(2)(B);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3d8dd069ef3d4f8b87903c646014496e"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>expungement petition</term> means a petition for expungement filed under section 5045(b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd44ce3e5b0de4455a66f632064b47c38"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>high-risk, public trust position</term> means a position designated as a public trust position under section 731.106(b) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfee94126587546daa56899f4d1d6344f"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the term <term>juvenile</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idfa18bd63ffc6413e91f66add48c25513"><enum>(A)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (B), a person who has not attained the age of 18 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id480072267f3346e3b2afa8ce01b890cf"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the purpose of proceedings and disposition under this chapter for an alleged act of juvenile delinquency, a person who has not attained the age of 21 years;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5aa752a874714337b068e1bb20c77174"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the term <term>juvenile delinquency</term> means the violation of a law of the United States committed by a person before attaining the age of 18 years which would have been a crime if committed by an adult, or a violation by such a person of section 922(x);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87ad73851a904bfe9908725942f017b8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the term <term>juvenile nonviolent offense</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="id3c46a35cc59d4d2dadce601355e3c367"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of an arrest or an adjudication that is dismissed or finds the juvenile to be not delinquent, an act of juvenile delinquency that is not—</text><clause id="idf2ecaaec9e2549359028b43a6b5322c3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a criminal homicide, forcible rape or any other sex offense (as defined in section 111 of the Sex Offender Registration and Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20911">34 U.S.C. 20911</external-xref>)), kidnapping, aggravated assault, robbery, burglary of an occupied structure, arson, or a drug trafficking crime in which a firearm was used; or</text></clause><clause id="id27f64d078e59443fbae5693984b48a14"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal crime of terrorism (as defined in section 2332b(g)); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1620d07aa2be42539cdc8de69fb6de87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an adjudication that finds the juvenile to be delinquent, an act of juvenile delinquency that is not—</text><clause id="id7b5fb6ee7f014f8faf66301171d066da"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (A); or</text></clause><clause id="ida2842481fe5748a1997d9d3b18c16d91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a misdemeanor crime of domestic violence (as defined in section 921(a)(33));</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida964dd69c4744af2aeea49a42da26698"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the term <term>juvenile record</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id7ebeb7dafb474a06b96c8a9a5a31e44f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a record maintained by a court, the probation system, a law enforcement agency, or any other government agency, of the juvenile delinquency proceedings of a person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2987198647a1475d85dc1cd03d8fcab6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="ideed49c3ed8bf445bad888600c1dffb82"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a juvenile legal file, including a formal document such as a petition, notice, motion, legal memorandum, order, or decree;</text></clause><clause id="id46d4ad1a03a94cee8c04e21f261fb83c"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a social record, including—</text><subclause id="id3574c852d9b4451f8f1fcd256b7f50ed"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a record of a probation officer;</text></subclause><subclause id="idf8124a833f2e434d8ab45406fbcbac60"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a record of any government agency that keeps records relating to juvenile delinquency;</text></subclause><subclause id="idd2853303c14047cbbaae0f3bf1c32871"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a medical record;</text></subclause><subclause id="id7c1fb3860a2743e384139dc7c6f10fda"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a psychiatric or psychological record;</text></subclause><subclause id="id9e4a41d2adb3416493ccdaa09a2917aa"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a birth certificate;</text></subclause><subclause id="id1accf925296349f6b22fa07d666225e9"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>an education record, including an individualized education plan;</text></subclause><subclause id="id3a65d96af8a148a38d28a524703a0544"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a detention record;</text></subclause><subclause id="id5c1b5da4c9d9428bb455045aaa47374c"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>demographic information that identifies a juvenile or the family of a juvenile; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id17c7a6cd883243ef9fdde59bb0d05092"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>any other record that includes personally identifiable information that may be associated with a juvenile delinquency proceeding, an act of juvenile delinquency, or an alleged act of juvenile delinquency; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ide6092fbbb487407abc00a934b800b285"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a law enforcement record, including a photograph or a State criminal justice information system record; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb2435db44ab94dd7b1c4a0b6658521ff"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="ida5e6b54814df45e497d7e504e699cfe3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fingerprints; or</text></clause><clause id="id878d5ca68f39428b8733c5df4915a39b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a DNA sample;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id01c5cb76177642718eef5faacd4130cf"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the term <term>petitioner</term> means a person who files an expungement petition or a sealing petition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id323b9cdc3afa4158898fd0d37bddeb84"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the term <term>seal</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idf5770020899449939bf626bcc54bfe44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to close a record from public viewing so that the record cannot be examined except by court order; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1295e2e1ff84c6886a832442d871354"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to physically seal the record shut and label the record <quote>SEALED</quote> or, in the case of an electronic record, the substantive equivalent;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5fb6e0c2f6f2459c87c82bbad3ae9de0"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the term <term>sealing hearing</term> means a hearing held under section 5044(b)(2)(B); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6222ac2446e746269cce5fa8d00da4ee"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the term <term>sealing petition</term> means a petition for a sealing order filed under section 5044(b).</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id9e930966a5b64410b30b4d9641f6b9b7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>Section 5038 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="id9d4b0e4ff5044969818cb55f7974fe13"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the flush text following paragraph (6), by inserting after <quote>bonding,</quote> the following: <quote>participation in an educational system,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id29158c213b6f4e4aaa78a6169ced589a"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>District courts exercising jurisdiction over any juvenile</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>Not later than 7 days after the date on which a district court exercises jurisdiction over a juvenile, the district court</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idf63b524f53984503ae634ead905e2413"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sealing; expungement</header><paragraph id="id8747d9fd9c8d46e680087536dd6b0e20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">Chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45425d6b1d5c4c64830f0dbc64969016"><section id="id0b2cfa0762974739959e9d18d50cc2f9"><enum>5044.</enum><header>Sealing</header><subsection id="ide618cf7ea58245b7856211d9310fe9d4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Automatic sealing of nonviolent offenses</header><paragraph id="id72cc0f0474014f8fb91c18db5c36df17"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Three years after the date on which a person who is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense completes every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense, the court shall order the sealing of each juvenile record or portion thereof that relates to the offense if the person—</text><subparagraph id="id5e2ce945739f4ac9a397ecfbc3247106"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has not been convicted of a crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency since the date of the disposition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1a9f7baa8494c069d438cd8d5b59f90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id392a85e0d3ea40d89c5f2c61fa315cc9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Automatic nature of sealing</header><text>The order of sealing under paragraph (1) shall require no action by the person whose juvenile records are to be sealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id175e855dea2c4e718881181e6be6e7c7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of automatic sealing</header><text>A court that orders the sealing of a juvenile record of a person under paragraph (1) shall, in writing, inform the person of the sealing and the benefits of sealing the record.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idac881d542eea4e6da6deac787d80152e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Petitioning for early sealing of nonviolent offenses</header><paragraph id="id4185258e91e7469c9542c3fdb86c2ce3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Right to file sealing petition</header><subparagraph id="id3cdd24ebc5174063a08b887c8eb89d1c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 3-year period beginning on the date on which a person who is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense completes every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense, the person may petition the court to seal the juvenile records that relate to the offense, unless the person—</text><clause id="ida61595705d4e47219daeb6e7ac097e3c"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been convicted of a crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency since the date of the disposition; or</text></clause><clause id="id2f06dc3f8a714fd899950ffee017ffd9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a1dfdca196f4b079650494aaef1aac2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice of opportunity to file petition</header><text>If a person is adjudicated delinquent for a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court in which the person is adjudicated delinquent shall, in writing, inform the person of the potential eligibility of the person to file a sealing petition with respect to the offense upon completing every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense, and the necessary procedures for filing the sealing petition—</text><clause id="id475afb315bdc4e4aa3fe35dae75d2189"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on the date on which the individual is adjudicated delinquent; and</text></clause><clause id="idab623d5a672b49b4a2eae30fd8604f5b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on the date on which the individual has completed every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idaf5aa0191ed04e08a9b8843222003c3b"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><subparagraph id="id8fda5fe8112d424da4cacf0199d1828a"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification to prosecutor</header><text>If a person files a sealing petition with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court in which the petition is filed shall provide notice of the petition—</text><clause id="idbfe43036e2a744dfa29933698fa3f4bd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the Attorney General; and</text></clause><clause id="id29eb9c884a964e2484d7cf82395cf713"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon the request of the petitioner, to any other individual that the petitioner determines may testify as to—</text><subclause id="id15bbc6598a9f4ce79f7e126312b5cd9e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the conduct of the petitioner since the date of the offense; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id2ba39ec9d1fc44b98cd11ab0e89f9875"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the reasons that the sealing order should be entered.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87bb3c2e1f634da3b92f21914e46faf3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hearing</header><clause id="ida644f40d8e1a431b91f2294df13ce97c"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a person files a sealing petition, the court shall—</text><subclause id="idebae207970db47e392c4cede62b98b4d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in clause (iii), conduct a hearing in accordance with clause (ii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="id005c91e872a246a880520a9422e0cb58"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determine whether to enter a sealing order for the person in accordance with subparagraph (C).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id31d92e7afbd840958a67f995a49a1cb1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Opportunity to testify and offer evidence</header><subclause id="id9ad72f79bd7e4df8bc765232fc58e79f"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Petitioner</header><text>The petitioner may testify or offer evidence at the sealing hearing in support of sealing.</text></subclause><subclause id="ide48559d6dba340d18ce56e24eceaf1b5"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Prosecutor</header><text>The Attorney General may send a representative to testify or offer evidence at the sealing hearing in support of or against sealing.</text></subclause><subclause id="id18c7c201d7114462ab9cd228844aa10a"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Other individuals</header><text>An individual who receives notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) may testify or offer evidence at the sealing hearing as to the issues described in subclauses (I) and (II) of that subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id3b0ec9d3fc6c4866b37d1a2f7abd4394"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Waiver of hearing</header><text>If the petitioner and the Attorney General so agree, the court shall make a determination under subparagraph (C) without a hearing.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddd85526029f64c198a33460e3d7fbf43"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Basis for decision</header><text>The court shall determine whether to grant the sealing petition after considering—</text><clause id="id6654c70a20d1438a958b42e131aa2a68"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the sealing petition and any documents in the possession of the court;</text></clause><clause id="idf06079d0e3e74d27a7fa056dc714634f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all the evidence and testimony presented at the sealing hearing, if such a hearing is conducted;</text></clause><clause id="id51091b1b2e2e4004a6a0928187d22b58"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the best interests of the petitioner;</text></clause><clause id="idf83856b6eb6f47ee997f43d976eb834d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the age of the petitioner during his or her contact with the court or any law enforcement agency;</text></clause><clause id="idb58686e61893497396c4ad4ae83badcc"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the nature of the juvenile nonviolent offense;</text></clause><clause id="idb7be7e3a086147f6879d9027be17237b"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the disposition of the case;</text></clause><clause id="id5d1847219ba842e5b314749444b6437b"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the manner in which the petitioner participated in any court-ordered rehabilitative programming or supervised services;</text></clause><clause id="id39986edd8751412eae50c6686adba116"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the length of the time period during which the petitioner has been without contact with any court or law enforcement agency;</text></clause><clause id="id21546b75bc1f49048d279190914e3d0c"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>whether the petitioner has had any criminal or juvenile delinquency involvement since the disposition of the juvenile delinquency proceeding; and</text></clause><clause id="idb542ba510589424d801edef323638f6d"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the adverse consequences the petitioner may suffer if the petition is not granted.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3d89861289324b01a8be21d1f83de54e"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Waiting period after denial</header><text>If the court denies a sealing petition, the petitioner may not file a new sealing petition with respect to the same juvenile nonviolent offense until the date that is 2 years after the date of the denial.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id697ff96521b84856a6408ef5ea04b51b"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Universal form</header><text>The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall create a universal form, available over the internet and in paper form, that an individual may use to file a sealing petition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5e5197dd035545d099bdfbd2618cb29c"><enum>(F)</enum><header>No fee for indigent petitioners</header><text>If the court determines that the petitioner is indigent, there shall be no cost for filing a sealing petition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3832c9c226784717a1824794576c6097"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall issue a public report that—</text><clause id="idc9c61c8d168f4c5c963b0c6fff1cd4a6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes—</text><subclause id="id5aafd93038e444c7bcbec7b6119d94da"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of sealing petitions granted and denied under this subsection; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idfcc482cbc3db4881bda3dc5d8a8592c9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of instances in which the Attorney General supported or opposed a sealing petition;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id6b965ffc586746eb88e5492484a0ece9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes any supporting data that the Director determines relevant and that does not name any petitioner; and</text></clause><clause id="id1f7d4d5333a24b1ba105ca7f92cf2e55"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>disaggregates all relevant data by race, ethnicity, gender, and the nature of the offense.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida40b9d79c530402b8ae09c90c43744f9"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Public defender eligibility</header><clause id="id9b0de7ae46b84f37baa29fd5137e5a40"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Petitioners under age 18</header><text>The district court shall appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent a petitioner for purposes of this subsection if the petitioner is less than 18 years of age.</text></clause><clause id="id7373c38cd0d940439a1dc191bb3c3569"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Petitioners age 18 and older</header><subclause id="idf9fb47f7039c4ed2a29304897dfb413f"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Discretion of court</header><text>In the case of a petitioner who is not less than 18 years of age, the district court may, in its discretion, appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent the petitioner for purposes of this subsection.</text></subclause><subclause id="idd35d99d113e1449fa273935245b7c105"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to appoint counsel under subclause (I), the court shall consider—</text><item id="idc9868a770279496bb53d37230aa298f8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the anticipated complexity of the sealing hearing, including the number and type of witnesses called to advocate against the sealing of the records of the petitioner; and</text></item><item id="id0c6bd02e6cf248879270254f857d286a"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the potential for adverse testimony by a victim or a representative of the Attorney General.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idfc5ca2fa45014890954a44d2fbda4f7a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect of sealing order</header><paragraph id="id96a84d06cb814f0b85aa4eae99571177"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Protection from disclosure</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), if a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the proceedings in the case shall be deemed never to have occurred, and the person may properly reply accordingly to any inquiry about the events the records of which are ordered sealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaba3ba5efd334ae5a19b2e805c89a092"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Verification of sealing</header><text>If a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court shall—</text><subparagraph id="id5f02ce09401145dd8bb6493bf1c8a696"><enum>(A)</enum><text>send a copy of the sealing order to each entity or person known to the court that possesses a record relating to the offense, including each—</text><clause id="id07f99a71640b4eb7acb3c3068b47fc9a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>law enforcement agency; and</text></clause><clause id="id53c5593d82b24c07bf0aa897807e5dec"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>public or private correctional or detention facility;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6a249d62404a486eb6b548c3e024dc22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the sealing order, require each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) to—</text><clause id="id84bab70be00d4d4c8fe65146b447f028"><enum>(i)</enum><text>seal the record; and</text></clause><clause id="id145bcf1709894c08924e49945c3fb0c6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit a written certification to the court, under penalty of perjury, that the entity or person has sealed each paper and electronic copy of the record;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbec4760719bb4547bf8179065fc86a6c"><enum>(C)</enum><text>seal each paper and electronic copy of the record in the possession of the court; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9caa99c814b441f69ceff03035d385fe"><enum>(D)</enum><text>after receiving a written certification from each entity or person under subparagraph (B)(ii), notify the petitioner that each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) has sealed each paper and electronic copy of the record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id572f51ae6f2b4d2d974fe68863012ec3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Law enforcement access to sealed records</header><subparagraph id="id87d24ccc248e475288aa6d13394321f0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a law enforcement agency may access a sealed juvenile record in the possession of the agency or another law enforcement agency solely—</text><clause id="idda175d6c71114806b4e0873ef61c744f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to determine whether the person who is the subject of the record is a nonviolent offender eligible for a first-time-offender diversion program;</text></clause><clause id="id8a6c285e73884d44bdf1bbd7c0977503"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for investigatory or prosecutorial purposes; or</text></clause><clause id="idce5f3ef8398545bca1b1c0adc90ceb9e"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for a background check that relates to—</text><subclause id="id4ecba2f432a8468cae029138264a40d1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>law enforcement employment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id3335c23803ad41b3b7a5f6e953bba451"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any position that a Federal agency designates as a—</text><item id="id7ecc88b83e464459828ae250961890d5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>national security position; or</text></item><item id="id4ec28206d4ce4db5af5803a8d862fec7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>high-risk, public trust position.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id87b146f30e7d412ab14e4eacd4e0233f"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transition period</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the date on which a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record under this section, a law enforcement agency may, for law enforcement purposes, access the record if the record is in the possession of the agency or another law enforcement agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf8c50d3f584468da33ce2cef50993e6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on disclosure</header><subparagraph id="ide68f420481ba499794b206460ef90454"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), it shall be unlawful to intentionally make or attempt to make an unauthorized disclosure of any information from a sealed juvenile record in violation of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id97c0333d90b1483e8e8ce78a5bd2d25d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any person who violates subparagraph (A) shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae7182de38a24c38954174bb1a818d6f"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><clause id="id38793bc109eb4ff1befc63a0afdbd847"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Background checks</header><text>In the case of a background check for law enforcement employment or for any employment that requires a government security clearance—</text><subclause id="id428d7b32c0e04725aaef11f888c421d1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a person who is the subject of a juvenile record sealed under this section shall disclose the contents of the record; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id15eacd930e924f4aa85a24cf6737deb8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a law enforcement agency that possesses a juvenile record sealed under this section—</text><item id="idd9bc7afb4c8b45fc93d17ddb64c33d69"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>may disclose the contents of the record; and</text></item><item id="id10f27c21d3004777b44f93595acaa3b7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if the agency obtains or is subject to a court order authorizing disclosure of the record, may disclose the record.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="idf0548ef46dfa4e11997510f541dd6324"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disclosure to Armed Forces</header><text>A person, including a law enforcement agency that possesses a juvenile record sealed under this section, may disclose information from a juvenile record sealed under this section to the Secretaries of the military departments (or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy) for the purpose of vetting an enlistment or commission, or with regard to any member of the Armed Forces.</text></clause><clause id="idaeb6246fc8a74a19bf2a4c404b11309b"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Criminal and juvenile proceedings</header><text>A prosecutor or other law enforcement officer may disclose information from a juvenile record sealed under this section, and a person who is the subject of a juvenile record sealed under this section may be required to testify or otherwise disclose information about the record, in a criminal or other proceeding if such disclosure is required by the Constitution of the United States, the constitution of a State, or a Federal or State statute or rule.</text></clause><clause id="id4cc51131522f47769c64d159a70a3faa"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Authorization for person to disclose own record</header><text>A person who is the subject of a juvenile record sealed under this section may choose to disclose the record.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9d34bc74191b49f297d2fb587793b713"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation relating to subsequent incidents</header><paragraph id="id175d95c72474483bbe0976620024b7cf"><enum>(1)</enum><header>After filing and before petition granted</header><text>If, after the date on which a person files a sealing petition with respect to a juvenile offense and before the court determines whether to grant the petition, the person is convicted of a crime, adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency, or engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings, the court shall deny the petition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6fbae0ef006e45fb9d45bd08431e46a8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>After petition granted</header><text>If, on or after the date on which a court orders the sealing of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (b), the person is convicted of a crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency—</text><subparagraph id="idc8f93bdfadfa4440bca1d10bc12fc6db"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the court shall—</text><clause id="id2d6dc4c46e8942aea0668aa62a3fd98a"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vacate the order; and</text></clause><clause id="id78955be2d2f74dad915f958c9961f3ae"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the person who is the subject of the juvenile record, and each entity or person described in subsection (c)(2)(A), that the order has been vacated; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8776904cce8f47edb9ee3cf194907237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the record shall no longer be sealed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ida92c776e21ee4af9a3596d8cff892f68"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inclusion of State juvenile delinquency adjudications and proceedings</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1), clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (b)(1)(A), subsection (b)(2)(C)(ix), and paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d), the term <term>juvenile delinquency</term> includes the violation of a law of a State committed by a person before attaining the age of 18 years which would have been a crime if committed by an adult.</text></subsection></section><section id="id64a1371ff23249f6b8f49d7480fdedc9"><enum>5045.</enum><header>Expungement</header><subsection id="id4d660d9bca384dedac8c84a3f1989a05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Automatic expungement of certain records</header><paragraph id="id8837f511b3454ed5942b7f7ed9bdb083"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Attorney general motion</header><subparagraph id="ide4a7682c6c794164963e886df7274fa6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Nonviolent offenses committed before a person turned 15</header><text>If a person is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense committed before the person attained 15 years of age and completes every term of probation, official detention, or juvenile delinquent supervision ordered by the court with respect to the offense before attaining 18 years of age, on the date on which the person attains 18 years of age, the Attorney General shall file a motion in the district court of the United States in which the person was adjudicated delinquent requesting that each juvenile record of the person that relates to the offense be expunged.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74d66154a6e54acbb0bc0e3529274fe8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Arrests</header><text>If a juvenile is arrested by a Federal law enforcement agency for a juvenile nonviolent offense for which a juvenile delinquency proceeding is not instituted under this chapter, and for which the United States does not proceed against the juvenile as an adult in a district court of the United States, the Attorney General shall file a motion in the district court of the United States that would have had jurisdiction of the proceeding requesting that each juvenile record relating to the arrest be expunged.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb0b97a4630fa482c800f2273df2ab2cd"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Expungement order</header><text>Upon the filing of a motion in a district court of the United States with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense under subparagraph (A) or an arrest for a juvenile nonviolent offense under subparagraph (B), the court shall grant the motion and order that each juvenile record relating to the offense or arrest, as applicable, be expunged.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a236b07c99f424884faba389f8dd870"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dismissed cases</header><text>If a district court of the United States dismisses an information with respect to a juvenile under this chapter or finds a juvenile not to be delinquent in a juvenile delinquency proceeding under this chapter, the court shall concurrently order that each juvenile record relating to the applicable proceeding be expunged.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida52809fc4542478e9fdb7455e6067882"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Automatic nature of expungement</header><text>An order of expungement under paragraph (1)(C) or (2) shall not require any action by the person whose records are to be expunged.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0989a509672d4108988deac657efbc7e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice of automatic expungement</header><text>A court that orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under paragraph (1)(C) or (2) shall, in writing, inform the person of the expungement and the benefits of expunging the record.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id172c7266604c434186af32f1790eb6d0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Petitioning for expungement of nonviolent offenses</header><paragraph id="idb5cc7a65076542cbbd954efbd56a11ac"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person who is adjudicated delinquent under this chapter for a juvenile nonviolent offense committed on or after the date on which the person attained 15 years of age may petition the court in which the proceeding took place to order the expungement of the juvenile record that relates to the offense unless the person—</text><subparagraph id="id2453319ea4b74d9fa17025e0160e5025"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been convicted of a crime or adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency since the date of the disposition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id53c0b6803ac44f47bd3eb1856c8220e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8133f7e0aaa94d7f8b2821962b523b2f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has had not less than 2 adjudications of delinquency previously expunged under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1c973c0b1bc645878da6e8b1a9d4cd01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><subparagraph id="id07ce5cf14a094ebd832e10955aff9a9f"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification of prosecutor and victims</header><text>If a person files an expungement petition with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court in which the petition is filed shall provide notice of the petition—</text><clause id="id9a230439084042ccaaacd5cb48179bbb"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the Attorney General; and</text></clause><clause id="id4b488014cf3343878042b984e5155ad8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon the request of the petitioner, to any other individual that the petitioner determines may testify as to—</text><subclause id="id711fd4d609c34ba1b750c176fc6df6e4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the conduct of the petitioner since the date of the offense; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id420c9e563cd440a7a2b7f1df6e3e3e92"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the reasons that the expungement order should be entered.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcef257552381495aa2ae903042bd27a6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hearing</header><clause id="id2cf61e55786943ccb64f9dcff3dd090f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a person files an expungement petition, the court shall—</text><subclause id="id4e234b939ded4e6c85d8f401e7158047"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in clause (iii), conduct a hearing in accordance with clause (ii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="idf8ae1c0595a1460480c7a252fd009523"><enum>(II)</enum><text>determine whether to enter an expungement order for the person in accordance with subparagraph (C).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ideb2ef5e1ddcc4bd4908f487546de6b2b"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Opportunity to testify and offer evidence</header><subclause id="idb46776dad8f848249df7aa13723e145c"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Petitioner</header><text>The petitioner may testify or offer evidence at the expungement hearing in support of expungement.</text></subclause><subclause id="id9a80d62ef72645f793a45c2cb645bcca"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Prosecutor</header><text>The Attorney General may send a representative to testify or offer evidence at the expungement hearing in support of or against expungement.</text></subclause><subclause id="id472069b405e143fe8dc60ffc809531a9"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Other individuals</header><text>An individual who receives notice under subparagraph (A)(ii) may testify or offer evidence at the expungement hearing as to the issues described in subclauses (I) and (II) of that subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ida638e75d59244916b55a7bd84948e832"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Waiver of hearing</header><text>If the petitioner and the Attorney General so agree, the court shall make a determination under subparagraph (C) without a hearing.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id79b96a3782ba40feb4d901ac2072fce0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Basis for decision</header><text>The court shall determine whether to grant an expungement petition after considering—</text><clause id="id1a520369b1154d8fa666c1202bb9c3ad"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the petition and any documents in the possession of the court;</text></clause><clause id="id4f13fb93095c49979c6d05768108bc6d"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all the evidence and testimony presented at the expungement hearing, if such a hearing is conducted;</text></clause><clause id="id12167ecc78c145f6a50fe6a34d1bc94c"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the best interests of the petitioner;</text></clause><clause id="id67e8ffe9e81a41a6a8fe1e500472ae90"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the age of the petitioner during his or her contact with the court or any law enforcement agency;</text></clause><clause id="id40eb30233b8b499a98a2fe2314063510"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the nature of the juvenile nonviolent offense;</text></clause><clause id="id690a8f794dc44ef5a52ceb6e2a73bbf2"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the disposition of the case;</text></clause><clause id="id83154cf50fad459486d671751ce35eb2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the manner in which the petitioner participated in any court-ordered rehabilitative programming or supervised services;</text></clause><clause id="id55a61fe3b6ef471484928cb188a4e4c0"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the length of the time period during which the petitioner has been without contact with any court or any law enforcement agency;</text></clause><clause id="idc567e75e15d9425c81a6a70ab27e5a7d"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>whether the petitioner has had any criminal or juvenile delinquency involvement since the disposition of the juvenile delinquency proceeding; and</text></clause><clause id="id9626fd3db0e740ddba072d3f67369c27"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the adverse consequences the petitioner may suffer if the petition is not granted.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1a0d002872cf4531af792e1dbefc6ea9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Waiting period after denial</header><text>If the court denies an expungement petition, the petitioner may not file a new expungement petition with respect to the same offense until the date that is 2 years after the date of the denial.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26a209bbf64b424dbd6680d02d2191bd"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Universal form</header><text>The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall create a universal form, available over the internet and in paper form, that an individual may use to file an expungement petition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3ee2df45da01450ca4c8ca69d4672e66"><enum>(F)</enum><header>No fee for indigent petitioners</header><text>If the court determines that the petitioner is indigent, there shall be no cost for filing an expungement petition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1429c79a78564e4381e3b13abe249745"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts shall issue a public report that—</text><clause id="id9dd462deb2314ffa907e5ce261401b4f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes—</text><subclause id="id82f9133db68a4ac58d3548f054866584"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of expungement petitions granted and denied under this subsection; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idcbe082238ba54a32a37416b3094e143b"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of instances in which the Attorney General supported or opposed an expungement petition;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id5b94f0475e3b49af9a5c736c8f39ee18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes any supporting data that the Director determines relevant and that does not name any petitioner; and</text></clause><clause id="id884537c9989c4b1bb39058b610387668"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>disaggregates all relevant data by race, ethnicity, gender, and the nature of the offense.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id10098cfe5d3640baae1a76b71c8c49e5"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Public defender eligibility</header><clause id="id2e1022c65e9b459a8eeabfa64367121f"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Petitioners under age 18</header><text>The district court shall appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent a petitioner for purposes of this subsection if the petitioner is less than 18 years of age.</text></clause><clause id="id36273c9598ed49edbe7c235245a2ee66"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Petitioners age 18 and older</header><subclause id="id970f8f276ca24dc692c05f973f1f310d"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Discretion of court</header><text>In the case of a petitioner who is not less than 18 years of age, the district court may, in its discretion, appoint counsel in accordance with the plan of the district court in operation under section 3006A to represent the petitioner for purposes of this subsection.</text></subclause><subclause id="id72f9a92e08f349649cb152e550bc188a"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to appoint counsel under subclause (I), the court shall consider—</text><item id="idf22ee9c4529845b6819f5c96a3977fa9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the anticipated complexity of the expungement hearing, including the number and type of witnesses called to advocate against the expungement of the records of the petitioner; and</text></item><item id="id3ce24ef27bd942e49cf0dcd98d403cd4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the potential for adverse testimony by a victim or a representative of the Attorney General.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide37a0532bb2246f0adb7a9f8683a9b64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect of expunged juvenile record</header><paragraph id="idf222decc09f4416b98fcb68354a28e70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Protection from disclosure</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (4) through (8), if a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the proceedings in the case shall be deemed never to have occurred, and the person may properly reply accordingly to any inquiry about the events the records of which are ordered expunged.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide50aeab44e2740d78a4d6d2fb5a90df2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Verification of expungement</header><text>If a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense, the court shall—</text><subparagraph id="id667b3935bfeb4026bf0092029960b32b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>send a copy of the expungement order to each entity or person known to the court that possesses a record relating to the offense, including each—</text><clause id="idbbd1dc0794224183baf45144b5cbcd89"><enum>(i)</enum><text>law enforcement agency; and</text></clause><clause id="id1496d78a4fb546b1bc508b4c842bb0e2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>public or private correctional or detention facility;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id182d1df28aea4f9eb4ceadb854c5db19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the expungement order—</text><clause id="id73cd3f71103042c5ba0ab49a40df95f4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>require each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) to—</text><subclause id="idefbfd6a3c627437fa9badd81d7b0cf6e"><enum>(I)</enum><text>seal the record for 1 year and, during that 1-year period, apply paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 5044(c) with respect to the record;</text></subclause><subclause id="id53495a06842148848565f14d249b1742"><enum>(II)</enum><text>on the date that is 1 year after the date of the order, destroy the record unless a subsequent incident described in subsection (d)(2) occurs; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id1867e9b21b824c129e7f7a7c6a6d9529"><enum>(III)</enum><text>submit a written certification to the court, under penalty of perjury, that the entity or person has destroyed each paper and electronic copy of the record; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id9b10e128b3d242468ecf2649a40d87ee"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>explain that if a subsequent incident described in subsection (d)(2) occurs, the order shall be vacated and—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id726512f529f64f318f111876dd9e938e"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the incident occurs during the 1-year period described in clause (i)(I) of this subparagraph, the record shall no longer be sealed; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4226c48647b34744a25a238bc8efcf7e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the record has been expunged because the incident occurs after the 1-year period described in clause (i)(I) of this subparagraph, the record shall not be treated as having been expunged;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idda36ccd199e34e619ae8ae5614e06e8f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on the date that is 1 year after the date of the order, destroy each paper and electronic copy of the record in the possession of the court unless a subsequent incident described in subsection (d)(2) occurs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0dae34eb1f174ba3abdb503ff648bacf"><enum>(D)</enum><text>after receiving a written certification from each entity or person under subparagraph (B)(i)(III), notify the petitioner that each entity or person described in subparagraph (A) has destroyed each paper and electronic copy of the record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddbd0ada63a4f434f97097ac6a39e7287"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reply to inquiries</header><text>On and after the date that is 1 year after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under this section, in the case of an inquiry relating to the juvenile record, the court, each law enforcement officer, any agency that provided treatment or rehabilitation services to the person, and the person (except as provided in paragraphs (4) through (8)) shall reply to the inquiry that no such juvenile record exists.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5b1ae77b95f645699f6eaab6622fd79e"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Civil actions</header><subparagraph id="id7f9fa4e18a704b01bca00d99dc8364df"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under this section, if the person brings an action against a law enforcement agency that arrested, or participated in the arrest of, the person for the offense to which the record relates, or against the State or political subdivision of a State of which the law enforcement agency is an agency, in which the contents of the record are relevant to the resolution of the issues presented in the action, there shall be a rebuttable presumption that the defendant has a complete defense to the action.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idedf208add9a84f8eb6938e87967ca3de"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Showing by plaintiff</header><text>In an action described in subparagraph (A), the plaintiff may rebut the presumption of a complete defense by showing that the contents of the expunged record would not prevent the defendant from being held liable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7bedcc9c086742c880c8e45e4a24ca88"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Duty to testify as to existence of record</header><text>The court in which an action described in subparagraph (A) is filed may require the plaintiff to state under oath whether the plaintiff had a juvenile record and whether the record was expunged.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcb383cad1f7e4f98ac145469ab911a1c"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Proof of existence of juvenile record</header><text>If the plaintiff in an action described in subparagraph (A) denies the existence of a juvenile record, the defendant may prove the existence of the record in any manner compatible with the applicable laws of evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0421a25ddaf04fa2aa3fc2e8de585246"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Criminal and juvenile proceedings</header><text>On and after the date that is 1 year after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under this section, a prosecutor or other law enforcement officer may disclose underlying information from the juvenile record, and the person who is the subject of the juvenile record may be required to testify or otherwise disclose information about the record, in a criminal or other proceeding if such disclosure is required by the Constitution of the United States, the constitution of a State, or a Federal or State statute or rule.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddac41e330ab044d18b2a2e6d97064ae9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Background checks</header><text>On and after the date that is 1 year after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under this section, in the case of a background check for law enforcement employment or for any employment that requires a government security clearance, the person who is the subject of the juvenile record may be required to disclose underlying information from the record.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfc9503be858d4a4688a76c5f6b826775"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Disclosure to armed forces</header><text>On and after the date that is 1 year after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under this section, a person, including a law enforcement agency that possessed such a juvenile record, may be required to disclose underlying information from the record to the Secretaries of the military departments (or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy) for the purpose of vetting an enlistment or commission, or with regard to any member of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbe907158751b4ab882c34a6be5b731da"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Authorization for person to disclose own record</header><text>A person who is the subject of a juvenile record expunged under this section may choose to disclose the record.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d3168d262aa45de8b69e95635efadc9"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Treatment as sealed record during transition period</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record under this section, paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 5044(c) shall apply with respect to the record as if the record had been sealed under that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id07e03927e6df42d88fb2b12900df6cc6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation relating to subsequent incidents</header><paragraph id="id443d5a5d03624f3ebe6932827d292a68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>After filing and before petition granted</header><text>If, after the date on which a person files an expungement petition with respect to a juvenile offense and before the court determines whether to grant the petition, the person is convicted of a crime, adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency, or engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings, the court shall deny the petition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf21165d187f8446c997fd6304d7cf1cc"><enum>(2)</enum><header>After petition granted</header><text>If, on or after the date on which a court orders the expungement of a juvenile record of a person under subsection (b), the person is convicted of a crime, adjudicated delinquent for an act of juvenile delinquency, or engaged in active criminal court proceedings or juvenile delinquency proceedings—</text><subparagraph id="id8eaa0ff239c24533bc2e5185a530b626"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the court that ordered the expungement shall—</text><clause id="ide75b0825fedf43aab103a8cd8e5e168d"><enum>(i)</enum><text>vacate the order; and</text></clause><clause id="id0801cf94e22145359e846dbf0b881a6b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the person who is the subject of the juvenile record, and each entity or person described in subsection (c)(2)(A), that the order has been vacated; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id16a81714b6d94ca6b0477bb380450331"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the record—</text><clause id="id0f285fb6a9e547a29c368106820f1db0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall not be expunged; or</text></clause><clause id="idfd3f3044cf3d4b528025012a6248e783"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the record has been expunged because 1 year has elapsed since the date of the expungement order, shall not be treated as having been expunged.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id9a78ba3739df49c993cbe2cdba0eb641"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Inclusion of state juvenile delinquency adjudications and proceedings</header><text>For purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (b)(1), subsection (b)(2)(C)(ix), and paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d), the term <term>juvenile delinquency</term> includes the violation of a law of a State committed by a person before attaining the age of 18 years which would have been a crime if committed by an adult.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="idb4ac3bc3e6f4437592163beb521ee7f7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/403">chapter 403</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="id2a821d14-3bd0-4abc-bca3-31772d085f0a"><toc><toc-entry idref="id0b2cfa0762974739959e9d18d50cc2f9" level="section">5044. Sealing.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="id64a1371ff23249f6b8f49d7480fdedc9" level="section">5045. Expungement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="id3fec8b52fd754b54a93647b439832418"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Sections 5044 and 5045 of title 18, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), shall apply with respect to a juvenile nonviolent offense (as defined in section 5031 of such title, as amended by subsection (b)) that is committed or alleged to have been committed before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6a2a70e43a074659b1d43ee5f8b60af4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in the amendments made by this section shall be construed to authorize the sealing or expungement of a record of a criminal conviction of a juvenile who was proceeded against as an adult in a district court of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="id449a12e740944b0584b20cab1aa7899d"><enum>203.</enum><header>Ensuring accuracy of Federal criminal records</header><subsection id="id5676202deb314c999b6a5b7e21608451"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 534 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida8e2ff2ef37d434fa8147056520b2bab"><subsection id="id5833ab9985aa405e83413c139546e4be"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Ensuring accuracy of Federal criminal records</header><paragraph id="id7b43f24b67cd47f9be68e572cc3a655b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><subparagraph id="id8b1e198ac3e4488b9d0899921f7200ae"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this subsection—</text><clause id="idd02d7f160ab2448782bfa187fd166705"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>applicant</term> means the individual to whom a record sought to be exchanged pertains;</text></clause><clause id="id76048d73cdd946e9a9116fa5fef78d23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>high-risk, public trust position</term> means a position designated as a public trust position under section 731.106(b) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation;</text></clause><clause id="id45f5772748b74d3cbd994a8aa9e489e3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <term>incomplete</term>, with respect to a record, means the record—</text><subclause id="ide94cfa286f434f5f91c3e095a83f0fc9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>indicates that an individual was arrested but does not describe the offense for which the individual was arrested; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id05f750a2dcb9435387b583ebd6352241"><enum>(II)</enum><text>indicates that an individual was arrested or criminal proceedings were instituted against an individual but does not include the final disposition of the arrest or of the proceedings if a final disposition has been reached;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="ide74f21140d714a88a2d50029a16b1ab0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the term <term>record</term> means a record or other information collected under this section that relates to—</text><subclause id="id814966f0023148909f019485e5c50d6f"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an arrest by a Federal law enforcement officer; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id07f8f5fd08564b9794d0476aaccc0d13"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a Federal criminal proceeding;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id4bbfba7fde7b4ab3940753bb63ea139e"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the term <term>reporting jurisdiction</term> means any person or entity that provides a record to the Attorney General under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="id4eea2822d9a54a4eb158ce09d5272b48"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the term <term>requesting entity</term>—</text><subclause id="id2833dfa2d5a94289ae9ccb16c7709ff8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>means a person or entity that seeks the exchange of a record for civil purposes that include employment, housing, credit, or any other type of application; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idbff5f71dc9244fa7847b2933bd40dea7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not include a law enforcement or intelligence agency that seeks the exchange of a record for—</text><item id="idfbb994f5e7004489b2a6df468e9aea10"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>investigative purposes; or</text></item><item id="id5f848dad8ddc41a78121f753e42e0b9f"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>purposes relating to law enforcement employment.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd7b768ed90fc42d58abdfbc1b27841ab"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The definition of the term <term>requesting entity</term> under subparagraph (A) shall not be construed to authorize access to records that is not otherwise authorized by law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0dfec99e4974642b62d47a404120cc0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incomplete or inaccurate records</header><text>The Attorney General shall establish and enforce procedures to ensure the prompt release of accurate records exchanged for employment-related purposes through the records system created under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0931696981fe4a45893d6075465a4e4d"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required procedures</header><text>The procedures established under paragraph (2) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="id0d2f0a66af544c598cddf8164fa836c3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Inaccurate record or information</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a record is inaccurate, the Attorney General shall promptly correct the record, including by making deletions to the record if appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89e3e2a7ae854c70ade684ed21f98ad4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Incomplete record</header><clause id="idd0d94e07342046809badbf0bbf7083ce"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a record is incomplete or cannot be verified, the Attorney General—</text><subclause id="id0bf53ef6927145cba4b44ab720903cd2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall attempt to complete or verify the record; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id17fd45daf4f34516b024dee0caf74e70"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if unable to complete or verify the record, may promptly make any changes or deletions to the record.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id1c4fb30872ab4623a091b2296374d6db"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Lack of disposition of arrest</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph, an incomplete record includes a record that indicates there was an arrest and does not include the disposition of the arrest.</text></clause><clause id="id286b55d4cf444b9b855a675b8d157ab2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Obtaining disposition of arrest</header><text>If the Attorney General determines that a record is an incomplete record described in clause (ii), the Attorney General shall, not later than 10 days after the date on which the requesting entity requests the exchange and before the exchange is made, obtain the disposition (if any) of the arrest.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id06be901825674093a92bda813582d83e"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification of reporting jurisdiction</header><text>The Attorney General shall notify each appropriate reporting jurisdiction of any action taken under subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id63605d1c67154921bcb7847cbbaa8441"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Opportunity to review records by applicant</header><text>In connection with an exchange of a record under this section, the Attorney General shall—</text><clause id="id7f5939bb45c9464c981e094b1d6f8714"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notify the applicant that the applicant can obtain a copy of the record as described in clause (ii) if the applicant demonstrates a reasonable basis for the applicant’s review of the record;</text></clause><clause id="idc060f2ab96154fff97ec9a6c84a226da"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide to the applicant an opportunity, upon request and in accordance with clause (i), to—</text><subclause id="idbd2b0f63134143d5a6a1d9d2c86156ab"><enum>(I)</enum><text>obtain a copy of the record; and</text></subclause><subclause id="ide7a11bff740541358ecf2ecae47b950f"><enum>(II)</enum><text>challenge the accuracy and completeness of the record;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id0555198f9ba34d419e3daab13deee62d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promptly notify the requesting entity of any such challenge;</text></clause><clause id="id18a497f0372548fd9511002225b970d2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date on which the challenge is made, complete an investigation of the challenge;</text></clause><clause id="id49ec3f7fb48b43ff8122f429fda1d7c7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provide to the applicant the specific findings and results of that investigation;</text></clause><clause id="id0e372cfae078414b8ab4afeffa482ff9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>promptly make any changes or deletions to the record required as a result of the challenge; and</text></clause><clause id="id6dfdc3bcdec046dfbd1c88d70f9b2a74"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>report those changes to the requesting entity.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2fb4011e76f645349c6a547310b59df6"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Certain exchanges prohibited</header><clause id="id9e04174ca8f54fa395a819ee1eebce71"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An exchange shall not include any record—</text><subclause id="ida6102f95a84943a899e592f8d466dc17"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except as provided in clause (ii), about an arrest more than 2 years old as of the date of the request for the exchange, that does not also include a disposition (if any) of that arrest;</text></subclause><subclause id="id540a71d3f7824fc388ae05c6b54dbc0e"><enum>(II)</enum><text>relating to an adult or juvenile nonserious offense of the sort described in section 20.32(b) of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on July 1, 2009; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id5958bdacbdf44c9ebaa88f52b9bfe93a"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to the extent the record is not clearly an arrest or a disposition of an arrest.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id729a3b62b1d74de1a6cf7156958f6560"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicants for sensitive positions</header><text>The prohibition under clause (i)(I) shall not apply in the case of a background check that relates to—</text><subclause id="iddb4ad9fba81f441e9e4d91cc978ec57d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>law enforcement employment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id3858e20188704c82a1816f30ac048ca7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any position that a Federal agency designates as a—</text><item id="idfb9d8af29fdc4b66b97b1a0c3e9d29b5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>national security position; or</text></item><item id="idcdb92bdafb3e468e868945dc4c6ce40c"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>high-risk, public trust position.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idd219dc9b56af4e45b86ae95b6f1861eb"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The Attorney General may collect a reasonable fee for an exchange of records for employment-related purposes through the records system created under this section to defray the costs associated with exchanges for those purposes, including any costs associated with the investigation of inaccurate or incomplete records.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id641c61b375f24db18a29dc33ddefcd48"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations on reasonable procedures</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall issue regulations to carry out section 534(g) of title 28, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="id13645bae7c8a4e88b0d77743d8ab5a78"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="id6ec9290819704cbf8f118fe90d727f71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>record</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (g) of section 534 of title 28, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id69d3b2e4f37c4e98bfe5f88807065f2f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of subsection (g) of section 534 of title 28, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), that includes—</text><subparagraph id="id9c2739be054d4d60af7bbff60997bf60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of exchanges of records for employment-related purposes made with entities in each State through the records system created under such section 534;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id14eda888c3a545569255b6b85e0233ab"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any prolonged failure of a Federal agency to comply with a request by the Attorney General for information about dispositions of arrests; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide60000bfef0c49a4a91b46755c48390f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the numbers of successful and unsuccessful challenges to the accuracy and completeness of records, organized by the Federal agency from which each record originated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill>

