<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72353FBFA7DC435A82E538D43FE4771A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8059 IH: Unserialized Firearm Harm Oversight and Serialization Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8059</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260324">March 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001241">Mr. Min</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001226">Ms. Salinas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000606">Mrs. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require serialization of firearms produced through additive manufacturing and of unserialized firearms possessed by federally licensed firearms dealers and gunsmiths, to establish penalties for violations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9D69087871B4497CAFDE8F473EEA998A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC48B5D9C1FEC458C924FCDDE69414FDC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unserialized Firearm Harm Oversight and Serialization Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD6A9D10129014634A693038C45085A27"><enum>2.</enum><header>Codification of Supreme Court decision clarifying that certain firearm assembly kits are firearms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 921(a)(3)(A) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, and any combination of parts which is clearly intended to function, or may readily be converted,</quote> before <quote>to expel a projectile</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H50A0CB5555584469968065D12803428D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Serialization requirement for firearms produced through additive manufacturing</header> <subsection id="H9625860B266B4A3C92D5A822D06FE5B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 923(i) of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3FE9ECCC4E0048C88DB4AE6E6412C77B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> after <quote>(i)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6AF5FC478174FB18E451868D04391C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after and below the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCB77F682E5B84CE496336E4F4D347191" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H964ADD327C924909BC6434C6A5B6AEB7" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person licensed under this section who produces or completes a frame or receiver for a firearm, or a collection of parts that, with other readily available parts, could be used to produce a firearm, through additive manufacturing or any other process involving the use of a technology, machine, or device that enables the creation of such components other than by traditional manufacturing methods, for sale or transfer in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, shall cast or engrave a serial number on the receiver or frame or each part in the collection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H99BBB4C6922B4FF7B88195CFF32DE84B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 921(a) of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0A9430DA0AFC4A3D9631CEBE62FB68AA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H3B2E900068F44C0298708ABB4571D6E2" indent="up1"><enum>(39)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>additive manufacturing</quote> means a process of joining materials to make objects from 3-dimensional model data, usually layer upon layer, including powder bed fusion, material extrusion, directed energy deposition, vat photopolymerization, and binder jetting.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC9CE153D62E4CEEBB7B26CC6774F75B" indent="up1"><enum>(40)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>non-traditional manufacturing method</quote> means any process of producing a firearm, frame, or receiver outside of conventional manufacturing, including additive manufacturing, digital fabrication, or other emerging technologies.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1E84D03FB0142E4B0F7319093742CDF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>Section 924 of such title is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE63CF6E4E8CC48919FE2F44C7CD6221F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H9DE49B2396124078B6312E2ADE3C7673"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Penalties relating to requirement that firearms produced through additive manufacturing have serial numbers</header> <paragraph id="H0AA147DE9F744D48B48B3C0DB63D21C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil penalty for <enum-in-header>1</enum-in-header>st offense</header><text>Whoever knowingly violates section 923(i)(2) shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $10,000.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9AF5E5D560F4EF7BC3278938469DBF0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal penalties for subsequent offense</header><text>Whoever, having been convicted of violating section 923(i)(2), willfully violates such section shall be fined not more than $100,000, imprisoned not less than 1 year, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H7621EB51650B42FCA1BEA9C810D52426"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement that licensed dealer serialize unserialized firearms taken into inventory</header> <subsection id="HFADA8B6E30134848B9CAF2367AF017CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 923(i) of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 3(a) of this Act, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEDA4026617EB4A2AA3E4C042F278CA10" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="HB33CC2901D6347E2B3929C9CFEA902C1" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person licensed under this section who receives a firearm that does not have a serial number engraved or cast on the receiver or frame of the firearm shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H0010E1F797D04452AB33370957A9E639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engrave or cast a serial number on the receiver or frame of the firearm, in such manner as the Attorney General shall by regulations prescribe;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAEF3AD1FF01D49CEB686B92B1B6A87D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transmit to the Attorney General a record of the receipt, which shall set forth the serial number; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8B32493A6EF4A3CBE5C980FB9431215"><enum>(C)</enum><text>keep and maintain a copy of the record.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7E539184422B458EA4DF59EC744117F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of serial number information only in active criminal investigations</header><text>Section 923(i) of such title, as amended by section 3(a) of this Act and subsection (a) of this section, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H04DEBD4CC386400490DFEEA5267DB722" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HFCE5120B92B946EDAB7D82E0DF8264AD" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Attorney General may use information in a record transmitted under paragraph (3)(B) of this subsection only in the course of an ongoing bona fide criminal investigation. The 2nd sentence of section 926(a) shall not apply with respect to the information in any such record.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H601284D2CF2C44948D1F344943843DCC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Firearm dealer serialization credit</header> 
<subsection id="HCEA98D7923814C78AE59EB1E73A83402"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="HA2EFE2CD4F794584B88355612A7901DF" style="OLC"> <section id="H986F859525074CCDB9AFDD313B1F0BF2"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Firearm dealer serialization credit</header> <subsection id="HF538EE1D555342CD8BFAB509D6B11EC0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, in the case of a taxpayer who is licensed under section 923 of title 18, United States Code, to engage in the business of importing, manufacturing, or dealing in firearms, the firearm dealer serialization credit determined under this section for the taxable year shall be an amount equal to the firearm serialization expenditures of the taxpayer for the taxable year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6021451D0076487D8D52172E0A78C82D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Firearm serialization expenditures</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>firearm serialization expenditures</quote> means any amounts paid or incurred during the taxable year to comply with section 923(i)(3) of title 18, United States Code, including the purchase or lease of equipment (or related software) for the engraving or casting of firearms.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4FCBC66DA8544AC68ACC62A8E6109EAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount of firearm serialization expenditures taken into account by the taxpayer under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall not exceed—</text> 
<paragraph id="H866D0C612EF84429B62530FA16347558"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of amounts paid or incurred for the purchase or lease of equipment (or related software) for engraving or casting firearm receivers or frames, $1,000, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62611049ABC94BE2A88A621DE93AE1EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of any other expenditures, the lesser of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB74E2B0A7E27426D9F2D36FE5AC2A342"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an amount that does not exceed $50 for each firearm the engraving or casting of which is required of the taxpayer under section 923(i)(3) of title 18, United States Code, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8B32863240C4A40955743B947E687F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$1,500.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC433FF0A3B7F42C79D5C7E9B7A9D9FBE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Controlled groups</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 41(f) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H27A1F5E122894DBEBF31135FAE9AC4B0"> <enum>(e)</enum> <header>Denial of double benefit</header> <paragraph id="H60FDA25E224C4C46B728833D8ED9A337"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>No deduction</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No deduction shall be allowed for any expenditures taken into account in determining the credit under this section for the taxable year.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                            <paragraph id="H8A4016D1DB8E4BFCAD3962C3428BD83C">
                                <enum>(2)</enum>
                                <header>Basis adjustment</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a credit is determined under this section with respect to any property purchased by the taxpayer, the basis of such property shall be reduced by the amount of the credit so determined with respect to such property.</text>
                            </paragraph>
                        </subsection> 
<subsection id="H974B5176277446CEA8C7153FC8E4E6A5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header> 
<paragraph id="H65F2286134FD49F9A3A4A8F212BA6567"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except to the extent provided in paragraph (2), this section shall not apply to any amount paid or incurred more than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C879D66D6A9418EBEB047D67373D3A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary (after consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives) certifies to Congress that the credit allowed under this section has improved firearm serialization and compliance with related Federal law, paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>7 years</quote> for <quote>5 years</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAF1023214FFB435B8C63FDB67755957F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFF6DA3230491470493762E80D7D6DD0B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H0904BA4B562A4C689AB63487E3B48C0E"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the firearm dealer serialization credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA1832D86CEFF43A8848A9D6BAD5FB55D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA4C25A298897453BA6952FD47CC831F7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45BB. Firearm dealer serialization credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4FDA8B47552E43B68A713C9E53AB59CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8EF7777E70C8477494843A549FAB59B6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No amendment made by this Act shall be interpreted to supersede State law.</text></section> <section id="HE94088B66A9441F4B015A3BF4EE6D3D3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided in section 5(d), the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

