<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC02E299177D4CCFB55D4B4B22B35946" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8865 IH: Protecting Taxpayers from Fraudulent Providers Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8865</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260515">May 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to exclude providers convicted of certain fraud-related criminal offenses from participation in Federal health care programs on a permanent basis.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8D98E80B614D4FBB8887616122022E50" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H372EEFACA5454397AD9F15D6BCD263C8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Taxpayers from Fraudulent Providers Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3748721DA7BC46EF9A1282C4C03FE437"><enum>2.</enum><header>Excluding providers convicted of certain fraud-related criminal offenses from participation in Federal health care programs on a permanent basis</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1128 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320a-7">42 U.S.C. 1320a–7</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H12C99A74F7F54FDBAAC048B7B31BD02D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3)—</text> <subparagraph id="H2159D26BBC7B4C8784EDCF16B145C8E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>subparagraph (G)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (G) and (H)</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC0FFC3A2B51D49139B974609406BE6CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking <quote>In the case of</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraph (H), in the case of</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7598D7E93AC24D57AA77192E32AD8EC3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3571021B70A449389432AE958AE0593E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HBFBB6C9B1ECC4785BAB7FCEABB34E8E7" indent="up2"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an exclusion of an individual or entity under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(3) based on a conviction occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph relating to fraud, theft, embezzlement, breach of fiduciary responsibility, or other financial misconduct, the period of the exclusion shall be permanent.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H316025F051D64095AB0B06A51A5311B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(2)(B)(i), by inserting <quote>(other than such an exclusion under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(3) based on a conviction occurring on or after the date of the enactment of subsection (c)(3)(H) relating to fraud, theft, embezzlement, breach of fiduciary responsibility, or other financial misconduct)</quote> after <quote>paragraph (2)</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FE52A86919B4B7A999E099FDF021B66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBD5D14E581354316946A028CFC443150" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="HC2C349D675B04814A2E6B65928BF14F1" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The preceding provisions of this subsection shall not apply with respect to an exclusion of an individual or entity under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(3) based on a conviction occurring on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph relating to fraud, theft, embezzlement, breach of fiduciary responsibility, or other financial misconduct.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

