<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87D1412185364CD6A843A97EBBEA0E2F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6973 IH: Creating Opportunities to Use Received Student Exam Credit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6973</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001230">Mr. Subramanyam</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001103">Mr. Hernández</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to collect and report information on the treatment of Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate course credits at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8553AEF5DFBF4280B06B776375C5F56C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H87E06247D5C4474D8BDC4521FF02384C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating Opportunities to Use Received Student Exam Credit Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COURSE Credit Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB10879A16D26453ABE50F47D1DE614EE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Data collection and reporting by Department of Education</header> 
<subsection id="HFB56AD4DB858441F88E0B9FE45F5D8D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall collect and annually report on the College Scorecard website (or any successor website) information regarding the treatment of Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate course credits by institutions of higher education.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4E3A33F797774EA2B233DD4091DAC8FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Education shall coordinate with relevant stakeholders within and outside the Department of Education, including the technical review panel of the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1AA34656F41A40FEBB7B6B67018BB83C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The information reported under subsection (a) shall include, with respect to each institution of higher education, the following:</text> <paragraph id="H699F6B56D0BB478AAA25514EBD4EF883"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation of whether the institution provides credits toward a student’s degree for Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate exam scores.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD19F70982BEC46AA819E79C8171BC6AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If the institution does provide such credits, identification of—</text> <subparagraph id="HD22489EAA7664F4E9836C8FB37A5B545"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total maximum number of such credits that may be provided to an individual student for a given program of study;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H415EDA329A474F46B4827CB4390A0789"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the minimum score a student must earn on an Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate exam for the institution to provide the credits and, if applicable, whether such minimum score differs based on the subject matter of the exam or the student’s program of study; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H273203651E3D4A9CBAA90E2C8CF31030"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type of credit provided by the institution for a given exam score, whether it be full course credit, elective credit, or a course exemption, and an explanation of whether the type of credit provided or the score required to receive such credit differs based on the degree program of the student.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCC33FE5392AF4CAA91BC2FC1A5A2290C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other information with respect to an institution’s policy on the treatment of Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate course credits that the Secretary of Education considers relevant.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA5734E2E846E493A958C0B2CBEEFD991"><enum>3.</enum><header>Dissemination of information by institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 485(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8F329282B31C4F79A1FBC3AB4AA7B030"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4385D0EE2544FCD9517E5539EF6AD83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (U), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCCDD628EA33A4DA5AED3E2252BEECBB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (V), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H708DF9FEB7844558A7E310A8B5B8D91B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4477F70C7D504935971BE74574EB3ADA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="HD05F1F0F742E4300B38FD4293479A645"><enum>(W)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">institutional policies regarding the treatment of Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate course credits, including all information required to be published under subsection (n).</text></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H594D97A10C004FE3A46BE62BCB1D6031"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAFE064FFDCC04D0FAD6AF407892D0024" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H902BACF96BA547E6954804F2C22737E6"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Information on treatment of AP and IB course credits</header> 
<paragraph id="H8A4AE814AE8340C0A58E8C783DF98618"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each institution of higher education participating in any program under this title shall publish, in a prominent location on the public website of the institution, information regarding the treatment of Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate course credits by the institution. Such information shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H12F982A8FC5F463B982B7A9CF7FC76CB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of whether the institution provides credits toward a student’s degree for Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate exam scores;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE10C25E9C35F42CB8A6BC5BA73E52E45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the institution does provide such credits, identification of—</text> <clause id="H33F1219191B341FFA2FFB5912CF22131"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total maximum number of such credits that may be provided to an individual student for a given program of study;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFEA66B59065D449BB35DD406E4FDEA74"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the minimum score a student must earn on an Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate exam for the institution to provide the credits and, if applicable, whether such minimum score differs based on the subject matter of the exam or the student’s program of study; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9868343659404629BD9CF5B0EBCFF046"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type of credit provided by the institution for a given exam score, whether it be full course credit, elective credit, or a course exemption, and an explanation of whether the type of credit provided or the score required to receive such credit differs based on the degree program of the student; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD4700B17AB742BB9947C2422E6BF263"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other information with respect to the institution’s policy on the treatment of Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate course credits that the institution considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H507350EB429F44EE801D4C91E2E285B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The information required to be published under paragraph (1) shall be updated by the institution, as necessary, to ensure it remains accurate and current.</text></paragraph> </subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

