<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H300F6AAB695A4FCD9E4FB2228C614998" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 904 IH: Recognizing November 30, 2025, as “Yom Haplitim” or “Jewish Refugee Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000601">Mr. Goldman of Texas</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Workforce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Recognizing November 30, 2025, as <quote>Yom Haplitim</quote> or <quote>Jewish Refugee Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas November 30 is commemorated as <quote>Yom Haplitim</quote>, otherwise known as <quote>Jewish Refugee Day</quote>;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas November 30 is marked as a day of recognition for the 900,000 Jewish people who were exiled from the Arab world during the early years of the State of Israel;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas Jewish people lived continuously in North Africa, the Middle East, and the Gulf region for over 2,500 years;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas Jewish people were subjected to societal and political discrimination and denigration over generations but persevered as citizens who contributed significantly to the culture and development of Egypt, Lebanon, Syria, Iraq, Yemen, Libya, Morocco, and several other Arab and Muslim-majority countries;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas, in the wake of World War II and the Arab-Israeli War of 1948, entire Jewish communities were forced from the countries in which they had lived for millennia;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas many refugees fleeing in the wake of war became citizens of Israel, and they and their descendants are an indispensable part of Israeli society;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas many Jewish refugees also migrated to the United States, where they have made meaningful contributions to our Nation’s culture and history; and</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Congress continues to support the security of the State of Israel and the Jewish people around the world: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H22BBADF872114042925E1CE41D42ACBF"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H9566FBE998834E3893BBD9765E278425"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HBD697F6179E748128BC36046A931A4B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes and commemorates <quote>Yom Haplitim</quote>, or <quote>Jewish Refugee Day</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2C945220ED664EB0AA246DE3D93FAA2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes the hardships of the Jewish people and condemns antisemitism in all its forms;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5551CBE4B71341EEA1937D757EE7C554"><enum>(3)</enum><text>calls for educational efforts throughout the United States, the Middle East, and North Africa to teach the history of the forced displacement and exile of the Jewish people; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0CC4A3E2B25D427F84D42ECECF7CC639"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supports efforts in safeguarding the well-being of the Jewish people against present and future threats.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution> 

