<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A618E51654443CDB1FB13E2E8840EDD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6217 IH: Revitalize Our Neighborhoods Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6217</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251120">November 20, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001225">Mr. Sorensen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000488">Mr. Thanedar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001315">Ms. Budzinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000621">Ms. Randall</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to make grants to eligible entities for use to eliminate blight and assist in neighborhood revitalization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8AFF08B86AF4488AE3D828198C70C25" style="OLC"><section id="H026E46A36F0249109BD179B72DDC5BD2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Revitalize Our Neighborhoods Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE44169C0DC1F45128030920375CD2D29"><enum>2.</enum><header>Blight elimination and neighborhood revitalization grants</header><subsection id="H3358A441D2E34FA6B22DA67BD7962C97"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may make grants under this section, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities for use for eligible activities designed to eliminate blight and promote neighborhood revitalization.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1E63B76AEE54D43BAD1732297CB03A0"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Use in low-Income areas</header> <text>Amounts from a grant awarded under this section may be used only to carry out eligible activities within low-income communities.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="H306C3AD38C2D49AC9EC5A8ACDA972108"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, and entity shall be—</text><paragraph id="H3E24E20AB8774FF6AFF09F81C6A6F084"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35BD8F9A8C0747E4AD4A840250B92951"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a unit of general local government, including a city, county, town, parish, village, or other general-purpose political subdivision of a State; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7561376E544CB3B0ED3F4AC4641C83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a multi-jurisdictional entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H205E94D8523C4E2CA963379F17DCAEAA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><paragraph id="H0060DD40164C4360B4C366AF424AFD6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts from a grant awarded under this section may be used only for the following activities:</text><subparagraph id="H860BCF1310F14F048E3C155074659658"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Demolition, clearance, and removal of blighted structures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34A2DB31366044EE9921574C0E2A6A62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Boarding of vacant properties and blighted structures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8211024C1B2D4A85A472AB318A5528B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Deconstruction of structures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB50F030B4C584759905D2FE6D72AF08D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Removal of waste and site clearance and vacant land management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04D096B5959E498B9A3CC50183B34634"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Renovation of existing structures that are blighted or abandoned.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00D2A02D6A25409AAD5B52EDCEFB06B3" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Construction or preservation of affordable rental or owner-occupied housing as an outcome of blight elimination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC73A806AC24249B7AE5E4F9DFAC00EA6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Administrative costs, including for staffing and compliance with grant requirements, in an amount that is not more than 10 percent of the total grant for the recipient.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A8AC8B409DD4A94839BBCE6BD75F945" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of amounts by land banks, Community Housing Development Organizations, and local governments</header><subparagraph id="H285A76C53A3E40259B16E463F4E8B24E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of grant under this section that may provide such grant amounts to land banks or Community Housing Development Organizations (as such term is defined in section 104 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12704">42 U.S.C. 12704(1)</external-xref>)) to carry out eligible activities within low-income communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A2172A80EE49FABA4F0973D67823F6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State grantees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a grant under this section that is a State may provide such grant amounts to units of general local government whose jurisdictions include low-income communities to carry out eligible activities within such low-income communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E44603A1BC46408E43E6DC41F57A1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts from a grant awarded under this section may not be used to acquire any occupied residential dwelling unit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C73EF3063B44BA8B8FD5DAA5681C975"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><paragraph id="H7A19CD8436B6457DBA52C45568A40B8D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section to contribute an amount of matching funds that is equal to or greater than 15 percent of the amount of the grant, to be used for eligible activities under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDF1A026900146CC9BBDB5FC161FA848"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Source of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts from the following sources may be counted towards compliance with the requirement under paragraph (1):</text><subparagraph id="HFCC8D32ABF514F6FAFB3644E9D836891"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any amounts received pursuant to any Federal program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BF5C55E493E4441B14A1F30B94929A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any amounts provided by the applicants.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9667294F271B47D595A5F46BB27B1F9F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any proceeds from sales of properties renovated using grant amounts under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H626092FF0A1E40948E16A0EA2051B3D2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application and plan</header><paragraph id="HC2CCBC5056474933BD2FCC699BDA0AD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section may only be provided to an eligible entity that submits to the Secretary an application for such a grant that contains a plan for use of grant funds in accordance with paragraph (2) and such other information, certifications, and assurances as the Secretary considers necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H959F66D533CA4F5B81445BE5EFBA1088"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>A plan under this paragraph shall be a detailed 5-year plan for the use of grant amounts awarded under this section and matching amounts contributed that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H330A64143988486D95707F1330C6B54C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identification of the low-income communities in which eligible activities under subsection (d)(1) will be carried out using grant and matching amounts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA24ED0CFEC0A4916AB034DBB1CFEE6BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the eligible activities under subsection (d)(1) to be carried out using grant and matching amounts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36905542EE6E49939E70C3CBA6AEE8BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a timetable for carrying out such eligible activities, which shall provide for the expenditure of grant and matching amounts within 5 years after receipt; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6170146622B44ABA8ACB822909E43CA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identification of the sources of matching amounts to be provided and assurances of the availability of such matching amounts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE156C7EFD3D4AE7A940838CFF4F0A3D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Selection; criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select applications to receive grants under this section pursuant to a competition and based on criteria as established by the Secretary for such selection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H57F79B02C2CD4D59AE1DEC5C2B6C44A3" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Coordination with other Federal programs</header><text>An eligible entity that receives grant amounts under this section may use such grant amounts in coordination with the eligible activities of other Federal programs, including with—</text><paragraph id="HFAF6CE4D54F045DE96C52446D26CC252" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Community Development Block Grant program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE2BED485B2141F2B43BA0A25DE332EA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the HOME Investment Partnership program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1714D44FC3A5400F882535294462B702" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Housing Trust Fund;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4731B22413BD495991018EEB85F36FBF" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC961009514C74593B01D6863D0C526BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency Brownfields Program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBED85DF15414E05A5341A23C58B58B5" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the New Market Tax Credit program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4C4C918D7B1438F9AC01F649D07D7F1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><paragraph id="HB3433239969548C0902D6FEC13E61DAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to eligible entities that receive a grant under this section for the life cycle of the grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADC162FA972845259BEBABB2C572116F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may not use more than 5 percent of amounts appropriated under this section for technical assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A575B0D9002448B82C7872A2F50AE95"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HB96C9BFF080240EAACA1D6E89C47741F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grantee reports</header><subparagraph id="HB0B46F7D2A7C4E9B827C8477262F2C07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 15 months after receiving an initial grant under this section, and annually thereafter, a recipient of such grant shall submit to the Secretary a report on the activities funded with amounts under this section, through a report template developed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E7AA3693195473BB7A51CD2E7B1211D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The report required under subparagraph (A) shall include a description of—</text><clause id="HBD8CF5A662A942A9B8A24F5B0057E7A0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>amounts used for the matching requirement;</text></clause><clause id="H659D889918974E949381F86F1CC2F10B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>amounts used for eligible activities funded under this section, apart from the amounts provided under this section;</text></clause><clause id="HB7018EE67EDD43D782CAABDD05B817F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>resources made available by amounts provided under this section;</text></clause><clause id="H9478332A51B64A3CAD6A5ACA6FF80B27"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how the recipient invested amounts under this section;</text></clause><clause id="H294D697431904C7B8EB154194311021C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the geographic distribution of such investments;</text></clause><clause id="HF4D538A7371C409DAA0F0633952AD265"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the families and persons assisted under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="HF23313CB55904532A1746BA80C1B61A6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the progress meeting planned objectives using amounts provided under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C54CC2675864F48AB75600366DD7A97"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the reports submitted under this paragraph publicly available on a website of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D10E921D71A45719441D393CD68BC81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GAO reports</header><subparagraph id="HA7409666AE894CE193ED21E446B6A80C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after initial grant awards are provided under this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Congress a report that describes, with respect to the grant program under this section—</text><clause id="HB7AABC6B86814BE5880D9B91E020F89C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>planned projects;</text></clause><clause id="H2C012176850B4D83BB6162DECC8B5DD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>populations impacted;</text></clause><clause id="HC123262034C247F0955C425D404F48E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">challenges and recommendations; and</text></clause><clause id="H60DEC8E8C5354BCBAAB883091CD02E05"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>expected outcomes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF74B3093D7DD4E82A55A283303A43AFD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 years after initial grant awards are provided under this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Congress a report that describes, with respect to the grant program under this section—</text><clause id="H60A1B167B1D6441893B81501CBCDB0CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>final outcomes;</text></clause><clause id="HE9BECE9E630B43FAA91381E25907F9B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the implementation and projects completed;</text></clause><clause id="H5425E48B86C745DD84C7A332BFAB8C37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>populations impacted; and</text></clause><clause id="H38CB41D5A606488FBDA7E278F77538E5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>challenges and recommendations for future recipients of grants under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53264AD88A54480DA74A128C0C5C608F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</text><paragraph id="H99A8C7C336E9450F925241E04105A67F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abandoned</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>abandoned</quote> means, with respect to an unoccupied structure—</text><subparagraph id="H34A91DE731F749BB9231712B4AFC3A98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the mortgage, tribal leasehold, or tax payments are at least 90 days delinquent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA34ABD43F73049F9938CC477E36F9F82"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a code enforcement inspection has determined that the property is not habitable and the owner has taken no corrective actions within 90 days of notification of the deficiencies; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BE027B0653E4CEA9BB7A53F4E89EAE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the structure is subject to a court-ordered receivership or nuisance abatement related to abandonment pursuant to State or local law or otherwise meets a State definition of an abandoned structure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H530682CBF1C348079AFA5E5CE82D365A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affordable rental or owner-occupied housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>affordable rental or owner-occupied housing</quote> means housing that qualifies as affordable under section 215 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12745">42 U.S.C. 12745</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C9C159C0C7D4BD0AB94D8398B56AE98" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Blighted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>blighted</quote> means a structure that exhibits determinable signs of deterioration sufficient to constitute a threat to human health, safety, and public welfare, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07781EDD606F4F3DA12631EF850B4535"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Land bank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>land bank</term> means a government entity, agency, or program, or a special purpose nonprofit entity formed by 1 or more units of government in accordance with a State or local law with respect to land banks, that has been designated by 1 or more State or local governments to acquire, steward, and dispose of vacant, abandoned, or other problem properties in accordance with locally determined priorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H666F29C527A948D89457D063CD7964FA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Low-income community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>low-income community</term> has the meaning given such term in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45D">section 45D</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45D">26 U.S.C. 45D</external-xref>) and includes any census tract or other area that is treated as a low-income community for purposes of such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7545211A29F04E9EB92B2FCDED0D9575"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Multi-jurisdictional entity</header><text>The term <quote>multi-jurisdictional entity</quote> means an association of local governments or public agencies which are bound by a collective agreement, as determined appropriate by the Secretary for the purpose of carrying out the eligible activities under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H136A38E419AF4E94A046A41631C42FC1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD3BE6600D91048C4A8892CC2DE12AA28"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB45C88815ED454A9328BF9AE3F31D23"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Structure</header><text>The term <term>structure</term> includes residential structures and commercial structures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6F1CC1C5554E6EBB0D9AD20C87B6D9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Unoccupied</header><text>The term <quote>unoccupied</quote> means a structure that—</text><subparagraph id="H6F2527C7128A4845B036F242E7BCD281"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has no occupants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB72750B499864C698BBC35090A973149"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not being maintained for seasonal use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74AF62F5FD784B05B7C42E49DE15DF4F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is not actively marketed for sale or rent; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29045D4502D74FF1885C479465C45D1C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>is not being held vacant pending re-occupancy by a buyer or tenant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAF92BF54555408BAEFC3504C48194D5"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may issue any regulations necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02825D3A8BCB40CDA177828DC8DA5173"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2031.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

