<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7B8A2F5EB67642DDBF8458F050ABAA65" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8746 IH: Violent Incident Clearance and Technological Investigative Methods Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8746</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to establish a grant program to establish, implement, and administer violent incident clearance and technology investigative methods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H062D4C08748047BBAB23BAFED9BB395B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H4BF6214BF7AD4E0FB323A064292AA36E"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Violent Incident Clearance and Technological Investigative Methods Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>VICTIM Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8F96BE6C3ADB4D409B05CB96141C81EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program with respect to violent incident clearance and technological investigative methods</header> <subsection id="H545BADAA92C84145BD15F8CB35C5892D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H574B086097224FA5BD7B44245EE24A9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clearance by arrest</header><text>The term <term>clearance by arrest</term>, with respect to an offense reported to a law enforcement agency, means the law enforcement agency—</text> <subparagraph id="H62D384E9B4504992B5F7BA8E9EE9E1A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has—</text> 
<clause id="H93704810D7AF4EF49D22123CE31A91B7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>arrested not less than 1 person for the offense;</text></clause> <clause id="HF89613A63C954DCE8A656E53A2EFBF96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>charged the person described in clause (i) with the commission of the offense; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6896794C9DFE44D4BE8944CCA827BE15"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>referred the person described in clause (i) for prosecution for the offense; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBCFBFF37FB0A422380FA8467848FF159"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has cited an individual under the age of 18 to appear in juvenile court or before another juvenile authority with respect to the offense, regardless of whether a physical arrest occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24E69B6F577844648BECBE4523A1B7F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clearance by exception</header><text>The term <term>clearance by exception</term>, with respect to an offense reported to a law enforcement agency, means the law enforcement agency—</text> <subparagraph id="HC02232063D564FB6A39F4182B05C8D9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has identified not less than 1 person suspected of the offense; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9661A96FDB5B4ED9B5E68D8C1AB2D7A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the suspect described in subparagraph (A), has—</text> <clause id="HB691BB37A2384D59B0715C5F7B12890A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>gathered enough evidence to—</text> 
<subclause id="H31D9D6040E0A4AFF8FFD787F6425D25E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>support an arrest of the suspect;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2FC45444BA5445DF9FB6A1FC7FBEC1A8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>make a charge against the suspect; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H13949E9A904E4855AAA8460C84AD197D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>refer the suspect for prosecution;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD46A9C8F41F64EBCB6FE32C743615056"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identified the location of the suspect so that the suspect could be taken into custody immediately; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6F0A4B7F29AC4789AD4B8B9C981BB158"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>encountered a circumstance outside the control of the law enforcement agency that prohibits the agency from arresting the suspect, charging the suspect, or referring the suspect for prosecution, including—</text> <subclause id="HB92C02978233420AB1D55BEC81F56095"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the death of the suspect; </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC3C50EB6EF0F4ABEBAF5EE3863823D12"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the refusal of the victim to cooperate with the prosecution after the suspect has been identified; or </text></subclause> <subclause id="H66A783DAF01A469EBE9CE61ACB6D5135"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the denial of extradition because the suspect committed an offense in another jurisdiction and is being prosecuted for that offense.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3371B4A4E6A24927AF0E944C2B22529B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clearance rate</header><text>The term <term>clearance rate</term>, with respect to a law enforcement agency, means the quotient obtained by dividing— </text> <subparagraph id="H54FD77DCEA08462FB53185CAE78D5B15"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the number of offenses cleared by the law enforcement agency, including through clearance by arrest and clearance by exception; by </text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H030B7452C3874CA98B7FDE1609DBB89F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of offenses reported to the law enforcement agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9B4F67D592564B8E81FBA9D8E85C82A1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State, Tribal, or local law enforcement agency or a group of such law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80F69ADF73E04485BC51D1705591C88B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant recipient</header><text>The term <term>grant recipient</term> means a recipient of a grant under the Program. </text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6ACD32B1ACDC4A968C398EDC1F910CCB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement agency</term> means a public agency charged with policing functions, including any component bureau of the agency (such as a governmental victim services program or village public safety officer program), including an agency composed of officers or persons referred to in subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 2(10) of the Indian Law Enforcement Reform Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2801">25 U.S.C. 2801(10)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCA1AA0B23479482B9B85D21B8ECE41DF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the grant program established under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H889B082867934B91B1662D56F0CB0C2B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Rural</header><text>The term <term>rural</term> means an area that is not located in a metropolitan statistical area, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD55BBA4F5AE64635981307DD800DA891"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program</header> 
<paragraph id="H3C02A82A31F14B3E89E8742BCD9272F4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish a grant program within the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services under which the Attorney General awards grants to eligible entities to establish, implement, and administer violent incident clearance and technological investigative methods.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB56564E3ED4A4ABCB79F1713792E6F81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under the Program shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD690CA61EA4A48E9A477D182CB45943F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9AD80362DB0443495357E588862408E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of each eligible project under paragraph (4) that the grant will fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBDFC60E8C3841659DF7EDF698CB4488"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients</header><text>The Attorney General, in selecting a recipient of a grant under the Program, shall—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4FA75736FD584B4B972A5F693EAF45D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider solely the specific plan and activities proposed by the applicant to improve clearance rates for homicides and firearm-related violent crimes, notwithstanding other Department policies for grant eligibility; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE8F5CFE02B7249098DC4F2178EAD33CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop criteria to ensure that funds are distributed to rural and urban applicants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF5E617FF197430DA5FD1F7FB65146AD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>A grant recipient shall use the grant for activities with the specific objective of improving clearance rates for homicides and firearm-related violent crimes, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H64A83C049CED4647B23A741E988D2CFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hiring and training additional personnel who will be assigned to investigate homicides and firearm-related violent crimes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8136AA11F63643869632C0B2D8163398"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring the retention of personnel who are assigned to investigate homicides and firearm-related violent crimes as of the date of receipt of the grant;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F7E13CCFDA04A0FA183BC8E949E2790"><enum>(C)</enum><text>hiring and training personnel for collection, processing, and forensic testing of evidence;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA39B798F02F0407292D6E3BC2B5277A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>acquiring, upgrading, or replacing investigative, evidence-processing, or forensic testing technology or equipment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF69CF28F6B80410DBBEAF578B39E00F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>developing competitive and evidence-based programs to improve clearance rates for homicides and firearm-related violent crimes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19F0BE293ABB452992B818D6F001C815"><enum>(F)</enum><text>hiring and training of personnel to analyze violent crime and the temporal and geographic trends among homicides and firearm-related violent crimes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA9C17BC03D34DDC91C5256A46C570B9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>retaining experts to conduct a detailed analysis of homicides and firearm-related violent crimes using Gun Violence Problem Analysis (commonly known as <quote>GVPA</quote>) or a similar research methodology;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0CDB64725646427183D7B1D7A124537D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>development and implementation of policies that safeguard civil rights and civil liberties during the collection, processing, and forensic testing of evidence;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB3D58E403DB42D1811691E16FA01018"><enum>(I)</enum><text>establishing programs to support officers who experience stress or trauma as a result of responding to or investigating homicides or other violent crime incidents;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE52A6A2B0C6449AB464E915E5441A49"><enum>(J)</enum><text>developing policies, procedures, and training to improve clearance rates for homicides and firearm-related violent crimes, including implementing best practices relating to—</text> 
<clause id="HD07F4E4364664954AD108EB9208E4A03"><enum>(i)</enum><text>improving internal agency cooperation, organizational oversight and accountability, and supervision of investigations;</text></clause> <clause id="HFB53089B99154E23937A7F439DB547E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>developing specific goals and performance metrics for both investigators and investigative units;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA04A4AC0CFBF4BEDADB83C25FA6302F8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strengthening relationships with communities the agency serves; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCCCE55F2F96C402582B6EEBFFB6B6363"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>collaboration with and among other law enforcement agencies and criminal justice organizations;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08B3F7F50FF44A10B3019C104DF2E75A"><enum>(K)</enum><text>ensuring victims of firearm-related violent crimes, and family members of victims of homicides, have appropriate access to emergency food, housing, clothing, travel, and transportation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C6B99D163B94729B93B6CB334DF575D"><enum>(L)</enum><text>training to address the needs of victims of firearm-related violent crimes, and family members of victims of homicides, or collaborating with trained victim advocates and specialists to better meet the needs of victims and family members of victims;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE60687896CE2442EAE4FBB66AC38435B"><enum>(M)</enum><text>developing best practices for improving access to and acceptance of victim services, including victim services that promote medical and psychological wellness, ongoing counseling, legal advice, and financial compensation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EEAD45974284A738C357C12038550F3"><enum>(N)</enum><text>training personnel in trauma-informed interview techniques; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3CD98EADD444AD1A1493E5AB9218254" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(O)</enum><text>ensuring language and disability access supports are provided to victims and their families so that victims can exercise their rights and participate in the criminal justice process. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC9D21D382DA145879B1FC07C7393B23C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Grant funds made available under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, Federal and non-Federal funds available for carrying out the activities described in this section. </text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFF2827EB2CBA44E99C09D372C52E820A"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hiring</header><text>A grant recipient using funds for hiring personnel under subsection (b)(4)(A) shall make a good faith effort to determine whether an applicant with prior law enforcement experience has a disciplinary record or internal investigation record by—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3E87433CFF34910827BFECC7AD8D710"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting a search of the National Decertification Index and, if available, the National Law Enforcement Accountability Database; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8CCC6CCE1CA147D7A0FE2BBFFD269913"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requesting the personnel record of the applicant from each law enforcement agency that employed the applicant.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD3B1A60CB60F496183DB6F0A8B5F4832"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report by grant recipient</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving a grant under the Program, and each year thereafter until a final report is submitted regarding fiscal year 2032, a grant recipient shall submit to the Attorney General a report on the activities carried out using the grant during the preceding fiscal year, including, if applicable—</text> 
<paragraph id="HEA16DB6309F04603AB7249ED2C3EC94C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of personnel assigned to investigate homicides and firearm-related violent crimes hired by the grant recipient;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H245525C8D991433BA89D0F84E7A70EC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of personnel hired for collecting, processing, and forensic testing of evidence by the grant recipient;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1090E742EFDD458191E3F7A58E473619"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any training that is designed to assist in the solving of homicides and firearm-related violent crimes and improve clearance rates;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC94C0A9BC3E7409B945BBE23EAADA135"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any new investigative, evidence-processing, or forensic technology or equipment purchased or any upgrades made to existing (as of the date on which the grant was awarded) investigative, evidence-processing, or forensic technology or equipment, and the associated cost;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1308DF23A2B4FF39B2E029004BE3CCD"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of investigative, evidence-processing, or forensic technology or equipment purchased with the grant to determine whether the technology or equipment satisfies the objectives of the use of the technology or equipment in increasing clearance rates, and any policies in place to govern the use of the technology or equipment;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA68B2EB7CC714978AF13F62D109698FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the internal policies and oversight used to ensure that any technology purchased through the grant for the purposes of improving clearance rates does not violate the civil rights and civil liberties of individuals;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8C6F96DF02B84B4CA49F805933A49FAA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>data regarding clearance rates for homicides and firearm-related violent crimes, including the rate of clearances by arrest and clearances by exception, and crime trends from within each jurisdiction in which the grant recipient carried out activities supported by the grant;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA4625B54EE04B78A38D9C3063F16E63"><enum>(8)</enum><text>data on the race, sex, and age of victims of homicides and firearm-related violent crimes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1276E4D1C981442B99DCBFB903CEB72E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>data on the race, sex, and age of suspects of homicides and firearm-related violent crimes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAB05A5CB8164494A35A546F8B18D6A2"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the length and outcomes of each investigation, including whether the investigation was cleared by arrest or exception; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EE3F165DFAF4CE7AE7427227D4B6272"><enum>(11)</enum><text>to the extent reasonably available, identification of the services most used by victims and their families and identification of additional services needed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5DDA07BBA2DB417A914654D22365E538"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clearance Rate Reporting</header><text>If 2 or more law enforcement agencies collaborate on a criminal investigation that results in a clearance, only the agency that initiated the investigation shall include that clearance in the report submitted under subsection (e).</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC4C60A2008C43D493A2802D8CA9BBAA"><enum>(g)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant oversight</header> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EE88C86397B4AB18AC5F119FFCE2629"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All grants awarded by the Attorney General under this section shall be subject to the requirements under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF29C114F72A944939BC39C491CD18A58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Audit requirement</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF5C0FA57A6A446AE80068F7CE9498025"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>unresolved audit finding</term> means a finding in the final audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that the audited grant recipient has used grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved within 12 months from the date on which the final audit report is issued.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EBCE90B74F84CACAEF1B5D4B4FD2DD8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audits</header> 
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D8AE902E82D41DB9EAB502F4F08C4F9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the first fiscal year after the date of establishment of the Program, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of grant recipients under this section to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds by grant recipients.</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C53E6FF5E70437BAA05E88B7F3ED4A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Selection of grant recipients for audit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall determine the appropriate number of grant recipients to be audited each year.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB21B9D379434CD787799C0B6A8587CB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mandatory exclusion</header><text>A grant recipient that is found to have an unresolved audit finding shall not be eligible to receive grant funds under this section during the fiscal year following the 12-month period after the final audit report has been issued.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBECD80E6F5B7453C9F02165B4D14CF18"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Annual certification</header> <text>Not later than the end of the fiscal year during which audits commence under paragraph (2)(B)(i), and each fiscal year thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary </committee-name>and the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00" >Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> and the<committee-name committee-id="HAP00"> Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name> a certification, including—</text>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="HD38649F57613419BBDD66EF0C5EB9F3B">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCEFB6D28DF214487BB258F6B9087D6F0"> <enum>(i)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all audits conducted by the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice under paragraph (2) have been completed and reviewed by the appropriate Assistant Attorney General; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                            id="HFBFA7291BF7F45549B00D8B2079165BF">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>all mandatory exclusions required under paragraph (2)(C) have been issued; and</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"
                        id="H5A468BF6336A428A89A0D49EE5866F36">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>a list of any grant recipients excluded from receiving grant funds under paragraph (2)(C) from the previous fiscal year.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AF2F4D7661F406984D70219C51141EC"><enum>(h)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">National institute of justice evaluation and report to congress</header> 
<paragraph id="H71E6C5579A7A414DB6ED37EBF42A3A6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Director of the National Institute of Justice shall conduct an evaluation of—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E410F23A55A41EB9E196BB3E5CE08A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the practices deployed by grant recipients to identify policies and procedures that have successfully improved clearance rates for homicides and firearm-related violent crimes; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB946AAAE8444243B390812A90D4FB9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the efficacy of any services provided to victims and family members of victims of homicides and firearm-related violent crimes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB891BB88CC1A4B09AA3B87917DDB0136"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after completion of an evaluation by the Director of the National Institute of Justice under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0454350E606A43EAB3CA5AFEE700F0C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the evaluation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H625811E2033F477A88C2A430D8181023"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information reported by each grant recipient under subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07E786F4C4DB4D428A1C8D15E0D85C5D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application Process</header> 
<paragraph id="H954F7ABD8AEA49589AD95BE4663E9188"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Barriers</header><text>The Attorney General shall determine whether barriers exist to establishing a streamlined application process for grants under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0F5429C26B64E32883AF1BCA2D635F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header> <subparagraph id="H6FC9164C26AE474A98F5CB26D8CB8658"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report that includes a plan to implement a streamlined application process for grants under this section under which an eligible entity seeking a grant under this section can reasonably complete the application in not more than 2 hours.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB0659C8804884F57889DEE7094ACE41F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of plan</header><text>The plan required under subparagraph (A) may include a plan for—</text> <clause id="H559C84AAFC6E414DA34F4419819605C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>proactively providing eligible local governments seeking a grant under this section with information on the data such eligible local governments will need to prepare before beginning the grant application; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7A836EC5FF3C466E950C8827BFB5A6EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring technical assistance is available for eligible local governments seeking a grant under this section before and during the grant application process, including through dedicated liaisons within the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5DAF253583C342788DE24B0292366F32"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>In selecting eligible local governments to receive grants under this section, the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services shall use the streamlined application process described in paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4ED7CEEACDF04B55B68CB83EC86CCABE"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Attorney General shall develop criteria governing the award of grants under this section to ensure that the funds are distributed as widely as practicable in terms of geographical location and to both large and small law enforcement agencies. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H78381344DD084360A557AB0F0F7BD15F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <paragraph id="H33940BD74F884AF38C5D9EAC468D2D5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2031.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA85366D110EA4037837EF4664A2E4142"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Percent for certain eligible entities or projects</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA1B49CD4B93749FBB767BF1A3B5C3C5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Tribal entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall use at least 5 percent of the amount made available under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year to award grants under the Program to Tribal law enforcement agencies or Tribal prosecuting offices, or groups of such agencies or offices.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5CB1F72D00574799A4A1261C44939679"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rural entities</header><text>The Attorney General shall use at least 5 percent of the amount made available under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year to award grants under the Program to law enforcement agencies classified as rural.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

