<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN26025-WF7-SX-RT3"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 581 IS: Honoring the life of Corporal Grade One Matthew T. “Ty” Snook of the Delaware State Police.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 581</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260113">January 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S430">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Honoring the life of Corporal Grade One Matthew T. <quote>Ty</quote> Snook of the Delaware State Police.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas Corporal Grade One Matthew T. <quote>Ty</quote> Snook was a devoted law enforcement officer who served the State of Delaware with honor, integrity, and courage;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corporal Grade One Snook was a husband, a father, a son, a brother, a coach, and a mentor whose life reflected a deep commitment to family, service, and community;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corporal Grade One Snook was a 10-year veteran of the Delaware State Police and was widely respected by his colleagues for his professionalism and dedication;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corporal Grade One Snook served as a field training officer beginning in 2018, helping to shape and mentor the next generation of Delaware State Troopers, and trained more than 20 troopers who continue to serve the State;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corporal Grade One Snook was known for his love of coaching and mentoring young people and for his steadfast commitment to the community he served;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on December 23, 2025, Corporal Grade One Snook was tragically killed in the line of duty while working an overtime assignment at a Division of Motor Vehicles (referred to in this preamble as <quote>DMV</quote>) facility near New Castle, Delaware;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corporal Grade One Snook was killed during an act of senseless violence while protecting DMV employees and members of the public during the holiday season;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas more than 50 employees and members of the public were present at the facility at the time of the shooting and Corporal Grade One Snook gave directions and pushed an employee out of harm’s way, even after being mortally wounded himself, to save the lives of others while giving his own;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Delawareans mourn the loss of Corporal Grade One Snook and recognize his extraordinary sacrifice;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the service of Corporal Grade One Snook exemplified the highest ideals of law enforcement and public service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Corporal Grade One Snook is remembered as an American hero whose legacy will endure through his family, the Delaware State Police, and the community he served; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the sacrifice made by Corporal Grade One Snook stands as a solemn reminder of the risks faced daily by law enforcement officers across the United States: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id17786fc65de84ea9a32a7e5c8fd8267a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>honors the life and service of Corporal Grade One Matthew T. <quote>Ty</quote> Snook of the Delaware State Police;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc0fd94935f97423cb9429d1502799c58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses its deepest condolences to the family of Corporal Grade One Snook, including his wife, Lauren Snook, his daughter, Letty Snook, his parents, Matthew and Karen Snook, his brother, Joshua Snook, and his sister, Kassi Dunphy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideeef655562fb457dac665c06421ec90d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the noble acts Corporal Grade One Snook performed in the line of duty, sacrificing his own life on December 23, 2025, to save the lives of others; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id483d72be4eac4b668c09824a682212f1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirms its support for law enforcement officers and public servants who dedicate their lives to keeping our communities safe.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

