<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26938-560-N2-RK8"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4746 IS: American Innovation and Choice Online Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4746</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260610">June 10, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S153">Mr. Grassley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S370">Mr. Booker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide that certain discriminatory conduct by covered platforms shall be unlawful, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Innovation and Choice Online Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id9e490c8425b94849bb14fb03173d48ac"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection id="id6edaced48df34597a46c0e97dc44d529"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="id61359cb8be5d4ae0a027ae6f329b4c27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Antitrust laws; person</header><text>The terms <quote>antitrust laws</quote> and <quote>person</quote> have the meanings given the terms in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd9542c490f354964af977d23111735a6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Average annual gross revenues</header><text>The term <term>average annual gross revenues</term> means, with respect to a person, the average of the total gross revenues or net sales of the person and all entities controlled by the person for the 2 most recently completed fiscal years, as reflected in the consolidated financial statements of the person prepared in the ordinary course of business.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id05d791745bb7449893294f8c32eb7d7c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business user</header><text>The term <term>business user</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id1021044e34744a28a9a9b5896e8b99f6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a person that uses or is likely to use a systemically important platform to advertise, sell, provide products or services, or access users and customers, including such persons that are operating a systemically important platform or are controlled by a systemically important platform operator; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6f7ea9f52fa4fa1b5303757f837498f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a person that—</text><clause id="idf746d4b2c2b843fd87f84a9041fa28cf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a clear national security risk; or</text></clause><clause id="ida58e102cdbc9404a97b16d23271c6baf"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of or controlled by the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the government of another foreign adversary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id4fbff43d1203426f91acebe26e2c7c43"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a33ca8ecae94fdbb6dee36d94f8a2d4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Control</header><text>The term <term>control</term> means, with respect to a person—</text><subparagraph id="id65a591691cf44768b28127b59a645031"><enum>(A)</enum><text>holding 25 percent or more of the stock of the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf5d471af85434001a5a536730d16fddd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>having the right to 25 percent or more of the profits of the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0abd41f1ca214db4937d873bc6101fef"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the event of the dissolution of the person, having the right to 25 percent or more of the assets of the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9ea3485dc911489892593f8fb9f48971"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if the person is a corporation, having the power to designate 25 percent or more of the directors of the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id54eaadfcbe1d4f6e9dce5d8f4e00f686"><enum>(E)</enum><text>if the person is a trust, having the power to designate 25 percent or more of the trustees; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id839c1446cd2a49d386ea87494c31858b"><enum>(F)</enum><text>otherwise exercising substantial control over the person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a914f7ee37a42f49bb5cc7813f64714"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Data</header><text>The term <term>data</term> means information that is collected by or provided to a systemically important platform or business user that is linked, or reasonably linkable, to a specific—</text><subparagraph id="id0ab1dcd014504458a842a039412da562"><enum>(A)</enum><text>user or customer of the systemically important platform; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc9e10baa724d4705849f7afff30f5b5a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>user or customer of a business user.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ide7694355de3a4b659c8ae6ff024d53c9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Foreign adversary</header><text>The term <term>foreign adversary</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8(c) of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1607">47 U.S.C. 1607(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1a45d0c68a5429b9ab9593ebc5b25a5"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Materially harms competition</header><text>The term <term>materially harms competition</term> means any actual or reasonable risk of lessening of competition or impairing the competitive process that is more than a de minimis amount.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ideddf42af9a14436ca56e0d06d557d244"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Monthly active user</header><text>The term <term>monthly active user</term> means a unique person in the United States who, during a calendar month, initiates an interaction with the online platform, regardless of whether the user logs in or otherwise authenticates themselves.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8dd62c150eb948d09cd8ad99cbab8213"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Online platform</header><text>The term <term>online platform</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id6ba76ed61d7944e584ec4ec3051152e9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a website, online or mobile application, operating system, digital assistant, or online service that—</text><clause id="idf9fa88ebabba4983b517806340d77dba"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enables a user to generate or share content that can be viewed by other users on the platform or to interact with other content on or through the platform;</text></clause><clause id="id430d4463b033492d9a06a747b95e2c36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>facilitates the offering, advertising, sale, purchase, payment, or shipping of products or services, including software applications, between and among consumers or businesses not controlled by the systemically important platform operator; or</text></clause><clause id="iddc5dc22b42534ee984cc21cd2655a5ca"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enables user searches or queries that access or display a large volume of information; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id72d1a5086ed1472abe6fc7865349076e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a service by wire or radio that provides the capability to transmit data to and receive data from all or substantially all internet endpoints, including any capabilities that are incidental to and enable the operation of the communications service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0dcbc510fb964f4b98943d84c5bdeeb9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Publicly traded company</header><text>The term <term>publicly traded company</term>—</text><subparagraph id="id1ab75e3a8f0b4ef0889253671d38fcee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a company that has a principal class of shares registered under subsection (b) or (g) of section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78l">15 U.S.C. 78l</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbfdf2a7175d54cdd8ed30898b8fe9530"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a subsidiary of a company described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddce75643b88d4972abc610382f279ef0"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Similar platform</header><text>The term <term>similar platform</term> means an online platform controlled by the same person that offers substantially similar functionality or serves substantially similar use cases to users or business users.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idcc3994265bb9453bb9c4e346ce5ce482"><enum>(13)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id467b1d2451ee4111a90c852780808edc"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Subscriber household</header><text>The term <term>subscriber household</term> means a household in the United States in which at least 1 member pays for access to the online platform during a calendar month.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id080049f93f25467da2e7f7883f66de96"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Systemically important platform</header><subparagraph id="id418d249da4c64d3eb95bbd2f6a3b0963"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>systemically important platform</term> means an online platform that—</text><clause id="id30520368eeb8482b88c7994f351fdbe2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is controlled by a person with average annual gross revenues of not less than $175,000,000,000, as adjusted under subsection (c); and</text></clause><clause id="id1ab76960d2e24e6abcc220189f62562a"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idd8ffd96f1a1d4c17b53be039b8530c94"><enum>(I)</enum><text>during a period of not fewer than 3 consecutive calendar months in each of the 2 consecutive 12-month periods preceding the filing of an action under this Act, has monthly active users in the United States equal to not less than 34 percent of the population of the United States over the age of 12, as determined by the most recent decennial census of population conducted by the Bureau of the Census; or</text></subclause><subclause id="idb036616492f54e7688dcd880ce122dea" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>during a period of not fewer than 3 consecutive calendar months in each of the 2 consecutive 12-month periods preceding the filing of an action under this Act, has subscriber households in the United States equal to not less than 34 percent of households in the United States, as determined by the most recent decennial census of population conducted by the Bureau of the Census.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89547a037edd4238a4cc5b4d9471c01d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Counting rules; aggregation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the number of monthly active users and subscriber households under this paragraph, the platform shall—</text><clause id="idf35d5875d8f143ae94a41720d54b8fbf"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exclude non-human, automated, or test accounts to the extent identified in the ordinary course of business;</text></clause><clause id="id91b1ddc8aec749e9b8b87de3c1e29071"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use reasonable ordinary-course methods to avoid double-counting the same individual or household across multiple accounts;</text></clause><clause id="id10ef33cbcd4842c0a124e817b5db4ea1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the monthly active users and subscriber households of similar platforms controlled by the same person shall be aggregated; and</text></clause><clause id="idc95613089b3348b48e74ac5fb71c7f99"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>if such aggregation causes the threshold described in subclause (I) or (II) of subparagraph (A)(ii) to be met, each such similar platform shall be treated as satisfying the applicable threshold.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idcf7b46b115984bf98e9dea91886e3dab"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Systemically important platform operator</header><text>The term <term>systemically important platform operator</term> means a person that owns, controls, or operates a systemically important platform.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8c2209763e91486e8ef207e2d4f51207"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall promulgate regulations in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to define the term <term>data</term> for the purpose of implementing and enforcing this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id51ffd5bebab247de846287887dedfdb6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual adjustment of revenue threshold</header><paragraph id="ide42cefe365fe443c9fe1748c7b4e2d77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning with the first calendar year that begins after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall revise the dollar amount set forth in subsection (a)(15)(A)(i) to reflect the percentage change in gross national product, as most recently published by the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id49c36f48ddd14eb893032ce768a6c045"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Commission shall publish any revised dollar amount under paragraph (1) in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id320134ddfcbe46098332a4ee7f910f80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>Any revised dollar amount under paragraph (1) shall be rounded to the nearest $1,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id345b9336edfd4d6f96b245000f62e4fa"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Any revised dollar amount published under paragraph (2) shall apply to any action filed on or after the effective date specified in the notice published by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id24bb830b0a974d68842af237d9ad2c1f"><enum>3.</enum><header>Unlawful conduct</header><subsection id="id43794eaba0c14c4aa413fa815221acf1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><paragraph id="ide1a8578d67fb4dbeaf9e5411d03567ea"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on preferencing, limiting, and discrimination</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person operating a systemically important platform in or affecting commerce to—</text><subparagraph id="idd99a47ece80848eeb7ec5bab52324f63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preference the products, services, or lines of business of the systemically important platform over those of another business user in a manner that would materially harm competition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id458024b605cc4566af011b42f4c505c6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>limit the ability of the products, services, or lines of business of another business user to compete on the systemically important platform relative to the products, services, or lines of business of the systemically important platform operator in a manner that would materially harm competition; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89e209364a4b4615bac192d94710555d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>apply or enforce the terms of service of the systemically important platform among similarly situated business users in a discriminatory manner that would materially harm competition.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id16654e61e6a84b6cacbc0e413ef1854e"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on access to platform features</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person operating a systemically important platform in or affecting commerce to restrict, impede, or unreasonably delay the capacity of a business user to access or interoperate with the same platform, operating system, or hardware or software features that are available to the products, services, or lines of business of the systemically important platform operator that compete or would compete with products or services offered by business users on the systemically important platform.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idff04c52597774ba5aaff41aeca6d3c07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on tying</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person operating a systemically important platform in or affecting commerce to condition access to the systemically important platform, any part of the systemically important platform, or preferred status or placement on the systemically important platform on the purchase or use of other products or services offered by the systemically important platform operator that are not part of or intrinsic to the systemically important platform.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1884f1a2294c470aaed7bc98c1933c77"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Prohibition on access to platform data</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person operating a systemically important platform in or affecting commerce to—</text><subparagraph id="id0fcb1575181849328990abc0150cbed5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use nonpublic data that are obtained from or generated on the systemically important platform by the activities of a business user or by the interaction of a platform user with the products or services of a business user to offer, or support the offering of, the products or services of the systemically important platform operator that compete or would compete with products or services offered by business users on the platform; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7d6fb1e88fd34359b7476ce468229873"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restrict or impede a business user from accessing data generated on the systemically important platform by the activities of the business user, or through an interaction of a user with the products or services of the business user, such as by establishing contractual or technical restrictions that prevent the portability by the business user to other systems or applications of the data of the business user.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2c6c76ab8b9f4038a038599395d3d391"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Prohibition on user lock-in</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person operating a systemically important platform in or affecting commerce to restrict or impede users from changing default settings or selecting an alternative default product or service, if the default directs or steers users to products or services offered by the systemically important platform operator, unless necessary—</text><subparagraph id="idba720bd0a8ef485f88bdd5b03a0a57ee"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the security or functioning of the platform; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89db13303fdc48d4b213811564414e17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to prevent data from the systemically important platform operator or another business user from being transferred to the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the government of another foreign adversary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id95f0b3cbdbfa48ab8a846977392b9e86"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prohibition on ranking and presentation</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person operating a systemically important platform in or affecting commerce to treat the products, services, or lines of business of the systemically important platform operator more favorably relative to those of another business user in connection with any user interface, including search or ranking functionality offered by the platform, except pursuant to standards that are neutral, nondiscriminatory, and fairly applied to all similarly situated business users.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id80a962f8899a46acb39c08b2b855aa99"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Prohibition on retaliation</header><text>It shall be unlawful for a person operating a systemically important platform in or affecting commerce to retaliate against any user or business user that raises concerns with any law enforcement authority about actual or potential violations of State or Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2348af2a14c5448fa44b4d1099d03811"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Affirmative defenses</header><paragraph id="id88d5f7b006014786a0e9fe55bbf0561b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance with law; protection of safety, privacy, and security; prevention of fraud</header><text>It shall be an affirmative defense to an action under this section if the defendant establishes by clear and convincing evidence that the conduct at issue was—</text><subparagraph id="idacd53c5c207c4393a3a081e39d2ae88b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>necessary to—</text><clause id="id3f8381f60f5b4f74ae887d894c4af4cc"><enum>(i)</enum><text>comply with Federal or State law; or</text></clause><clause id="id2df015e127d74de29182aba514327a4f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protect safety, user privacy, the security of nonpublic data or of the platform, or any other significant cybersecurity risk, or to prevent fraud or spam; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id088a2667f3c842899e28af6eac675b4c"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="idb780fd0246cb41aeb306ae80d2aa57cd"><enum>(i)</enum><text>applied on a consistent basis;</text></clause><clause id="id87445e1930a44646a859967cbf9fa440" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not used as a pretext to exclude or disadvantage competitors;</text></clause><clause id="id22f9489f0fb54a2bbc4dde82b8d3b975" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>narrowly tailored in scope; and</text></clause><clause id="id1ff9aa7295d34d6f884ed2f0df6c1b81" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>could not be achieved through less anticompetitive means.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id7a5a6788b3cd42b89354843866857f09"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No harm to competition</header><text>It shall be an affirmative defense to an action under paragraphs (2) through (6) of subsection (a) if the defendant establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that the conduct has not materially harmed and would not materially harm competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb59dbd553865439595386edc8bbd8bb3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of other laws</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, whether user conduct would constitute a violation of section 1030 of title 18, United States Code, shall have no effect on whether the defendant has established an affirmative defense under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id01c424cc54c14c46933a59bb007512e3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Contemporaneous records requirement</header><subparagraph id="iddad843f0b10d4901892e4fd46d9247f4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A defendant may not rely on the affirmative defense under paragraph (1) unless the defendant produces records, created in the ordinary course of business at or before the time the challenged conduct was undertaken, that—</text><clause id="id959f912bf90a42bcba4a6e37fb099ce0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe the specific purpose for which the conduct was undertaken; and</text></clause><clause id="id010d52034f2d452199071526c5f401d9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify the material risks or harms the conduct was intended to address.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8a3fb2b0f44844ad86167fd04b8ae087"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to require a defendant to create records that were not otherwise created in the ordinary course of business.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd92f3d28e25d425e86721a5c99cd78bc"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="id13db20657c5b4f619d1aa7069145d6c7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act—</text><subparagraph id="idc4a5777f2c1143c5accb5f86002e8973"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Commission shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb727d14af6a7454ea68e46d2aec1bd00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Attorney General shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id78a5b175565d47f49bf901ca84236280"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any attorney general of a State may bring a civil action in the name of such State, or as parens patriae on behalf of natural persons residing in such State, for a violation of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id94a90983edb84397ab3910d68fc0b3d7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission independent litigation authority</header><text>If the Commission has reason to believe that a person violated this Act, the Commission may commence a civil action, in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, to recover a civil penalty under paragraph (4), and seek other appropriate relief, including any form of relief provided for in paragraph (4), in a district court of the United States. Except as otherwise provided in section 16(a)(3) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/56">15 U.S.C. 56(a)(3)</external-xref>), the Commission shall have exclusive authority to commence or defend, and supervise the litigation of, any civil action under this paragraph and any appeal of such action in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, unless the Commission authorizes the Attorney General to do so. The Commission shall inform the Attorney General of the exercise of such authority, and such exercise shall not preclude the Attorney General from intervening on behalf of the United States in such action and any appeal of such action as may be otherwise provided by law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f73a2f221f742bca6bb8b21b19f9fd7"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Enforcement in Federal district court</header> <text>The Commission, the Attorney General, or any attorney general of a State may enforce this Act only through a civil action brought before a district court of the United States.</text>
 </paragraph><paragraph id="iddd030ae8e7e24f32a3c51de64cf00279"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Remedies</header><subparagraph id="idd4613cf7ee694c3aa59bb2ca844b8fd3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>In an action brought by the Commission, the Attorney General, or a State attorney general under this Act, the court may impose a civil penalty on a person that violates this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf31a648b8dcf411aa620be82660c4441"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Civil penalty amount</header><text>Any person who violates this Act shall be liable to the United States for a civil penalty, to be deposited in the Treasury of the United States, in an amount not greater than 10 percent, and not less than 1 percent, of the total United States revenue of the person for the period during which the violation occurred.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45c52048fdcf42ada2861187ae86e9ea"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Injunctive and other equitable relief</header><clause id="ide519fb74184d4a34aecec18abb016da3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General, the Commission, or the attorney general of any State may seek, and the court may order, equitable relief as necessary to prevent, restrain, or prohibit violations of this Act.</text></clause><clause id="id1e96bf44122e472eba2f2b232902a1e4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Temporary injunctions</header><subclause id="id1da1d4318d4441af9f2475afc014b903"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission, the Attorney General, or any attorney general of a State may seek a temporary injunction requiring the systemically important platform operator to take or stop taking any action for not more than 120 days.</text></subclause><subclause id="idbebd60be67b44fa4a3b310535133e6ec"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Grant</header><text>The court may grant a temporary injunction under this clause if the Commission, the Attorney General, or the attorney general of a State, as applicable, proves—</text><item id="idf2a94811f170494c9f3755c61b1db2df"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>there is a plausible claim, supported by evidence, that the defendant is a systemically important platform operator;</text></item><item id="id9982949222dc48acbb132e1e9fdc58c0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the defendant took an action that would violate this Act;</text></item><item id="id113058023b2a426790c7245cb0459b65"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>that action materially impairs the ability of business users to compete with the systemically important platform operator; and</text></item><item id="id02a80225bc15402aac1a408e8900d154"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a temporary injunction would be in the public interest.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="id780dd327127b4d7487e2b7698be0c73e"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The court shall terminate a temporary injunction under this clause if the systemically important platform operator proves that—</text><item id="idb6d244cc48624d5ab87b1eb8ee3785cc"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Commission, the Attorney General, or the attorney general of the State seeking relief under this subsection has not taken reasonable steps to investigate whether a violation has occurred; or</text></item><item id="id800959eced0242fd9e985af4dda82221"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>allowing the temporary injunction to continue would harm the public interest.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="ida16ee13f06da4cd599b63c95e6c24baf"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Other equitable relief</header><text>Nothing in this clause shall prevent or limit the Commission, the Attorney General, or the attorney general of any State from seeking, or a court from granting, other equitable relief.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided0061f2bf4d4bf3909542f72f38cd1a"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Forfeiture for repeat offenders</header><clause id="id509ba9513a0143f9af774c13d15a06e4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to any other remedy provided in this Act, if a court finds that a person engaged in a pattern or practice of conduct that violates this Act, the court shall consider requiring, and may order, the forfeiture by the chief executive officer, and any other corporate officer as appropriate to deter violations of this Act, of any compensation received during the 12-month period preceding or following the filing of a complaint for an alleged violation of this Act.</text></clause><clause id="id698c82e7d0ab4936ae8aebe6d781d887"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>Prior to ordering any chief executive officer or corporate officer to forfeit compensation under clause (i), the court shall provide such chief executive officer or corporate officer reasonable notice that the court is considering ordering forfeiture under this subparagraph and provide an opportunity for such chief executive officer or corporate officer to appear and be heard before the court at a hearing on such potential forfeiture.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfd627a2bfd2d4e3c9a4d0f9bd7811a37"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><text>An action under this Act shall be barred unless commenced not later than 6 years after the date on which the cause of action accrues.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9aa71acd2b6f40329b41744cdfcdbfa7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subparagraph id="id589a611126ef4fbdaf55943eb2c9095c"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in subsection (a) may be construed—</text><clause id="id78108d7b9eae450db6199a3afd5dd5d3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to require a systemically important platform operator to divulge or license any intellectual property, including any trade secrets, business secrets, or other confidential proprietary business processes, owned by or licensed to the systemically important platform operator;</text></clause><clause id="id7df6ab8520a84331b5778cf0486976ff"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to prevent a systemically important platform operator from asserting its preexisting rights under intellectual property law to prevent the unauthorized use of any intellectual property owned by or duly licensed to the systemically important platform operator;</text></clause><clause id="id531a794c7f6a4e53a2c089c67024c2ae"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to require a systemically important platform operator to interoperate or share data with persons or business users that are on any list maintained by the Federal Government by which entities are identified as limited or prohibited from engaging in economic transactions as part of United States sanctions or export control regimes, or have been identified as national security, intelligence, or law enforcement risks;</text></clause><clause id="id51c60d373d464689b0a95b336ac15833"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to prohibit a systemically important platform operator from promptly requesting and obtaining the consent of a user prior to providing access to the nonpublic, personally identifiable information of the user to another user;</text></clause><clause id="idff3b46b36a37490eb11a5b206d8f8163"><enum>(v)</enum><text>in a manner that would likely result in data on the systemically important platform or data from another business user being transferred to the Government of the People’s Republic of China or the government of another foreign adversary; or</text></clause><clause id="id6ac246df058b497ca5e9dc505d5e3ac3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to impose liability on a systemically important platform operator solely for offering—</text><subclause id="ida55f3139c24e4bc1a7e50c24d59ecaa3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>full end-to-end encrypted messaging or communication products or services; or</text></subclause><subclause id="id1cb3029df6f14066a43011952ac52646"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a fee-for-service subscription that provides benefits to users on the platform.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ided297b71d4cb4c5ab4ed222f49589069"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Copyright and trademark violations</header><text>An action taken by a systemically important platform operator that is reasonably tailored to protect the rights of third parties under section 106, 1101, 1201, or 1401 of title 17, United States Code, or rights actionable under section 32 or 43 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes</quote>, approved July 5, 1946 (commonly known as the <quote>Lanham Act</quote> or the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1114">15 U.S.C. 1114</external-xref>, 1125), or corollary State law, shall not be considered unlawful conduct under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idf7c266a7c4f5497eb2e63b50295f10b5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Expedited antitrust proceedings for systemically important platforms</header><subsection id="ide1a229043a17486dbfaee3486d60b9ca"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assignment and priority docketing</header><paragraph id="id8e5a279171a34458aa49894a2ab068df"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon the filing of a civil action by the United States or the Commission against a systemically important platform under this Act or any of the antitrust laws, the chief judge of the district court in which the action is filed shall assign the matter for expedited consideration consistent with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idfec5bc4c2b6c4de696ee7a87da8ca6c0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>Any such action shall be advanced on the docket and expedited to the greatest extent practicable. The court shall give the matter priority over all other civil actions, except matters of the same character given equal precedence by statute.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5eb2e5bdc0fa449581057f25f8419563"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final judgment</header><text>The district court shall endeavor to issue final judgment not later than 1 year after the date on which the complaint is filed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf02ffd9f068049db80fc305b526e2dc0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text>An appeal from a final judgment under this section shall be taken to the court of appeals for the circuit in which the action was filed, which shall expedite such appeal to the greatest extent practicable. If the Supreme Court of the United States grants a writ of certiorari, the Supreme Court shall advance the appeal on the docket and expedite the appeal to the greatest extent practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc922513cc6d3432d8f46e88c347dbdce"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of investigative materials</header><paragraph id="id29fed41ff64942a0b243f610be96ce5b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any documentary material, interrogatory response, deposition, testimony, or data obtained by the United States pursuant to a civil investigative demand or other compulsory process under this Act or the Antitrust Civil Process Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1311">15 U.S.C. 1311 et seq.</external-xref>) shall not be required to be produced to a party during discovery if that party provided the material to the United States or obtained the material during the course of the investigation of the United States, unless—</text><subparagraph id="id6e97def9ae984a2e9b6a21b6197a4954"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States uses the material to support its claims against that party; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idffdf220676b541cfae0c4e1eec8560c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the court orders production of the material for good cause shown.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id04e7be368ada4eefbfb51522ea7d69b7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No duplicative discovery</header><text>The district court shall not permit duplicative discovery of materials referenced in paragraph (1) absent a showing of good cause.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ided9b09ae4fc640648a7c3953662e2112"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited enforcement of civil investigative demands</header><paragraph id="idd0eb95599974491091c374b299f2cba4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any proceeding brought by the United States or the Commission to enforce compliance with a civil investigative demand issued in an investigation relating to a violation of this Act, the chief judge of the district court in which the demand is sought to be enforced shall assign the matter for expedited consideration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0d51b04d61040e49c13dbbdd2242dc6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advancement</header><text>Any such action shall be advanced on the docket and expedited to the greatest extent practicable, and absent extraordinary circumstances, the court shall endeavor to issue a ruling not later than 30 days after the date on which the petition is filed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id2d1dff5f980a461b8db5746d82a004f3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to limit—</text><paragraph id="id0aeb5edc66af4a38b27cb7d643a74bf3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any authority of the Department of Justice or the Commission under the antitrust laws, section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>), or any other provision of law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78674a15008f48f5953756121d956078"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any right guaranteed by the Constitution of the United States, including under the First Amendment; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb500e3e056ae4d019137a6023962412e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the application of any law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id516431f15ed74079a6ed23cbc5955667"><enum>6.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the provisions of this Act to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></section><section id="idea8fa8de81d344a0b52a2a0aee8147e6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 1 year after the date of enactment.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

