<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD71D109538A54C3A86E185B7E8D81685" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1191 IH: Commemorating the 10th anniversary of the Columbine Day of Service and honoring the memories of the victims, survivors, and their families.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1191</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260420">April 20, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Commemorating the 10th anniversary of the Columbine Day of Service and honoring the memories of the victims, survivors, and their families.</official-title></form><preamble> 
<whereas><text>Whereas, on April 20, 1999, 13 individuals, including 12 students and 1 teacher, were murdered in a shooting at Columbine High School in Littleton, Colorado;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas another 24 individuals sustained physical injuries;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the tragic events resulted in profound trauma for countless members of the Columbine community that they continue to navigate today;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas we must continue to remember and honor the 13 victims whose lives were tragically cut short, and those whose lives were irrevocably changed by this senseless act of violence;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas a Columbine Day of Service was established in recognition of the students, staff, alumni, first responders, and community members who reacted to the tragedy by pouring love into the Columbine community with dignity, compassion, and solidarity;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the Columbine Day of Service is a celebration of community and resilience;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas the Columbine Day of Service encourages participants to remember the lives lost, reflect on the lives forever changed, and recommit to acts of service in their communities;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the global impact of the shooting is reflected in the outpouring of support for Columbine to this day, turning the Columbine Day of Service into a global movement committed to kindness, selflessness, and community building;</text></whereas> 
<whereas><text>Whereas communities from 6 States and 10 countries engaged in the Columbine Day of Service in 2024, which exceeded 60 projects and over 1,600 participants worldwide;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas the State of Colorado recognizes April 20 annually as a Day of Recommitment, demonstrating widespread enthusiasm for community service and redefining the Columbine legacy as one of hope and rebirth; and</text></whereas> 
<whereas>
 <text>Whereas April 20, 2026, marks the 10th anniversary of the Columbine Day of Service: Now, therefore, be it</text>
        </whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HABA5649B901648568055C2CA9F60C41A"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H45BCB4A9B6EB4ADCAD1C24F8A83A76F4"><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="H5F0893636E494876858CA5BE2B388354"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commemorates the 27th remembrance of the Columbine High School shooting and honors the memories of the victims, survivors, and their families;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H31860222284349B1B0839F4070FE5340"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expresses heartfelt condolences to all those whose lives were forever altered by the Columbine tragedy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDAC120F4A274BABB33F02E40D293262"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commemorates the 10th anniversary of the Columbine Day of Service and recognizes community service as a fundamental tool used by the Columbine community and others across the world to rebuild from tragedy and strive for new beginnings;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BF25876C26A4929BB0DA4007662FECE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reaffirms the Columbine legacy as one that celebrates the selfless contributions of thousands of students, staff, alumni, first responders, and community members, redefining Columbine beyond the tragic events of April 20, 1999;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7041C00CC9C4A2F9D99411101C205CB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>urges the community to continue its efforts to empower individuals across the world to invest in their communities and to participate in acts of community service; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43A801D84F0B4F00B56C1184F2A293E7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourages every United States citizen to remember the victims of the Columbine tragedy, commit to acts of gratitude, and participate annually in the Columbine Day of Service.</text></paragraph></section> </resolution-body></resolution>

