<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-RYA26060-76L-MJ-2WP"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4101 IS: Grocery, Farm, and Food Worker Protection Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4101</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260316">March 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S409">Mr. Luján</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAF00">Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a grocery, farm, and food worker stabilization grant program.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section id="id20ad722a41be42e9831570538390fef7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grocery, Farm, and Food Worker Protection Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idb724a97c95884bce8dca42eae74a0941"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grocery, farm, and food worker stabilization grant program</header><subsection id="iddfe2f7ca4669419fa4fe8025c3cf81d6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="id4db874e4e6cc41f1b136b266eb9b354f"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a membership organization, as determined by the Secretary, or labor union representing farmworkers, meat processing workers, or grocery workers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3a079297865b4764943da193fcf30471"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id85947787d6094f0fbfb27e382ac08006"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service, shall establish a grant program to provide funding to eligible entities representing farmworkers, meat processing workers, and grocery workers for stabilization payments in the case of a natural disaster or other disaster, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="idf3c74b42636f434bb529bab8d3930ba7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing the outcomes and evaluating the impacts of the program established under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id01d1a95502f44926b3f997c988842732"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

