<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC7254B7956C34DF8BAECD4991BF6B166" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6313 IH: Military Child and Youth Program Abuse and Neglect Notification Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6313</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251125">November 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000487">Ms. Tokuda</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001228">Mr. Schmidt</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000399">Mrs. Kiggans of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require military child and youth programs to provide prompt notice of alleged or suspected neglect or abuse of children to the parents or guardians of those children, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBFC56AF78AE747009F57D2E0C6071B93" style="OLC"><section id="HC733E26DD47D45B89E0E5C4A228CDD23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Child and Youth Program Abuse and Neglect Notification Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBD5B8BC0C14946FAB8BA6C2A6AE72145"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notification of suspected child abuse at providers of child care services or youth programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1794 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H77A3AD5F20F1457DBE4224743DDD9D40" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA9A2F8EB4C6A493089A0FA6923B9951B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Notification of Suspected Child Abuse</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H893CCCC466FB454B9B1F59D397FB8841"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe a policy that requires covered child and youth programs to—</text><subparagraph id="HD421E201739B49128DD6C2874A0CDF4E" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 24 hours after a program becomes aware of alleged or suspected abuse or neglect of a child occurring in such program, notify the parents and guardians of such child of such alleged or suspected abuse or neglect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3E815046A6141D6976CE2FD757A4F47" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 72 hours after a program becomes aware of alleged abuse or neglect of a child occurring in such program, provide notice of such alleged abuse or neglect to—</text><clause id="H8E049FE5BBD64CB58C32CCA124261B70"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives;</text></clause><clause id="H5698387D5A3C46E28974B63FF374B984" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the alleged abuse or neglect occurs in one of the several States, the Senators that represent the State in which the alleged abuse or neglect occurred; and</text></clause><clause id="HA62E62B0C4AA46F0BD2C87361EF08286"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the alleged abuse or neglect occurs in a location represented by a Member of, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the House of Representatives, the Member of, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the House of Representatives that represents such location.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2693D9AFD632467FB9945109C04BE1D3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered child and youth program</quote> means a military child development center, a Department of Defense youth program, a family home day care, or a provider of child care services or youth program services that receives financial assistance under section 1798.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

