<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF708D0A3EADF4E819B976C6AAF940D49" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 928 IH: Affirming support for most-favored-Nation drug pricing for United States patients.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 928</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Affirming support for most-favored-Nation drug pricing for United States patients.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas, according to a study conducted by the Department of Health and Human Services Office of the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation and RAND Health Care in 2024, the United States spends a higher and growing share of total drug spending on new drugs compared to other countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United States prices across all drugs, both brand name and generic, were nearly 2.78 times as high as prices in the comparison countries;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on average, according to the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, United States citizens spend over $1,400 on prescription drugs every year, the highest per capita drug spending in the world;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to polling done by the Kaiser Family Foundation, 21 percent of United States adults say they have not filled a prescription because of the cost, 23 percent say they have instead opted for over-the-counter alternatives, and 1 in 7 adults say they have cut pills in half or skipped doses of medicine in the last year because of the cost;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas lowering prescription drug prices to levels obtained in nations similar to the United States has long enjoyed bipartisan support from Congress and Presidential administrations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on May 12, 2025, President Trump signed an Executive order titled <quote>Delivering Most-Favored-Nation Prescription Drug Pricing to American Patients</quote> directing the Administration to take numerous actions to bring United States drug prices in line with those paid by similar nations;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, on July 31, 2025, President Trump sent letters to leading pharmaceutical manufacturers outlining the steps they must take to bring down the prices of prescription drugs in the United States to match the lowest price offered in other developed nations; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas bipartisan Members of the 119th Congress have introduced legislation that align with the goals of President Trump’s May 12, 2025, Executive order to align drug pricing for United States patients with the lowest price offered in other developed nations: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="H0B3278B6A66244CC849D06B8BA7F497D"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HF7035F00EF584C72B97F67172EC7499F"><enum/><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H5981514A4479410988BF255D3008E109"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the idea that patients in the United States should not be charged more than those in other countries for the exact same prescription drugs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44E504D363EF42C797BFCD37AF156741"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognizes and affirms the commitment of the United States to reducing the cost of prescription drugs for all United States citizens by—</text><subparagraph id="HC53499A261AF413492C94F97F3B1F844"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting policies that align the pricing of drugs sold in the United States with that of other developed nations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1227E27CEE94407937424DC8FFBF26A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting other available methods, including expanding Medicare drug price negotiation and promoting price competition in the drug market; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD025FC511F14B87A2C749403EAAEACE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the idea that United States citizens should have access to high-quality, affordable prescription drugs.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

