<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7EC1AD78352147099712799EC0491F34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6104 IH: Dark Web Interdiction Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6104</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251118">November 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the delivery of opioids by means of the dark web, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H99C99B7A90A647C8B3DC75E805C847AA" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H57E4C0AF362C414E84A3845226D08DAD"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dark Web Interdiction Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H58E7205C9732452B86105D7FB1321361"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H6E1AB25552DB4ECE8C61F67342A87C7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H081D55A38A844360A1F80CE72EE32789"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The dark web is made up of websites and other network services that leverage overlay networks providing anonymity. These overlay networks use the internet but require specific software and configurations to access. The overlay networks use multiple encrypted traffic relays for which an individual relay computer knows its source of information and where the individual computer is sending the information but never knows both the original source and ultimate destination of the traffic simultaneously. This anonymity has provided criminals with the ability to host illicit material in a way that circumvents the ability of law enforcement agencies to serve legal process to remove or effectively investigate websites offering illegal content or goods for purchase or sharing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5A6C729BAE84ABD81B87296F912768A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Dark web marketplaces include e-commerce websites based on the dark web on which individuals use virtual currencies to engage in transactions involving drugs, weapons, malware, counterfeit currency, stolen credit cards, personal identifying information, forged documents, unlicensed pharmaceuticals, and other illicit goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1990F03E8654A60850B692FEA2E93B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Due to the anonymity provided by the dark web, illicit activities can be hosted from anywhere in the world without accountability to—</text><subparagraph id="HF8DBBE52FD70414E943355B05E89C8F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3D8947B348042A0BD57386B7BB32FE2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal laws; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3BE594897FF4A57AC16448607AFB061"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other government or system of laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4591A8BC9293437CBF2CA79BD0347CAD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The use of the dark web to distribute illegal drugs has contributed and continues to contribute to the substance abuse crisis that is devastating communities across the United States. This devastation is due in large part to the fact that the dark web has made illicit goods obtainable anonymously.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1717859F35434749BF4B3AF1C8CC234A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Law enforcement agencies at every level of government continue to investigate drug trafficking and the sale of illegal goods and services through the dark web that occurs as a result of interactions on the dark web, both within the United States and at the international border of the United States, but the increased anonymity the internet provides has made it more difficult to identify and prosecute the individuals and organizations who—</text><subparagraph id="H1F41A354F447400F82500680AC5BA37D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administer or otherwise operate websites on the dark web that facilitate the distribution of illegal drugs, goods, or services; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A7C1E4C319047FD9401518C251DDF88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>buy and sell illegal drugs, goods, or services through illicit marketplaces hosted on the dark web.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5D0710A87AF49C19BDBD4CBA962CBE2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite difficulties in identifying and locating individuals and organizations who engage in drug trafficking on the dark web, law enforcement agencies have been effective in investigating and prosecuting the distribution of illegal drugs through illicit marketplaces on the dark web, as evidenced by Operation SpecTor, an operation conducted across 3 continents that resulted from a partnership between the Department of Justice and foreign law enforcement agencies, which—</text><subparagraph id="HD603F466A2BF401AAF403D99E930DB68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was announced in May 2023;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8BC8864905046779418995155209E26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resulted in—</text><clause id="H28ABD1745DC04552BA5CCB1DCE7D50F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>288 arrests;</text></clause><clause id="H738BFEBA814D451EA17B74A714050A6E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the seizure of approximately 850 kilograms of drugs, including 64 kilograms of fentanyl or fentanyl-laced narcotics;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD03D46C58574BE3BF7F398ADAE11E23"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the seizure of 117 firearms; and</text></clause><clause id="HD3BB3A9820F94BDEB7179D381CF8BF97"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the seizure of $53,400,000 in cash and virtual currencies; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37DB22FF38AA4FB2B4F91F145F6F4304"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is an example of one of many cases conducted jointly by—</text><clause id="HF8048972301247CDB218354C7B3672D7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></clause><clause id="HBAAA9D50721D4978A240DCAEE147A922"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Drug Enforcement Administration;</text></clause><clause id="H641674DEE8CD4B64B45B8BFA424678C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Homeland Security Investigations;</text></clause><clause id="HE07AF73EAB8444868E5E14355D81451C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>United States Customs and Border Protection;</text></clause><clause id="H54704DE6076F4C9D9B88CDA156271B6D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the United States Postal Inspection Service;</text></clause><clause id="H7A9B643178024902A7A9BF57A154BB40"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></clause><clause id="H7B66B432A1424D5FADCF18C213CA0BE4"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives;</text></clause><clause id="HFE47C036AFDA4EECAA10B7FA0A84299E"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the Naval Criminal Investigative Service;</text></clause><clause id="HDFE646A300364D52995DFDA54D901923"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the Department of Justice;</text></clause><clause id="HC8519A155FCC46F7BDBEB69C16117EB1"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the Department of Defense; and</text></clause><clause id="H753E05ABE35A45CE88065E7F95C0BA04"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>additional local, State, and international law enforcement partners.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H797C9F92DBF241008B10BF9F1BD66DAB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Although law enforcement agencies have succeeded in investigating the distribution and sale of illegal drugs, goods, and services that occurs as a result of interactions on the dark web, investigative and prosecutorial collaboration, innovation, and advancement are critical to—</text><subparagraph id="H8EF9990DE649404AB6A879C03AB0EC07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing the capacity to combat the threat posed by the dark web and the illicit marketplaces hosted on the dark web; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3071B468BB1A4CFAB8D335D5A510C2C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhancing collaboration and coordination among Federal, State, Tribal, local, international and other law enforcement partners, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1660D76F4314AFA891853C0998A0939"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H842325F70532451AA497BC3DD04BA203"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the dark web and illicit marketplaces hosted on the dark web facilitate the distribution of illegal drugs and pose a unique threat to the public health and national security in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H414A213FEA934B458B5B4BB213041487"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Congress should—</text><subparagraph id="H3FECAE3DA0E848F4B7369387F958634E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support law enforcement agencies and prosecutors at the Federal, State, Tribal, local, and international levels in their efforts to investigate and prosecute the distribution of illegal drugs, goods, and services through the dark web; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00ADB27B47FD405AB4E30DABACD97F13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase the investigative and prosecutorial tools available to law enforcement agencies and prosecutors to address the distribution of illegal drugs, goods, and services through the dark web.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5A9AC3BB71814843B035810C52784FC9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H8A08FC0E8FEA4467B981892363AAE225"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dark web</header><text>The term <term>dark web</term> has the meaning given the term in subsection (i) of section 401 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841</external-xref>), as added by section 4 of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE331BCC8465D4000A66524D89B2D04C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the task force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1484D40F3554714B6DFFEE589CCDE36"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Illicit marketplace</header><text>The term <term>illicit marketplace</term> means a website on the dark web on which individuals can use virtual currency to engage in transactions involving drugs, weapons, malware, counterfeit currency, stolen credit cards, personal identifying information, forged documents, or other illicit goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C8F8D4C746A4E6FAC90FD75396F6E7A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <term>Indian tribe</term> in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10B23F2D58C04643A36DFF324827F7DB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Opioid</header><text>The term <term>opioid</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12FF853FDCB041FB8DD9A07BC005994A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>The term <term>task force</term> means the Joint Criminal Opioid and Darknet Enforcement Task Force established under section 5(a)(1).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAD311D60F86A44A9A0C9410702DB9742"><enum>4.</enum><header>Offenses involving the dark web</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 401 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14C3F4A7680342ED883FF538E1D4AD99"><subsection id="H4B090F3E3B67426A99BA1FF1F2F66DF4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Offenses involving dispensing of controlled substances by means of the dark web</header><paragraph id="HC928F323FA8343CCBC30D2CD3CEECED2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of dark web</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>dark web</term> means a portion of the internet in which there are hidden sites and services that—</text><subparagraph id="H4C4F110F144143C7B75D139AED696113"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are not indexed by an internet search engine; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E01CD753287416BB8846B3BE97A1250"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are only accessible to users of specific devices, software, routing and anonymizing services, authorizations, or configurations that conceal the identities and locations of users.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AD5861D46C949708BFFD21D2CB7D09D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly or intentionally—</text><subparagraph id="H559FB56BA53747D9A1BAB70467195712"><enum>(A)</enum><text>deliver, distribute, or dispense a controlled substance by means of the dark web, except as authorized by this title; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C14671E1863459A8136FEC2D03E0437"><enum>(B)</enum><text>aid or abet (as such terms are used in section 2 of title 18, United States Code) any activity described in subparagraph (A) that is not authorized by this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H332716A9E2664C22B4BAD6B35492DFC5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Pursuant to its authority under section 994 of title 28, United States Code, the United States Sentencing Commission shall amend the Federal sentencing guidelines and policy statements to provide for a 2-level increase above the sentence otherwise applicable for a violation of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HB5FC5A7F2E2F4840847A21831945DFE2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Joint criminal opioid and darknet enforcement task force</header><subsection id="HAA5BE321CE23488885141CF881AD0237"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H1233DFC0C6914FCDA1855E05D00DD29E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Federal Bureau of Investigation an interagency program that shall be known as the Joint Criminal Opioid and Darknet Enforcement Task Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA48EF259D6345D2BE6918E2727C1B05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The task force shall be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H350303B7EE8C4660AB58AA84DDA7BC62"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the task force shall be to detect, disrupt, and dismantle illicit marketplaces.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1F7FFDE7B2D49678931F6FF2FF93E71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Components</header><paragraph id="H65CF2DB9E58241F3B510C75E9AAFE160"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Representatives</header><text>The task force shall include representatives from—</text><subparagraph id="H98390D6481A64FD6A348DAD578C5D58D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2578F35B1E8B447EB1E8F738D006BF35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Drug Enforcement Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BB17C139E0D4684B86319BD0C4051C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States Postal Inspection Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD558C6ED0B174763AC5AB3CD2200C2F0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Immigration and Customs Enforcement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09FFD271755A4B0EB624E3A051AA80BE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD432E1B7DEFD48BDB900407E5F0AE940"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Homeland Security Investigations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A16BC28998A440AB9A2F4267539099E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>United States Customs and Border Protection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H665AE842DF0D4CD7B5A2CB09C4B96127"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAD3DB2FE13E43BDB57962A54F4BC7F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H979FF0FEF96B478A9F8288F61D7740B7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Department of Justice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA4CAD2674F4112BE4613526BF3A037"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Director may consult with any State, Tribal, local, or international department or agency the Director determines necessary to carry out the purpose of the task force described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5829485FFF29422EAA4BC904D32F92BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties and functions</header><text>To further the purpose of the task force described in subsection (b), the task force shall—</text><paragraph id="H14595B00F4D34B81B2133ABB72A76F7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engage in—</text><subparagraph id="H053DDDAECE01492F98705E4613E0C164"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proactive and reactive investigations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70C53F615AA141178E031A06E022EF7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>forensic and cyberforensic examinations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFDEF48E6DDE491095A1FC3D8DE8F0F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide forensic and cyberforensic, technical, preventive, and investigative training and assistance to—</text><subparagraph id="H1FD8DBE283954BF188C58B1299337A68"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prosecutors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19827CAF0AA948E189E701CD7C0D18EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>law enforcement agencies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC993604731784264B6BD982C21B0A6C4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop best practices to assist Federal, State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, prosecutors, and others, as appropriate, in the collection of evidence in order to determine and investigate possible nexuses to the dark web and virtual assets, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5B5D43EFEF5A477797EBC9BD74D8475C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence logging;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1DEED1470684C53BB2D267BD25974BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evidence maintenance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57F115093B4C486795B74EA84244F3AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evidence sharing;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H898836521165402F83D12261F262ADD4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop multijurisdictional and multiagency responses and partnerships with Federal, international, local, and other law enforcement agencies, as appropriate, by—</text><subparagraph id="H5FD40E08C6D645BA84F66FA8F6FC7B1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing procedures for information sharing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7ECF1BD8D0E547C597B6EA802F3BE018"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing lists of recommended specialized equipment and tools to investigate and prosecute the distribution of illicit drugs, goods, and services on the dark web; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA026F0A70516424E90102CDF4505019D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>helping the agencies acquire the necessary knowledge, personnel, and specialized equipment to investigate and prosecute the distribution of illegal drugs, goods, and services through the dark web;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H703D8A16FC924AB4A9449B5CC39A0B0D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>create novel investigative approaches to—</text><subparagraph id="H2209265C6F6A4392ABC814F1A0CED48E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>target emerging technologies that facilitate the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces on the dark web; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CA41E0622E24B3780ECF3C94F9D2F08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>build forensic capacity and expertise to meet the challenges posed by the technologies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94C3B5816840493B823F9B20F8764D10"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enhance collaboration and coordination with international partners; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ADF8618E6F44160970BC138723D9AE9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>engage in any other activities the Director determines necessary to carry out the duties of the task force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7CBA0251CBC49B49D5BA8A44D1C8CFE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Guidance and training</header><text>The task force shall provide guidance and training to officers and employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation and other Federal, international, and other law enforcement agencies, as appropriate, relating to—</text><paragraph id="H989FB39A7CBF4C0C860D00F732F3C50D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>techniques and procedures to—</text><subparagraph id="H9DA105A349C04D9D8C0213C6D17BF36F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognize evidence or potential evidence relating to the dark web; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E922A4ECFFB42F18CD628A6AF12D0B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and recognize patterns and practices relating to the distribution of illegal drugs, services, and goods through the dark web;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AE4BBE7C45944AAB25C122271870806"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the types of information that should be collected and recorded in information technology systems used by the Federal Bureau of Investigation to help—</text><subparagraph id="H6FC84F10D7DE4559AEE2A96D9F0DB58B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify administrators and operators of illicit marketplaces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24796F5A6B424978A636DB1F6404AF73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify vendors, buyers, and other individuals involved in the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB94C425BFDE489DB5E75AC829B31CC4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>detect, disrupt, and dismantle illicit marketplaces;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D35C496558D4A2385B364E8E1993815"><enum>(3)</enum><text>procedures for systematic and routine information sharing within the Federal Bureau of Investigation and between Federal, State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91DFCE3F19A24E57BBD6A9BED77DFA04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other training or guidance the Director determines necessary to carry out the duties of the task force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEE912484206D41B4A7B7D403BFE3BD59"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, acting through the Director, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report, which shall include, for the previous year—</text><paragraph id="H2537A5E9FC4A4E26BBD5982AE1C7A099"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the activities and accomplishments of the task force;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3DACC870F974934B1BE90F71EA625CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the investigative methods used by the task force, including an assessment of the effectiveness of the methods;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A0058A88D3543A8A85E1E568127D0CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information on investigation and prosecution performance measures for the task force, including—</text><subparagraph id="H09C34662FD2348A29F45EE2D8C2CCDB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of investigations the task force conducted or assisted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59FCE51915634F24AB428D49CBE5F071"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of illicit marketplaces detected, disrupted, or dismantled as a result of an investigation conducted or assisted by the task force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3B68F3086084C43B502C25E801C957D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of arrests relating to an investigation conducted or assisted by the task force; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A87C5A4C7BB4CDB926B888A181DB108"><enum>(D)</enum><text>statistics that account for the disposition of investigations by the task force that did not result in an arrest or a prosecution;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H301658D9502C4561ADB0BED06653E90A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of partnerships between the task force and other Federal, State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, including the effectiveness of guidance and training provided by the task force to personnel of other Federal, State, Tribal, and law enforcement agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1085C024F08C4D2885E2CF0F700007AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an evaluation of the collaboration and coordination between the task force and international partners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A2D9BAA68964A3999EB1D6721533735"><enum>(6)</enum><text>recommendations for additional congressional or legislative action, as appropriate, that would be useful or necessary to achieve the purpose of the task force described in subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C970371E5D14968AD3115C0D365F6FD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a summary of how transactions involving the distribution of illegal drugs, goods, and services through the dark web are financed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FB83C2F78164E208924BE5F5290700F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of a plan to increase the capacity to investigate the distribution of illegal drugs, goods, and services through the dark web; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BC0417A9B4244E5AA19BDFD15FF041D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>recommendations for additional congressional or legislative action, as appropriate, that would improve the efforts of Federal agencies to detect, disrupt, and dismantle illicit marketplaces, including efforts to identify individuals and groups involved in the distribution of illegal drugs, goods, and services through the dark web.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4DAEA7491A094EF3A31B7260CB5BFC25"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Director shall carry out this section using amounts otherwise made available to the Attorney General.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6BDBEE6ECA614CA989FBCB83F8B8E236"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to have force or effect on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA481416935154C0DA279F2A540B5969F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report on virtual currencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to Congress a report on the use of virtual currencies in the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces on the dark web, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="H110F8992207D4E4887B55D3BAB2565DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of how virtual currencies are—</text><subparagraph id="HCB6BC10EBB434F9AB36134AB6887DE6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used to finance transactions involving the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces on the dark web; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE42FA939EC124C2B9A7AE7203D352412"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exchanged in the course of transactions described in subparagraph (A), including transactions involving—</text><clause id="HFFEFFB194C5A45B5BC66804DC5BEFB2D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>peer-to-peer networks;</text></clause><clause id="H807997738C0C40FD83D270BA005D8067"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>virtual currency;</text></clause><clause id="H7C276DDA0ACA4533B37AF82BD165EB1E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>money transmitters; or</text></clause><clause id="H24D388B48E2F443C8F31FA47CD1242E2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other financial institutions;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E42EA510F4A4639AFE6A689ECB7332C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of instances involving the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces on the dark web in which an individual involved used a virtual currency to finance the distribution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15F659B4551D49ABB25E019EC9A81637"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the most common types of virtual currencies used by individuals involved in the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces on the dark web;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CBA9CD94CB24AD388E3F70B51156C8E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of the capacity to investigate the use of virtual currencies in the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces on the dark web, including—</text><subparagraph id="H4F816231278644899B64DC35C6710491"><enum>(A)</enum><text>efforts to assist financial institutions in detecting, identifying, and reporting suspicious activity and money laundering;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB2D70C30C7845DDB0E80BF5B5C61F26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to obtain financial records and other documents from virtual currency operators and exchanges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07516FDEEED54875AC9D1BEB89EEF1BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>training and guidance to Federal, State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies and prosecutors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0C10ACE09AD4410965146EFF7DDB4CC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>coordination and collaboration with international partners; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05E1CF31A2FA49338B6B234B444B6B93"><enum>(5)</enum><text>recommendations for additional congressional or legislative action that would improve the efforts of Federal agencies to detect, disrupt, and dismantle illicit marketplaces on the dark web, including efforts to identify individuals using virtual currencies in the distribution of opioids through illicit marketplaces on the dark web.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB8DAA46FD79E4C899C6247B619A6603A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Five-year update</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that, not less frequently than once every 5 years, Congress should evaluate and, if necessary, update the definition of the term <term>dark web</term> in section 401(i) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(i)</external-xref>), as added by section 4 of this Act.</text></section><section id="HFD5D55C317154043BFFC78749FF1C6AC"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any portion of this Act, or the amendments made by this Act, or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of this Act or the amendments made by this Act to other persons not similarly situated or to other circumstances shall not be affected by the invalidation.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

