<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H48D80B1873834B75A3562DACBB380479" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1288 IH: Supporting the designation of May 14, 2026, as “National Scam Survivor Day”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1288</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260514">May 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001229">Mr. Shreve</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000380">Mr. Amo</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Supporting the designation of May 14, 2026, as <quote>National Scam Survivor Day</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble>
<whereas><text>Whereas the Better Business Bureau found that 44 percent of scam reports in 2024 resulted in dollar loss for the individual, with a 30 percent increase in average dollar loss per scam report;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas approximately 3,000,000 Americans filed fraud reports with the Federal Trade Commission in 2025, an increase of 400,000 from the previous year;</text></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas it is estimated that American citizens lost more than $195,000,000,000 to scams in 2024, an increase of $35,000,000,000 from the previous year;</text></whereas> <whereas><text>Whereas scammers continue to develop new strategies to target American citizens, including—</text>
<paragraph id="H44DA18AF821B473EB841B083ED9BAEB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">social media scams, where the Federal Trade Commission estimates nearly <fraction>1/3</fraction> of successful scams originate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA3E8E7175C347ADB0D312AA00C54C5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cryptocurrency scams, which resulted in more than $11,000,000,000 in losses in 2025, according to the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB845AAD8CCB94047B260EC74EB2D69F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>small business scams such as fraudulent invoices, advertising offerings, and impersonations of government officials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB47525803DC146F8ACD96DDC530C6509"><enum>(4)</enum><text>scams using artificial intelligence to create false audio or video files;</text></paragraph></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas targeting of at-risk individuals for scams is on the rise, including— and</text> <paragraph id="HD10E2D961546435193FFD7E0712ECD8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>veterans, who reported $584,000,000 in losses to scams in 2024 alone, according to the Federal Trade Commission, and who are often targeted by individuals posing as Department of Veterans Affairs officials or health care providers;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H37C2081BA2144501AE21CD9CBAFD202F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seniors, in which a study by the University of Michigan found that 75 percent of Americans ages 50 to 80 experienced a scam attempt between 2021 and 2023, and 30 percent fell victim to a scam; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB3708DD8F784E7EA6EA0EF29E3FB75F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>young adults, who are now losing more money to scams than any other age group through fraudulent employment offers, investment opportunities, and checks and money orders, according to the Better Business Bureau; and</text></paragraph></whereas>
<whereas><text>Whereas there is a greater need for increasing awareness of scams, including—</text> <paragraph id="H78BD811B36C54CAD933271BBA9EFDE18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing consumers and business owners with knowledge and tools to avoid scams;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H72BD0506D8024BFE91797EE13D641CE3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encouraging Americans to utilize Federal Government resources to identify and address potential scams; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA9E934D4F554DB592F058953E8E36B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improving the ability of Federal law enforcement to discover, track, and halt scam operations to protect the American people: Now, therefore, be it</text></paragraph></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HC90CCE29B7E645889E2A74EC3C028C73"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="H701A0F29866E4B95A86636FFD39BEBEC"><text>That the House of Representatives—</text> <paragraph id="HFBA4E8FDC25143FC877FABB32E10D9D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports the designation of <quote>National Scam Survivor Day</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1157C7F8CA244EA6A1278BD413AFA5AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourages increased public awareness of scams and strategies to prevent or address scams;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA39F9A9B03E3404EAC19330E2ABD519B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the impact of scams on American citizens and businesses;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H408EA8A6E4E34690928ACE950DAE422C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the importance of improving public access to scam prevention resources;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HABE980B52F3F44D5A94BA5A72F30C07C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supports the role of Federal and local law enforcement entities in addressing scams;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1BB386DBCDC746A991CED7AE2FCD4F51"><enum>(6)</enum><text>urges a collaborative approach to supporting scam survivors and prevent future scams among governmental, private, and nonprofit organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD662FD681B464A04BE224E9B86730CBF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>encourages continued improvements to existing scam prevention resource toolkits, support for scam survivors, and law enforcement efforts to hold scammers accountable.</text></paragraph></section> 
</resolution-body></resolution>

