<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC4140199CA6482E82229563934DCAB0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7140 IH: Customer Legal Ease and Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7140</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260116">January 16, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect main street retailers and end users in secondary patent actions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC036698F48E34A2EA40122D635E851AB" style="OLC"><section id="H7B6C56F1EB344673826C335C2EA6A0D3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Customer Legal Ease and Relief Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE7FF22BE56C54786963DCE552C6451D4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Stay of action against retailer or end user</header><subsection id="H49EAF4C069724EF2BECC0B3BFC3C2781"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/35/29">Chapter 29</external-xref> of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HCCAF5BE5C3EA43EDB155090486A0C799" style="USC"><section id="H01A4A6BF1269476286D697CBC6043CC9"><enum>299A.</enum><header>Stay of action against retailer or end user</header><subsection id="HE19D35FDE9934F239E580CEDABCCE124"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Entry of stay</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a civil action in which a party asserts a claim for relief for infringement of a patent, the court shall grant a motion to stay at least the portion of the action against a retailer or end user of an accused instrumentality if—</text><paragraph id="H858047521DE745AC97DE36B40C180BD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the manufacturer of the accused instrumentality is a party to the action or a separate action involving the patent and the accused instrumentality;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC9C3D7D2C1B4A67B81275C05AC6F72A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the retailer or end user does not manufacture, assemble, integrate, or transform the accused instrumentality or a relevant part thereof;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F3C7B18940849D1812B5F729B0DDCC0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the retailer or end user agrees that if a final judgment on the merits is entered in the action to which the manufacturer is a party, for any future action involving the same accused instrumentality supplied by the same manufacturer, the retailer or end user—</text><subparagraph id="HE617CEC1238C4BD7B8424C2D17A89719"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waives all defenses under section 282(b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24BDBCF024D04576A8722A35ABCBE49B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is bound by any issue decided in the action to which the manufacturer is a party; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81C91E2975B647858EA5D05E66044418"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the retailer or end user agrees to be bound by any injunction issued with respect to the accused instrumentality in the action to which the manufacturer is a party.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB29B97AE272B432CA713198187E1401E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Lift of stay</header><text>A stay entered under this section shall be lifted upon a showing that the manufacturer cannot be made to satisfy a damages judgment.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAEB3148686424CF1A0DBFF18A358D777"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Bond or escrow</header><text>The court may conduct an initial hearing or inquiry to determine if the manufacturer can be made to satisfy a damages judgment. If the court determines that there is a substantial likelihood that the manufacturer will not satisfy a damages judgment, the court may require the retailer or end user to post a bond or place funds or other property in escrow.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1D969F704684F699894B1FF73BE84FC"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Stipulation as To use of accused instrumentality</header> <text>The court may, as necessary in view of an infringement claim against the manufacturer, require the end user or retailer to stipulate as to the extent of the use of the accused instrumentality and allow limited discovery as to such use.</text>
 </subsection><subsection id="HBBCF56BBAE1D41B48111CBA7EEE32A47"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Time limit</header><text>A motion for a stay under this section shall be filed not later than the later of—</text><paragraph id="H2886B43E67934C20905781BDE5316AEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>six months after the service of the first pleading or paper in the action that specifically identifies the accused instrumentality and how the accused instrumentality is alleged to infringe the patent;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A8E3478A58C42FDAA408DE2F01C8903"><enum>(2)</enum><text>six months after the date on which the manufacturer becomes a party to an action involving the patent and the accused instrumentality; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10EB77ADDFE743D4B9DC113069E8AC70"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the entry of the first scheduling order in the case.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81A8F48AEADE4308B737F76AD0635075"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the discretion of a court to enter a stay under other authority.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFC05DE80EF9846C081C6CD93D5929961"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H351AD81DAC2A407BAD93E434CD286B4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accused instrumentality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>accused instrumentality</term> means a product, or an instrumentality that implements a process, that is a material part of the claimed invention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA42B50D7674C408BA631D34954D319D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affiliate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>affiliate</term> means any entity that controls, is controlled by, or is under common control of another entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H815D2A66AC754810BCB376E293E5F9DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>End user</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>end user</term> means an entity that does not use the accused instrumentality other than for the ordinary and intended purpose of the instrumentality and that does not direct, obligate, or induce the manufacturer to make the accused instrumentality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BDF97CF05CF42B6A199A21BA2ABF1A0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Manufacturer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>manufacturer</term> means an entity that makes, assembles, integrates, transforms, or supplies the accused instrumentality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80A790CEB3E94D2FA820255CA5326D7C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Retailer</header><text>The term <term>retailer</term> means an entity that generates revenues predominantly through the sale to the public of consumer goods or services, or an affiliate of such entity.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC018860B036D4E4EA843D672FBD46A9C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/35/29">chapter 29</external-xref> of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HF90AB1B39BD24437A337828C1374C754" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="item">Sec. 299A. Stay of action against retailer or end user.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE8590A59A03A46BBA6C8F041FC5234D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall apply to any action for which a complaint is served on and after such effective date.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

