<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF889C8668A2483CA8E7604938BE5D91" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6302 IH: Whistleblowers Aiding National Security Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6302</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251125">November 25, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to establish a whistleblower incentive program with respect to defense exports control enforcement.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F12E81B0B6D4BDE97B9495EA8DBE8F8" style="OLC"><section id="HAE6259924B7D44DDB9BC5F9CB8B6DF4E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Whistleblowers Aiding National Security Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE3F53227FDC542798C236BC0557BD719"><enum>2.</enum><header>Defense exports control whistleblower incentive program</header><subsection id="H646E6F5C53F0436FACC5098267634B1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2651a">22 U.S.C. 2651a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 36A the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFB55A9D4DCDD495D8F0E4A43203A266C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H4CBDE263442B4F068A5ABCFC20BA2E1B"><enum>36B.</enum><header>Defense exports control whistleblower incentive program</header><subsection id="HEBB394F24AFF4B42BCE2B1021F19DF94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H2701AF2EECCF463E885A2C6FA163BAEA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a whistleblower incentive program (hereinafter the <quote>Program</quote>) to reward an individual who voluntarily provides original information that leads to the imposition of any civil penalty with respect to a covered violation—</text><subparagraph id="HB6FA99F2D6304B47BEF8C5F0BFF58DA9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary shall issue an interim rule establishing such Program not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA2FE101932F43EAB5B92038DDC77757"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary shall issue a final rule establishing such Program not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FE5BA8DB6444882A5309FA1B7AF3BD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text>Not later than the date on which the online portal is established under subsection (b)(2), the Secretary shall provide public notice of the Program in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H796CC8A4061A45E49ADC74B339D831FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of original information</header><paragraph id="HCB51E0D71BB140ADADA5D0A60FCDF6A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission procedures</header><text>The Secretary shall by regulation establish procedures for an individual to submit original information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6314628439418FA266A402C5CB0795"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Online portal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall develop, implement, and maintain a secure online portal, on a website accessible to the public, for the reporting of original information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9901D1F17088459F89D07D9EB1F3EBEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Anonymous submissions</header><subparagraph id="HEE5D18396EDE48C3A6506F0A913277BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the procedures under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall include a procedure for an individual to anonymously submit original information, including through counsel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB559C0E64D384BF69D5BB3973FA16926"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Identity disclosure</header><text>The Secretary may require an individual to disclose their identity, directly or through counsel, at any time prior to issuing an award under the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDFD366EF233429F82F015CC8456C129"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Review of original information</header><paragraph id="HAF31DA9855F4420F8BB49F033B0DDEE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date that original information is submitted under subsection (b), the Secretary shall determine whether the original information is credible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEDE0A0F9BDF471E9A000D534EEDD7F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Secretary determines under paragraph (1) that original information is credible, the Secretary shall, unless the Secretary determines impracticable, complete an investigation into the allegations contained in the original information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF81C2B41120E46CFB3E6D13F27AB906A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duty to update</header><subparagraph id="H3915168F1CE94232BB72F86B6EB4D7B1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall update the individual who submitted original information under subsection (b) not later than 30 days after the date on which the original was submitted and not less than every 30 days thereafter until the original information is determined not credible under paragraph (1) or an investigation is completed under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FC2DC52ABC148D99F1D49AEBFB3B622"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sensitive information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may omit from the updates required by subparagraph (A) any information that the Secretary determines could compromise a review of original information under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF952963FA9434D279D4A0958646C53BD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Frivolous reports</header><text>The Secretary may determine that review of original information under this subsection is not warranted if the individual who submitted the original information has previously made not less than 2 submissions of original information that the Secretary determined under paragraph (1) were not credible.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10950EE899974D5B9DFF3A49449AFDA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Award amount</header><paragraph id="H2B5F7421487E48FEBF7E96B0F345E27C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An award issued under the Program shall be in an amount equal to—</text><subparagraph id="H364CD0AFC0AB4ABFA0493DE796D2CA99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 10 percent of the covered civil penalty; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3879F7C4E3AF426C88C2AF09BD9D999F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 30 percent of the covered civil penalty.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78F4C62AC40540CE9F1AD57438972FB3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of award amount</header><text>To determine the amount of an award issued under the Program, the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="HA6B13B8540704CED9518E2E51E8858DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall consider—</text><clause id="H86C89322E6F84E7A90603EB2E319B285"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how significant the original information provided by the individual was with respect to a final determination that a covered violation occurred;</text></clause><clause id="H8398083B05BC4646AB46941180FD2325"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the degree of assistance, other than providing original information, provided by the individual, or any legal representative of the individual; and</text></clause><clause id="HE2C8746420964D9E8518CC4E16DA8A57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other additional factor the Secretary determines relevant, including—</text><subclause id="HCC27EA15AC374DAF9EE3BEF828C62CDA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>accuracy;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6BF950CFEBDC466D96E65267C4223A97"><enum>(II)</enum><text>relevance;</text></subclause><subclause id="H61FE76CA176C45E5A6032E227347D6D7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>timeliness; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6AD59E645FB14B6FB917051988A360DD"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>usefulness; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1B130AEFF884931BF858167A17044B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not consider the balance of the account established under subsection (g) for the Program in the Treasury of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A51B206C3BF4034BF7F0CB2CF11AA44"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Joint submissions</header><text>In the case of original information submitted under subsection (b) jointly by not less than 2 individuals, any award issued under the Program shall be equally distributed among each individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85341CFA42184D8DB194D612FE019A16"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Denial of award</header><paragraph id="H10F7C67C45EA472DA9EB0679A48BAB82"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a), and except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary may not issue an award to an individual to whom an award otherwise would be issued, if such individual acquired the original information submitted under the Program—</text><subparagraph id="H0988E03786B74664BE61EA1689D95D99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through such individual’s role as—</text><clause id="H21D247D25AF84EB5A07434417A79E483"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an officer, director, trustee, or partner of an entity that handles internal processes for legal violations for the person or persons; or</text></clause><clause id="H3181628A3F94469697A034D7CB3EB14D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an employee of an entity that conducts compliance or internal audits for the person or persons; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD07395E07C8742988686B562D6A80F5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any means that violates Federal or State criminal law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H81B9969B71564D2B9D5AB8EEA871FE12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibition on issuing an award to certain individuals under paragraph (1)(A) shall not apply if—</text><subparagraph id="HECCD3A39D8D54673AA0E4D546DEA14DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual had a reasonable basis to believe that disclosing the original information to the Secretary was necessary to stop conduct likely to cause significant harm to national security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EC531FA923D493FBDBC457B98FB8E7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the individual had a reasonable basis to believe that the relevant entity was obstructing an investigation into the misconduct; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H429EC4419C0845279F351ECDE206F3D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 120 days have passed since the individual provided the information to the audit committee, chief legal officer, chief compliance officer of the relevant entity or the supervisor of the individual, or their equivalent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56EFF7847BC54F9FB51D7B39F23FBFA2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Representation by counsel</header><paragraph id="H38610A3E2A224A2BA256BAA83445956E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), an individual may choose to be represented by counsel at any time while cooperating with the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B0B8CC39D254BBBB7B894581FE41630"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required representation for anonymous claims</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who, under subsection (b)(2)(A), anonymously provides original information shall be represented by counsel while cooperating with the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6789A63A787B4A84BEDCF7A721446686"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Defense Export Compliance Accountability Fund</header><paragraph id="H6FBEED0239E54898A277A09AB6E05CDE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish in the Treasury of the United States an account with respect to the Program to be known as the <quote>Defense Export Compliance Accountability Fund</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE1B90F01D3A47C4A6581F22EBB39CBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposits and credits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be deposited into or credited to the fund an amount equal to any fine collected by the Secretary on or after the date of the enactment of this section in any judicial or administrative action brought by the Secretary that depends on or was initiated because of original information submitted by an individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE818B6F8AFBB4917BC7C56A93CB54837"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The amounts deposited in the fund—</text><subparagraph id="H24EAA3622F744D76B0F0F4B30425DAA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be used to pay each award issued under the Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D653EB4BA7F4E81BDB9CB9A8333A779"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be used for the administrative costs of the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA7815BB67724A7AAEC1320C7B54668E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Insufficient amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there are insufficient amounts to pay an award issued under the Program, the Secretary shall deposit into the account established under paragraph (1), or credit to such account, an amount equal to the remaining balance of such award from any monetary sanctions collected by the Secretary pursuant to the final determination of a covered violation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03A8128B88B44AB5A70AC7B820C96ADF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 31st, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Program, including a description of the number of awards made under the Program and the types of cases in which such awards were made with respect to the fiscal year preceding submission of such report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3FE9597596D443CFA5D77E06B2F31ABD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prohibition against retaliation</header><paragraph id="H77333C5B783040EF9C72DC79FAA646E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual who submits original information under subsection (b) or otherwise participates in the Program, and except as provided in paragraph (2), no employer may, directly or indirectly, discharge, demote, suspend, threaten, or harass such individual, or discriminate against such individual in any other manner in the terms and conditions of employment, because such individual submitted original information or otherwise participated in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08B41752142B42F2A566B3485C2AAF41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The protection against retaliation established by paragraph (1) shall not apply to any individual who reports information under this section knowing that such information is false.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4C38A36BE2F421EA699BC0353EA87D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph id="H2E790CE801E645DABBF28742BEA90822"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><text>An individual who alleges a violation of paragraph (1) may bring an action under this subparagraph in the appropriate district court of the United States for the relief provided for in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB2650812EF449E2A87C50CF3A411044"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subpoenas</header><text>A subpoena requiring the attendance of a witness at a trial or hearing conducted under this clause may be served at any place in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51801FCE70E444FF833295208ACA3CF7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Statute of limitations</header><clause id="HB12FAB9ED8084194BB400AEBD4130AAC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), an action under paragraph (1) shall not be entertained if commenced more than 6 years after the date on which the violation occurred or 3 years after the date on which facts material to the right of action are known or reasonably should have been known by the employee alleging such a violation.</text></clause><clause id="H5B12CC48566349F68002943D2F52B05A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Required action within 10 years</header><text>An action may not in any circumstance be brought more than 10 years after the date on which the violation occurs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H21CD0C6B4A26477CB392168AD7C1CE48"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>The relief provided for under this paragraph shall be the following:</text><subparagraph id="H21C75B61474741DA990BBD39A1E5FB03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Reinstatement with the same seniority status that the individual would have had, but for the discrimination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38DCD54A6AE949DEA357295B031F862F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Back pay in an amount equal to twice the amount otherwise owed to the individual, with interest.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F5E48080C94431481F26DFCAF5EAB1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Compensation for litigation costs, expert witness fees, and reasonable fees for attorneys.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6556592D2E9D42D7A221AAF07C9DF3F0"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><paragraph id="H92C970AAECD04A41A2C9DF8E6B5A10C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clauses (ii) and (iii), the Secretary and any officer or employee of the Department of Commerce may not disclose any information, including original information submitted under subsection (b), that could reasonably be expected to reveal the identity of any individual who provides original information to the Program, except in accordance with the provisions of section 552a of title 5, United States Code, unless and until required to be disclosed to a defendant or respondent in connection with a public proceeding instituted by the Secretary or any entity described in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E02BBDAFF72459A989575ED89EC6DC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public disclosure exemption</header><text>For purposes of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, this subparagraph shall be considered a statute described in subsection (b)(3)(B) of such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEFE3DBE26E6435DAFE4AB42B9C0EE34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the ability of the Attorney General to present such evidence to a grand jury or to share such evidence with potential witnesses or defendants in the course of an ongoing criminal investigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A3CEAED61D14EDBA313275E7C540C66"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability to Government agencies</header><subparagraph id="HB8FA2ED2D62A4FA48478159917290EF5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>When determined by the Secretary to be necessary to accomplish the purposes of the Program, or any regulation, order, license, or other authorization issued under a covered regulation, the Secretary may make any information referred to paragraph (1) available to—</text><clause id="H2AB6FBFA78C1409AA6648A71C1FFC2F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federal law enforcement agency;</text></clause><clause id="H89840FE12D4E4DDFA6888322ACAA6931"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a national security agency;</text></clause><clause id="HDB9E30393A504A90BBF08E6B97E726FB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a State law enforcement or regulatory agency;</text></clause><clause id="H68F19A3B898A4D1CBFAF18577134F604"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an appropriate regulatory authority;</text></clause><clause id="H4286BE84EE9E4D5289E6A4E150BF5993"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a self-regulatory organization; and</text></clause><clause id="H8A554ED39B9C4D0F9173C041C6E8B797"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a foreign law enforcement authority.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC637DD07CF445D28B10E998C18954EC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Preservation of confidentiality</header><text>If the Secretary makes the information referred to in paragraph (1) available under subparagraph (A), such information shall remain confidential.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3962D83CC3A4CFC9714A6F45613309A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Directed Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary shall issue such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A44679AB425447482374F76BB65C9A8"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H83D1373F01574291AEF1167DF26779DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C6971D0CC7C4468826F106A3C2E7249"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered civil penalty</header><text>The term <quote>covered civil penalty</quote> means a civil penalty imposed, with respect to a covered violation, as result of the original information submitted by an individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B628F238D284F79A9E270DBBBD9648E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered regulation</header><text>The term <quote>covered regulation</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H417362E8E6504C0991066E5E09761678"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any regulation, license, or order under the administrative jurisdiction of the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls of the Department; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6198004C61FF437289996BA6F12886BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (parts 120–130 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations) (or any successor regulation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F623ACCF3E94463B598CAD8C6BE805E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered violation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered violation</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="HE79010CD96F84F309AFF2A5E28D722B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a violation, an attempted violation, or a conspiracy to violate a covered regulation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ACD1A17FFA04ADD825EA3721ED21598"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes each such violation, attempted violation, or conspiracy to violate that occurred before the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H544ACB5CB7C441E6899E46604D6C9AAC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Original information</header><text>The term <quote>original information</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H2EE5EBB22B4C495882A2D495CBA1F444"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means information—</text><clause id="HD0E21DD3298D450F80E82D9AF044FD60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>derived from the independent knowledge or analysis of an individual;</text></clause><clause id="HEC36A58CE87D48C0986FF545CD326439"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not known to the Secretary from any other source;</text></clause><clause id="H2258429B818C4DD1B3D2E22A12A77C78"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>not exclusively derived from an allegation made in a judicial or administrative proceeding, government report, hearing, audit, or investigation, or from news media, unless such individual is the source of such allegation; and</text></clause><clause id="HD5238DDA7C75462BB7C424EF7504D1AB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>provided to the Secretary voluntarily without any request from the Secretary or any other Government official; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56BC0323E86A4547A69ED3FD5ADA4112"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes information that meets the qualifications described in subparagraph (A) and is submitted to the Secretary by such individual—</text><clause id="H0D15E3AFA3F44AE6BBBB2C917CCF1F4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>after the date of the enactment of this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H605B5FB763BA4B9C8C820C707F00B9EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>before the establishment of the Program under subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8582A774CDC4635BCEB1E3105837CC5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of State acting through the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Defense Trade Controls.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H82130D2669984D3B975B220C0E6D0B93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HC87731191AED4AE0967C9BE7B04FCA53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization to make award</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 36(b) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2708">22 U.S.C. 2708(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HE55A9A7071C640C29C5E904B21DDDA3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (14), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D39743233004CDBBF4C910F2E0BF5F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (15), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19C4E32697714FCD9031D0394AD6EAAA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H5D8772F194ED45AC97639BCC396CDC49" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H16FC8D76A6624EEA8BA65DA96B887300" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the imposition of any civil penalty with respect to a covered violation under section 36B.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE9AB0729BD43CB9B435DFA0AFC5BE6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion of funds from Crime Victims Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1402(b)(1)(B) of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20101">34 U.S.C. 20101(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HAA72393E8A164177AB835396FCB81925"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (iii), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE71B875CBEC481F90ECBF336EEC0679"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2B252BF2A8F4679A82B2A1F0514CF88"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF7743BBF4F00472E88E9DB3C4E8BAB33" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H23E17CC5A9754C5DB4063F7EB8E005D4"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Defense Export Compliance Accountability Fund pursuant to the Whistleblowers Aiding National Security Act of 2025;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B3249EE4FEF4629AAC102182BFCA4A5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text>There is authorized such sums as may be necessary for the Secretary of State to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

