<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF4668AA94ACE4EE2B0FADB89BC6CD5A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9302 IH: Student Athlete Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9302</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish rules regarding eligibility of student athletes for intercollegiate athletics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H65FA335E26E74BABBCAF473FB04EC2DE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HA11A186A74BA42BE921EEE95B7885DA2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Athlete Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5DA79FE6E5F2470B9079A62D8EC94EEB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="HA021676F944449AFA942F50BFE8DF2AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Athletic department</header><text>The term <term>athletic department</term> means a department at an institution of higher education that sponsors or conducts 1 or more varsity intercollegiate athletics programs in which student athletes enrolled at the institution of higher education compete in athletic contests against student athletes enrolled at another institution of higher education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56FA5B6BA2C74976B9B246BDCCE30CBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conference</header><text>The term <term>conference</term> means an organization that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3DD6D647428346D28EA00D68F2F47F4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has as members 2 or more institutions of higher education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF29474F6301746F8B6B765A30EF55279"><enum>(B)</enum><text>arranges or conducts season-long intercollegiate athletic events to determine, among its members, a champion in a particular intercollegiate sport; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA59F451724F64FB58EBC5031275E808F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sets rules for varsity intercollegiate sports competition among its members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H4794ACA431B441B5ACA04CA5D2218BF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant-in-aid</header><text>The term <term>grant-in-aid</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H573B405BC8C04BE9A01A179A816C0D96"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tuition, room, board, books, fees, and personal expenses paid or provided by an institution of higher education up to the full cost of attendance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H7A306BEDED3049E6B0C99247C2DB54A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal Pell Grants and other State and Federal grants unrelated to, and not awarded with respect to, participation in varsity intercollegiate sports competition;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B856F102CFA4831B8B83FEE3D589450"><enum>(C)</enum><text>health insurance and the costs of health care wholly or partly self-funded by the National Collegiate Athletic Association, a conference, or an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA4FA08E0833E45A28FE58D8001E029B7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>disability and loss of value insurance that is wholly or partly self-funded by the National Collegiate Athletic Association, a conference, or an institution of higher education; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1AB9A365127A4E24A90910F2303976F2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>career counseling or job placement services available to all students at an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H38B3E538A2604B6FA05AC862B05F4EA2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4BA55A2965CF4EC2935A66A2C2D9B2C4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National Collegiate Athletic Association</header><text>The term <term>National Collegiate Athletic Association</term> means the National Collegiate Athletic Association that functions as an authority for intercollegiate athletics in the United States (or a successor organization).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB15423B7B4534ACE9FCA0404B82C0E78"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Student athlete</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>student athlete</term> means an individual who engages or is eligible to engage in intercollegiate athletics.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD3495498F08545F8B560853679EE316E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Transfer portal</header><text>The term <term>transfer portal</term> means a process managed by the National Collegiate Athletic Association that facilitates the transfer of student athletes from one institution of higher education to another institution of higher education for the purpose of engaging, or being able to engage in the future, in intercollegiate athletics.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE8A6D337A5AF42F893D203032E547DD4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Varsity intercollegiate athletics program</header><text>The term <term>varsity intercollegiate athletics program</term> means a sport played at the intercollegiate level, administered by an athletic department, for which eligibility requirements for participation by student athletes are established by the National Collegiate Athletic Association or a conference.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H641C14E3DC1F4E40A45D7F189B998AD3"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Varsity intercollegiate sports competition</header><text>The term <term>varsity intercollegiate sports competition</term> means a competition—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E133077B9BD4CDB99670F4138F5B0A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">between or among student athletes; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE346C0432D954CF8A4AAB2CFCE346071"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">involving 2 or more varsity intercollegiate athletics programs sponsored by different institutions of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H988A3E446F36465E82D629BBADF47112"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation of student athlete eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any rules set forth by the National Collegiate Athletic Association, a student athlete shall have 5 consecutive years of eligibility to play intercollegiate athletics, regardless of injury or any other event.</text></section>
<section id="H9503876FA6B44D2B8022CB72FBAC9B55"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transfer portal</header>
<subsection id="H58128473BA9E4D42A8CECD9D6D714422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Role of National Collegiate Athletic Association</header><text>The National Collegiate Athletic Association shall set forth rules relating to the transfer portal, including with respect to the 1 or more periods during which a student athlete may formally notify the institution of higher education in which the student athlete is enrolled of his or her intent to transfer to another institution of higher education.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H61D1D432BCA34100A003F564AAC7E4AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of transfer</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC3455F01D93B493DAAA6A9433041DEF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a student athlete enrolled at an institution of higher education who transfers to another institution of higher education shall be ineligible to participate in any athletic competition sponsored by the National Collegiate Athletic Association during the academic year, beginning at the start of the fall semester and ending at the end of an institution of higher education's final summer session, in which the student athlete entered the transfer portal.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9D69FB70432945EDB06F2F89C0683D01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for initial transfer</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the first transfer of a student athlete from an institution of higher education to another institution of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9E6A24A5A7044ABDB74E8102FDA5BFFB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain other rules and regulations</header><text>This section shall supersede any National Collegiate Athletic Association rule or regulation related to transfer eligibility that is in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB430FD1A73864008A2D0A17614BAF54C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Antitrust exemption</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>) to the contrary, the National Collegiate Athletic Association (or any successor organization) may establish rules relating to the transfer portal under this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H702353660E794835AFE59FAF8399BBFE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Additional protections for student athletes</header> <subsection id="H2F9790E4CD53425295AC22CE5A3ABB4E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant-in-Aid protection</header><text>Subject to subsection (b), an institution of higher education shall honor the original grant-in-aid commitment made by the institution of higher education to a student athlete.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H17EB621B4DBA4033B1564BB483BCA509"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect of transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a student athlete who transfers from one institution of higher education to another institution of higher education, subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF38A1CF7AE55414D9A9D8F877E74F395"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not apply to the former institution of higher education of the student athlete; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H821756DD9CA74F0BA519F97860EE234B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall apply to the new institution of higher education to which the student athlete transfers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC9E848EB21524E7A9005DA1A8D08FB86" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to prohibit an institution of higher education from revoking the grant-in-aid of a student athlete or former student athlete who does not remain in good standing in accordance with the standards or code of conduct of the institution of higher education.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H64767CE0BB0841EFA38A50A3EB2C15A6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to State law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No State or political subdivision of a State may adopt, maintain, enforce, or continue in effect any law, regulation, rule, requirement, or standard that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H093C4CE279CE4B62A5E7DD5AC6F97DCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conflicts with the provisions of this Act; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H773BBC17C62B46DDA98983B1E7DCBD73"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">limits or restricts the rights of student athletes, the National Collegiate Athletic Association, conferences, or institutions of higher education under this Act.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

