<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM26535-0RL-VV-P8H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4294 IS: Taiwan Relations Reinforcement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4294</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260414">April 14, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of War to submit an annual report to Congress that assesses the capacity of the United States to fully implement the Taiwan Relations Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan Relations Reinforcement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id13b67764e54e40009356823e77477bee"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idf96b2fd4a74b4d6d8dc4b218cf2c5952"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="idf7af78465fde4d6aaa596f12723ea8ca"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf9fdbeb103d8405a99375c1fad8c127e"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb736e23aa9c44d6aa1fd5243aa1d1b6a"> <enum>(C)</enum> <text>the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text>
                </subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id09f528478d6b4224a0f0ecd14f132bb2">
                    <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text>
 </subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id33a0d81a98ad4272b99d48ad5e49bcbe"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gray zone tactics</header><text>The term <term>gray zone tactics</term> means coercive actions, including military, paramilitary, cyber, space, economic, informational, and legal actions and other activities conducted below the threshold of armed conflict to alter the status quo without triggering a conventional military response.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id092f013c16324004b2771cfdfedc7942"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Taiwan contingency</header><text>The term <term>Taiwan Contingency</term> means any attempt—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9685c16cbb724f248089ba359339767e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to overthrow or dismantle the governing institutions in Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id040b58223786453e81d8952f1e824af3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to occupy any territory controlled or administered by Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfce25199e1ae400aaedbc5041cc8cbda"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to violate the territorial integrity of Taiwan; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f4b4a05c92a42c3bce7dc09852f0d15"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to take significant action against Taiwan, including—</text><clause id="id618e007cf66b4f40b34a889321f776ca"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conducting a naval blockade of Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="id7abed81fc137400c8050353823c03d5b"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>seizing any outlying island of Taiwan; or</text></clause><clause id="idae3378c29b804242ab7147b0d94e9fde"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>perpetrating a significant physical or cyber attack on Taiwan that erodes the ability of the governing institutions in Taiwan to operate or provide essential services to the citizens of Taiwan.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idea021f5cceed4558b05623391ef53df7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on United States capacity to comply with the Taiwan Relations Act</header><subsection id="idbb48be478f2045fcb7e50621a8ca7ee2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of War, in coordination with the Commander of the United States Indo-Pacific Command, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that assesses the capacity of the United States to fully implement sections 2 and 3 of the Taiwan Relations Act (22 U.S.C. 3301 and 3302), including—</text><paragraph id="id711e2ff2f23d4bc2882e53db85fd33a8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>maintaining the capacity to resist any resort to force or other forms of coercion that would jeopardize the security or the social or economic system of the people on Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94f636ced13f49b293769e6386878b42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing Taiwan with arms of a defensive character in such quantity as may be necessary to enable Taiwan to maintain a sufficient self-defense capability; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc495aa159c6544219537a9c39cf831e1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>preserving peace, security, and stability in the Western Pacific as matters of international concern.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id3b1a0ae754714dc6ac95c69aa93aeba4"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Matters To be included</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id06774f0df0b6455f8ce3707d32c6d464"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (b) shall include—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="id703ac49692e348a1887b0c0dd20b630b">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>a detailed assessment of whether the current and projected military posture, force structure, operational plans, and capabilities of the United States are sufficient to credibly deter—</text>
                        <clause id="idba2b9aeb034c41bb8efb210eff8f4a14">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>a large-scale amphibious invasion of Taiwan;</text> </clause> <clause id="id6996417c945c48afbb766d387b359fde"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text>a maritime or air blockade of Taiwan; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id892726f3d6d94e5694cd2691c98676e5">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>major missile or air strike campaigns against Taiwan;</text> </clause> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="id471aa75dd5a3404b8de5474e908d54f3"> <enum>(B)</enum> <text>an assessment of the United States capacity to credibly deter and resist forms of coercion that would jeopardize the security, or the social or economic system of the people on Taiwan, including sustained forms of coercion across air, maritime, cyber, space, economic, and information domains;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="iddf4a63c07dce4fca924e12016cfb6007">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of the United States operational readiness and sustainability, including—</text>
                        <clause id="idd199da91380840bdaa0db112b5fdf9ee">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>readiness, posture, basing access and overflight, mobility, logistics resilience, prepositioned stocks, and munitions sufficiency in the Indo-Pacific region;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="idbf1ecd45e9bf4591ae148c93af889c34">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>projected munitions expenditure rates and replenishment timelines under high-intensity conflict scenarios;</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id04fa5e6b68fc42e0bdb6d5a6f916bc7b">
                            <enum>(iii)</enum>
 <text>the ability of the defense industrial base to sustain operations in a protracted conflict of not less than 1 year; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="id4f0bec61979845c68354b5a1c8686aeb">
                            <enum>(iv)</enum>
 <text>vulnerabilities to supply chain disruption, cyber attack, or anti-access/area denial strategies across domains;</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id7c99ea4c9eab421d8423559300404ec9">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of the availability, reliability, and sufficiency of allied and partner contributions to deterrence and defense in a Taiwan contingency and to resist gray zone coercion; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id55cdf57428d54ad985ce6129d4178d64">
                        <enum>(E)</enum>
 <text>an assessment of the capacity of the United States to comply with the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>) in a scenario in which the United States is simultaneously responding to aggression initiated by the Russian Federation, the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, or a terrorist organization.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="idaa68f5a36edb42b4a2c3bd03d8da939d">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Capability gaps and resource requirements</header>
 <text>For each assessment described in paragraph (1), the report shall—</text> <subparagraph id="id0964657a0e074540a86822cf98039ecf"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>identify current capability gaps, shortfalls, and vulnerabilities;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id50339ca0738c40679128b7c7fa4fae5b">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>estimate capability gaps during the following 10 years based on current budget projections;</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="ida501e631a5ea42cd832499b9cdaec36f">
                        <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>specify budgetary, force posture, acquisition, industrial base, and legislative changes required to mitigate the gaps referred to in subparagraph (C); and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="id835030daca3f4fab9d96c88d2ad40cb6">
                        <enum>(D)</enum>
 <text>include an estimated timeline and costs to achieve a level of capability sufficient to credibly deter and, if necessary, defeat aggression against Taiwan.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
 </subsection><subsection id="id39ffe010fd68402cb55428602263e42c"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required shall be submitted in classified form, but may include an unclassified executive summary.</text></subsection></section><section id="idff830f824b094b1ab141632765ca4662"><enum>4.</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after submission of each report pursuant to section 3, the Secretary of War shall provide a classified briefing to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the findings and recommendations contained in such report.</text></section><section id="id3d549ba921b44e3e944e0c4e29956a60"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb1b575dad1214b9c9ad8b9e4b17ae405"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to authorize the use of military force; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3404e0fc257b4477b4f4086e0cb924ef"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to alter or supersede any existing statutory requirement under the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

