<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HFE4ABD9F4D1B4F61AFC87E8226D01710" resolution-type="house-resolution"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 970 IH: Calling on the United States government to be more involved in bringing peace to Sudan.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 970</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251219">December 19, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Calling on the United States government to be more involved in bringing peace to Sudan.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas this resolution may be cited as the <quote>Original Resolution Calling on the United States Government to Help Bring Peace to Sudan</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the United Nations has reported at least 40 thousand have been killed, 12 million have been displaced, and 47 million are facing acute hunger in Sudan since April of 2023;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the Rapid Support Forces (RSF), a paramilitary force whose break with the Sudanese Armed Forces sparked the civil war in 2023, have perpetrated atrocities in al-Fashir;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the horrific conditions in Sudan have been exacerbated by funding cuts to USAID’s humanitarian assistance;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas a Quad agreement with Egypt, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE) states <quote>external military support to the conflict parties in Sudan serves to intensify and prolong the conflict and contribute to regional instability</quote> and that <quote>an end to external military support is essential to ending the conflict</quote>;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Amnesty International published a report in May identifying Chinese manufactured GB50A guided bombs and 155mm AH–4 howitzers found in Darfur;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the UAE is the only country confirmed to have imported these specific weapons;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas Executive Order (E.O.) 14098, <quote>Imposing Sanctions on Certain Persons Destabilizing Sudan and Undermining the Goal of a Democratic Transition,</quote> signed on May 4, 2023, authorizes the United States Secretary of State to impose sanctions on foreign persons responsible for undermining stability in Sudan;</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body style="traditional" id="HA74CEC3D44A34F5EAFF235DE31781716"><section display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section" id="HE257D6F862DD4736AC6C542E3158FFAD"><enum/><text>That the House of Representatives—</text><paragraph id="H0C505522F1934A54B93F13ABF86C5DB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">calls on all branches of government to hold the constituent states of the Quad accountable for their own commitments to ending external military support to Sudan, namely the UAE.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution>


