<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF64683F12A0D4EFFADBB5DFB7E97235E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7593 IH: Reserve Forces Travel Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7593</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260217">February 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001219">Mr. Moylan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000230">Mr. Davis of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000135">Mr. Van Orden</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001218">Mr. McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 37, United States Code, to reimburse a member of the uniformed services for costs incurred to rent a motor vehicle for travel relating to a period of reserve component inactive-duty training, or of Ready Reserve muster duty, performed more than 150 miles from the member's permanent residence.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H20F75B54A6424D3F88C50AE501D42F2D" style="OLC"><section id="H90FC311A18CE486AA7A10588C393F6A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reserve Forces Travel Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC115661B58DC435ABAA760131B4C49EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Travel allowance: reimbursement of costs incurred by a member of the uniformed services to rent a motor vehicle for certain travel relating to certain training or duty</header><subsection id="HD1E719C3152142C384CB80BA405988CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 452(j) of title 37, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H7455845BF2BB43038FC162B0573E4450" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H74127835470C444D830802B0E16199D2" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a member who travels more than 150 miles for training or duty described in paragraph (1) and whose actual and necessary expenses described in subparagraph (A) of such paragraph include the costs to rent a motor vehicle, the allowance paid to such member in accordance with this subsection shall reimburse the member for such costs incurred during—</text><subparagraph id="H125266DF53994D09B9D7ED85382A2B34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the entire period of training or duty described in such paragraph; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17E1F81707F74199BF3F430EC1914920"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a day of travel, described in such paragraph, that precedes or follows such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9307B94015EF4D92906C149DCF908183"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall amend the Joint Travel Regulations for the Uniformed Services in accordance with the amendment made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

