<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-CAN26105-828-P8-X0C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3938 IS: TAP Promotion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3938</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260226">February 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S363">Mr. King</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S398">Mr. Cramer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S408">Mr. Hickenlooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S323">Mr. Risch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S372">Mrs. Capito</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S316">Mr. Whitehouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S322">Mr. Merkley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S431">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S324">Mrs. Shaheen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S313">Mr. Sanders</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize representatives of veterans service organizations to participate in presentations to promote certain benefits available to veterans during preseparation counseling under the Transition Assistance Program of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TAP Promotion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="iddef631aa16cb456f87798c6bd5a16e6a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Presentation to promote benefits available to veterans in preseparation counseling under the Transition Assistance Program</header><subsection id="id6a1f87646e324d299761128b906f6605"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1142(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idda4cccc4e81f4b2c95479611b747e7f8"><paragraph id="idd5e7a9f3f765409a9d828e9bad117e4a"><enum>(20)</enum><text>A presentation that promotes the benefits available to veterans under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. Such presentation—</text><subparagraph id="id99361a5677a844fb9c5769d851731603"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be standardized;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb1eb549dd22d4def9c94fdbbe5611b5d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall, before implementation, be reviewed and approved by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in collaboration with veterans service organizations that provide claims assistance under the benefits delivery at discharge program of the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id836927d3349a45efbedeeec9fe8dee93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall be submitted by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives for review at least 90 days before implementation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd0b0306ecfcb4ddca8e31cb2251f42cb"><enum>(D)</enum><text>where available, shall be presented with the participation of—</text><clause id="id1fc7c7e57dd94d35bb4e9be5b6470a28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a representative of a veterans service organization recognized under section 5902 of title 38; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id82724512e8f34c558052c90c605bac4e"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida1ce1f82dde449e99044fb7400efe852"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recognized under section 5903 of such title; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idcdff5fc85a574fa590e9139840a5f9af"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized by the Secretary concerned to so participate;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5c9c830891364162a6d3342986620d8f"><enum>(E)</enum><text>shall include information on how a veterans service organization may assist the member in filing a claim described in paragraph (19);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd13cf6a0ce7c4023ac1491b88db29908"><enum>(F)</enum><text>may not encourage the member to join a particular veterans service organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca1245a30d284e07b71bd279300bb76c"><enum>(G)</enum><text>may not exceed one hour in duration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="idb78fb24b59e44e78a88bab96535eb3fe"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not less than frequently than once each year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><paragraph id="id89190452dba2464b9c06746d448188a8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies each veterans service organization that participated in a presentation under paragraph (20) of section 1142(b) of title 10, United States Code, as added by subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id090c92051e0448a7aaaccd3cdc988b55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains the number of members of the Armed Forces who attended such presentations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5e28b17952c64c1e8871c3b35420ad7c"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes any recommendations of the Secretary regarding changes to such presentation or to such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

