<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HFC8774463831480C814EC8ACADBF488B">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8998 IH: Researching Innovative Shipbuilding and Next-Generation Transit Infrastructure for Durable and Efficient Systems</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8998</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001221">Ms. Scholten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Transportation Research Board to evaluate innovative hull designs and the use of alternative material construction technologies to enhance operational fleet performance and payload capacity of waterborne transit systems.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3793BDBE7E8E47BD9864C3C8C43E084A">
<section id="H0442E265B8B645A29915D4D664CE0508" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Researching Innovative Shipbuilding and Next-Generation Transit Infrastructure for Durable and Efficient Systems</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H38"><enum>2.</enum><header>Innovative hull designs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Transportation Research Board shall evaluate innovative hull designs, as well as the use of alternative material construction technologies, to include the use of carbon fiber, hybrids, and other composite fiber-reinforced polymers to enhance operational fleet performance and payload capacity of waterborne transit systems.</text></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

