<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A156C9040324A0DA4431DE4AA54D55A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9410 IH: VA Education Oversight Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9410</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001230">Mr. Mackenzie</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide additional authorities to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and State Approving Agencies with respect to third-party contractors of educational institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H513213DE4D8940C4BAADFDB7899225C6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H30211CB436D045EFAF01B43553CD1C6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Education Oversight Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H96FEA01618B1460A938503116BCA76F1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorities of Secretary of Veterans Affairs and State Approving Agencies with respect to third-party contractors of educational institutions</header> <subsection id="HA9DF79B3309248D0A52205C50156A7B5"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Scope of oversight of third-Party contractors</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3673A of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
        <paragraph id="HE9186B6491B84999B00E77E1E9C66197">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (a), by inserting after <quote>oversight of educational institutions</quote> the following: <quote>, including third-party contractors of educational institutions,</quote>;</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HED87D398E15D4FDD9FD75EE14356EC14">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (b)(2)(G), by striking <quote>advertising and recruiting practices</quote> and inserting <quote>advertising, marketing, recruiting, and enrollment practices</quote>; and</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H12DA33524B2945B4AA17296B592C6334">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text>by adding at the end of subsection (b) the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H501620056D2E463EBE149F804AC41A01" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H4087270BF2B245BAB72E31B348909E48" indent="up1"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The scope determined under paragraph (1) shall include any location at which the educational institution offers a course or program of education approved under this chapter, including a location in a foreign country.</text>
            </paragraph>
            <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
          </quoted-block>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5CED2DBB18A4E8B854CC2B64DE029EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3672 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H9A26582E2874454183DC73616B555692" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H6B338E6558264E538D7FD7B6122952D1"><enum>(f)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 1 of each year through 2028, the Secretary shall conduct an assessment of the activities carried out under this chapter with respect to the approval of courses or programs of education provided by third-party contractors of educational institutions and shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the results of the assessment. The report shall include the recommendations of the Secretary with respect to any legislative or regulatory actions the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H4E9F36724EA2476BB194B3F534733B9B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization for State Approving Agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3671 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H196EF18B845440AABA0EDC37859AE162" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H4F62FE2CD2634BD38CDAB411B5C2D782"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority of the Secretary to recognize a State department or agency as the State approving agency for a State for purposes of this chapter or chapter 34 or 35 of this title shall be authorized until October 1, 2028, and after such time any provisions of this chapter or chapter 34 or 35 of this title which refer to the State approving agency shall, with respect to such State, be deemed to refer to the Secretary.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

