<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9476 IH: To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services in administering the Veterans Community Care Program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9476</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services in administering the Veterans Community Care Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBC5D73C1CC9E48458C05FC2E7CA73023" style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"> 
<section id="H9FE83A5CB7D445C8938BB55D3127A75D" commented="no" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Coordination between Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Health and Human Services with respect to administration of Veterans Community Care Program</header> 
<subsection id="HAA1A9B20B6314798B0645D97E0738A5D" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall, for purposes of coordinating medical benefits and hospital care and medical services furnished under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to reciprocal access between the Veterans Health Administration and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to data and information for veterans who are concurrently enrolled in the patient enrollment system under section 1705(a) of title 38, United States Code, and—</text> <paragraph id="HD3B0DD0FFE174396B15115DD47DBF942" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Medicare program; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H584EAA30BC6F4330A0FBD569A9C00AB9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a Medicare Advantage plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H54D07B68FBA843D4A9EDD2E1F4E112BA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Veterans Community Care Program administration</header> <paragraph id="HDF7AAC7F729C4CECA4EFB015DFC0AC8A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In administering the Veterans Community Care Program under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Office of Integrated Veteran Care of the Veterans Health Administration, shall use the information transmitted to the Secretary by the Secretary of Health and Human Services pursuant to the memorandum of understanding required under subsection (a) to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9D879CEA3AEE4D02B5A52B3E761F2B22" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure, with respect to veterans who are concurrently enrolled in the patient enrollment system under section 1705(a) of such title and the Medicare program, that the Department of Veterans Affairs does not—</text> <clause id="HFD66643E685A4171A0E304A4D7550A75" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>furnish duplicative health care to such veterans; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H05B7B82B04074778994C764E10DB7F3D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make erroneous or duplicative payments for health care furnished to such veterans; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H904558FFEEFF4D4B949D200F320626E0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify specialized MA plans for special needs individuals that the Secretary determines offer benefits important for veteran health care, including at least three of the benefit categories described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFE058BB7F394199932BE340287B0F81" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Benefit categories described</header><text>The benefit categories described in this paragraph are the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H64B2AA04EC184FD2BC5CDFD3E8C941D4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Adaptive sports equipment.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00794B03AFF14838BF2FF314B0A95ECA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Hearing aids and related audiology services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE52511ADC1914D59B06E892462BBC68D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Integrated traumatic brain injury rehabilitation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H50FF90C3EBCC426BBA086526FD4894E0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Hyperbaric oxygen therapy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AD09E07BAC543DEA4605CFABF55C65D" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Massage therapy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H741ADDACB3AF4CE6AA50464F44F7292E" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Residential rehabilitation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF40F3F83C6E94B6CB33D633B8B47E613" commented="no"> <enum>(G)</enum> <text>Complementary and integrative health services.</text>
                    </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78E4A75B7A874FB4BD0A1CE49649117A" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Other benefits or services the Secretary determines are effective in improving health outcomes for veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H82CA9CAC7FA848F48B1D16AD65CE76F0" commented="no"> <enum>(c)</enum> <header>Coordination Offices</header> <paragraph id="H50431A9407A84A4CA76564377BE1EF39" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>Veterans Health Administration</header> <text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Office of Integrated Veteran Care of the Veterans Health Administration, may coordinate with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an office (to be known as the <quote>Veterans Affairs-Medicare Dual Eligibility Coordination Office</quote>) within the Office of Integrated Veteran Care.</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph id="H4D0143F344D1432198DF7422D54F3018" commented="no">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <header>Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services</header>
 <text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, may coordinate with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, to establish a office (to be known as the <quote>Medicare-Veterans Affairs Dual Eligibility Coordination Office</quote>) within the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
<subsection id="H88A46685E5234757AF7A955E4F2CDF7E" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HDC50519B4543408D81714118469E788E" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>Medicare Advantage plan</quote> means a Medicare Advantage plan under the program established under part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-21">42 U.S.C. 1395w–21 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0DCF2F5D3612456AB93557BE1D6C1F24" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>Medicare program</quote> means the Medicare program under such title.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H67ADDB88B1F5423DB062B9C023D80E7F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>specialized MA plan for special needs individuals</quote> and <quote>special needs individual</quote> have the meaning given such terms in section 1859(b)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-28">42 U.S.C. 1395w–28(b)(6)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

