<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB09C9CFDD3F44539842ED9E08F3CD8EB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7591 IH: Secure Firearm Storage and Suicide Prevention Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7591</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260217">February 17, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000599">Mr. Goldman of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001217">Mr. Moskowitz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000477">Mrs. Foushee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000620">Ms. Pettersen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000310">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001130">Ms. Crockett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require certain local educational agencies to distribute guidance to students, parents, and other local community members regarding firearm safety, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD8A9F3E5A2DC444E89EC022F59C18F4B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D451AFF886D4189A2F57AA42DFF9ADB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Firearm Storage and Suicide Prevention Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H7C21F2218DC641299C9EF6C356F65DFF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE56581129F2A4874A32F18207602972D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Unintentional injuries and suicides related to firearms are significant causes death among children and teenagers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6EE10776BAD4C6CADACEA42474EC95A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAC0D4CD212574974B628C3229175A241"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the annual rate of suicide by firearm in the United States increased approximately 11 percent from 2019 to 2022, with provisional data suggesting that 2024 may have had the highest rate of gun suicide since at least 1968;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD37FD66494C439995D382B8B5FE117B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nearly 60 percent of all gun-related deaths in the United States are suicides;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB06D78943372423D913E4CBB2D317607"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in 2021, 2022, and 2023, firearm suicides accounted for approximately 55 percent of all suicide deaths in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9901C9A3EB9F4B1184973DF3089E084F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in 2023, an average of 75 individuals in the United States died by firearm suicide each day;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD03F9055FB4F4C8BB9D8BBCC64840D52"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in 2023, the third leading cause of death in the United States for youth under the age of 18 was suicide; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B1CF8D4EB584AF9AF142615CB802EA9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in both 2022 and 2023, firearms were the leading mechanism of death among youth under the age of 18 in the United States.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE2DDA56BA824B5C921401B849676800"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Department of Health and Human Services, 79 percent of the firearms used in the suicides of youth under the age of 18 are the guns of family members.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H724A09191C924EF98EAE2C1E5EA7EA01"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Suicide attempts involving firearms are almost always deadly, with 9 out of 10 firearm suicide attempts resulting in death.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6FB369A00D34B379AD895196168E56E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Education about the importance of proper secure storage of firearms, including the risk of firearm-related suicide associated with unsecured weapons, is critical to reducing firearm-related unintentional injuries and suicides.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E7A3498FEBC41E2A1A5A027AB24EE03"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Implementing firearm safety and education on suicide prevention can foster a culture of responsible firearm ownership and handling, benefitting both individuals and communities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7C36C6CF8D54D1C87CFABD60C3AFF65"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It can take less than 10 minutes between thinking about suicide and acting on it. Putting barriers between individuals and lethal means in moments of crisis can save lives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99F0FABF765B4252893633C7AA35859B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Secure storage of firearms is effective in reducing suicide deaths.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA3F8B49E6F204992A8579A7594FF9E6A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Firearm safety resources</header> 
<subsection id="H83294986485F4A8AB023AFDBB0BD00DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7101">20 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF79B3FBEE8434B6B975A36E0A5104EA8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subpart id="HD4D0C3BB4EA74FD2AF5FE07C9FDD52E0"><enum>3</enum><header>Firearm safety resources</header> <section id="HF621FB372F3347AF8B70235C4046424D"><enum>4131.</enum><header>Firearm safety best practices</header> <subsection id="HDE362CA5565A4E13A366E1A53E953E3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall develop best practices relating to the secure storage of firearms and the prevention of firearm-related suicide or unintentional injury in consultation with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H84CDCD64D1ED4470A2844FE85C1804BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Firearms and Ammunition Technology Division of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D659874753246B4B808ACB08656E444"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF4B636EBB79D4A4CB15E5D7CB1C6206E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE68BEDFFA4884EFFA8F369009FB991AF" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the National Institutes of Health;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD686B46FE27D44348256ACE77DAE504F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDF7995924BA4642902822CAB0DBF221"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C7E16AEDB9844338B6511D5CC3DCFEF" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Evidence-Based Practices established under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/665k">6 U.S.C. 665k</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9078564D04904312AE6180A6112982A2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Firearms-Toolmarks Unit of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H520C2C71F2B8453E950B410AA2CFA4D0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>law enforcement agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0DE57EE99B7432FBAC39BA65F03038E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>non-profit organizations that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1BE43A8D7C7E4BDBAD8235DA6A03CB69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have experience in firearm safety and education; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE8B8F1B65B7643B88F903C809A57B242"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not affiliated with the firearm industry or lobbyist working on behalf of the firearm industry;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECDE079B19B049C99F746B64DC9A9609"><enum>(11)</enum><text>educators; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7C3243EDE484B4FB9F7E0D6D468B67E"><enum>(12)</enum><text>independent experts in firearm safety and education, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H0ACE461C5CB64E7E81778D97C873B719"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>The Secretary shall include as part of the best practices described in subsection (a) the following information:</text> <paragraph id="HBD7993F94F8D4F2DBE086340E12E9EA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>How to securely store firearms, including how to use secure storage devices.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51F2FDB7EBD041C990C380F7D6D19F52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>How to evaluate and regularly re-evaluate firearm safety protocols, including secure storage practices for firearms in places were firearms are commonly kept, including in homes and motor vehicles.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9063569D518E48CEB7D219A9E03F7BFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The risks associated with the improper use of firearms or unsecure storage of firearms, including firearms that are not lawfully possessed, and the correlation of such factors with suicide or unintentional injury.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H351AE013BB044EA18565CF633EF2EADD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Strategies for preventing unintentional injuries or suicides related to the use of firearms.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9115911C09954FC8BD17289853958998"><enum>(5)</enum><text>How to educate students about the proper steps such students should take upon encountering an unsecured firearm, including to not handle the firearm and to contact a trusted adult.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50BE9BE063464B1483DDCBF51D66C06C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>How community members, including parents, can acquire secure storage devices, including any resources that provide secure storage devices for free.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B646FA3602E4E6687ED65D8007FD008"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A summary of Federal laws directly related to firearm safety and secure firearm storage, including information about the Second Amendment to the Constitution of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B454933C16F4BBBB2DD1E6A028A9A09"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A survey of State laws and programs related to firearm safety, including laws related to the secure storage of firearms and the implementation of State crisis intervention court proceedings and related programs or initiatives.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8E1882E59C343F6B6EB7B53A5FAA640"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Firearm safety resources created by academic institutions or organizations with experience in firearm safety and education, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A573E3DF31F47A2AAA61E6310759180"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Any other information determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H04387E5087BC4767817362EC1DEA695A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Neutrality requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the best practices described in subsection (a), the Secretary may not include as part of such best practices materials encouraging or discouraging the possession or ownership of firearms.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26744854512F4CE482A22DFA0749CB6C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3A04E5E2239D44988ABC331DC8D958BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>distribute the best practices described in subsection (a) to each local educational agency;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FF0AFC448CE4C4E904C238FDF829A88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notify each covered local education agency of the local firearm safety guidance requirements under section 4132; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB57EFCEA38DF4493B7A1FD4DD8F10523"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide guidance to each covered local education agency regarding the most effective time during an academic year to satisfy the distribution requirement under section 4132(e) in order to maximize the prevention of firearm-related suicide or unintentional injury.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD82D247BDEFB458BB770446D6C379BB9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this section, and once every 3 years thereafter, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2C2F8A2957A24B95B6EB7C2E89A3313E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>solicit feedback from school staff, students, parents, and experts with experience in firearm safety and education on the best practices described in subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B980FDD1A5E4CE9B21D1D4AF05295CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update the information in such best practices, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="H21CC440FEA3F417C8D5B0C59EA7331F8"><enum>4132.</enum><header>Local firearm safety guidance</header> <subsection id="H027D73E4624E4C18A2204CE81FBA160D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the Secretary distributes the best practices described in section 4131(a) as required under section 4131(d)(1), each covered local educational agency shall develop guidance relating to the secure storage of firearms and the prevention of firearm-related suicide or unintentional injury in consultation with—</text> 
<paragraph id="H177C1538C5DA4F5597EE462CCC3C05F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>community-based health and violence prevention organizations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H864442CD27C44055AA9025D9360020A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>public safety officials and emergency personnel, including police and firefighters;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1BD394946A364D0B9E4A33CF12487CB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>mental health professionals, including doctors and psychologists;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C1CC4B4C1484D4A9DA9AB6FAC551089"><enum>(4)</enum><text>educators; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36DF23AB5D5648209D59E809E357B57C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other stakeholders determined appropriate by the local educational agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFB66FD79F23F4975B3650FAD74020E64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship to best practices</header><text>In developing the guidance described in subsection (a), each covered local educational agency shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H02E7CE75582D4CA2B6F3A5911D68F7FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate the best practices distributed to the covered local educational agency as required under section 4131(d)(1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7CE94D8F5FD84E5AA6B7266E8AFE60C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modify such best practices to be relevant to the local community, as determined appropriate by the covered local educational agency; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0AB5D89FF1144879559B2EC1F42D48A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regularly update such guidance to reflect any changes to such best practices, as determined appropriate by the covered local educational agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H263D25B2F50646C8B1FAC1E6267EB45A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered local educational agency shall include as part of such guidance the following information:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3320C6D4E18D4170B86F5DB3C6B2F2A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mental health resources available to students, including resources available in schools served by the covered local educational agency and resources provided by the local community.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H393A32E27D384C9BAF3B7FC9AE19CF30"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other information determined appropriate by the covered local educational agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5263114CB2C444E98CD3B2AF408773E0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Neutrality requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the guidance described in subsection (a), each covered local educational agency may not include as part of such guidance materials encouraging or discouraging the possession or ownership of firearms.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA964280303054794BB6F996A982EE5DF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Distribution</header> <paragraph id="HC0D5DA22DAD54DCD80AF6C4140728212"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the beginning of the 2027–2028 academic year, and not later than 90 days before the end of each academic year thereafter, each covered local educational agency shall distribute the guidance described in subsection (a) through email and physical means (including by sending students home with such guidance as a handout or by mail) to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H47B3266DEA6C48B79D955F0A07B5F0BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>students;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD6746A1D51C4B449C57C05CCB646139"><enum>(B)</enum><text>parents;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8F0CCB61C6FA44A9B4F3DA5954E5D9DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>school staff; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3D283C489A444E08A54C4A16D0595291"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other members of the local community determined appropriate by the covered local educational agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BEB9EF79CC14F66B61F613149612253"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibility</header><text>A covered local educational agency may delegate responsibility for carrying out any part of the distribution activities required under paragraph (1) to the schools served by such covered local educational agency.</text> </paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="HB2DBD3018C7C42E4A593210B143F5D22"><enum>4133.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subpart:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE1D6035BAAEA4C19A39220DC268505EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency, or consortium of such agencies, that receives an allocation under section 4105(a).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBB78CB164924A2EAA6B2F042664FD99" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secure storage device</header><text>The term <term>secure storage device</term> means a device which is designed to prevent unauthorized access to, or render inoperable, a firearm, including a firearm safe, lock box, trigger lock, or cable lock.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H337D4955BFAD43BFB658D7B51BAD305B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>School staff</header><text>The term <term>school staff</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H9ECF4135CB7F49DBBC2F1EC51A56CFDB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>school leaders;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H37593F4613424B87984CC094CBEDA9FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specialized instructional support personnel;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F6705E5D5ED479F9B7358D158D3D574"><enum>(C)</enum><text>teachers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A95301BA36A4F2BA2FDD680C351DC7F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other staff.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HD42EC693D11846B793D2284C949F61C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 2 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 4121 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC9A603E6DA524FBD9A769933822F92D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="subpart">Subpart 3—Firearm Safety Resources</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry bold="off" level="section">4131. Firearm safety best practices.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4132. Local firearm safety guidance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">4133. Definitions.</toc-entry> </toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

