<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HED9DCDE252454DC48AA1B66EC8AB2EC8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9291 IH: Federal Flood Risk Management Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9291</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260611">June 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Federal standard in order to improve the Nation’s resilience to current and future flood risk.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H760FA2FE3442421589B8A4D30FCD9384" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H215BCC0CD13D4C86BC853D0D399F231A"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Flood Risk Management Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCAA8AE57DCD74697A724E876BBF3F304"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H2D62C7C9D4104CD1BB93CEB895528055"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency or any successor agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19E251FB6D0A4D49A1D145A2F8416A05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term <term>agency</term>—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4A5F5B100EE94A53BC21673F6F0E63E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term <term>Executive agency</term> in section 105 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86D6754B80444715BDDC4886CDEF3B9F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not apply to an agency that does not take agency actions in or affecting floodplains.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B06F9F5ED48475BAE02298E46EA245D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agency action</header><text>The term <term>agency action</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6FE8600CD914C35A7900A31227342E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means, with respect to an agency—</text>
<clause id="H52C79AC3EFFE43B4B77DE37652606C7E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>acquiring, managing, and disposing of Federal lands and facilities;</text></clause> <clause id="H24E56F564C404BE98BAFA335128125E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>providing construction and improvements that are undertaken, financed by, or assisted by the Federal Government; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC04742E28D9040C0AE56508600D3F526"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>conducting Federal activities and programs that affect land use, including planning, regulating, and licensing activities relating to water and land resources; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H101CE8BABC9944DABD09313AF7F0B60A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a military construction project described in section 2802 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6AA9FFE99A3644BE865CDBA3DECFC70C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Base flood</header><text>The term <term>base flood</term> means a flood that has a not less than 1 percent chance of occurring in a year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE54F08A9FA64824B6797E1173815B31"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Critical action</header><text>The term <term>critical action</term> means any agency action with respect to which the head of the agency determines a slight chance of flooding would present an unacceptable amount of risk.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC565F2C75E584B26960E26BC9C76080F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Emergency</header><text>The term <term>emergency</term> means a situation that would result in an unacceptable hazard to life, a significant loss of property, or an immediate, unforeseen, and significant economic hardship.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C0CF17E10EB4162A8A86AB96BB6A0D1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Executive Order 11988</header><text>The term <term>Executive Order 11988</term> means Executive Order 11988 (42 Fed. Reg. 26951; relating to floodplain management).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD93CD71A147E41AA8D12087B4B69A4CC"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Federally funded project</header><text>The term <term>federally funded project</term> means an action in which Federal funds are used, with respect to a structure or facility, for new construction, for substantial improvement, or to address substantial damage.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EEF9DC9E4F64280A30184457E86FAE4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Floodplain</header><text>The term <term>floodplain</term> means, subject to section 4(b)(2), the lowland and relatively flat area that adjoins inland and coastal waters (including flood-prone areas of offshore islands).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCBC777F73CC64281B25980559A741342"><enum>(10)</enum><header>National Flood Insurance Program</header><text>The term <term>National Flood Insurance Program</term> means the program established under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD191648DF1FC4E129EBDE249B4CD740E"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Standard</header><text>The term <term>Standard</term> means the Federal Flood Risk Management Standard set forth in Appendix G to Guidelines for Implementing Executive Order 11988, Floodplain Management, and Executive Order 13690, Establishing a Federal Flood Risk Management Standard and a Process for Further Soliciting and Considering Stakeholder Input, published on October 8, 2015.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0581E8C2167D471AB350FFAFB437C01B"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Water Resources Council</header><text>The term <term>Water Resources Council</term> means the Council established under section 101 of the Water Resources Planning Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1962a">42 U.S.C. 1962a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HDA90B1FB938245D7BC07A6F57C44C15C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H1CCDE18D965F4F8F8F7BA38D4A9F6B19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it should be the policy of the United States to improve the resiliency of communities and assets of the Federal Government against the impacts of flooding;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDDC927DAC2D342AFA1D38FD8C923E8F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the impacts of flooding are anticipated to increase over time due to increased future risk and greater development on floodplains;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52ECBB55B4CB45E8962F40A4ACE21166"><enum>(3)</enum><text>losses caused by flooding affect—</text> <subparagraph id="H7CB03C9B07A94BFAA7A5302A98BBFD13"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the environment;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDCD04E2BBAA24316ABC8FE81742CB890"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the economic prosperity of the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3063A387042841E2B72472821B1B7E9C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>public health and safety; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9838E26780A34E55BD16C3F05613A9EF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the national security of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69E85949F9BF40ACAA519F42DC0A131C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Federal Government must take action, informed by the best available and actionable science, to improve the preparedness and resilience of the United States with respect to flooding;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H60110B686A7447C895F5182E5E524D69"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Executive Order 11988 requires agencies to avoid—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D184A9ED9154869A58BCB701383A582"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, the long- and short-term adverse impacts associated with the occupancy and modification of floodplains; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H356A9BCB0DE141B98847334057CD56C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>direct or indirect support of floodplain development whenever a more practicable alternative is available;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEB544B1D9F249CBB7C25FAF9DCA012E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to implement Executive Order 11988, the Federal Government has developed processes for evaluating the impacts of Federal actions in or affecting floodplains;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H132BB3E09F2244379D448C6DD568F679"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in June 2013, an interagency effort to create a new flood risk reduction standard for federally funded projects was initiated;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CFCA8B770DD4021B2173F3AD0B508F4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in establishing the standard described in paragraph (7), the views of governors, mayors, and interested members of the public were solicited and considered;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H709EAA1488DA44EEA4FCD4824F349A0D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the result of the efforts described in paragraphs (7) and (8) is the Standard, a flexible framework to increase resilience against flooding and help preserve the natural values of floodplains; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4BDD6C4F2434B7F9C11BB1F4F1E5DB2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>enacting the Standard will ensure that agencies expand management from the base flood level in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act to a higher vertical elevation and a corresponding horizontal floodplain in order to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H62D2E34147174DE3B5636E47DB05951B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address current and future flood risk; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H974D2042A3BB4E938C3148A2E9F15C19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that federally funded projects last as long as intended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="H9C9B8D6C380B48798475D8CF4DED4A89"><enum>4.</enum><header>Floodplain management</header>
<subsection id="H22724E412309470FAACBF7D22049514C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of each agency shall provide leadership and shall take action, when carrying out an agency action, to—</text> <paragraph id="H58583C3DF5B7453BACECDC949810EECC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reduce the risk of losses resulting from floods;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C67FD2596CE43AC8D6B9A59EFAA0B52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>minimize the impact of floods on human safety, health, and welfare; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC040150B87EF4A9FA48F7785FC7F236E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>restore and preserve the natural and beneficial values served by floodplains.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H483FD48B284847A6A8971530AB2F4B7C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency responsibilities</header>
<paragraph id="HB1FB458F8D3243409BD4B01F6646D1E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out an agency action, as described in subsection (a), the head of each agency shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF9862AA07F148AE9C1DABA1302365A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate the potential effects of any agency action taken by the agency in a floodplain, as determined under paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7098A508F5DC40D2880A4F205B2D03DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the planning programs and budget requests of the agency reflect consideration of flood hazards and the management of floodplains; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA3AA76652FF47458E4C061D51163C5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prescribe procedures to implement the policies and requirements of this Act—</text>
<clause id="HBA6D1380B297401694F7DA3F93E41DC5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to the extent permitted by law; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDD238B58C9474F3488E266D28F4CF710"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in accordance with the procedures described in paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB7018BC512F1473AAF1BF68822F7EA81"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of floodplains</header><text>The head of an agency shall, when determining whether an agency action will take place in a floodplain—</text> <subparagraph id="H40B5D4CE5F504EC98B4A303F574FEE7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use—</text>
<clause id="HAC0F9CAECA3844E9BFA828E1F32012EB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the elevation and flood hazard area, as determined by—</text> <subclause id="H3DD91758CBC449168BCFFBEFEFC3D013"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a climate-informed science approach that—</text>
<item id="HDDA6804DC2174525A3F36EB2489D4472"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>uses the best available actionable hydrologic and hydraulic data and methods;</text></item> <item id="H6582E537ACDC4F159FD5BE74ECB45BB7"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>integrates current and future changes in flooding based on climate science;</text></item>
<item id="HFB58D22299094D16AA64D3FE7FB5E141"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>includes an emphasis on whether the agency action is a critical action; and</text></item> <item id="HB513ABA1997F447196EECB85C13C2BE1"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>takes into consideration changes over the lifetime of the project that is the subject of the agency action;</text></item></subclause>
<subclause id="H438D32AA29C94ADBA498DBB495CF8769"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the freeboard value, reached by adding an additional—</text> <item id="H051C6D7F032341AF9A5C2BD930901BE2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>2 feet to the base flood elevation for an agency action that is not a critical action; and</text></item>
<item id="HF382330E015F426992F155479B772385"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>3 feet to the base flood elevation for an agency action that is a critical action; or</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H431A399C8725471A8CA9358A39C9D46F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other method that is identified in any amendment made to this Act; or</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HCE8F5FBE5F814DCEB239120A0BBC3539"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an area that has a 0.2 percent chance of flooding in a year; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2A442AA085246689EE83FB918394A1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rely on—</text>
<clause id="HA490DA56FC0F4E87A567BBC88EE2EF99"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the best available information; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13894576E30F4240B00549CED9E6703F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Flood Insurance Rate Map published by the Administrator for the community in which the agency action shall take place.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC211AEE5E88D4D80905BD93120C95033"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The procedures described in this paragraph are as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H76D0BE101CB149BCBFFAD7AA749D64EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Before an agency takes an agency action, the head of the agency shall determine under paragraph (2) whether the proposed agency action will take place in a floodplain.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3D94AE5BCDA146F3A795C3E8C1241A44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If an agency action described in subparagraph (A) may have a significant effect on the quality of the human environment, the evaluation required under paragraph (5) shall be included in any statement prepared under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA735353105C446883CBDC5607A57B50"><enum>(C)</enum><text>If the head of an agency has determined to, or proposes to, conduct, support, or allow an agency action that will take place in a floodplain, as determined under paragraph (2), the head of the agency shall—</text>
<clause id="HF8881BBC828B42A982A22D5414EA203F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consider alternatives in order to avoid adverse effects and incompatible development in the floodplain;</text></clause> <clause id="H097EF930ACD544F58A509D58901A9712"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>when possible, rely on natural systems, ecosystem processes, and nature-based approaches when considering alternatives under clause (i);</text></clause>
<clause id="HD16167FE94204046992D2DD18D8299A9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the head of the agency determines that the only practicable alternative consistent under law, including the requirements of this Act, requires taking an agency action in a floodplain, before taking the agency action—</text> <subclause id="HDDFD2EAAD35C4778911150A85DAF6078"><enum>(I)</enum><text>design or modify the agency action to minimize potential harm to or within the floodplain consistent with regulations issued under paragraph (6); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE952614C3059496091BD78DCF8BBB0DC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>prepare and distribute a notice that contains an explanation with respect to why the agency action shall take place in the floodplain;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC83C4AAD21734289B63089FF13D02CA0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>send a notice to all State, local, and Tribal governments with respect to the geographic areas that are affected by the agency action that—</text>
<subclause id="HDB7D4166B3D24DC1B02EC945FCF55627"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is not more than 3 pages long;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H903ACADB4738400A8B02C0B973328DED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>includes—</text>
<item id="HB5DAF35EFE4340DABB8B29231174C71C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a location map;</text></item> <item id="H286B31120174456C945B587D47AE8E99"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the reasons why the agency action shall occur in a floodplain;</text></item>
<item id="HC50C5E3A8DF444CCBF5658F7161549B1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a statement indicating whether the agency action conforms to applicable State or local floodplain protection standards; and</text></item> <item id="H2894918B8B044101BBAEA1742D75ECEA"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>a list of the alternatives to the agency action that the head of the agency considered; and</text></item></subclause>
<subclause id="H411DB4E33D2B4DAFB002009243EC5E11"><enum>(III)</enum><text>allows for a brief comment period before the head of the agency may take the agency action; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H043E373CFD41418E81328DE9195668A0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>provide the opportunity for early public review of any plan or proposal for the agency action, including the development of procedures for any Federal action the impact of which is not significant enough to require the preparation of a statement under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC66FBEF022E0468F82D99B33A69211A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requests for authorizations and appropriations</header><text>The head of an agency, when making any request to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget for a new authorization or for appropriations, shall indicate, if an agency action to be proposed shall take place in a floodplain, as determined under paragraph (2), whether the agency action complies with this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF237B8368D1046ACBA412855CFA15D57"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Water and land use plans</header> <subparagraph id="HC4B5572B8B734DC9AACF3FB6C2BE63D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The head of an agency, when formulating or evaluating any water and land use plan, shall—</text>
<clause id="H998C975097634027BA0D4514C00A03D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>take floodplain management into account; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8D99FD4DFF964C78A9B2B36C2E2CF025"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require the use of land and water resources that are appropriate when compared with the degree of hazard that is involved.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H88A99114C09649C6A85B2749415776DE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The head of each agency shall—</text> <clause id="HB6D1B8F9303D4AF68A18AAC4DE16F0A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide for the adequate evaluation and consideration of flood hazards with respect to the regulations and operating procedures for the licenses, permits, and loan or grant programs administered by the agency; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H39D4FCB97ACD478E98415C23804D19A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to an applicant for a license, permit, loan, or grant that is issued or administered by the agency, encourage, and provide appropriate guidance to, the applicant to evaluate, before submitting the application, the effects that the application, if granted, would have on floodplains.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A6F64D434E24DC0887833A43F7D0ADA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regulations and procedures</header><text>To the extent permitted by law, the head of each agency shall, in consultation with the Water Resources Council, the Federal Interagency Floodplain Management Task Force, the Administrator, and the Council on Environmental Quality—</text>
<subparagraph id="H72E8C197A9AD48A8861388F1767831F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue regulations, or amend regulations that are in effect as of the date of enactment of this Act, to comply with the requirements of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0D100DE50ACB4AED806F975FA35871A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>amend the regulations described in subparagraph (A) as warranted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4A5B31A9AEB04AB19DA193A2BF7A2D2E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reassessment</header><text>The Mitigation Framework Leadership Group, in consultation with the Federal Interagency Floodplain Management Task Force, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H397444C21CC24DC4A95349EA74BA7285"><enum>(1)</enum><text>annually reassess the implementation of the requirements imposed under this section; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA902C57E18FE4E31BD344174D3D862DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide recommendations to the Water Resources Council for updates to the requirements imposed under this section that are warranted based on accurate and actionable science that takes into account changes to climate and other changes in flood risk.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H54522FF8DF90413F979655EF0611F314"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federal Flood Risk Management Standard</header> <subsection id="HE10B71CCAB51472DBC513DCC131F71F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an agency shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H4251FD0D754444778A6FE0641CEB0BE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>except as provided in subsection (b), with respect to a federally funded project undertaken by the agency, ensure that the agency complies with the Standard; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5C8BAAA614D4BD983425503403A9AB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the agency has responsibility for the administration or management of Federal real property and facilities, in addition to the requirements under section 4 and paragraph (1)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H819098A24BC049F2B656F25574C61A97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require the construction of Federal structures and facilities to comply with—</text> <clause id="H241925F8505C4E2188CC2281822063DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the regulations and procedures issued under section 4(b)(6); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC7606A0637E248148CA666E0C07FA977"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any regulations issued under the National Flood Insurance Program unless those regulations are demonstrably inappropriate for a structure or facility;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4ADF643FBF6E4157842352577F98FD91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>apply accepted floodproofing and other flood protection measures to the construction or rehabilitation of a structure or facility that is located in a floodplain;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1F6AEC958652494587205BF345F1B6B5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>when practicable, elevate a structure above the floodplain instead of filling in land;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF2528DD41DEF481E8F0920FC2A69BE07"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide on structures and, where appropriate, other pieces of property a conspicuous delineation of past and probable flood height—</text>
<clause id="HFA5B338F6AA44679AEC384EDC11DEB57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if the structure or other property—</text> <subclause id="H57D20B00171141ADAE43E5DDEC006C3B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is used by the general public; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H456D50023D2A4BAB83D74C439D9CE5D5"><enum>(II)</enum>
<item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB54833DA438148E3A6F061F866C0B729"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>has suffered flood damage; or</text></item> <item id="H3646CA3D41D1495599932CE9350DA06C" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is in an identified flood hazard area; and</text></item></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H9666246AA7464D7094973FA135579DE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in order to enhance public awareness of, and knowledge about, flood hazards; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFF8871EA9DF4696A1853AB922795B52"><enum>(E)</enum><text>when Federal property in a floodplain is proposed for lease, easement, right-of-way, or disposal to a non-Federal public or private party—</text>
<clause id="H4D1567008212499FA5E58CADE3131C30"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reference in the conveyance those uses that are restricted under Federal, State, or local regulations relating to floodplains; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDC49A7B2B3DA46CC9585E2EE48A5F8A8"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF64DCC6DA6794E83B333B760554FCFEA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>except where prohibited by law, attach any other appropriate restrictions to the uses of the property by the grantee or purchaser, as applicable, and any successors; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HBCA9964424144941A5413F0D65AABB6C" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>withhold the property from conveyance.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4EDC8B0EADAA4CD49DA6CF618A5B020E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HADC2150C77294EA6A16DEF510EE194D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The head of an agency may exempt a federally funded project from the requirement under subsection (a)(1) if—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7227BA6AAF6648DE952D3153734329F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the exemption is in the interest of national security; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCA4E0DFD6B84C1E8792EF0156BECF4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the undertaking of the federally funded project is because of an emergency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1B2B00D9C4D44879A6F9EC5A58A006D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The head of an agency shall publish in the Federal Register notice of any exemption used by the agency under paragraph (1)(B), which shall include factual findings in support of the exemption.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA377D4C7D6204D5CA02D83B06D1CEDC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 5 years, the Water Resources Council shall update the Standard, as determined appropriate by the Water Resources Council.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H006B2B57FF1E48508CECE13B521BA628"><enum>6.</enum><header>Financial transactions in areas subject to flooding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to any responsibilities under this Act and sections 102, 202, and 205 of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a</external-xref>, 4106, 4128), the head of any agency that guarantees, approves, regulates, or insures any financial transaction relating to an area that is subject to a base flood shall, before completing any action relating to that transaction, inform any private parties that are participating in the transaction about the hazards of locating a structure in that area.</text></section> <section id="H25E10D72123C40139B33D45C1F40A88B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reports</header> <subsection id="H35A98845D66B44BFAADB7826AFB395F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of each agency shall submit to the Council on Environmental Quality a report regarding how the requirements of this Act impact the procedures and operations of the agency.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H14BF22ADA8B84EE8BB5060E57AFC8001"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Analysis of Standard</header><text>Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall contain a separate analysis regarding how the requirement under section 5(a)(1) has impacted the agency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6D319F9A648641698D8ECEE11DF58920"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 2 years, the Water Resources Council shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HAD99352A4E2441058E0A56CA9E514130"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the procedures, including the effectiveness of the procedures, of each agency relating to the requirements of this Act, taking into account each report submitted under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H364C49A34BE64E5BBF9F93FE90999CE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that contains the result of the evaluation required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H4A0ECB81CC8B408AA23C948F86670180"><enum>8.</enum><header>General provisions</header>
<subsection id="H872BE03AF65640508EBE1232315852CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text> <paragraph id="H9D35DF8DBE664C1BA68A38A72F557C26"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as applying to assistance that is provided for emergency work that is—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF0C0065BC8C34F95826E877FFC33A708"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performed under sections 403 and 502 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170b">42 U.S.C. 5170b</external-xref>, 5192); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD38CF508D34D4791BC40FEF50B59EA47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>essential to—</text>
<clause id="H97074236BCF14B7EAF0720C8860D27BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>save human life; and</text></clause> <clause id="HEC90DE8DBF704730AEBBD0D18FF7446A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protect—</text>
<subclause id="HEF6DD6B82B9648B9AAB5E19F89E5D22A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>property; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCC356188B05449B6BE3B7234BD8FCD0C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>public health and safety; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H992B68E5D7454FD0A59CEB04D65743B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to impair or otherwise affect—</text> <subparagraph id="HBCAC56D6C05D4143A136C08CCBA5671E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the authority granted by law to an agency or the head of an agency; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H63774E25D1A14BC0933AC701B272DB23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the functions of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget relating to budgetary, administrative, or legislative proposals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4924BC18B3EA418D85BD036B7EFCB89A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>This Act shall be implemented consistent with applicable law and subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H350C07E86BF0464D9D18C1961562C0FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of Water Resources Council</header><text>Except as otherwise expressly provided, the Water Resources Council shall carry out the responsibilities of the Council under this Act in consultation with the Mitigation Framework Leadership Group.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H27360594E6564A4CBADF888FF3F1DF60"><enum>9.</enum><header>Assumption of responsibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of section 4(b)(3) apply to a project to which section 104(h) of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5304">42 U.S.C. 5304(h)</external-xref>) applies, an appropriate applicant may assume the responsibilities under those subparagraphs if the applicant has also assumed, with respect to the project, all responsibilities for environmental review, decision making, and action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

