<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8B6023DC94CF43DB88BC2DCBC6B984B8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8176 IH: Moldova Support Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8176</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260402">April 2, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to facilitate strategic dialogue with Moldova and submit a report on support for Moldova, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8957789E6E374E399008C25C5B50CE83" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7E0FC5D958144458998AA2CC1BEDE106" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Moldova Support Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB3A43A6C55F544009E4E70A06DAF61A3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8141132750144314AC3182D43C2EFDA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For more than 3 decades, the Republic of Moldova has demonstrated a strong commitment to advancing democracy, strengthening civil society, furthering accession to the European Union, and deepening cooperation with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization through the Partnership for Peace Program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H648577109D9346B4AA5B9DA24D57000F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation’s illegal invasion of Ukraine has threatened the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Moldova by destabilizing the country’s economy as well as its energy security.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FF6427985D5450FB7E252CE8C52C64D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reelection of Moldovan President Maia Sandu further cements Moldova’s pro-European path and Moldova’s expedient accession to the European Union is in the direct interest of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31EF72A5637D41AE98392C09B4DE5837"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Moldova represents a United States foreign assistance success story with United States foreign assistance to Moldova contributing to Moldova’s energy security, economic development, and democratic values as well as furthering the United States-Moldova bilateral relationship, all which benefit the people and businesses of the United States and strengthen the transatlantic relationship.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2569FD41DE2432AB6322406F00A7C57"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States-Moldova Strategic Dialogue is an important platform for strengthening the United States-Moldova bilateral relationship.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE23E3794CBC34DD6B0958DA9635E0451"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation has historically targeted Moldova, seeking to undermine its democratic institutions, weaponize energy supplies in Moldova (including through Transnistria), and use Moldova as a lynchpin of a wider campaign to expand its malign influence and promote broader instability across Europe and the world.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC48E3A6B9DF9449DBBA2D9C7C222D3C3" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>United States-Moldova strategic dialogue</header> 
<subsection id="HAE16C1228FFD47DFBDF42391559E18FC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall facilitate a strategic dialogue between the United States and the Republic of Moldova to—</text> <paragraph id="H26A2BD4FB0ED49879BF5003763C8672A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advance bilateral priorities, including defense and security cooperation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F7DC7F368F34BC6B2424E6192FC0966" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discuss Moldova’s progress towards European Union integration and ways the United States can facilitate, through foreign assistance, investment, and public-private partnership, Moldova’s process of accession to the European Union;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7380718F3EF47B29A50963CC53A1971" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthen economic and energy ties between Moldova and the United States, including expanding United States Government support for the Straseni-Gutinas transmission line project that will provide opportunities for United States businesses, strengthen Moldova’s energy independence, and enhance Moldovan and European energy security;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7691CF072F124CBBBC47687588B88A63" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reaffirm support for Moldova’s sovereignty and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFB7E07CBBE04ED2B9DD9890CB5766B1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand support for the State Partnership Program between Moldova and North Carolina; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1FA944D18DCB4293A72BEC76E6FDA360" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expand and support State Department facilitated American Spaces in Moldova.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H87E28ACAB5E044F7948364DDB7361B82" commented="no"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Frequency of dialogue</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in partnership with the Government of Moldova, shall facilitate the strategic dialogue required in subsection (a) not less frequently than annually.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="HDDF40B2623274C9FABB30A8612B76EF7" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strategy to promote Moldova’s pro-European future</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate Congressional Committees a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H3B3D4C9566C44D92AB605EF1607AA774" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a 4-year strategy to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA21661FE1F1B441BB819A69818D8A4B5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bolster United States-Moldovan bilateral relations, including to advance the priorities outlined in the strategic dialogue required in section 3; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H012C44072014458CAFA27F6939848356" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support Moldova’s process of accession to the European Union and Moldova’s goal of becoming a member of the European Union by the year 2030, including through United States foreign assistance that avoids conflicts with Moldova’s obligations related to European Union accession or agreements with international financial institutions or other official creditors;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H490F43D82D0F47EEA491F95485E1C3DE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of actions taken by the Department of State to counter malign influence by the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China in Moldova since January 20, 2025;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25E685F4158E412FB4A99E4FD9F9C00E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of active and cancelled foreign assistance programs in or related to Moldova since January 20, 2025; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB95F998F0AAF4F1590DAF69C980FE0FD" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of actions taken by the Department to support the accession of Moldova to the European Union and expand, where appropriate and within the interests of both the United States and Moldova, Moldova’s cooperation with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5052C7D9700D49FC8E87A7769E9CCEE9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Maintenance of certain sanctions</header> <subsection id="H318BB59D2A1B41668C62C9FD657CE5F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any sanction imposed by the United States and in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act with respect to a person described in subsection (c) may not be terminated until the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury have, in addition to any other measure required by law—</text> 
<paragraph id="H78EBD2AAF69A4752825C3B111DFB78A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submitted to the appropriate congressional committees a written certification that the person (or the immediate family member of such person, as appropriate) is no longer engaging in the behavior that caused the person to be subject to the sanction;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4908B331B35E46C4B44BBC6EAC01F1AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>briefed the appropriate congressional committees regarding such certification; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDA7AD0240A6742ED87C1718799308E88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consulted with the appropriate congressional committees regarding such certification.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H356FCD91228C4F27A610D9A52EF1811D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ineligibility for entry</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including paragraph (3) of section 7031(c) of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note), the Secretary may not waive or terminate the application of paragraph (1) of such section with respect to an individual described in subsection (c) unless the Secretary has—</text> 
<paragraph id="H744A741D869743FBBCA98531618667A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submitted to the appropriate congressional committees a written certification that the individual (or the immediate family member of the individual, as appropriate) is no longer engaging in significant corruption or a gross violation of human rights described in such section 7031(c)(1);</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3674DF7CC9EB4CC4B8CC123312FD8F12"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provided to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing regarding such certification; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFFD8D6C892AC473E95A55D3B27F3F826"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consulted with the appropriate congressional committees regarding such certification.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEF77A4B6502A47C29D480B881CE16559"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Persons described</header><text>A person described in this subsection is any of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H821A339CE3A94AC19D38F3D25FDA53BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Former member of the Moldovan Parliament Ilan Shor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H181D551BECD84712A877B5A78BD73FCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Shor Party.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E7C27A311C545C9A60E9C72A28CD2C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Former member of the Moldovan Parliament Vlad Plahotniuc.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC72D912737F4424DA929B63B3DF439C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Igor Yuryevich Chayka.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5FC3F9C30C14013B4E2121E5408DD85"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Ivan Alesksandrovich Zavorotnyi.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F3B9BA60BCF48CB9C7C73F0035B206C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Yuriy Igorevich Gudilin.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C5C3213B9FB4D38BB969ABE1D223DEB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Olga Yurievna Grak.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDFAEFB72BC264EB6AC2715B798E207ED"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Leonid Mikhailovich Gonin.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6BC1BFFA04C24DB1B360FFD9B686D270"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Aleksei Valeryevich Troshin.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B372828A5D74D21A7153A6FE21AA6AB"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Maksim Yakubets.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96E9E13EC53A431A9B1509D66362A33E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The National Engineering Corporation (commonly known as <quote>NIK</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD397C0890FA8475B87C0CF436C670662"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Any person with respect to whom sanctions have been imposed by the United States due to the relationship between such person and an individual described in paragraphs (1) through (11).</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9CF67E8BBB0F47E2BA175091D6DFB16C" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="HA10F7200317A4D5CBD0AC46BFEF44627" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB78A7488ED44444A2F5947F5FFEB382" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

