<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EDW26097-FJV-KN-504"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3786 IS: Balance the Highway Trust Fund Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3786</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260205">February 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S346">Mr. Lee</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To limit spending from the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idF06E3B5DA8D7415A91819688108FB353"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Balance the Highway Trust Fund Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idA8204B87246149CDA499B7B706B64C85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Obligation limitation</header><subsection id="idCD8DA436A7C844FC95C4D65FA6A6F86B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (d) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, for each fiscal year, the obligations for Federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs shall not exceed the net highway receipts most recently estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury for that fiscal year under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(d)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida9de69ce9cbf4750968005e051142674"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of obligation authority</header><text>For each fiscal year, the Secretary of Transportation (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>)—</text><paragraph id="idf8752df7f1cb456db45934dc3019cee2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not distribute obligation authority provided by subsection (a) for the fiscal year for—</text><subparagraph id="ida1bfabd4029e44d3985ca42b2ef04780"><enum>(A)</enum><text>amounts authorized for administrative expenses and programs by section 104(a) of title 23, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4061bf4a389a4a0b88554e7ce8a498ef"><enum>(B)</enum><text>amounts authorized for the Bureau of Transportation Statistics;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb1b4c4eb0e39496d9f2c1d9db1403a53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not distribute an amount of obligation authority provided by subsection (a) that is equal to the unobligated balance of amounts—</text><subparagraph id="id1947b3f6b04e405b8f122794615f68ed"><enum>(A)</enum><text>made available from the Highway Trust Fund (other than the Mass Transit Account) for Federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs for previous fiscal years the funds for which are allocated by the Secretary (or apportioned by the Secretary under section 202 or 204 of title 23, United States Code); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4a1a96444387466cbb274828dcb4dfce"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which obligation authority was provided in a previous fiscal year;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ideaf87cbe6aca4990b3fe32333f5e6771"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall determine the proportion that—</text><subparagraph id="idae896c9b21094348a49735a108803730"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the obligation authority provided by subsection (a) for the fiscal year, less the aggregate of amounts not distributed under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection; bears to</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2752d5c3e5cd4f9297268cd2800b2ca8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total of the sums authorized to be appropriated for the Federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs, less the aggregate of the amounts not distributed under paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc5c89cca6c934426a4008fc081cd0c17"><enum>(4)</enum><text>shall distribute the obligation authority provided by subsection (a), less the aggregate amounts not distributed under paragraphs (1) and (2), for each of the programs (other than programs to which paragraph (1) applies) that are allocated by the Secretary under this Act and title 23, United States Code, or apportioned by the Secretary under section 202 or 204 of that title, by multiplying—</text><subparagraph id="id5fa2c000ea574db6a6e6c5c4c1b4f777"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>the proportion determined under paragraph (3); by</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfa3637ec343946cb99a4f2fa4fba8aa3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amounts authorized to be appropriated for each such program for the fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8566a79a5bfc4ce8995138b81ef3acea"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall distribute the obligation authority provided by subsection (a), less the aggregate amounts not distributed under paragraphs (1) and (2) and the amounts distributed under paragraph (4), for Federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs that are apportioned by the Secretary under title 23, United States Code (other than the amounts apportioned under sections 202 and 204 of title 23, United States Code) in the proportion that—</text><subparagraph id="id1af45e5772374fc1a5f3d210decc13e0"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>amounts authorized to be appropriated for the programs that are apportioned under title 23, United States Code, to each State for the fiscal year; bears to</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6f8d4dd17f6b48beaf5b59c863228d39"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for the programs that are apportioned under title 23, United States Code, to all States for the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id062b047287804d2a954ccf8f385de98a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Redistribution of unused obligation authority</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary shall, after August 1 of each fiscal year—</text><paragraph id="id9787f5a53391451f8368515d497aef7b"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revise a distribution of the obligation authority made available under subsection (b) if an amount distributed cannot be obligated during that fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id764a513bd2fa4252985e5308ba550732"><enum>(2)</enum><text>redistribute sufficient amounts to those States able to obligate amounts in addition to those previously distributed during that fiscal year, giving priority to those States having large unobligated balances of funds apportioned under sections 144 (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of MAP–21 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/141">Public Law 112–141</external-xref>)) and 104 of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idcc1385a3809c4c7788d35a6fbc432b28"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability of obligation limitations to transportation research programs</header><paragraph id="ida443ad075121469d8d1ed1335361e2fb"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), obligation limitations imposed by subsection (a) shall apply to contract authority for transportation research programs carried out under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb973335f55f945b3b36672827a2263b0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Obligation authority made available under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id94f624e8bd914d7ebba260cc5fe5ccef"><enum>(A)</enum><text>remain available for a period of 4 fiscal years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89335221f52649019c87a0a56c535c83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be in addition to the amount of any limitation imposed on obligations for Federal-aid highway and highway safety construction programs for future fiscal years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id341953c9eaea4184b1cba7dca3499c30"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Redistribution of certain authorized funds</header><paragraph id="id9d8a25dda4af457897e10ce70767376c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of distribution of obligation authority under subsection (b) for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall distribute to the States any funds (excluding funds authorized for the program under section 202 of title 23, United States Code) that—</text><subparagraph id="id647e1531de1f4c998ef8b3dc3ba20802"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year for Federal-aid highway programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idff34332e11294796af3501af035b966d"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines will not be allocated to the States (or will not be apportioned to the States under section 204 of title 23, United States Code), and will not be available for obligation, for the fiscal year because of the imposition of any obligation limitation for the fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d6d76b5d151406ea6d0dfe9be174f9f"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ratio</header><text>Funds shall be distributed under paragraph (1) in the same proportion as the distribution of obligation authority under subsection (b)(5).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbb3bea2ab3f64dc7a57aadfb31c31ea1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Funds distributed to each State under paragraph (1) shall be available for any purpose described in section 133(b) of title 23, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idF1C3083FBC6A467690D7CE77FB3A1428"><enum>3.</enum><header>Obligation limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5338 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id76380F72D84F4FB8BAC3DB7F13DDD464"><subsection id="idEEF93338C751466D9383B2A557759EFB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Obligation limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (a) or any other provision of law, for each fiscal year, the total of all obligations from amounts made available from the Mass Transit Account of the Highway Trust Fund by subsection (a) and any other provision of law shall not exceed the net mass transit receipts most recently estimated for that fiscal year by the Secretary of the Treasury under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(e)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" id="id0AB5D98441114210BD16A923F5A5E0DD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act take effect October 1, 2027.</text></section></legis-body></bill>

