<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAB53A2B502C34827B4F016C3EF799F91" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9042 IH: Blue Skies for Taiwan Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9042</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260526">May 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000138">Mr. Vindman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote the development, production, and deployment of secure and resilient Unmanned Aerial Systems (UAS) to enhance United States national security and support the defense and resilience of Taiwan in the Indo-Pacific Region.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9149272F1CAF4DD0BE76BD0A4736EFF5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF46E2BF055044201A6C999B59BF35BCD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Blue Skies for Taiwan Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H31075793D26D42E3A93C0D29E7A5524C" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DE19FA0A39E407EA720ABF0E5CFE0A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A36D6B0D7F642D6A65DC7B34DCBE340"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC71A93FC216647BE9CF5F9E4C390A449"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on the Budget, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61C6BA71C16A48258CBFE71AA6460174" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Blue UAS</header><text>The term <term>Blue UAS</term> refers to UAS components and systems that comply with Defense Contract Management Agency’s Blue UAS program and its associated list.</text></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H502C11DB58F447B8BA36E78DB0B804EC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="H8317ACF78C5440B8A89F7E6B47A75DAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Taiwan is a longstanding and vital democratic partner whose security is central to United States strategic interests and regional stability in the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5F2C8CD74B774CA1A99ECE6108F58479"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China (PRC) is increasingly employing gray-zone tactics, including routine use of unmanned aerial systems and other low-cost platforms, to pressure Taiwan and undermine its security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE892FBD77084E5C88C24EC44301F38B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As set forth in the Taiwan Relations Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>), it is United States policy to maintain its capacity to resist any resort to force or other forms of coercion against Taiwan and provide Taiwan with arms of a defensive nature.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H97490EF38033428295E13717A6CB149A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As set forth in the Taiwan Enhanced Resilience Act (subtitle A of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>), it is the sense of Congress that the United States should support Taiwan’s acquisition and employment of capabilities that advance asymmetric strategies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FB73D0C6BC94451888404DF54D3C1D9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The vast majority of commercially available UAS contain PRC-sourced components, creating significant cybersecurity, supply chain, and operational risks for both Taiwan and the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H182EE86803D04FFDADB8551947959BDA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Taiwan is well-positioned to develop and produce UAS components and systems but faces challenges in competing with PRC commercial companies, accessing capital, and meeting United States certification and cybersecurity requirements.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3677F6488AE84769807F930BDF4FBDC6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The United States should support UAS supply chain development in Taiwan to strengthen Taiwan’s asymmetric defense posture and expand United States access to secure, PRC-independent UAS components and systems.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF459E8732740402AB51A66BC9387491D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Army Organic Industrial Base, including its arsenals, depots, and ammunition plants, is undergoing modernization to support emerging technologies and may provide opportunities to support the testing and sustainment of unmanned aerial systems and related components in coordination with allies and partners.</text></paragraph></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A04C4015BCD4D089AF8FDFD384F22A9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Blue UAS Working Group</header> <subsection id="H7BA29D434B214BE8A7B3A6BB9E5427ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a Blue UAS working group, leveraging existing workstreams and expanding scope as needed, inclusive of government, industry, and academic experts, to—</text>
<paragraph id="H59A83F15A5A54374A6A4766DCC8A07ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess Taiwan’s domestic drone production capacity, including research and development, legal and regulatory frameworks, testing, certification, and production capacities for dual-use drones;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H84379AB2088849A18CBFC2A8AFCD575E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate opportunities for public-private partnerships between the United States and Taiwan for co-development and co-production of UAS systems and components, including pilot programs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H82BD1D6D5FF64029BCD3775A451A75A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify barriers to the inclusion of Taiwan-manufactured components and systems manufactured in Blue UAS programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EC8CE99E65C4A72840547CB868C743A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify regulatory, export-control, and certification barriers that impede Taiwan’s participation in Blue UAS programs;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A346ECEACF34D829722484D8612BA91"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide recommendations to expand and improve incorporation of Taiwanese suppliers into Blue UAS programs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CDEF14BE9734CD3A0FEDC3E34070663"><enum>(6)</enum><text>identify specific UAS components or systems that could be integrated into Blue UAS programs within 12 to 24 months;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H794C928076C249618CCA2C820368EA63"><enum>(7)</enum><text>analyze opportunities and impediments to including Taiwan in Replicator programs and similar initiatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H821818138CE7405484CB16876C5F3906"><enum>(8)</enum><text>assess opportunities for collaboration with the Army Organic Industrial Base, including its arsenals, depots, and ammunition plants, to support the testing, evaluation, production, maintenance, and sustainment of Blue UAS components and systems, including those co-developed or co-produced with Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7E8620AE8E064855A911ECA421DA437B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for three years, the Working Group shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an unclassified report on its activities, including findings, recommendations, timelines, resource needs, and potential funding mechanisms, with a classified appendix as necessary.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H186A93512F914F129AF42BBFCB6234E2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Cooperative framework with allies</header> <subsection id="HB27102877CA5486BB25FE9B3C92B53AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish a cooperative framework, drawing on the Partnership for Indo-Pacific Industrial Resilience (PIPIR), among the United States, Taiwan, and regional allies and global partners to promote secure, PRC-independent UAS supply chains and enhance interoperability.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04DB2AD61C8F4F858AD1BFB99FE29CCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The cooperative framework shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H723B2BF1202543538CD806DFF6E43B4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support regional allies in the acquisition of Blue UAS components or systems from Taiwan in lieu of PRC-sourced components; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6534176AD3C94DD285B6A8BDED8C2BA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fast-track Blue UAS certification for components co-developed or co-produced by Taiwan and regional allies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H463749013A44431D84C8F67497F819EC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Fast-track certification</header> <subsection id="HA54124CFB9534DADB99D250B06C5BC4F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall develop a fast-track process for Blue UAS companies in Taiwan to obtain Blue UAS certification.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3997BF1D52EC469CB151501B47542E0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The fast-track certification process shall include the following procedures:</text> <paragraph id="H742B33E61DEC474285A2929396C1036E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Expedited export control reviews and licensing for Taiwan drone and drone component manufacturers, including streamlined technical reviews for components with no PRC-connected subcomponents.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5F41102CF45245A5AE5FF735917F46D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A fast-track certification procedure for Taiwanese manufacturers, including reciprocal testing arrangements or recognition of equivalent Taiwan cybersecurity standards where appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HDCDCA2FB8C914850A4C75310324A68CB"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act.</text></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HC356B7DEA84E4835A914F3FD31BE2D9A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed—</text> <paragraph id="HBD57A1B445B24E16A3D4BF72BF1F3847"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to alter United States policy towards Taiwan as codified in the Taiwan Relations Act of 1979 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4B306BAC2CED474899664DCD1DFAE715"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to alter the United States Government’s position with respect to the international status of Taiwan.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

