<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E580D46228543978701E9027668B0C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6259 IH: No Fentanyl on Social Media Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000300">Mr. Evans of Colorado</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Trade Commission to submit to Congress a report on the ability of minors to access fentanyl through social media platforms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H85D933C6C75746549B3497B4042C09AB" style="OLC"><section id="HB6A4FDE73AFE498384381F5D16DCCF90" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Fentanyl on Social Media Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H03F6AD8FE28A4527BF576C8D348E4C60"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on the ability of minors to access fentanyl through social media platforms</header><subsection id="H1338BE9561164B96B97D00A352DF9117"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Commission, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, and the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, shall submit to the relevant congressional committees and make publicly available on the website of the Commission a report on the ability of minors to access fentanyl, including through pressed pills, on social media platforms that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="HC8E3C5B277B14867926E58039780D1B0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prevalence and ability for minors to access fentanyl from drug sellers on social media platforms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H410DCBE9E4BF4744862A237873F43E41" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The impact of such prevalence and access on minors, including health risks and risks to physical safety.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33FBF966F6EB48C68B61E0E7560B5D76" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How drug sellers use social media platforms to market, sell, deliver, distribute, dispense, and engage in other transactions related to the provision of fentanyl to minors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA53A475DF9DD4666B93EE28711A7D33A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>How design features and other characteristics of social media platforms affect the ability of minors to access fentanyl.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0281C736E1E24C568A5AEF6B53BDF7FE" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Practices, policies, and other measures taken by social media platforms to address the ability of drug sellers to use social media platforms and the effectiveness of those practices, policies, and measures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04B34BCCE4CC4A61996CFCBF11FCB8D1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Other measures taken by law enforcement, the medical community, and others to address the issues described in paragraphs (1) through (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H519375C76C3646C98C02AAB122C43874"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for Congress to eliminate the prevalence and ability for minors to access fentanyl on social media platforms.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H359840A82A844583B7A21888D44B15EB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the report required pursuant to subsection (a), the Commission shall consult with stakeholders including parents, social media platforms, law enforcement, medical professionals, and other relevant experts.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB7CD1EC381449179905B07310362E70"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Redaction permitted</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In publishing the report required under subsection (a), the Commission, in consultation with the Attorney General, may redact any information relating to paragraphs (3) and (6) that may compromise any law enforcement tactic, strategy, or technique.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED4C9BA7FB3E4FD282B28D6A9F451B9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H4BCC0AD6EB4A47B19575BA14D4BA344D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C5368D9BDD443438694D20F06468AE3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fentanyl</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fentanyl</term> includes any fentanyl analogue and fentanyl-related substance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H483C51D00B934DC7A3D0D231CA35B99D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fentanyl-related substance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>fentanyl-related substance</term> has the meaning given that term in subsection (e) of schedule I of section 202(c) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/812">21 U.S.C. 812(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE65F16BDAD0B428B8955FAB402AB0A10"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minor</term> means an individual who is under the age of 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5FB43D2A203402D8CFEFFDF13EF072C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>relevant congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7C97E90B5144E36A3F50E05B33DAF55"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Social Media Platform</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>social media platform</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H635B940EFAAA4E29A8BD7A706D28F5E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a public-facing website, internet application, or mobile internet application, including a social network or video sharing service—</text><clause id="H78BD9779C43644FAA9EBEBC1347C6844"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that serves the public; and</text></clause><clause id="HEF5DE9AB907D4DF18D03E22243FE514D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that primarily provides a forum for user-generated content, including messages, videos, images, games, and audio files; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E5CADC497A4972BD3F6A6C75438521"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="H5A9A3E7589CA47CC94C94631F5656636"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a provider of broadband internet access service (as described in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulation); or</text></clause><clause id="H6B2334D30E1D4C6F96BE95B1A2150052"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>electronic mail.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

