<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HF330E68EC42C4D909B032F9FA3F6011C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7432 RH: Foster Youth Housing Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 560</calendar><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7432</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 119–643, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260209">February 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HWM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260511">May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 9, 2026</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 477 of the Social Security Act to improve coordination with Federal housing assistance programs for youth who have experienced foster care.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HWM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H59A8277A3841492DBB3B2F3F5B27AD15"><section id="H18DFA023B73B4746A5EB357BC93CEAD7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foster Youth Housing Opportunity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H83DC163A47954241A78AC4762172B0A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improving access to housing for foster youth</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 477 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/677">42 U.S.C. 677</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE47BFE02EA664B9C92225C98B298D4E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H93535D8A2EDD4F009C1819B93E4EE8E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and preventive</quote> and inserting <quote>preventive</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E585175E8C04C1D9C33BFE5286E2C8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and access to housing for youth age 18 or older</quote> before the semicolon;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF05843F823E14860BCAF871264BA9404"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(4), by inserting <quote>current and</quote> before <quote>former</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6D8710080E54E7A9AF90491EB55AE74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(D), by inserting <quote>, including by collaborating with public housing agencies that administer Federal housing programs serving foster youth under section 8(x)(2)(B) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 and receive funding to partner with public child welfare agencies to serve youth who have experienced foster care</quote> before the period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H046B8ABB2132424586F2AA27B464087A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(3)(B), by striking <quote>not more than 30 percent of the amounts paid to the State from its allotment under subsection (c) for a fiscal year</quote> and inserting <quote>an average of not more than 30 percent of the amounts paid to the State from its allotment under subsection (c) for the 5 fiscal years covered by the application submitted by the State pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3155D49AC6E49E4A0D7BFA1F7A5D417"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF88CD4813A474CE2A226A939402E5B5A" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HWM00"><paragraph id="H596A00E9E817427890B8C3D5FBB4F2C7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Housing supportive services</header><subparagraph id="H48E7B802FEEA405A9518E3919195B5FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may use amounts from its allotment under subsection (c) to provide supportive services to assist eligible youth who experienced foster care to obtain or retain suitable housing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11574D3214034FD19111966EB3FDF119"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><clause id="H3EB97E3F492943CFA0D03764E48A2DB7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligible youth</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>eligible youth</term> means an individual who receives assistance provided under section 8(x) of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</text></clause><clause id="HBBC7671C298A400A91CF8FFB58022C6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Supportive services</header><text>The term <term>supportive services</term> may include—</text><subclause id="H98D58D91035344808D0976FCD05FCE87"><enum>(I)</enum><text>basic life skills information and counseling on financial literacy, use of credit, and money management;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4DCC271807CD41338692B6600BB27ED7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>counseling on rental lease contracts and assistance with rental insurance; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD591B587C72649EF83EE6A4A1E1B980A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assistance with security deposits, utility connection fees, moving costs, and other fees associated with establishing tenancy.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8158161494BA43BBA2FC8A10D052AC36"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Expenditures in accordance with this paragraph shall not be considered expenditures for room and board for purposes of subsection (b)(3)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD218CFDDC98943159A2A4AF093D8CD75"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Aligning age eligibility</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b)(3)(A)(ii), a State may use funds from its allotment under subsection (c) to provide supportive services to eligible youth who have not attained 26 years of age for the purpose of supporting continued access to housing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H579C2F0DA7F74158B89CB558B5586B8D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(1), by inserting <quote>access to housing,</quote> before <quote>and personal</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEF64F7AF370849C5B94BF3DDC6806F0F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Joint agency guidance</header><subsection id="HEA830C9B4CFE436EB07DBA7C9E707DD0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall develop and issue joint guidance to State public child welfare agencies and public housing authorities to improve alignment and coordination of housing supportive services provided under section 477 of the Social Security Act and housing assistance provided under section 8(x) of the United States Housing Act of 1937.</text></subsection><subsection id="H145D60FFF01244068A185FE633EDEB72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The joint guidance shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H8F5692E6099248A5A044E8CEDBACE212"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Clarification and alignment of Federal policies to improve access to housing for youth who have experienced foster care, including youth who are in independent living arrangements while in extended foster care.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38B0BB5AB1DC47498EACFA14843226A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Guidance on State use of funds provided under section 477 of the Social Security Act for supportive services (as defined in subsection (d)(6) of such section) to improve access to housing programs administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4014BBF87E734F7CB04CC0A9EB42EF05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Best practices for building partnerships between public child welfare agencies and public housing authorities, including ways to improve access to supportive services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B4E229959154007A0C01B24D8D5E0B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Additional information the Secretaries deem necessary to effectively coordinate Federal programs serving current and former foster youth.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H16FB1A20333A409C8397FC92E84A2B02" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Production</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall designate an official of the Department of Health and Human Services to lead development of the joint guidance in collaboration with the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></subsection></section><section id="H407E4BFAEA7E4433802480B440FA1A47"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Within 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report that sets forth—</text><paragraph id="HA03C9929138E45B0A4D1519B5FBBA977"><enum>(1)</enum><text>aggregate data on the number of eligible youth who have experienced foster care who are receiving Federal housing assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H391146517A0045D1A45A01F416888769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the outcomes for the youth, including the extent to which youth are able to access stable housing and rates of homelessness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5A884E8FDBE46CDA10DE0B4DB183AAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings from any evaluations of State programs conducted pursuant to section 477(g)(1) of the Social Security Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEFE493E9D6142969533A931F2B45B0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>statutory recommendations for improving coordination between public child welfare agencies and Federal housing programs.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD3DD9AA78F544220A8BEB621741BEAA8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HWM00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date>May 11, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

