<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCEADB56684334F6181DD4997C5C3287C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6446 IH: To modify the procedures for investigating claims of evasion of antidumping and countervailing duty orders.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6446</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251204">December 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000530">Mr. Deluzio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify the procedures for investigating claims of evasion of antidumping and countervailing duty orders.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H178E9EC0244D4037B108F68F5095847C" style="OLC"><section id="H81A78ABBBF2C4068BC232171516EC7DD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Modification of procedures for investigating claims of evasion of antidumping and countervailing duty orders</header><subsection id="H326728D3878049EEAAE433536B8C42E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 517(b)(1) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1517">19 U.S.C. 1517(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Commissioner may also self-initiate an investigation if the Commissioner has information that reasonably suggests that covered merchandise has been entered into the customs territory of the United States through evasion. In such case, the terms and conditions that apply to the processes for allegations and referrals under this section shall also apply to a process for self-initiation under the preceding sentence.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H94C2EC352843483593EF51C375DA6531"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Judicial review</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 517(g)(1) of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1517">19 U.S.C. 1517(g)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>A person determined to have entered such covered merchandise through evasion may seek judicial review under this paragraph only if all liquidated duties, charges, or exactions have been paid at the time the judicial review is sought.</quote>.</text>
      </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

