<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD30AD14955A54D39B6BBE158A536837A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6021 IH: Archie Cavanaugh Migratory Bird Treaty Amendment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6021</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251112">November 12, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001323">Mr. Begich</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to clarify the treatment of authentic Alaska Native articles of handicraft containing nonedible migratory bird parts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B616071A0A04352B8493CF333FF1212" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H19C16A0B435C40F0B60F811EF3824020"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Archie Cavanaugh Migratory Bird Treaty Amendment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC69580AA1A7E4276AAC3C62CA1957444"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H61A3C400AAB44C0DA183E5BCA448FDDF"><enum/><text>The purpose of this Act is to clarify the treatment of authentic Alaska Native articles of handicraft (as defined in subsection (c)(1) of section 2 of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703</external-xref>)) under—</text> 
<paragraph id="HCEE5DC7CE2904A56AE43A64A21B0FC23">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>the Convention between the United States and Great Britain for the Protection of Migratory Birds, signed at Washington August 16, 1916 (39 Stat. 1702; USTS 628);</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDAD02FAA45D41F8B32CDA524EE67FB3">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>the Convention between the United States and Mexico for the Protection of Migratory Birds and Game Mammals, signed at Mexico City February 7, 1936 (50 Stat. 1311; USTS 912);</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HECE4A0AC4C1649CB9F3FFEB59EFD51F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Convention between the United States and Japan for the Protection of Migratory Birds and Birds in Danger of Extinction and Their Environment, signed at Tokyo March 4, 1974 (TIAS 7990); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE34F37F514B74DB1BC69034C33080B3C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Convention between the United States and the Soviet Union Concerning the Conservation of Migratory Birds and Their Environment, signed at Moscow November 19, 1976 (TIAS 9073).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H999C651396E947FAB4EF177ECD303676"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clarification for Alaska Native articles containing migratory bird parts</header> 
<subsection id="H85686D396FAD42BC94EDB98C55EFB450"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 2 of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59DEC66F5AD74053A00250080459D6EE"> <subsection id="H8E28371B19574F54BC5A7E584771E162"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification for authentic alaska native articles of handicraft</header> <paragraph id="H30007D0CF3CB41E684ADC08563E0DF04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6FC186A923BE46E6A4C0F0A2C0C8351A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Alaska native</header><text>The term <term>Alaska Native</term> means a member of any Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)) that is based in the State of Alaska, as verified through issuance of—</text> <clause id="H7A7F1E8DD1324DE78B07D41BE5E95CBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Tribal enrollment card;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5A2444ED6E93430D933AF416F0A77AE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Certificate of Degree of Indian Blood (commonly known as a <quote>CDIB</quote>) by the Bureau of Indian Affairs; or</text></clause> <clause id="HC4B4DBA6AF5342728D6F6EB335A785A4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a permit under the Silver Hand program of the Alaska State Council on the Arts.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H77E605F439104A27B5584935AEAA7E52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authentic alaska native article of handicraft</header> 
<clause id="HDD3E076834694E27A540FF3AD73CF3FB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>authentic Alaska Native article of handicraft</term> means any item that is—</text> <subclause id="HB5461B0B2C344095BCB5AACA3FF5AAE6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>composed, wholly or in a significant respect, of natural materials that were found, foraged, or gifted; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4F9CB56DD0224A06A2C25498C3FD4870"><enum>(II)</enum><text>produced, decorated, or fashioned in significant part—</text> <item id="HE1F7F875EAFE454CBAC14FE825DD662C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by an Alaska Native;</text></item> 
<item id="H89C1532F10984F2AA8102E18E8B019F2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the exercise of traditional Alaska Native handicrafts; and</text></item> <item id="HBF6831D4D34341B8A70DB7FCC1306263"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>without the use of any mass copying device.</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFB6E039C1E894D84ACCAD164144C5D86"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>authentic Alaska Native article of handicraft</term> includes—</text> <subclause id="H0FE67CB7F3A3400D8708EF40F121A18E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any weaving, carving, stitching, sewing, lacing, beading, drawing, or painting that meets the criteria described in clause (i); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HABBD22D05C5B43068353E2CBBCFF750A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any item, including clothing, described in subclause (I) that combines the techniques described in that subclause.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1BCB61E0FE241B28827E20A89E082AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification for certain authentic alaska native articles of handicraft</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3) and notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, nothing in this Act prohibits the possession, offering for sale, sale, offering to barter, barter, offering to purchase, purchase, delivery for shipment, shipment, causing to be shipped or delivered for transportation, transport, causing to be transported, carrying, causing to be carried, or receiving for shipment, transportation, or carriage of any authentic Alaska Native article of handicraft on the basis that the authentic Alaska Native article of handicraft contains a nonedible migratory bird part.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB724C22A3D104BADAC455A89DD25AEE4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This subsection does not apply to an authentic Alaska Native article of handicraft containing a part of a migratory bird that was taken in a wasteful or illegal manner.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB250490C697E485D8487F1CD82535F7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE955788331174DCBBE0790135B3F981F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of State shall work with the Secretary of the Interior to enter into appropriate bilateral procedures, as necessary, with countries that are parties to the treaties described in paragraphs (1) through (4) of section 2 to clarify the treatment of authentic Alaska Native articles of handicraft (as defined in subsection (c)(1) of section 2 of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703</external-xref>)) containing nonedible migratory bird parts from the species of migratory birds listed in those treaties in accordance with the amendments made by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7516E31F85094F1688F6583CBFF493FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior shall modify any regulations implementing the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.</external-xref>), as appropriate, to implement the amendments made by this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5A51D1D79C214CB184ED50E59F2AFA1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 2(a) of the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703</external-xref>) is amended by inserting a comma after <quote>March 4, 1972</quote>.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

