<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Agreed-to-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-LAN25056-33Y-99-D1C"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 465 ATS: Designating September 2025 as “National Childhood Cancer Awareness Month”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 465</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251023">October 23, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S365">Mr. Scott of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S259">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was considered and agreed to</action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating September 2025 as <quote>National Childhood Cancer Awareness Month</quote>.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas each year more than 14,500 children under the age of 19 in the United States are diagnosed with cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas every year approximately 1,600 children in the United States lose their lives to cancer;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas childhood cancer is one of the leading causes of death from disease after infancy and one of the leading causes of death overall for children in the United States;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas the 5-year survival rate for children with cancer in the United States has increased from 58 percent in the mid-1970s to 85 percent in 2025, representing a significant improvement from previous decades;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 60 to more than 90 percent or more of children in the United States who survive cancer will develop at least one chronic health condition, and some survivors may face a late effect from treatment that can be severe or life-threatening; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas childhood cancer occurs frequently and spares no racial or ethnic group, socioeconomic class, or geographic region: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id9dd06ddb03ca4a2a9540716fd3b3cf0f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates September 2025 as <quote>National Childhood Cancer Awareness Month</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idde0875aca51342d288b997cc11c592d5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requests that the Federal Government, States, localities, and nonprofit organizations observe the month with appropriate programs and activities, with the goal of increasing public knowledge of the risks of childhood cancer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idea43dca27f7746ebab527031283bd81f"><enum>(3)</enum><text>encourages survivors of childhood cancer to continue to receive ongoing monitoring and care throughout their adult lives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf69eb2fb9a2a4c569ae1f14045621fed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recognizes the human toll of childhood cancer and pledges to make the prevention of and cure for childhood cancer a public health priority;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00d0393d98644cac92dbd5a7051191ab"><enum>(5)</enum><text>reminds the people of the United States of the bravery of children who are diagnosed with cancer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id061ff07986a5414bb4d1c7961190eb8a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commends and honors the courage of such children.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

