<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26392-SHW-PJ-WN6"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4094 IS: Corruption Clawback Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4094</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260312">March 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S427">Mr. Schiff</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S361">Ms. Hirono</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S386">Ms. Duckworth</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Attorney General to recover certain payments made to the President.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id9f86decb25c34ab5a4676f62e528d334" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corruption Clawback Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98d8eef501654f1aac9cfffffcc597ee"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>covered payment</term> means any portion of any monetary settlement, administrative award, including an award made under section 2672 of title 28, United States Code, or a court-ordered judgment—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id27da216731394a77a2d06abf73567371"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paid from the United States Treasury or in accordance with section 1304 of title 31, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idea0b6ef7f958484aa208a98a63acd4a2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>paid to an individual when they served as President;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida99b3e8810fd45b385b74716377ecb60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that would not have been paid but for the individual holding the status, authority, or duties associated with their position as President; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ac3ccf2026a4abf8275be80ef6d5a5c" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relating to an administrative claim filed or settlement reached on or after January 20, 2025.</text></paragraph></section><section id="S1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Recovery of payments made to the President</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd167dbdf38bc4ab58ce8c5aef2bd855b"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall bring a civil action in the United States Court of Federal Claims or the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit to recover any covered payment.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb35d5b1e29af43a880fe9dc17a875dd8"><enum>(b)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether a payment described in section 2 would not have been made but for the individual holding the status, authority, or duties associated with their position as President, the court should consider—</text><paragraph id="idad53572f404d458aa0f5e8746802f942"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether the officials who authorized or negotiated the covered payment on behalf of the Government were appointed by, or previously served as personal counsel to, the President;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e9c1380e71846309ce973cf0feb3bb6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether the amount of the covered payment exceeds typical payouts for similar claims by private citizens; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idd0034d615f88455990a914be86f3b4e8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the settlement bypassed standard legal defenses (such as statutes of limitations or sovereign immunity) that career Government lawyers would typically assert.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id69a0221bd2084c9e897a31c41ef077b2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of recovered payments</header><text>Any covered payment that is recovered under this section shall be used by the Public Integrity Section of the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4224cb5d887e422a8ff497159cc22751"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which a covered payment that is greater than $1,000,000 is made, the Comptroller General shall submit to Congress a report that includes the considerations described in section 3(b).</text></section></legis-body></bill>

