<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H69860B10A8E94A4AB5E4C09B2583BB31" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8524 IH: Kenya Merritt Renewing our Promise to Address Chemical Toxicity Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8524</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260427">April 27, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000621">Ms. Pou</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001228">Ms. Maloy</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Workforce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to improve access to workers’ compensation for civilian Federal employees exposed to toxic burn pits, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H79EC30F5094A4806B6EA5FEEE7BA0FC5" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H73DFA15B36134088BB6F8FFEFB07BF60" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kenya Merritt Renewing our Promise to Address Chemical Toxicity Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Kenya Merritt Renewing our PACT Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H415D59D1E7BD4F0F85856A6247642574"><enum>2.</enum><header>Certain diseases deemed to be proximately caused by employment for Federal employees exposed to toxic burn pits</header> <subsection id="H246D0B63234E415093CAAC0436BBE5B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of presumption</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8143b">section 8143b</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H71E24F6056D44FE28CCF687DF8746A02" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HE42AF6F133BB48E7B0A52262614BC4D6"><enum>8143c.</enum><header>Employees exposed to burn pits and toxic hazards in foreign contingency operations</header> 
<subsection id="H1560C5D991C94B16987FB7F281D76A69"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC3945BAEEA0449ACAFFAC76AE07143C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contingency operation</header><text>The term <term>contingency operation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 10.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0F564F37334042CA8A8E7CB23D1448B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible employee</term> means an employee of the Department of Justice, the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Homeland Security, or an element of the intelligence community, or a Federal law enforcement officer, who, on or after August 2, 1990, carried out the job responsibilities of that employee for not fewer than 30 total days in a country or territory while the United States was conducting a contingency operation in that country or territory.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DB0B638A8AB4DB783216FB47D8FEE1F"> <enum>(3)</enum> <header>Federal law enforcement officer</header> <text>The term <term>Federal law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given to the term in section 2 of the Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/50301">34 U.S.C. 50301</external-xref>).</text>
              </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B29730D15424E6385E7622DCA315F0F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85B6F5C6040A46299269A85AD4EEFD0B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Open burn pit</header><text>The term <term>open burn pit</term> has the meaning given the term in section 201(c) of the Dignified Burial and Other Veterans’ Benefits Improvement Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/527">38 U.S.C. 527</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9EC48F5C7A7C4C079882438E5EA3CE71"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presumption of employment connection for certain diseases associated with exposure to burn pits and other toxins</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a claim under this subchapter of disability or death of an eligible employee, a disease specified on the list established under subsection (c), as updated under that subsection, shall be deemed to have been incurred in or aggravated during the employment of that eligible employee, notwithstanding that there is no record of evidence of such disease during the period of such employment.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA2DD9BD41FB74977A8813FB45D038DF1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>List of diseases deemed proximately caused by employment</header> <paragraph id="HCF5ECDBB45A548E7938961754E0A298D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of initial list</header><text>There is established under this section a list of diseases that aligns with the diseases specified in section 1120(b) of title 38, including all diseases with respect to which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs prescribed regulations in the manner described in paragraph (15) of such section 1120(b) before the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC018565B2DF4E7A9E4789EF97DEA147"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additions to list</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD110708169254AE79A10BD8D1049EE2A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>On and after the date of enactment of this section, a disease may not be added to the list established under paragraph (1) unless the Secretary of Veterans Affairs adds that disease to the list under section 1120(b) of title 38 pursuant to regulations described in paragraph (15) of such section 1120(b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B45F5947FDB42A4AC874D9DE6D5245E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs finalizes regulations described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Labor shall, by direct final rule, add the same disease to the list established under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56BD8875745344889982061370A436E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maintenance by secretary of labor</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall maintain the list established and updated under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HEBB85994930344C0A3BFF13377BE0274"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/81">chapter 81</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/8143b">section 8143b</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HDEB94F32E6444AC48B9B6DB85091FCA0" style="USC"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">8143c. Employees exposed to burn pits and toxic hazards in foreign contingency operations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A77495A9A434A4B96E39A287AB8E22A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to a claim for compensation filed on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC74E81D34DC84D81869DF0A9EE46D977"> <enum>(d)</enum> <header>Report on implementation</header> <text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Workforce of the House of Representatives a report on the progress of implementing this Act and the amendments made by this Act, including the number of individuals who are eligible employees, as defined in section 8143c(a) of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text>
      </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

