<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6DCC0FF0AB7E4ACEBD7126B3CAB720C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8773 IH: Containing Effects of Mineral Extraction Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8773</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260512">May 12, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000830">Mr. Whitesides</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose certain conditions on mineral materials sales contracts and free use permits under the Materials Act of 1947 with respect to large-scale mineral extraction projects located near urban communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD0773F1042F54BE59DD49CD7D3655A9B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBE7EDCC5D9234EB08AA64CFC7708FB3C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Containing Effects of Mineral Extraction Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H36AD873B403245A6A2BBEB1CE8739A2D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements for certain mineral materials sales contracts and free use permits</header> <subsection id="H902EAE5BE279437AAB8BFDDD7AFF09E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <paragraph id="H01F2353D58E7466D852E15AD31E82E00"> <enum>(1)</enum> <header>In general</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may only enter into a mineral materials sales contract with respect to, or issue a free use permit for the disposal of mineral materials pursuant to, a qualifying project under the Act of July 31, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/601">30 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the <quote>Materials Act of 1947</quote>) if—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HECB1DCB7BA854CC9A63C4982369669E5">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the person carrying out the qualifying project—</text>
                        <clause id="H4D28F8E283EF4EA2A03D7060D04817C8">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>submits to the Secretary—</text> <subclause id="HA8B8E5F28B89478D9ABA80A51AE6DED2" commented="no"> <enum>(I)</enum> <text>a haul route impact assessment for the qualifying project—</text>
                                <item id="H0564719BBDAB4BDBA8924D465E009D76" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text>jointly developed by the person and the agency with jurisdiction over transportation of each State and political subdivision thereof within which the qualifying project will be carried out;</text>
                                </item>
                                <item id="HC2A6BDBDD0FB4EF28FFB336E6BC5AD3B" commented="no">
                                    <enum>(bb)</enum>
 <text>that concludes the qualifying project will not materially degrade the safety or level of service on highways on the haul route; and</text>
                                </item>
                                <item id="H1D3263B23D9A46AFBA76165ABF6D8557">
                                    <enum>(cc)</enum>
 <text>that, consistent with applicable laws and other standards relating to air quality and noise, identifies measures that shall be taken to minimize dust, particulate emissions, and noise impacts on land adjacent to the haul route that is used for sensitive or residential purposes;</text>
                                </item>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HFA46B852E1AC4B539EC4BCF1EECF2751" commented="no">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>a trip management plan for the qualifying project that sets limits on—</text>
                                <item id="H7E2A65616EE3469BBF3B1E988409DA98">
                                    <enum>(aa)</enum>
 <text>load staging;</text> </item> <item id="H9DB6E235924A417B81B709DDC145D2F2"> <enum>(bb)</enum> <text>hours of operation; and</text>
                                </item>
                                <item id="H1CD776D5F2C3487B9ECBCC5262C6995A">
                                    <enum>(cc)</enum>
 <text>debris controls;</text> </item> </subclause> <subclause id="H59BD89BC56304AC7BB81CE9242941443" commented="no"> <enum>(III)</enum> <text>a water use and conservation plan for the qualifying project that, consistent with applicable State and Tribal laws, ensures the projected annual consumptive use of groundwater and surface water by the qualifying project will be offset within the same basin through conservation or other feasible measures; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="H0495EEA08D0147B194A6C9AE0BADE55F" commented="no">
                                <enum>(IV)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a rail or lower-impact transportation analysis for the qualifying project that evaluates whether rail-served aggregate supply or other lower-impact modes of transportation are feasible for the majority of projected tonnage of the qualifying project; and</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HD3841DC0FEAC4E32A776514FE39B7FEE">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that, with respect to the qualifying project, the person—</text>
                            <subclause id="H3A2E75C28A6C44A8BC160FF01C1E1487" commented="no">
                                <enum>(I)</enum>
 <text>will implement each of the items submitted to the Secretary under clause (i);</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="HD39AE68C09D542CDA331CF4A52368688">
                                <enum>(II)</enum>
 <text>has coordinated in good faith with affected State, Tribal, and local governments to identify and undertake reasonable haul-route safety and maintenance measures;</text>
                            </subclause>
                            <subclause id="H1981A5131F894AD59B10328C8CC6FAEE" commented="no">
                                <enum>(III)</enum>
 <text>has acquired all necessary water rights; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H06A9EF6946E945EE9D6C97FBD8F83169"> <enum>(IV)</enum> <text>has been issued each required permit under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f et seq.</external-xref>); and</text>
                            </subclause>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H4640529DBE88495AB79C364DD351E6D8">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the Secretary determines each of the items submitted to the Secretary under subparagraph (A)(i)—</text>
                        <clause id="H17B5251AE3B2457F8E7F1FAA54228CCC" commented="no">
                            <enum>(i)</enum>
 <text>meet applicable Federal, State, Tribal, and local laws and other standards relating to transportation safety, air quality, noise, and water resources; and</text>
                        </clause>
                        <clause id="HA0E1DDB99DCF49B392B98432F180B750" commented="no">
                            <enum>(ii)</enum>
 <text>reflect any modification requested by an affected State, Tribal, or local government under paragraph (2) that is determined to be reasonable under subparagraph (B) of that paragraph.</text>
                        </clause>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H81961DEF05FD443CB148546DF3C08C37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Modification requests</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE4C4359F96DD41098EBDC1A0939E9D86"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State, Tribal, or local government that is affected by a qualifying project may submit to the Secretary a request for a modification of the qualifying project.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDE6C229C020460CB1A31DB456355964"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reasonableness determination</header><text>If a State, Tribal, or local government submits a request for a modification of a qualifying project under subparagraph (A), the Secretary and the applicable State, Tribal, or local government shall jointly select an entity to carry out an independent review of the modification to determine whether the modification is reasonable.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6F03E218A39D4D3D807BF4A8714764B4" commented="no">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Incorporation of lower-Impact transportation options in qualifying
                    projects</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the analysis submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A)(i)(IV) for a qualifying project demonstrates that lower-impact modes of transportation, including rail, are feasible for the majority of projected tonnage of the qualifying project, the Secretary shall, where practicable, take into account the incorporation of such modes into the qualifying project in entering into a mineral materials sales contract with respect to, or issuing a free use permit for the disposal of mineral materials pursuant to, the qualifying project under the Act of July 31, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/601">30 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the <quote>Materials Act of 1947</quote>).</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2DE400C649E4E76BF904B0C9E612DF2">
                <enum>(c)</enum>
                <header>Enforcement</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may require the suspension of operations under or terminate or revoke a mineral materials sales contract entered into with respect to, or a free use permit issued for the disposal of mineral materials pursuant to, a qualifying project under the Act of July 31, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/601">30 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>; commonly known as the <quote>Materials Act of 1947</quote>) if the Secretary determines, after notice and opportunity to cure, the person carrying out the qualifying project has failed to comply with a requirement of this section.</text>
            </subsection> 
<subsection id="HCDE50586B30041D090EDD24DBE964852"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header> 
<paragraph id="HAC98FA4D87CB4F788701576E5367E520"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person carrying out a qualifying project shall annually submit to the Secretary a report regarding the qualifying project, including, with respect to the preceding year—</text> <subparagraph id="H77F4E7EECA0A4409A031403C6491807A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the volume of groundwater and surface water consumed;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H18ADF385D16B40CA93BCCDFA67689C83" commented="no">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>the number of truck trips made by commercial motor vehicle; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CEC6E97FBAC48B69331D92CD33E202E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the implementation of each of the items submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A)(i).</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4FA630F197FF4C8E883DD0BF206623BC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidential business information</header><text>Each report submitted to the Secretary under paragraph (1) and information included in each such report—</text> <subparagraph id="H6F09D36B23B241F6B0B5A86FF1D0AC87" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be—</text> 
<clause id="H15FCEC7F767946D2BB11D1B2CDE5FCE5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treated as confidential business information; and</text></clause> <clause id="HE6FE05C8D7F04A33B2DB5B284059A573" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exempt from disclosure under section 552(b)(3)(B) of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Freedom of Information Act</quote>); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1B9BE647D04D45CFA18B13D83A96BDCE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as provided in paragraph (3), may not be made publicly available.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FA720530D0D480481F2F4BE73497D9B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publicly available summary</header><text>The Secretary shall annually—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA8BC4506B7884C48B16D76FF6877AD20" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>aggregate the information included in the annual reports submitted under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40FFF8D6FEEC476AA6BEE6BB3A277BA6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>publish and make publicly available a summary of such aggregated information.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H226456019FB44A0BB983DE92BE5F2C4F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning 5 years after the date of the enactment of this section and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HF8DF6FD9D9AC40E28B30C56BF6616B4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>aggregate the information included in the annual reports submitted under subsection (d); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H801871345F454C65BA0277D60D68E52D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate such aggregated information to identify any recurring effects on transportation and groundwater resources.</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA63F6496EB164A70BA36190CE8D3AFCD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary may issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section, including procedures and criteria with respect to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE3133900FDA94FF9AF30F372D0000068"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the analysis required to be submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a)(1)(A)(i)(IV); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4600C76F49F44D9DB36226689C517E9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring the consistency of qualifying projects with applicable State and local requirements.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF46DACCAD2A54DAFAC34DE3EE8E02327" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to duplicate or supersede—</text> <paragraph id="H3BF77C0AED1B45788F5FAC38129A6A75" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35A495E2845C414D9154C64F9667429F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>applicable State permitting processes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD6D86B742DAD4F5B8010E9E1294FC040"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H77EEC969829C402EBC478CC326BB4385"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Areas of critical environmental concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>areas of critical environmental concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3095BFFDC55E4E51B6B9422D71E2C1DC"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Mineral materials</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mineral materials</term> means mineral materials as the term is used in section 1 of the Act of July 31, 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/601">30 U.S.C. 601</external-xref>; commonly known as the <quote>Materials Act of 1947</quote>).</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1358A3A0C1C40A589CF8F0AF2702300"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifying project</header><text>The term <term>qualifying project</term> means a project to extract mineral materials that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB21E5C89E488453F9E41E188ACC66692" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located—</text> 
<clause id="HD984CFFE36494A5395ACB454BFBDA4A9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>within 25 miles of an urbanized area; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0C40BB8779274A598567EDD3862B500C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within or adjacent to areas of critical environmental concern, as determined by the Secretary;</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2E331E968F254D25A4F896E5F62B0C49" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is projected by the person carrying out the project or determined by the Secretary to be expected to produce more than 1 million tons of mineral materials in any 1-year period; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D0A6FC553A74618A37A071D92531564" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not begun commercial extraction of mineral materials before the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE988E217CF33498BB6167312B36FA95A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H384BC5BF68FB4631B390F7290D30D7A3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Urbanized area</header><text>The term <term>urbanized area</term> means an area designated as such by the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the United States Census Bureau.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

