<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MAZ25675-M10-WT-8DX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3316 IS: Water Authority and Timely Environmental Review Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3316</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251203">December 3, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S438">Mr. Husted</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish the Waterway Permit Section 404 Assignment program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Authority and Timely Environmental Review Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WATER Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb7ad941b6be044758cd5b3a922c32d4d"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waterway Permit Section 404 Assignment program</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54d7db6a3c6f4e0fab1ef3a51e1c8016"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb68837f6d73c44e6be2b9937a8cf2b0d"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee117bcc5c014117a6eddd3968ffd4c6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered project</header><text>The term <term>covered project</term> means a highway, railroad, or public transportation project.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf539fc8a3ef64dc6b8125aaf87444586"><enum>(3)</enum><header>FWPCA terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>navigable waters</term> and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 502 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id84355f1363a942fd80d2c9eb325d2a8b"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>program</term> means the Waterway Permit Section 404 Assignment program established under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide23c152a223d40c2864600fafa1af87d"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id36daa12b45184bf4b0cbb4e939efb6bc"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="idb76d83e11fe54722bf479e0c97965683"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Administrator shall jointly establish and carry out a program, to be known as the <quote>Waterway Permit Section 404 Assignment program</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id45c049aa535243c09d71816dc12113f0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assumption of responsibility</header><subparagraph id="idcd84ab674e7548d9beab6e0fc7157018"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the requirements of this section and notwithstanding subsections (g) through (m) of section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>), with the written agreement of the Secretary, the Administrator, and a State, which may be in the form of a memorandum of understanding, the Secretary may assign, and the State may assume, the responsibilities of the Secretary under that section with respect to the permitting of 1 or more covered projects in the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideeb4e872429e4c40be6bf4e4a98be37d"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional responsibility</header><text>If a State assumes responsibility under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="ide3e2ae767a7f4b388cb7dd3ba1e56ff1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary may assign to the State, and the State may assume, all or part of the responsibilities of the Secretary for the permitting of discharge of dredged or fill material into the navigable waters, including environmental reviews under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>), consultation requirements under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), requirements under division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code, or any other action required under any Federal environmental law relating to review under section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) or approval of a covered project; and</text></clause><clause id="id451195366c6d4341987bd1187462d2fc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (C), the Secretary may assign to the State, and the State may assume, all or part of the responsibilities of the Secretary under section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1899 (commonly known as the <quote>Rivers and Harbors Act of 1899</quote>) (30 Stat. 1151, chapter 425; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/403">33 U.S.C. 403</external-xref>), for the permitting of the construction of any structure in or over any navigable water of the United States, the excavating from or depositing of material in such waters, or the accomplishment of any other work affecting the course, location, condition, or capacity of such waters.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfe246e8fcda74620bba0917876803c24"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitations with respect to rivers and harbors act of 1899</header><text>The assignment of responsibilities under subparagraph (B)(ii) shall be limited to the program and is effective only as it is necessary to allow for the permitting of a covered project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id179267fdcb8947cea59b3840862a8c1b"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Procedural and substantive requirements</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida434f12c258649f7abbbed9655aba9eb"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this section—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id83f5f53cfdf6422b91fd4126db5b254c"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State shall assume responsibility under this section subject to the same procedural and substantive requirements as would apply if that responsibility were carried out by the Secretary; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3b51bc678f6d431b959f3cb6cbf2b450"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State shall ensure compliance with those requirements.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb74148ae3b2a4d23adac9b0ba9a126a8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No regulations required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section requires a State participating in the program to promulgate regulations to carry out the program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbb9a8baaf98249d9a032322e478885aa"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Federal responsibility</header><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8340e8b078ad4828ac9642a999f6a080"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any responsibility of the Secretary under section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) or section 10 of the Act of March 3, 1899 (commonly known as the <quote>Rivers and Harbors Act of 1899</quote>) (30 Stat. 1151, chapter 425; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/403">33 U.S.C. 403</external-xref>), not explicitly assumed by a State by written agreement under this section shall remain the responsibility of the Secretary.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9dbc60df30c4b0283b0e0ef3c8706a3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section requires the Secretary to assign to a State, or that State to accept, any of the enforcement authority of the Secretary under section 404(s) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(s)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id89a9557d5e40436d9295c98918197d89"><enum>(F)</enum><header>No effect on authority</header><text>Nothing in this section preempts or interferes with any power, jurisdiction, responsibility, or authority of a Federal agency, other than the Environmental Protection Agency and the Corps of Engineers, under applicable law (including regulations) with respect to a covered project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id60d2368513ee455baec83e309939bc14"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Preservation of flexibility</header><text>The Secretary may not require a State, as a condition of participation in the program, to forego project delivery methods that are otherwise permissible for covered projects.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id07c9fba605724209ad1fac64d77a41ba"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Legal fees</header><text>A State assuming the responsibilities of the Secretary under the program for a specific covered project may use funds apportioned to the State under section 104(b)(2) of title 23, United States Code, for attorneys' fees directly attributable to eligible activities associated with the covered project, including the payment of fees awarded under section 2412 of title 28, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id93910ebb698a43a69fa7066e0c3f9146"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State Participation</header><paragraph id="id15571ee41b2042afb1a1be8c146041c1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Participating States</header><text>All States are eligible to participate in the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0f9ab23868c845628b8673ede699e91d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary may promulgate or amend, as appropriate, regulations or issue guidance that establishes requirements relating to information required to be contained in any application of a State to participate in the program, including, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="id0ccc5ac7045742608cecb4c961963e8f"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the covered projects or classes of covered projects for which the State anticipates exercising the authority that may be granted under the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id873cc87a5c1c487e9fe6fa8a9a0e3e4f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a demonstration of the ability of the State to assure consistency with guidelines established under section 404(b)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1344">33 U.S.C. 1344(b)(1)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida398d1d20dd6454fabd56a6a237458af"><enum>(C)</enum><text>verification of the financial resources necessary to carry out the authority that may be granted under the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id92e356032f13483f9116beaf016fee06"><enum>(D)</enum><text>evidence of the notice and solicitation of public comment by the State relating to participation of the State in the program, including copies of comments received from that solicitation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f3294fee26044419fbcd4f9dc6d1a53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public notice</header><subparagraph id="ide65756ba19de4539a8c2ab76d3c9a0e7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days before the date on which a State submits an application under this subsection, the State shall give notice of the intent of the State to participate in the program, in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4515a95e9ba54368bb5b3533e7ca58e4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Method of notice and solicitation</header><text>The State shall provide notice and solicit public comment under subparagraph (A) by publishing the complete application of the State in accordance with the appropriate public notice law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idf90735fae0f84b88b2e69ab37e932c05"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>The Secretary may approve the application of a State under this subsection only if—</text><subparagraph id="id7f1d32a5d4a44f72a82c0cdc61bd1ca0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the requirements under paragraph (2) have been met;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3bf9236311c84d2fa1288112efff8ae8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the State has the capability, including financial and personnel, to assume responsibility under the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddcf892c8af8e412cb3a9de50527854e8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the head of the State agency having primary jurisdiction over highway matters enters into a written agreement described in subsection (d) with the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddcdc98c292dc40b3a6434f7b1ad2e2dd"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other Federal agency views</header><text>If a State applies to assume a responsibility of the Secretary that would have required the Secretary to consult with another Federal agency, the Secretary shall solicit the views of the Federal agency before approving the application.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd7fce2a6106545a3952f36df06e3c51d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Written Agreement</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd809a6f0783742dfba67be679afd931a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A written agreement under this section shall—</text><subparagraph id="id9918ccb491cf4a86a33bd78914784a59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be executed by the Governor or the top-ranking transportation official in the State who is charged with responsibility for transportation infrastructure operation, maintenance, and construction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1c15aed387fc42a09fe3b03d4edd6514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be in such form as the Secretary may prescribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1f0feb81d8304899b6c804f11594d7a3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide that the State—</text><clause id="id34b9432786be4f35a8a431ddbc78db96"><enum>(i)</enum><text>agrees to assume all or part of the responsibilities of the Secretary described in subsection (b)(2);</text></clause><clause id="id2d97dd3637e846a7bb82b90733f0d9fb"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expressly consents, on behalf of the State, to accept the jurisdiction of the Federal courts for the compliance, discharge, and enforcement of any responsibility of the Secretary assumed by the State;</text></clause><clause id="id8c5d5ddf5ad1452a929aea75f7f24d11"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>certifies that State laws are in effect that—</text><subclause id="idf8f651fa191942f0b697749a2dd7f82d"><enum>(I)</enum><text>authorize the State to take the actions necessary to carry out the responsibilities being assumed; and</text></subclause><subclause id="idcda8e11114c1437e87f1e754736268b6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are comparable to section 552 of title 5, United States Code, including providing that any decision relating to the public availability of a document under those State laws is reviewable by a court of competent jurisdiction; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="id71b2a0eb6b674390b542ac895e5fe8b7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>agrees to maintain the financial resources necessary to carry out the responsibilities being assumed;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbc9e2a6e93d54c7ea45f6fac0341a985"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require the State to provide to the Secretary any information the Secretary reasonably considers necessary to ensure that the State is adequately carrying out the responsibilities assigned to the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf229d1467c414d42ad3a3180ded689a4"><enum>(E)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id3cb33655895b449485536c013d30f032"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have a term of not more than 5 years; or</text></clause><clause indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64b688ee6216496390816b26afe68c03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a State that has participated in a program under section 326 or 327 of title 23, United States Code, for a period of not less than 10 years, have a term of 10 years; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1b698b15ecfb469c89ad3d4e5a9c5547"><enum>(F)</enum><text>be renewable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idc1ad0a4020f446839dfb3b5e583418f7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No additional requirements</header><text>The Secretary may not include any additional requirements in a written agreement under this section other than the requirements described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idabde811d8e2f431b88138867cc5e3bc8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><paragraph id="id243089d764a54037ae8270ae99a65291"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The district courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction over any civil action against a State for failure to carry out any responsibility of the State under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc25c63f11c20482ebde6b16e15487c8d"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Legal standards and requirements</header><text>A civil action described in paragraph (1) shall be governed by the legal standards and requirements that would apply in such a civil action against the Secretary had the Secretary taken the actions in question.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id761a0e1491604dbfbb2b6086fa974da3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Intervention</header><text>The Secretary shall have the right to intervene in any civil action described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd92e952cbdac41089a3b57f566610794"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect of Assumption of Responsibility</header><text>A State that assumes responsibility under subsection (b)(2) shall be solely responsible and solely liable for carrying out, in lieu of and without further approval of the Secretary, the responsibilities assumed under that subsection, until the program is terminated under subsection (k).</text></subsection><subsection id="idd7103dc8b5f1403684ff74ce7f2abe39"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitations on Agreements</header><text>Nothing in this section permits a State to assume any rulemaking authority of the Secretary under any Federal law.</text></subsection><subsection id="idd73dad3dda5e4752b300d28c44a66122"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Audits</header><paragraph id="idf89a38edf7754350960c3283cead47a0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure compliance by a State with any agreement of the State under subsection (d) (including compliance by the State with all Federal laws for which responsibility is assumed under subsection (b)(2)), for each State participating in the program under this section, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="idf006f58366cd48b6bc601d12115d067e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of execution of the agreement, meet with the State to review implementation of the agreement and discuss plans for the first annual audit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id30313658e71f4bdb89d50b4df85fd9b9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conduct not more than 2 audits during the first 4 years that the State is participating in the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb61484a1bca449ae940f9bfa768d2796"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of an agreement period of greater than 5 years pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(E)(ii), conduct an audit covering the first 5 years of the agreement period and a second audit covering the final 5 years of the agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5aa8dfbe7bfb4c72bccc6ebd876e1c2c"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that the time period for completing an audit, from initiation to completion (including public comment and responses to those comments), does not exceed 180 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id44fe6954ea5b4b998c4a937c7b6ca9a2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability and comment</header><subparagraph id="id66f2cc12939442f3adfd60a0916c874e"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An audit conducted under paragraph (1) shall be provided to the public for comment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf1f539a1bffb41d9872c2b38c220c6ae"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Response</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the period for public comment described in subparagraph (A) ends, the Secretary shall respond to public comments received under that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e5c4b50dc3d4bab9bc7f89ec7db241e"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Audit team</header><subparagraph id="id6cc141e6875a465aad7d669af46f5542"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An audit conducted under paragraph (1) shall be carried out by an audit team determined by the Secretary, in consultation with the State, in accordance with subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6db528bef4a348e6bfd3d4e2914201f2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>Consultation with the State under subparagraph (A) shall include a reasonable opportunity for the State to review and provide comments on the proposed members of the audit team.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="ide6c5fdb9620145f09a492479f84e8ac3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>After the fourth year of the participation of a State in the program, the Secretary shall monitor compliance by the State with the written agreement, including the provision by the State of financial resources to carry out the written agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="idc5dff6e690f54348bc20f749537607b4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report that describes the administration of the program.</text></subsection><subsection id="ida43a50da7bc24f7d942eca431927b07e"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="id97389f4197734ec6bfe8cc70e151b968"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary may terminate the participation of any State in the program if—</text><subparagraph id="id7b08eefc3ddd421db35342a1dbb66a85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that the State is not adequately carrying out the responsibilities assigned to the State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ideb1e641d275f4a6a96459452b2907469"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary provides to the State—</text><clause id="id24d93cd85cbf4c2196196777e39c79b1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a notification of the determination of noncompliance;</text></clause><clause id="id1d379470e1ef48dcaae1d262bb05ae98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a period of not less than 120 days to take such corrective action as the Secretary determines to be necessary to comply with the applicable agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="id80444078794243d694afb4ff99a4eabc"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on request of the Governor of the State, a detailed description of each responsibility in need of corrective action regarding an inadequacy identified under subparagraph (A); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1ce17f1514f4b8bb9b8316c12684290"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the State, after the notification and period provided under subparagraph (B), fails to take satisfactory corrective action, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idb7d69e13443048928d67052c703eb066"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination by the State</header><text>The State may terminate the participation of the State in the program at any time by providing to the Secretary a notice by not later than the date that is 90 days before the date of termination, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may provide.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7cdf2d09f7f34d85910c9cff050613ff"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Capacity Building</header><text>The Secretary, in cooperation with representatives of State officials, may carry out education, training, peer-exchange, and other initiatives, as appropriate—</text><paragraph id="id22037404b1da4474bf7d765cee4f81b7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to assist States in developing the capacity to participate in the program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3e1a4402e0f946e28ba894224324895c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote information sharing and collaboration among States that are participating in the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2ad241b779be45f28f8c9fad1a83aef5"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Relationship to Locally Administered Projects</header><text>A State granted authority under this section may, in its sole discretion on the request of a unit of local government in the State—</text><paragraph id="id442d30eaf89a45c4b763719fba0849a6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exercise such authority on behalf of the unit of local government for a locally administered project; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id693643082ed840d3884587a66305fe9b"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide guidance and training on consolidating and minimizing the documentation and environmental analyses necessary for sponsors of a locally administered project to comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and any comparable requirements under State law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id856e3146feed465b9010e9dc1d2f8025"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Agency Deemed To Be Federal Agency</header><text>A State agency that is assigned a responsibility under an agreement under this section shall be deemed to be an agency for the purposes of section 2412 of title 28, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

