<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA9E9B937AA5F4808AD33BDC33B087F0C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8656 IH: Ballistic Armor Made in America Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8656</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001101">Mr. Harrigan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001325">Mrs. Biggs of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Department of Justice to procure ballistic-resistant body armor manufactured using domestic ballistic fibers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7B09F8FA51D64039925EE4C0FCA82602" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2154B87AEE044DC58F8180A7ED52AAC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ballistic Armor Made in America Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HB0B5908964F04F85A0FE291F57345AAD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rules related to procurement of ballistic-resistant body armor</header> 
<subsection id="H7F3483164A1C4670AEFEFB3D3A40471C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required disclosure of source of materials</header> 
<paragraph id="HDDAB17469F97418F844DC662096E20D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institute of Justice shall require any entity, including a company or manufacturer, that submits or has submitted ballistic-resistant body armor to the National Institute of Justice’s Compliance Testing Program to disclose each country where such armor is manufactured and where ballistic fibers contained in such armor are grown, reprocessed, reused, recycled, or produced.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C0E1B4EA3754DEFB7E62A588ECE76E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institute of Justice shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBE308FEB01804F4EAE5C36A0ED7FC207"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">add as a part of the information listed for each ballistic-resistant body armor model on the compliant products list, including any ballistic-resistant armor model on the compliant product list prior to the date of the enactment of this Act, each disclosure required under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCADF4DC32D3748818C786E83D07A59FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update, as soon as reasonably possible and in not more than 30 days, the compliant products list each time ballistic-resistant body armor model has been certified by the National Institute of Justice as meeting the latest standard for such armor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FE9912BDF9F4B48A8E4FB11BA36B81E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Made in America</header><text>No product listed on the compliant products list that discloses ballistic fibers grown, reprocessed, reused, recycled, or produced outside of the United States of America may use any markings, symbols or other language related to the designation of <quote>Made in America</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C66DACA1FE14AF0A5CDF332471DB4CE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Emerging technologies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Justice shall determine if the requirements under paragraphs (1) through (3) shall apply to any advanced materials used to replace ballistic fibers in the manufacturing of ballistic-resistant body armor.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC09EA6396A81421ABC77EBE3BF16A388"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on procurement from outside of the united states</header> 
<paragraph id="H15524E26EDF147B4A035C9054CFC5ED5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/31">Chapter 31</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/509B">section 509B</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H2CBBEF24FE854BF180B13D15D215D10C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H4CF7C83B496B458F93A358715829EFA7"><enum>509C.</enum><header>Domestic Sourcing Requirement for Department Procurements</header> <subsection id="H223CBDA304C24D5E98969F0A240F5D15"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Attorney General may not use funds appropriated or otherwise available to the Department of Justice for the procurement of ballistic-resistant body armor if such armor is manufactured from or contains ballistic fibers that are grown, reprocessed, reused, recycled, or produced outside of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H51655DA031404BCB8FFAD85DA214919A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply if the Attorney General determines that ballistic-resistant body armor manufactured from or containing ballistic fibers that are grown, reprocessed, reused, recycled, or produced in the United States cannot be procured as and when needed at United States market prices or if the ballistic fibers have been found to be in compliance with the section 4862 of title 10, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Berry Amendment</quote>) and section 604 of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/453b">6 U.S.C. 453b</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Kissel Amendment</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H501C14D1A39E44DFBD2069F2344B6530"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H266179C7A0A14F5183D314D55F86E659"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ballistic-resistant body armor</header><text>The term <term>ballistic-resistant body armor</term> means an item of personal protective equipment, consisting of hard armor or soft armor, that is intended to protect the wearer from threats, including ballistic threats, stabbing, fragmentation, and blunt impact.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A00530D232A41A397248E46ECA97732"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hard armor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>hard armor</term> means an item of personal protective equipment that is constructed of rigid materials and is used in the composition of ballistic-resistant body armor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EA270120DF8423088F798F54FA4EDF9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Soft armor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>soft armor</term> means an item of personal protective equipment constructed of pliable or flexible materials and is used in the composition of ballistic-resistant body armor.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF50B3A709D74428B61D5BF93FB4949A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/509B">section 509B</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H0BFF4E5F14F1449CB731CA07FE6BDCC3" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">509C. Domestic Sourcing Requirement for Department Procurements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HACA70C6D20504D1CB905B4B385ECEFCD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Know before you buy training</header><text>The Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers shall provide an educational training program for any State or local governmental entity that has applied for or has received a grant from the Department of Justice to purchase ballistic-resistant body armor regarding the disclosure requirement under subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H03756E2010D24DB89662D3BAF5ABE10F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCD0C1D52F66F4A2E975955130A0AB776"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Ballistic-resistant body armor</header><text>The term <term>ballistic-resistant body armor</term> means an item of personal protective equipment, consisting of hard armor or soft armor, that is intended to protect the wearer from threats, including ballistic threats, stabbing, fragmentation, and blunt impact.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7741408BC84426AB3D446FE61B7573D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliant products list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compliant products list</term>means the official list of ballistic-resistant body armor that have been certified by the National Institute of Justice and is published as the <quote>Compliant Products List: Ballistic Resistant Armor</quote> (or a subsequent list) on the internet website of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A030AEE76994E1897472D658C42442F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hard armor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>hard armor</term> means an item of personal protective equipment that is constructed of rigid materials and is used in the composition of ballistic-resistant body armor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H54F56A38E5D641BBBCA75E41FA4F6DCB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Soft armor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>soft armor</term> means an item of personal protective equipment constructed of pliable or flexible materials and is used in the composition of ballistic-resistant body armor.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

