<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEB11B8409E4B4C00939AF6603333C7BD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7187 IH: Clarity for Compensation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7187</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000193">Mr. Nunn of Iowa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide an exemption
            from the definition of a broker for a certain registered representative-owned personal
 services entity, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEC0E900BAAA144318CDD8C8CC09AC53B" style="OLC"><section id="H30187C8B6B264E8DBDFA6ADE3E29FCFB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clarity for Compensation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF92C4647EB4543BAAFB3E4C4BCDCAE55"><enum>2.</enum><header>Broker definition exception for registered representative-owned personal services entity</header><subsection id="H92A495B7C7E04973BC7506B2779326F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3(a)(4) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H77D06584A44249469D75F35623C53810" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H1B30C4E377B24831AEE0F3D8A28CA951"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Exception for registered representative-owned personal services entity</header><clause id="HE9146DCE9E774F44BB5DD0DFBC007248"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A personal services entity shall not be considered a broker solely by reason of receiving compensation on behalf of a registered representative from that representative’s broker at the direction of such representative, if—</text><subclause id="H1CE039F5A9584285AF56ACB1F052F14D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the broker instructs or otherwise approves the amount and timing of the payment and maintains records regarding the payment made;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD8747B241CE14D37949B8A907400719A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the personal services entity does not hold itself out as a broker;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA21C73D00B11454D8D56A190B3F5D7BF"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the personal services entity does not engage in broker or dealer activity, other than the receipt of compensation on behalf of the registered representative;</text></subclause><subclause id="HAD1582F3E0724B81BFE12106F8D3D313"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the broker maintains adequate supervision and control over the registered representative;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA96C63D063834C6882682AE1CAE59282"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the broker and the personal services entity have a written agreement governing their relationship and the responsibilities of each party regarding compensation arrangements;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF3141B2AAC374093973AD27CA06193E0"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the personal services entity is only owned by—</text><item id="H4C02AAFD5C534BA78AE8CEB90186A9DB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the registered representative;</text></item><item id="H45CCE25AF35547AF98E1318EE223BB0A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>if the registered representative is an individual, immediate family members of the registered representative; or</text></item><item id="HF2151D52C0B84C20A8888E01036A59D5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entities wholly owned by—</text><subitem id="H22E519F816734A79AE0B8C2D41A32A53"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the registered representative; or</text></subitem><subitem id="H8406CD3C8D224D4EA2DBBCBE6C89519A"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>if the registered representative is an individual, immediate family members of the registered representative; and</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H18F53A239A5A4A1BB911B3222F5307DE"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the personal services entity meets such other requirements as the Commission may prescribe, by rule.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H886059981D254985AD527588CCB4A0BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Oversight and examination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to ensure that a personal services entity that is not considered a broker by reason of this subparagraph continues to meet the requirements to not be considered a broker by reason of this subparagraph, the personal services entity shall maintain, and make available upon request to the Commission and the applicable self-regulatory organization, all books and records that both—</text><subclause id="HEAFCE453B9E5445991DC3313EB2F8D2F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the broker from which the personal services entity receives compensation is required to maintain and make available to the Commission and the applicable self-regulatory organization; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9117611A37EF4180BC140DF9F4AEB889"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission determines necessary and appropriate to demonstrate that the personal services entity continues to meet the requirements to not be considered a broker by reason of this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H16DC28E2ECD649D1AD77417B860AFFE7"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph:</text><subclause id="H49074340586B4AD88BA10D0867ACAA11"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Applicable self-regulatory organization</header><text>With respect to a personal services entity or a registered representative of a broker, the term <term>applicable self-regulatory organization</term> means each self-regulatory organization with which the related broker is required to be registered.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1C1B79D8EEA44C96B9548F0EBA5173C3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Broker or dealer activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>broker or dealer activity</term> means an activity undertaken by a broker or a dealer who is registered, or required to be registered, under this Act.</text></subclause><subclause id="H933830B72EC64238B96F2828E2A09346"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual, the term <term>immediate family member</term> means a spouse, child, parent, brother, sister, grandparent, grandchild, stepparent, stepchild, stepbrother, or stepsister of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="HCCA4629DC4664B19B22DC59E5D988B1D"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Personal services entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>personal services entity</term> means an entity that is established by a registered representative to receive compensation for the services of the registered representative and for administrative purposes and other benefits.</text></subclause><subclause id="H23F824D7B91B48DAB1CDB5BE047004A2"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Registered representative</header><text>With respect to a broker, the term <term>registered representative</term> means a person who is—</text><item id="H17C4C61763D740E998D964CD0D996EDA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an <quote>associated person of a broker or dealer</quote> with respect to the broker; and</text></item><item id="H446141A09B7E43B6B732CE256C5B0A92"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>registered with the applicable self-regulatory organization.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB82A824E086B42F78F068CFE810F6D56"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 3(a)(4)(G) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

