<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCED4FD961E534351BA6FB8FAA5A8C692" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 5904 IH: To amend the One Big Beautiful Bill Act to provide an exception to the parole fee for the parole of an alien for a sacred Tribal or religious ceremony, cultural exchange, or celebration, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251104">November 4, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs of Arizona</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001133">Mr. Ciscomani</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the One Big Beautiful Bill Act to provide an exception to the parole fee for the parole of an alien for a sacred Tribal or religious ceremony, cultural exchange, or celebration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7815D820A8694BB8959132869A3E0989" style="OLC"><section id="H7B693BDCF8ED4BB9AC439156DCA2677A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Parole of an alien for a sacred Tribal or religious ceremony, cultural exchange, or celebration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of Section 100004 of Public Law No. 119–21 is amended—</text><paragraph id="HED55376C33104A5590F103B5E384D867"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4EB978F9E604FCA9A80BE0A30915F4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39D5D642FE994D2089A32488497AFEB3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF3A5CB3EB28F41A897F13C6D642CE489" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H189D8ABB495F4D4086960B2AF9DE62DF"><enum>(11)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD07FC498A045474181ECDC25CF0C352B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that a significant public benefit will result from the parole of an alien for a sacred Tribal or religious ceremony, cultural exchange, or celebration, and—</text><clause id="HC62A56755584443D87B24EEB7E97000E" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary conducts a preliminary criminal background check of the alien prior to the alien’s arrival at a port of entry;</text></clause><clause id="H753BB66AB5A14970803D4BAD74FBCBB8" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the alien presents a written request to the Secretary to be paroled into the United States from a federally recognized Indian Tribe for which the United States holds land in trust at or near the Southwest border; </text></clause><clause id="HD4F629AEEDC04447A83F0F7F4FB28360" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the alien is enrolled in a cultural participant program operated by a federally recognized Indian Tribe for which the United States holds land in trust at or near the Southwest border; and </text></clause><clause id="HA4C677C50598429EB31016CC1A1C6BF5" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the alien pays a fee, in lieu of the fee required under subsection (c), in the amount of $200.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

