<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-EDW26147-JPN-46-LNW"><form><distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3965</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260303">March 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S317">Mr. Barrasso</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S428">Ms. Alsobrooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S330">Mr. Bennet</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S385">Ms. Cortez Masto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S375">Mr. Daines</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S418">Mr. Fetterman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S311">Ms. Klobuchar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S410">Ms. Lummis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S347">Mr. Moran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S414">Mr. Ossoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S353">Mr. Schatz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S394">Ms. Smith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEV00">Committee on Environment and Public Works</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the establishment and use of short form applications for rural communities applying for economic development grant programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>EDA Short Form Application Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id90978D642D8F4651BFAC29A10AB9ED33"><enum>2.</enum><header>Short form applications for rural communities in economic development programs</header><subsection id="idCAFEB80EB7CF49419B2555B00C1AE183"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4296e48f972743628ad7b774b1a87ea2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4c9764412e14581baac55f789f68418"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rural community</header><text>The term <term>rural community</term> means an incorporated municipality, Tribal area, or territory—</text><subparagraph id="id57fcc7c448774c2aabe50e580da843d3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with a population of not more than 10,000 individuals, as determined by the Bureau of the Census in the most recent decennial census; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idb180bb4fc4dc4b4eafcff5bcddc8c29a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that, as determined by the Assistant Secretary, is not located in a metropolitan statistical area, as designated by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8DB72F1AF477402DB5C38F4602E94276"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Short form applications</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Assistant Secretary shall establish a short form application for rural communities that may be used by applicants in rural communities for any grant program administered by the Economic Development Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="id36D64F1C027C4C91AFAB0EA5EFB4E7FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rural stakeholder input</header><text>In establishing a short form application under subsection (b), the Assistant Secretary shall solicit input from a representative group of stakeholders in rural communities on ways to improve the application process for grants from the Economic Development Administration, including—</text><paragraph id="id6159d61082a9469c9628e81dc0a07546"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the length of the applications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf571e8dcd5734a6c874bebccd3a051dc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the information and documentation required or requested to be submitted as part of the applications;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0f07ec7bce754db6ab09d29e3dd33aaa"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the possibility of standardizing base materials, such as budget templates, forms, and required attachments, across grant programs administered by the Economic Development Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idaa70dbe77df94b518df48c21cb03062e"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the possibility of reducing repetitive sections of the applications that ask for information already provided to the Federal Government, such as information provided through SAM.gov, the Bureau of the Census, or a comprehensive economic development strategy (as defined in section 3 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (42 U.S.C. 3122));</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id119d4975f5c5454ea904e220bec32765"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the degree of applicability to rural communities of questions in the applications and information and documentation described in paragraph (2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id875f2aebe6ff4d7ebcbd569a6075687a"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other considerations the Assistant Secretary determines to be necessary for the establishment of the short form application.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77498bbb7cfa4543b179849f3ef33c27">
                <enum>(d)</enum>
                <header>Transparency</header>
                <text>In carrying out this section, the Assistant Secretary shall make publicly
                    available—</text>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb0dd9fa5c18a4cdbbc03c506fffdfc93">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <text>sample successful applications, with personal and sensitive information
                        redacted;</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idee1cff02f0aa43528389cd4df960f140">
                    <enum>(2)</enum>
                    <text>criteria decision guides that explain how applications are reviewed and
                        rated; and</text>
                </paragraph>
                <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16f84f3714874219800e7d3caf447e33">
                    <enum>(3)</enum>
                    <text>standardized guidance for rural communities to use in applying for grants
                        from the Economic Development Administration.</text>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection></section></legis-body></bill>
