<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDBB70A6C076C460987CC7F74AAC56854" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7294 IH: AI for Secure Networks Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7294</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260130">January 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001226">Mr. Menendez</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001227">Ms. McClellan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To study the impacts of artificial intelligence technology with respect to the security of telecommunications networks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8359C521657F433C87786EB9D94543E7" style="OLC"><section id="HBBC8B1B6A2864B90B878E892EC5CE56C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>AI for Secure Networks Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8EEADF5F1AFC498A890C7DA82CB20EE5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Artificial intelligence technology and the security of telecommunications networks</header><subsection id="H311DE3DD792C45B7B6F0141FAFAE6FC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct a study on the impacts of artificial intelligence technology with respect to the security of telecommunications networks, which shall include an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="H83288F3EB05541EBA7C9FC7D4946B120"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how artificial intelligence technology may be used to improve telecommunications networks, including by facilitating—</text><subparagraph id="H30BE897C0E6E4FB78D7CCCDDB56864C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>real-time threat and malware detection and zero trust security solutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H661B1F3206CC44CFAE54A956F2A4FAC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increased resiliency and interoperability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12C5647310CA4F559D3FCB2428E30A69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improved energy efficiency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58EC62AF75144505B53794075F93DFF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">integrated sensing and communications;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA53DD5037B5D40D3A54EBA11E0FCB94E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how artificial intelligence technology may be used in connection with Open Radio Access Network technology to increase the security of telecommunications networks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14E40E0F539B4F009486F8582788E121"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how artificial intelligence technology may be used in connection with virtualized security technology to increase the security of telecommunications networks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F33AEE110C24073ABF7F2E246034A14"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how artificial intelligence technology may be used to improve network security controls through firewalls and network segmentation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H268E966CFEDD4AD19B4C5FC8A0794697"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any risks artificial intelligence technology poses for the security of telecommunications networks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H991F1F30F73E4FA7B06512182400BAE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the study conducted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the Federal Communications Commission and industry stakeholders with respect to the use of artificial intelligence technology to improve the security of telecommunications networks, including with respect to research and development activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8AC50DB2F1F0480C9958313E2BD065A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HE3987FBF7F3D480FBE8ADB8E49715908"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a), which may include legislative recommendations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C8F5D1BE21C4D83B75DB8FB8CB670BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Opportunity for public comment</header><text>Prior to the submission of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for public comment with respect to such report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H309CB7F4D3EC4D14BC44526C3472A0B6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Secretary defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

