<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H051E750313E546B684AAA97B3E2192F3">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8624 IH: Workforce Apprenticeship Growth and Education Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8624</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20260430">April 30, 2026</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001224">Mr. Moran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit against employer payroll taxes for wages and other expenses paid or incurred for apprenticeship programs.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H86F1A271684B4FF7BA0A1A62C7A0709C">
<section id="H7C831072D8894C708717269D9811562C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Workforce Apprenticeship Growth and Education Support Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WAGES Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30F9AC357EA7402DB26F3C959BC486A5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H825668F62AD2468FB29AB9719A93D1EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Apprenticeships strengthen the American economy by addressing persistent workforce shortages, particularly in high-demand and essential industries, including construction, advanced manufacturing, health care, early childhood education and care, information technology, transportation and logistics, automotive repair and maintenance, hospitality, energy, agriculture, and the skilled trades.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC221FE68B7C4C47B66CF173A6C20F5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A skilled and resilient workforce is essential to maintaining the economic competitiveness of the United States in an increasingly competitive global economy, particularly as other nations expand investments in workforce training, technical education, and industrial capacity.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H01FC05742B004140836ED39D85552DF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Registered apprenticeship programs are a proven workforce development model that combines paid on-the-job learning with related instruction, enabling workers to earn wages while gaining industry-recognized credentials and skills aligned with employer needs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7317BD283E9940BEA22F213DDCA968BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Employers that invest in registered apprenticeship programs benefit from improved productivity, reduced turnover, and a more skilled workforce, but often face costs associated with program development, training, supervision, and related instruction that may limit broader adoption.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB1A523AD83CF40788428C207B5463AE2"> <enum>(5)</enum> <text>The Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>) and regulations issued thereunder establish a rigorous framework for registered apprenticeship programs, ensuring high-quality training standards, worker protections, and nationally recognized credentials.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H853A17FCE5014803BEF70FABEDB075C5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Expanding employer participation in registered apprenticeship programs is critical to promoting upward economic mobility, including for individuals without a four-year college degree, by providing pathways to higher earnings and stable, well-paying careers.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H3BB353387AE34B37B74DA5C3B44F6014"><enum>3.</enum><header>Apprenticeship credit</header>
<subsection id="HDBA2F30ABA5A45C1840E7999AB7FB6EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter D of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB2935339EF504B11B74A449D3FFA8635"> <section id="HC8F50BB34CEE493FA5126340167295CB"><enum>3135.</enum><header>Apprenticeship credit</header> <subsection id="H99D02728453C4B8992F0E060F84382F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an eligible employer, there shall be allowed as a credit against applicable employment taxes for each calendar quarter an amount equal to 50 percent of the sum of—</text>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B90E3153A8A4AF5B2704135C05BC474"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the qualified wages with respect to each qualified apprentice of such employer for such calendar quarter, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H638BB2EE50B54C059B7626E0E6CEED74"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the registered apprenticeship program expenses paid or incurred by the employer during the calendar quarter.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8C94D650CF7242129596239E63DD3E3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations and refundability</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FE8F8064FB14103944062A632474A52"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Wages taken into account</header><text>The amount of qualified wages with respect to any qualified apprentice which may be taken into account under subsection (a) by the eligible employer for any calendar quarter shall not exceed $5,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H165A66C3091C4B78AC384F359D455785"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship program expenses taken into account</header><text>The amount of registered apprenticeship program expenses taken into account by the eligible employer with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the greater of—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H496624F2829841559F5FBD7AB8A383E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000, or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFE832F7DB904D53BDEE53CD79B5D260"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the lesser of—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B985AF550A940AF8ED6FB8E005459D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,500 for each qualified apprentice which is an employee of the eligible employer during such calendar quarter, or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5044C2BC40C4C7DAF11BDEC95E7368D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>$50,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2FFC90457231417E957C277C369988CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Credit limited to employment taxes</header><text>The credit allowed by subsection (a) with respect to any calendar quarter shall not exceed the applicable employment taxes (reduced by any credits allowed under section 3111) on the wages paid with respect to the employment of all the employees of the eligible employer for such calendar quarter.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BBF0A5B298D4ADBB3048D53FA977280"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Refundability of excess credit</header><text>If the amount of the credit under subsection (a) exceeds the limitation of paragraph (3) for any calendar quarter, such excess shall be treated as an overpayment that shall be refunded under sections 6402(a) and 6413(b).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H01DAF6A8B9F949FAAE2D519B4294A553"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="HD2FE63F375EC4ABCA23E067613BEBBAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable employment taxes</header><text>The term <term>applicable employment taxes</term> means the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H82B4565C29B44862BAF63FE153300C5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The taxes imposed under section 3111(b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7843AEFED57B4191BB4D69986688B161"><enum>(B)</enum><text>So much of the taxes imposed under section 3221(a) as are attributable to the rate in effect under section 3111(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5C53F54BD537440D92465234D6513A0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible employer</header><text>The term <term>eligible employer</term> means any employer which, during the calendar quarter—</text> <subparagraph id="H217261A428804710AFB996F3DE304BA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>either—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H697E0FE819FA445F82965C2DD5CF72FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintains a registered apprenticeship program, or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H11B5755989364A8C816F64681FCC4F6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has entered into a written agreement (including a collective bargaining agreement) under which the employer agrees to adhere to the apprenticeship standards formulated and registered by a registered apprenticeship program sponsor with respect to qualified apprentices participating in the registered apprenticeship program of such sponsor, and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9CC11B4686884CDAA3FB35C8F3D1709A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employs a qualified apprentice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E4BB3DD5B764B698114B2F1C1EE049D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified wages</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ED2878600AC4E03AE5640C4D578438D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified wages</term> means, with respect to any qualified apprentice, wages paid for service rendered while such qualified apprentice is participating in a registered apprenticeship program.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5FDCF374EA44401382FABA358FBACED4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Such term shall not include any wages paid for service rendered after the date that is 2 years after the date the qualified apprentice begins participation in a registered apprenticeship program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B0BDA6953234F04B1638B67673F0026"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wages</header> <subparagraph id="HDB58A090B78444C782B733A9E437209E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>wages</term> means wages (as defined in section 3121(a)) and compensation (as defined in section 3231(e)).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H75567A35C2AB4E6FBDE8D1FBF6D19A34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allowance for certain health plan expenses</header>
<clause id="HF80889BF9FA84B44B97BF03CC8AE6A70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Such term shall include amounts paid by the eligible employer to provide and maintain a group health plan (as defined in section 5000(b)(1)), but only to the extent that such amounts are excluded from the gross income of employees by reason of section 106(a).</text></clause> <clause id="H00D46ABFE75A4CF6BEA8AB9B13261BAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Allocation rules</header><text>For purposes of this section, amounts treated as wages under clause (i) shall be treated as paid with respect to any employee (and with respect to any period) to the extent that such amounts are properly allocable to such employee (and to such period) in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe. Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, such allocation shall be treated as properly made if made on the basis of being pro rata among periods of coverage.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H13463787F64F4F3AACD8AAE1E1ACA329"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Qualified apprentice</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B3449186B6548989E0CC647811FAC3A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified apprentice</term> means an individual who—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H207C845C59B94E12955B2652D6F668E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an employee of an eligible employer, and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H79A840C2C0874C7ABA20398C92484F49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participates in a registered apprenticeship program pursuant to a written apprenticeship agreement with the registered apprenticeship program sponsor entered into after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57779E75345A47BB8FB60A29C1636907"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Such term shall not include—</text>
<clause id="H6F78484C134D44D9AFC717D740CFDF3C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any individual described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 51(i)(1), or</text></clause> <clause id="H69A348E39B3E40AAA89350C212A6D811" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any 5-percent owner (as defined in section 416(i)(1)(B)).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1D292CCF67A74EE0833582B9A2F90CB9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Participation in a registered apprenticeship program</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), an individual participates in a registered apprenticeship program if—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H788798EE929B414ABF5C6D20AC2EACC3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual has entered into an apprenticeship agreement that has been registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Department of Labor or a recognized State apprenticeship agency during the first 90 days of probationary employment with an eligible employer under a registered apprenticeship program, and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A6FE168A5514A218AB982C05DD08770"> <enum>(ii)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the individual has been certified by such Office of Apprenticeship or a recognized State apprenticeship agency as eligible for probationary employment as an apprentice (as defined in section 29.2 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph)).</text> </clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A49225B83EF400AB8C3C63537A1181C" commented="no"> <enum>(6)</enum> <header>Registered apprenticeship program</header> <text>The term <term>registered apprenticeship program</term> means an apprenticeship registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>) that meets the standards of parts 29 and 30 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph).</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75D2687899234778AE5C55BAB9976776"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship program expenses</header>
<subparagraph id="H110A3E8B5DBB45898F3C1646EB5AB9B3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>registered apprenticeship program expenses</term> means expenses (other than qualified wages) paid or incurred in connection with a registered apprenticeship program, including—</text> <clause id="HB278B7F264A849BC87E915B921B6A3BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>related instruction expenses,</text></clause>
<clause id="HFE0B65A226D44523B76A5132DD7B8CF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on-the-job learning expenses,</text></clause> <clause id="H0D4BE5F35D54426EBBD45A87FCC155BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mentor wages,</text></clause>
<clause id="HE1B133F746F24CED923135BAECC7D349"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>expenses directly associated with the development, registration, or maintenance of a registered apprenticeship program, and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA140A3F70D14457CAE0023406B8188C4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>amounts paid or incurred by an eligible employer to a registered apprenticeship program sponsor pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement (or similar binding agreement) for the purpose of supporting or funding such program.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H96CF8B4338AD4FED8A3CF50CCF62AC32" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Related instruction expenses</header><text>The term <term>related instruction expenses</term> means the costs of organized instruction—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCD6F94AE41A4D9F9F2F64A78D16249F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in technical subjects related to the occupation, and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H989018F698E14250BBDE68961DCE23ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that may be provided in a classroom, through distance learning, or other means of instruction, consistent with the requirements for such instruction under section 29.5(b)(4) of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this paragraph).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8C7AB74455E4191BED0B67CE397FED9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>On-the-job learning expenses</header><text>The term <term>on-the-job learning expenses</term>—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6ED4DEF5B81F4C378613148C3CE2D2F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means the costs of training that—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54026AECFA484B0E80283DB5E4DD3F75"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is provided to a qualified apprentice while engaged in productive work in a job, and</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0224EC381EDF4E158D229041A4CC9C3D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides knowledge or skills essential to the full and adequate performance of the job,</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC5981ACC0F004CAFA380A6FB15305D98" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes reimbursement or support for the costs of such training and of supervision provided during such training, and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD198622BBC5D40028196CBB56D0637F1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include the costs of any wages provided to the qualified apprentice during the training.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0C84A9631CF470AA85AAD92F6E47A7B" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Mentor wages</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFD8DB9F886034BEB81887ECB68539604"><enum>(i)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The term <term>mentor wages</term> means wages which—</text>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A340EB0FD2741278283933AA5FC3B72"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are paid by an eligible employer to an employee who is a journeyworker (within the meaning of section 29.2 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this subparagraph)), and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6445C091C7F44874B0C21774C228F573"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are in excess of the base rate of pay of such employee for pay periods in which such employee is providing mentorship or supervisory services to a qualified apprentice of such eligible employer.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDBA688B21254781AB7E66D74872F822"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Base rate of pay</header>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E91D20E79E64CAFB8DD887082A30F69"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>base rate of pay</term> means, with respect to any pay period for any employee providing mentorship or supervisory services, the average wages paid for pay periods occurring over the 12-month period ending with the pay period before the date on which such individual began providing such mentorship or supervisory services.</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81D917EBF20E4E8882C14BE69BF3CDF3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the employee was not employed for the entire 12-month period referred to in subclause (I), such subclause shall be applied on the basis of the period during which such employee was so employed. The Secretary may provide rules for the application of this clause in cases where the employee was not employed for any period before providing mentorship or supervisory services.</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HE2798EFA851246A38E3A486B31E0782B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation on mentor wages</header><text>The amount of mentor wages which may be taken into account during a calendar quarter with respect to any employee providing mentorship or supervisory services shall not exceed $10,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H742621EA1C7C4FFD9B6733E50EE0DF58"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Registered apprenticeship program sponsor</header><text>The term <term>registered apprenticeship program sponsor</term> means any person, association, committee, or organization operating a registered apprenticeship program and in whose name such program is registered or approved.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3E68485553A3420F987C496D2C4B6112"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Other rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph id="H27235536C9A944F3A69A046168767CA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><text>All persons which are treated as a single employer under subsections (a) and (b) of section 52 or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414 shall be treated as a single taxpayer.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4233FC7480214C0684E4207FA9B417D4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Certain governmental employers</header>
<subparagraph id="H7471F10EF4EE45D680B765FCA4F85FC5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This credit shall not apply to the Government of the United States, the government of any State or political subdivision thereof, or any agency or instrumentality of any of the foregoing.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD80516EAB3F64771B430E811E72AB9B0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to—</text>
<clause id="H3E1158CF41FC4536982DAAE7831EC54E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any organization described in section 501(c)(1) and exempt from tax under section 501(a), or</text></clause> <clause id="HB66159146E104C10A771BA5C87618EA5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any entity described in paragraph (1) if—</text>
<subclause id="HC28D694CC51445109977AC2B38397CD2" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such entity is a college or university, or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDA1D5D0B5B41453B83EE7917ABBD77A1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the principal purpose or function of such entity is providing medical or hospital care.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05CD6BCF82C5443D91FF9DFB61B1081E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26906745DCEA441AA1EAE470E6CB4088"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Credits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any wages or expenses taken into account in determining the credit allowed under this section shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining any credit allowed against the tax imposed by chapter 1.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8C48F7BDBAF40809168D214978B8D40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deductions</header> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7C35A2FCAD8B4C098D03B84FB80C919E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Wages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, rules similar to the rules of section 280C(a) shall apply.</text></clause>
<clause id="H2176622B8BE6423EA833625CEA83D184"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other expenses</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed under chapter 1 with respect to that portion of the registered apprenticeship program expenses (other than wages) taken into account under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABE9B2E36DA147538C3DFBDE2A24BD1F"> <enum>(4)</enum> <header>Coordination with other Federal payments</header> <text>This section shall not apply to any qualified wages or registered apprenticeship program expenses paid or incurred by an eligible employer if such eligible employer received payments for such qualified wages or registered apprenticeship program expenses under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act or any other federally funded program.</text> </paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6CD3E2AC457A448C948A6DD3C01759A7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Election to have apprenticeship credit not apply</header><text>This section shall not apply to so much of the qualified wages and registered apprenticeship program expenses paid or incurred by an eligible employer as such employer elects (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe) to not take into account for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF53732607BB40049C05537676DFA51F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Third party payors</header><text>Any credit allowed under this section shall be treated as a credit described in section 3511(d)(2).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H082E77E5904244EAAB1DE8F567E93894"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Extension of limitation on assessment</header>
<subparagraph id="H141AA3047A784E12B2CF42878A790794"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 6501, the limitation on the time period for the assessment of any amount attributable to a credit claimed under this section shall not expire before the date that is 6 years after the latest of—</text> <clause id="HC8D298DA64F541D2BB485C06E05F651D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the original return which includes the calendar quarter with respect to which such credit is determined is filed,</text></clause>
<clause id="H844E195C106D4DF390FA0713E35107B1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which such return is treated as filed under section 6501(b)(2), or</text></clause> <clause id="H2FCCE5335A3848B294A55E64DC8C1AE8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the date on which the claim for credit or refund with respect to such credit is made.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6E2F16229A874AC882EF0E94D5FFB9BB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Deduction for wages and expenses taken into account in determining improperly claimed credit</header>
<clause id="HB16C1C6F80F242D980B8E94C89475900" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 6511, in the case of an assessment attributable to a credit claimed under this section, the limitation on the time period for credit or refund of any amount attributable to a deduction for improperly claimed apprenticeship wages and expenses shall not expire before the time period for such assessment expires under paragraph (1).</text></clause> <clause id="H8566A1D3121C4560994198E31196FB34" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Improperly claimed apprenticeship wages and expenses</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>improperly claimed apprenticeship wages and expenses</term> means, with respect to an assessment attributable to a credit claimed under this section, the wages and expenses with respect to which a deduction would not have been allowed if the portion of the credit to which such assessment relates had been properly claimed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB9C69B053B394D7B936A8526D2D5A41A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Treatment of deposits</header><text>The Secretary shall waive any penalty under section 6656 for any failure to make a deposit of any applicable employment taxes if the Secretary determines that such failure was due to the reasonable anticipation of the credit allowed under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HADBCF5EC749B4E92848D9AC59E2170ED" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall issue such forms, instructions, regulations, and guidance—</text>
<paragraph id="HD092FFEB76504E928FBAFF6F66CAC68E" commented="no"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>with respect to the application of the credit under subsection (a) to third party payors (including professional employer organizations, certified professional employer organizations, or agents under section 3504), including regulations or guidance allowing such payors to submit documentation necessary to substantiate the registered apprenticeship program expenses of employers that use such payors, and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F00ECB600E04611BEC6C5D29372FED0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent the avoidance of the purposes of the limitations under this section.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">Any forms, instructions, regulations, or other guidance described in paragraph (1) shall require the customer to be responsible for the accounting of the credit and for any liability for improperly claimed credits and shall require the certified professional employer organization or other third party payor to accurately report such tax credits based on the information provided by the customer.</continuation-text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H0342A2D216974F139BF09387F503A081"> <enum>(b)</enum> <header>Notice of availability of credit</header> <text>The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate), shall take such steps as may be necessary or appropriate to keep employers apprised of the availability of the credit allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3135">section 3135</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section.</text> </subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFDC3C379F9F442ECA818FFA5B658B41E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter D of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/21">chapter 21</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H818682B7F779450E94D4238D5A1E436D">
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HC8F50BB34CEE493FA5126340167295CB">Sec. 3135. Apprenticeship credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H12B1EF8BB9D248A8AA951AEE3730FEC1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to wages paid, and expenses paid or incurred, for calendar quarters beginning after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HDBE45A6C3171489596C449C768C041E9" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Tax treatment of apprenticeship awards</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A1C2EC194924A918165F62F84417E6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Apprenticeship awards treated as employee achievement awards</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4A16087B98F441BCB8F1BC16EC96BC7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/274">Section 274(j)(3)(A)(i)(I)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking subclauses (I), (II), and (III) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE81676109F4C4055B24224456BC21C82">
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2C8211161D3543378D3E4C3AEEC60DA3"><enum>(I)</enum>
<item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2F4366C29A7A40419982F68295A0F25C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transferred by an employer to an employee for length of service achievement or safety achievement and awarded as part of a meaningful ceremony, or</text></item> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EEE82D9F7574C66AE8E73E76B567FA8" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transferred by an employer to an employee participating in a registered apprenticeship program in connection with the training and curriculum of such program, and</text></item></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H252E483C5E4D46AFBC37BF6545BE6FA5"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">awarded under conditions and circumstances that do not create a significant likelihood of the payment disguised as compensation.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H874E2B5EE7D6447EA80B7896BDADE7EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 274(j)(4) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text>
<quoted-block id="HEF8397698EA84F268B8F15630D109842" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC">
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H122CB1B96A804627B9A3FAD778C2EE71"> <enum>(D)</enum> <header>Apprenticeship awards</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An item shall not be treated as having been provided in connection with the training and curriculum of a registered apprenticeship program if such item is received during the recipient's first 90 days of participating in the registered apprenticeship program.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A54EA8A2CB04EB79281E98E05F9BD3C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Registered apprenticeship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>registered apprenticeship program</term> has the meaning given such term under section 3135(c)(6).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3062CE366847444B8522F5A44DDF70D4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Increased limitation</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/274">section 274(j)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H1D758C544DA449248AAB973AD822B911" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>($1,500 in the case of an employee achievement award described in paragraph (3)(A)(i)(I)(bb))</quote> after <quote>$400</quote> in paragraph (A), and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H44E6A7D132D9489DBA7F408A20A34B40" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>($5,000 in the case of a qualified plan award which is an employee achievement award described in paragraph (3)(A)(i)(I)(bb))</quote> at the end of paragraph (B).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H965F8F74DE8B413FA7512358B78854FB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to awards transferred after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill>

