<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99528078639F45F5A75737F5301986D5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6276 IH: Dredging Coordination Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6276</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251121">November 21, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001225">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000235">Mr. Ezell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Army to consult with stakeholders in determining the scope of contracts entered into for the purposes of maintenance dredging, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H64E0A62B8A9540319E55F33D5C166FCC" style="OLC"><section id="H24EAD7E3998E44B3BE4F2D0016F1F69C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Dredging Coordination Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0D8659A61F5747FD9EB4CD30EAAC3F27" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Maintenance dredging requirements</header><subsection id="HDB526FA35879460DBB0F8DF1EF819F4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Consultation and prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the scope and performance timeline to be included in any contract entered into on or after the date of enactment of this Act with an entity to carry out maintenance dredging, the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="HB146DD60EF5842A19143880204DA84D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2825676F7E6C479EA2215E110C7B7BC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consult with stakeholders, including the applicable non-Federal sponsor and other relevant entities determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE98F2AE4BEE74F36B844121D7594CD71"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent practicable, prioritize the completion of maintenance dredging in waters used for commercial and navigation activities, maintenance dredging that is needed for emergencies, maintenance dredging that is needed to accommodate environmental windows (as defined by the Secretary), and maintenance dredging that supports other activities in which there is an important national interest before the completion of maintenance dredging in waters used primarily for other activities, such as recreation, or for purposes other than to facilitate commerce or navigation; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34EE54E180564528B86883F587E4FA9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding paragraph (1), may determine the scope and performance timeline to be included in such contract without consultation with stakeholders that are not a party to such contract, if the Secretary determines that an emergency exists or there is an important national interest at stake.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0450A34C3F08440AB9CFA54AD749B6D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Communication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receiving information about changes with respect to the performance of maintenance dredging and determining that such changes are reasonably likely to affect the period of performance of a contract for such dredging, the Secretary shall notify the applicable non-Federal sponsor of such changes not later than the third business day after the date on which the Secretary received such information.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBD3E66FFB8F64274917574E284E357EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capability numbers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any maintenance dredging activity, the Secretary shall, upon request, make the respective capability numbers for such activities available to the non-Federal sponsor of such activity.</text></subsection><subsection id="H83CFC0CA4E3645AA9A8367AEE2B66A04"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Secretary defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

