<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution resolution-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE248E06A977B4DCFA1AB1B16303DEF61" public-private="public" resolution-type="house-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" key="H"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HRES 1104 IH: Directing the Office of Congressional Conduct to establish standards of conduct related to mental capacity of members of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IV</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. RES. 1104</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260304">March 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000600">Ms. Perez</sponsor> submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSO00">Committee on Ethics</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Directing the Office of Congressional Conduct to establish standards of conduct related to mental capacity of members of the House of Representatives.</official-title></form><resolution-body style="OLC" id="H9DD1E958692F4E499940A63B5090D933">
        <section id="H5675FC2D1A974814952059841AA5402F" section-type="section-one">
            <enum>1.</enum>
            <header>Standards of conduct and whistleblower portal relating to mental capacity of
                Members of the House of Representatives</header>
            <subsection id="H5E015032F39049CF9443FD72F94B3B54">
                <enum>(a)</enum>
                <header>Office of Congressional Conduct; standard of conduct relating to cognitive
                    impairment</header>
                <paragraph id="H8B05093771CE4597B90A81233F3425B9">
                    <enum>(1)</enum>
                    <header>In general</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the adoption of this resolution, the Office of Congressional Conduct shall—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="H567645D29E0A46BF8B634686A2557532">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a standard for what constitutes conduct, relating to a Member who is unable to behave at all times in a manner that reflects creditably on the House, as required under clause 1 of rule XXIII of the Rules of the House of Representatives, because the Member suffers from a significant and irreversible cognitive impairment; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="HF5C4F1B0A3AE4FED8FF4261E0B1EDFC3">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>submit a report on such standard to the Committee on Ethics.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HF180CA2C5E2647A9AD24C58C8F84A8EA"> <enum>(2)</enum> <header>Application</header> <text>In carrying out paragraph (1)—</text>
                    <subparagraph id="HC72961B3F32648738FAE7224FB5BC875">
                        <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Office of Congressional Conduct may consult with relevant offices of Congress and outside experts in developing such standard; and</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                    <subparagraph id="H26ED9A0A90ED48C890B19309912AB684">
                        <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>not later than 90 days after receiving the report under paragraph (1)(B), the Committee on Ethics shall develop and issue a standard described under paragraph (1)(A) or issue the standard contained in such report.</text>
                    </subparagraph>
                </paragraph>
            </subsection>
            <subsection id="HC7A68D02D2BA4EF19481EA5DD7AE3491">
                <enum>(b)</enum>
                <header>Committee on Ethics; guidance on mental capacity</header>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Ethics shall draft and make publicly available specific guidance for employees of the House to safely and confidentially make disclosures to relevant committees and legislative branch offices on the mental capacity of Members.</text>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </resolution-body></resolution>

