<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H839E42BAA5704C84A47FEB092F4B82C3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8648 IH: Framework for Oversight of Responsible Global Energy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8648</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260504">May 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish in the Department of State a Foundational Infrastructure for Responsible Use of Small Modular Reactor Technology program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE6C654C34C6E48C6A07BF0C04D14E998" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD5615E1566324879A66B1B4293A7F8A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Framework for Oversight of Responsible Global Energy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FORGE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFAE4B4950980454BA6AE66C112732695"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Foundational Infrastructure for Responsible Use of Small Modular Reactor Technology program</header> <subsection id="H659F186D56794896B67C797F8B21C8D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Department of State a Foundational Infrastructure for Responsible Use of Small Modular Reactor Technology program (hereafter in this section referred to as the <quote>FIRST program</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCF8B0B4D2F414E20B035A7DED9940A0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program functions</header><text>The Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security, or the designee of the Under Secretary, shall manage the FIRST program, which shall—</text> <paragraph id="H3B4C27CE5B5C40449706CADCD9AA045F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote responsible deployment of civil nuclear energy internationally that benefits United States economic and national security interests;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB8898D7DFC644F690B0B07F75E58828"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advocate, through relevant bilateral and multilateral diplomatic engagements and forums, for civil nuclear energy projects, technology, and products sourced or exported from United States businesses;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DBFF1BD972D49C1807F12F24FB7EB18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engage in diplomacy with partner governments on prioritizing the highest safety, security, and nonproliferation standards as requirements for civil nuclear reactor deployment decisions, including with regard to small modular reactor infrastructure, technology, and products;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H533CD19900FA4834BC0CE72B96943EBE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide consultation to partner countries regarding best practices in the field of licensing, legal, and regulatory frameworks for the importation or adoption of United States nuclear reactor infrastructure, technology, or products;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0C82DD7A7B074D479342B719B7DC7C92"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide early-stage commercial project development support, including feasibility and engineering studies, that are critical to launching United States commercial civil nuclear projects abroad and ensure fair market access for United States businesses relative to state-backed competitors; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A62E1605E2745E08493FF96BFD1B22D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cooperate with partner countries in the areas of training programs, technical resource sharing, and potential coordination of codes and standards to support the facilitation of small modular reactor fleet deployment.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H63D44C3E9F524FDF8E576F4D5E24308B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H6BB3785058A74F20BC11EC8239376A88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security, or the designee of such Under Secretary, shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H89D978F041844BFBA4F4271192E93B23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>details on the implementation of the FIRST program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6CABEF86FCC4B949BED9F2CFB5B1911"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of FIRST program diplomatic outreach and activities, including bilateral and multilateral engagements that promote activities described in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB1238A7A7AE04D3A8B751D0CAD9C2F8C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the list of current contributing partners of the FIRST program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2CCE6F3AACAF42838D94D742730939F1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details relating to potential or ongoing cooperation with contributing partners of the FIRST program related to program activities described in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8838DC5BA824FE6AB129BCB48D314A4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of engagements and activities conducted by the Department of State to promote and expand the FIRST program to additional potential contributing partners;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H536AD4CBCBE24BAF91C4C3D36F7D41C3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a description of FIRST program-related engagements with United States businesses in the civil nuclear sector; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF869A63A1A0C4E489070B72EAD465632"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of funds expended on FIRST program-related activities, including programming that uses funds from Nonproliferation, Anti-Terrorism, Demining, and Related Programs and related funding sources within the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3698C846447F4321862EF4E397047136"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by this subsection shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex submitted separately from the unclassified portion.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C59618AFD014948B349ACBB1AE4F5EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and on a triannual basis thereafter, the Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security, or the designee of the Under Secretary, shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing that includes the information required in subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H679DD520DBBB4AF28CAA3172589E8B3C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8F04E83062334BCEAC33A44EC5B6807C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H7917A68898814148816056A9159DA9A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of the Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H53325633491C4AFDA95F5815A1C69547"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21B222D32A6342DAA7BFE4D37DD18A61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States business</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2304 of the Export Enhancement Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/4724">15 U.S.C. 4724</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3296B5FEF2D04EB18C8C9C16B8FD7328"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on June 8, 2034.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

