<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCD43842C40FA462189063749E03C8F21" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6963 IH: To designate the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Lafayette, Louisiana, as the “Rodney C. Hamilton Sr. VA Clinic”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6963</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260107">January 7, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001176">Mr. Scalise</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000110">Mr. Fields</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Lafayette, Louisiana, as the <quote>Rodney C. Hamilton Sr. VA Clinic</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HABF4BB3098544D5F9913D359E464D3E6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE5552BA056DF47BAAB02B4295C5AE0B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Designation of Rodney C. Hamilton Sr. VA Clinic in Lafayette, Louisiana</header>
<subsection id="HACA60E707739424BAFC1C6AB17C4A19B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB745088450024877864E3834B6DF3DFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Rodney Carroll Hamilton Sr. was born in Fort Worth, Texas, on March 24, 1932, and his family moved to Lafayette, Louisiana, in the summer of 1948;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27B9A4E05C9745ACBCCA3B13A94F7918"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in 1949, at age seventeen, Rodney Hamilton joined the reserve components of the Marine Corps at the urging of his football coach Lou Campbell while attending Lafayette High School;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H94C7725E345340939A1BF7AB04847E46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Rodney Hamilton served the United States during the Korean War, was wounded in combat in September 1951, and was awarded the Purple Heart;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H88C649A9EC284E2FA8705F3B9F14F697"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Rodney Hamilton loved the Marine Corps and was proud of all Marines who served the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H256DCA48CDD643B9A984FF49D13D56B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Rodney Hamilton was a member of the Marine Corps League, the Military Order of the Purple Heart, and the Veteran's Action Coalition of Southwest Louisiana, where he served as Founder and Chairman Emeritus;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6F75CC3F76441F89AEA7942763EFC24"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Rodney Hamilton served as a full-time elected official in the Lafayette City Government from 1968 through 1972 as a Trustee of Public Property;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEC957830ABC4703A3E5D468CD56AF50"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Rodney Hamilton made numerous contributions to help make Lafayette a better place, including leading efforts to secure and build the community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Lafayette, which opened in 2016;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H92C510E5B6FB4159B0BFE2BE9E0A1DDE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>due to the dedication of Rodney Hamilton in realizing the community-based outpatient clinic in Lafayette, the street on which the clinic is located was named in his honor and now bears signs saying, <quote>Veterans Way, Honorary Rodney Hamilton</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2F3B731EFB2411E9690DCE849CFD62B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Rodney Hamilton passed away at the age of 88 on November 30, 2020.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C8DE2FCF8184001AEC679E07C53B17B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The community-based outpatient clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Lafayette, Louisiana, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Rodney C. Hamilton Sr. VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0823979B8E3C400EBE65F30CDA74662B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reference</header><text>Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in subsection (b) shall be considered to be a reference to the Rodney C. Hamilton Sr. VA Clinic.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

