<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-BAG25I17-9RT-42-S1P"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3000 IS: Fraud Reduction And Uncovering Deception in Department of Veterans Affairs Disability Exams Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-10-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code>II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3000</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251009">October 9, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</sponsor> introduced the following
                bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans’ Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to identify and report
            instances of disability benefit questionnaire fraud, and for other
 purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id1686a6b35eed4172b9231f41f9698a77" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fraud Reduction And Uncovering Deception in Department of Veterans Affairs Disability Exams Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FRAUD in VA Disability Exams Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idf313e09a4baa4585ba8426bf8d9393c9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identification and reporting of veterans disability benefit questionnaire
 fraud</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2ea81fffd5e94ed9bef84782645844d4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4f027f5b92a644629604b7b08087e544"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out actions to identify fraudulent activity relating to the submittal of disability benefit questionnaire data to the Secretary, without regard to the origin of the questionnaires; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idfbd7314e9a4545b79be8b02096f0ce31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmit to appropriate investigatory bodies, including the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs, reports of suspected activity identified pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id45306206b6af4bb7b8dce018f24c5b9e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Actions carried out pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id822c9d573e9449d9b644a1c5772077c7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment of a process for claim processors of the Department to identify instances of disability benefit questionnaire fraud and to transmit reports of suspected fraud as described in paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id47ad3302212c4e799274c87c396db45e"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establishment of a recurring audit of disability benefit questionnaires submitted to the Secretary, without regard to the origin of the questionnaires.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id0c3ea596b8b64e8eb2e4cde39d8bc451"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Informing individuals who have applied for, or submitted a claim for, a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary when their disability benefit questionnaires have raised suspicion of fraud.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc1068ef6e1954670a97bb2849f6c44f5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority of Inspector General of the Department of Veterans
 Affairs</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of Veterans Affairs may use any authority applicable to an inspector general of the Federal Government not otherwise available to the Inspector General that the Inspector General considers necessary to investigate suspected activity identified pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide338d0d67cb44648a688cf50c34424b2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may not reopen or change a decision of the Department regarding an application from an individual for, or claim of the individual for, a benefit under a law administered by the Secretary pursuant to an investigation carried out under subsection (c), except in a case in which, pursuant to such investigation, the individual has been convicted by a court of competent jurisdiction of fraud.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idab9768f3161b485ab84fb4948d8af9b5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the administration of subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>


