<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C680697C58B4CF99BB9986BCA938E4D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9395 IH: Transparency in Medicare Advantage Steering Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9395</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require certain reporting with respect to agents and brokers of Medicare Advantage organizations.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H507BBBAFED5447B4AE6582A1CD9C5A6A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB12C9A57B1A0469D82BB0638FBFE235D" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency in Medicare Advantage Steering Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H555C0F8B329142058EA8D14D13F2DA50"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring reporting on certain agent and broker information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1857(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H829CC0D53D9D476DB0E0B7762BD56D27" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H36CEC27F0E404708940D8C07A4E2CC92"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Requirement to report certain agent and broker information</header> 
<subparagraph id="H1FD37F9E1FBA414192ED5F852D813469"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2028, a contract under this section with an MA organization shall require the organization to annually report to the Secretary—</text> <clause id="HC57BC4BA318042BFB35526851DEC4B8F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to each individual enrolled in an MA plan offered by such organization for such year—</text> 
<subclause id="HD6914C5B114E4987B002A007FEF7FA5B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether such individual was so enrolled by an agent, broker, or other third party representing the organization; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC7732E6D9B014076A78E11C6070BAA23"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case that such individual was so enrolled by such an agent, broker, or third party—</text> 
<item id="H75AECC7EDA2E4AEDA5CD28B6F63E730B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the amount of compensation, if any, paid to such agent, broker, or third party in connection with enrolling such individual; and</text></item> <item id="H6CD136F35B89412A9A471560259E163B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the form of such compensation;</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HB2C8B43E52DC4AA49777CCD82897EC19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total amount of compensation paid to all such agents, brokers, and third parties representing the organization in connection with enrolling individuals in all MA plans offered by such organization for such year; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4878EC8F87A94027BD4489E9F0CB4DE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such other information relating to such agents, brokers, and third parties representing the organization as the Secretary may require.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DFC06CEC3454AEEA94A9B69CCA2AA3B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>Beginning with plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2030, the Secretary shall—</text> <clause id="HF17837ABE45046CF88717855C1611FA0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include in the Chronic Condition Data Warehouse maintained by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services pursuant to section 723 of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 an indicator to identify whether an individual was enrolled in an MA plan by an agent, broker, or other third party representing the organization offering such plan (as determined based on the information reported under <internal-xref idref="HD6914C5B114E4987B002A007FEF7FA5B" legis-path="(7)(A)(i)">subparagraph (A)(i)</internal-xref>); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFD413DAB3F7A491AAF138AE7D5710DF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make publicly available on the internet website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid services the information reported by an MA organization under clauses (ii) and (iii) of <internal-xref idref="H1FD37F9E1FBA414192ED5F852D813469" legis-path="(7)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> </legis-body></bill>

