<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-DAV26757-MW6-WD-0DJ"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4680 IS: Expanded Consular Fellows Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4680</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260604">June 4, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S423">Mr. Ricketts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the Secretary of State to extend limited consular appointments to eight years, with an additional two-year extension for needs of the Foreign Service.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanded Consular Fellows Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6e9949173c63403ba273cdd3b6797170"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="ide7a2a6e801494045a1f5d67ecb8d99e9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Consular services provided at United States embassies and consulates worldwide, and in the United States, are critical to protecting the safety and security of Americans abroad, safeguarding United States borders, supporting American families pursuing international adoptions, and facilitating legitimate travel to the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idc7e69695b530428f990c1234d1f4d849"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Foreign Service posts process millions of visa applications each year, conducting rigorous security vetting of each application to detect fraud, mitigate security risks, prevent unlawful migrations, and protect the homeland.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id674cdf505745460ebb351d3e70fa6f18"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Travel and tourism is the United States largest single services export, accounting for 22 percent of services exports and 7 percent of total exports in 2023. In 2022, the travel and tourism industry contributed $2,300,000,000,000 to the United States economy—approximately 2.97 percent of gross domestic product—and supported 9,500,000 United States jobs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida86841b2e788424ebe1feb5561e9c91f"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Demand for consular services will continue to increase as the United States enters an American decade of sports as the host of major international events between 2024 and 2034—including the Copa America, Club World Cup, FIFA World Cup, Olympic and Paralympic Games, and Rugby World Cups—which are expected to draw millions of international visitors and significantly increasing workloads for consular staff while simultaneously requiring enhanced security screening and adjudicative rigor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2bcbc513b2a46619200910940d1de12"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Expanding limited non-career appointments for Department of State personnel performing consular functions, including through the Consular Fellows Program, is essential to increasing staffing capacity, reducing recruitment costs and delays, and ensuring the continued efficient delivery of consular services.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7ce85a5a70b445f295465f5dc21dcea0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expansion of limited consular appointment authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 309 of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3949">22 U.S.C. 3949</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2fa159941473482d8e9edee9f6579b73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>, or 8 years in duration for personnel performing consular services,</quote> after <quote>may not exceed 5 years in duration</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5248aaee7e064dc4844331c696911ce4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(6)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id593ef10ef2074f3091cf504b1be6e140"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id88444b09e5d74706b5be26be40b9f45e"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida28b8fc2db4847ae860134404ddc9653"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="idEE6AE4CA521F4E84A026B02C78C0A39D" style="OLC" act-name=""><subparagraph id="id4A7EE1D23A414AF98B41789BB4428219"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a limited noncareer appointment for a period not to exceed 2 years, in the case of personnel performing consular services.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

