<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9069D047CE4C40639FED69FCDE19E620" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8779 IH: Patients Before Monopolies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8779</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260513">May 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000601">Mr. Landsman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit pharmacy benefit managers and pharmacies from being under common ownership, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H96EA9341F4474F298A859D14738F93AA" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HC0D96EF3274048719C88FCC556D9E978"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Patients Before Monopolies Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PBM Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7A3AD69D45904851BE2D244B0BF92EA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H11194BECE4CC42859BC5ABF2A4DBD11D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Pharmacy benefit managers are corporate entities that play a dominant role in pharmaceutical supply chains, determining which drugs health plans will cover for enrollees, what prices patients and health plans will pay for those drugs, and how much health plans will reimburse pharmacies for dispensing them.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C6F1C83B950462DB2960AE5039F42EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The market for pharmacy benefit manager services has become highly concentrated. As of 2025, the 6 largest pharmacy benefit managers are each integrated into large health care conglomerates that include downstream businesses such as retail, mail order, and specialty pharmacies. These conglomerates also processed more than 90 percent of the prescriptions in the United States in 2023.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6DD843EFA6B84AEB85D34BD159BE3D09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The 3 largest pharmacy benefit managers are also vertically integrated into health care platforms that include both upstream business lines, like health insurance, and downstream suppliers, like pharmacies and providers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2036035393864B1292AA1BA214690106"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission has found that vertically integrated pharmacy benefit managers have both the ability and incentive to steer business to their own affiliated pharmacies, which reduces competition and increases prescription drug costs for patients.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8DF3957F0AD04687B0FA1A1FAF61E583"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Pharmacy benefit managers increasingly leverage their market power to pressure smaller, unaffiliated, independent pharmacies to enter into unfavorable contracts with the largest pharmacy benefit managers. This dynamic has likely contributed to the closure of more than 7,000 pharmacies between 2019 and 2024.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E082F85850C431CABF4AD466FD81495"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Self-preferencing of affiliated pharmacies may also allow large, vertically integrated health conglomerates to evade statutory limits on profits known as the Medical Loss Ratio. Gaming of the profit constraint using transfer pricing techniques may allow affiliated health insurance businesses to hide profits in the unregulated pharmacy business segment, costing enrollees and taxpayers money.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C4DB53162834E048EDD68CD9E860E7B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Pursuant to its powers under article I, section 8, of the United States Constitution, Congress has the ability to create any law necessary and appropriate to regulate interstate commerce. As pharmacy benefit managers are part of large, national health conglomerates that operate across state lines, and engage in intrastate activities that also substantially relate to interstate commerce, Congress intends to regulate pharmacy benefit managers in the public interest.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7FC3CBE71064AE8936B2E05E1DC62C9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In order to eliminate the conflicts of interest described in paragraphs (1) through (7) and restore competition to the marketplace, the Federal Government should—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD0D0FB7CC21149E9B00242CD516629CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protect patients, independent pharmacies, and taxpayers by structurally separating vertically integrated health conglomerates;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0082F8F035A84095A0CED11B0EDA91BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require parent companies that own a pharmacy benefit manager or insurer to divest their pharmacy businesses;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FE7CC35D8CA44B68C72FD8869EBC164"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enable Federal agencies, state attorneys general, and private citizens to bring civil actions to enforce the structural separation of these companies; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5765D932575468DAD1BEBC9B6193A21"><enum>(D)</enum><text>grant the Federal Trade Commission and Department of Justice additional authority to review and block future transactions that would re-create these conflicts of interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51A606E6E0CF407DABE3A6EDC3B921C0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibitions relating to anticompetitive pharmacy ownership and contracts</header>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF22CEC5E99464372B1DE5781C7C42274"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibition on pharmacy ownership by entities providing insurance or pharmacy benefit management services</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FB1DBA3D2FB447C9961A2FFC3E8763E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person to both—</text> <subparagraph id="H2661108E10DD45728360C730F5C4223C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>directly or indirectly own, operate, control, or direct the operation of the whole or any part of a pharmacy; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1D888B53A0F24620BEB94DA0D1C608B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directly or indirectly own, operate, or control the whole or any part of—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0024E82CC5145BA880F42E3AF0AEE46"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an insurance company; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2A04C8E7BE634B65ACBBF0DF1388D78C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a pharmacy benefit manager.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F5C26697BAE49E89F561DE2AB248B4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Divestment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, any person in violation of paragraph (1) shall divest the pharmacy of such person.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFB5DED188BC449D9B25EE86444329028"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Antitrust enforcement</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H170FD219BCB94BF2B8BFFAFCB0EF982B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Both the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division shall have jurisdiction, jointly or separately, to enforce this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB825409F32754D0BBA197712E7552E8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties for failure to divest</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EA8599EA385417381C731F3D0690D45"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division shall issue guidance specifying milestones for divestment within the deadline under subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCF649A42D27A46CFA24510934C70FF3C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Penalties</header>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H70D2DE50782E4CCBBB3E9001E6B78FC1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any person that does not comply with the milestones specified under subparagraph (A), the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission or the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division shall cause 10 percent of the profits of the person to be transferred into escrow on a monthly basis, to be—</text> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9DA70E093434E239FCE0218F7774A6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">returned to the person if divestment occurs by the deadline under subsection (a)(2); or</text></subclause>
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB6DDA9AAC44149CEBD023572D20A993E"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deposited into the fund described in subsection (c)(7) if divestment does not occur by the deadline under subsection (a)(2).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BE1198FC8AB4600AABE23C10479C048" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Trustee</header><text>If divestiture does not occur by the deadline under subsection (a)(2), a divestiture trustee shall oversee the divestiture required under that paragraph. The divestiture trustee shall have the authority to sell the pharmacy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBFB18DDD55C346729CC2245E417623D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil actions</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCA5124AF6F441E38219D04D24673732"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>When the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice, the Federal Trade Commission, or an attorney general of a State has reason to believe that a person is in violation of subsection (a), such Inspector General, Assistant Attorney General, Federal Trade Commission or attorney general of a State may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF25F2596B91452680F6F21C3BA3D3C9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private right of action</header> <subparagraph id="H9530BBD4556647C18D175967B63515EF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual alleging damages as a result of a violation of this Act may bring a civil action in any court of competent jurisdiction, State or Federal.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H197C46541EF74B13963E0DF307F3DBD4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the plaintiff prevails, the court may award—</text> <clause id="H39315B068FA2402D907FD29494529E22"><enum>(i)</enum><text>treble damages;</text></clause>
<clause id="H93FD0C27A45044F9AD4EDE28179D64C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonable attorney’s fees and litigation costs; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD78AE7BB863B4C7BA02FCC02FAA7C3BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other relief, including equitable or declaratory relief, that the court determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H60B003741B7449859B82E0A6028E4CF5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Actions by State attorneys general</header><text>If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is being threatened or adversely affected by a practice that violates subsection (a), the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate relief, including monetary damages.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA21F99137EE7411E82C299FAE4472B47"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Injunctive and equitable relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any action described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3), the applicable court, on a finding that a person is in violation of subsection (a), shall issue an order requiring such person—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD76AED9C9C17428F9E678CE92D9A100F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to cease and desist from such violation, and, if applicable, divest the pharmacy services of such person; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30CEAEDCE7BA4E7281F89BEC40E6B289"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to disgorge any revenue received from the pharmacy from the sale of prescription drugs during the period of such violation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E974742D8834F9EB940ACA98C9CD632"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Other relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any relief obtained under paragraph (1), (2), or (3), the court may grant any other equitable relief necessary to redress and prevent recurrence of the violation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBCB536A63B844AAB77B10352594DCF0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Right to jury trial</header><text>Either party, upon request, shall have the right to a jury trial.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBED8E827B48C41D48D2D49012A0F5916"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text>Any revenue received from the sale of prescription drugs disgorged pursuant to an action under paragraph (1) shall be deposited in a fund created by the Federal Trade Commission and distributed by the Federal Trade Commission to be put to use in the interest of serving the health care needs of the harmed community, including consumers overcharged at vertically integrated pharmacies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF43EFBFE9BC4EE98EEFB73434EBD520"><enum>(d)</enum><header>FTC and DOJ review</header> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8F92F614627E40328BE67B761DB6E903"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Reporting required</header><text>Any divestment of a pharmacy or pharmacy benefit manager required under subsection (a) shall be reported to the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice under section 7A of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>) without respect to the thresholds under subsection (a)(2) of that section.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7982DB0409544F1D879BB05747FF0CB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tolling of divestment period during review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The divestment period under subsection (a) shall be tolled during the pendency of any waiting period required under section 7A of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D9614C9BC5B4392A9E847CA992F1D0C"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review of effect of divestiture</header><text>With respect to each divestiture undertaken pursuant to subsection (a), in addition to any applicable review under section 7A of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/18a">15 U.S.C. 18a</external-xref>), the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice shall review the effect on competition, financial viability, and the public interest—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDDF2A7760F541E199C1590FAB79155D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the divestiture; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23F50F8E33524CC59309CEF84513DBDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the subsequent acquisition of the divested pharmacy by the acquiring person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H012749C939854D9D989EA161D7DD611B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Blocking of actions</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice, jointly or separately, may bring a civil action in any court of competent jurisdiction to block any action that would harm competition to the detriment of the public interest with respect to the conflicts of interest described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A27D4A4EE214BCA8F5FF7AE73819C11"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall promulgate rules to carry out this section. Such rules shall not diminish any obligation under this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4DFDE3B66704AFF868639A56FA353A4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>The Chair of the Federal Trade Commission and the Assistant Attorney General in charge of the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees quarterly reports on compliance with this Act, including the status of any divestitures required under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0DD3748121204DA4A7368F9769D1A61F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Federal Trade Commission, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice, the Department of Health and Human Services, or the attorney general of a State under any other provision of law.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HBC5E5B376C01450D91847F080B5946D1" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act or the application thereof to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the remainder of this Act, or the application of that provision to persons or circumstances other than those as to which it is held invalid, shall not be affected thereby.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9591EF3BEE1E4F2584C20895E88E8A80"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HAF94656495D14E43837429591112C02F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Health plan</header><text>The term <term>health plan</term> means any public or private health insurance plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H940E5129FEF84539A8BB57F6B92DC193"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8 of the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7">15 U.S.C. 7</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0812A1C64D1D4D51BC1EB82777D6CF1F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pharmacy</header>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E368B8DFACE45C5A2CE901C780FCC96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pharmacy</term> means any person, business, or entity licensed, registered, or otherwise permitted by a State or a territory of the United States to dispense, deliver, or distribute a controlled substance, prescription drug, or other medication—</text> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF552E2D8064B4C09A954029F706B7C3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the general public; or</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F9FD84F7F9347FC9E7C89A28CCC19F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a bed patient for immediate administration.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5C4FDF8B56844E7BAE70A5F7ACA7D8F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pharmacy</term> includes—</text>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83DCBE26AC594AD18422382ED8212D72"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a mail-order pharmacy;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2345FE326DAA4BF3B27B92607F8AB722"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a specialty pharmacy;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB640C8C9FB7B4DAD8C8CB28248507D9A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a retail pharmacy;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D99D33E0E014C7AB29D29CCD8C0973A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nursing home pharmacy;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H600A08397F614E2A820FE7B1AAFFF90E"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a long-term care pharmacy;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC2A8F5997F954E9D8D5F76F4CDB011EC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a hospital pharmacy;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC129E9637C340B3AD14A21ED30EFF31"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an infusion or other outpatient treatment pharmacy;</text></clause> <clause id="HB7F3A915CD4A4AB89468955079AB42A7"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any organization the National Provider Identifier (NPI) registration of which has 1 or more taxonomy codes under the pharmacy section of the National Uniform Claim Committee (or a subsequent organization); and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8548036388624E3AACA744FC9D49E53D"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other type of pharmacy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCBEFABC20AFB400996939396A9D8B2F2"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pharmacy benefit manager</header><text>The term <term>pharmacy benefit manager</term> means any person, business, or other entity, such as a third-party administrator, regardless of whether such person, business, or entity identifies itself as a pharmacy benefit manager, that, either directly or indirectly through an intermediary (including an affiliate, subsidiary, or agent) or an arrangement with a third party—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF5E9347BFCB54E7CB9213C03061E2551"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acts as a negotiator of prices, rebates, fees, or discounts for prescription drugs on behalf of a health plan or health plan sponsor;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A744ECC2AC64A1C8D38F6966FC7896E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contracts with pharmacies to create pharmacy networks and designs and manages such networks; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC428EB4B5D64A46ACF3C3E35EECBEB3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>manages or administers the prescription drug benefits provided by a health plan, including the processing and payment of claims for prescription drugs, arranging alternative access to or funding for prescription drugs, the performance of utilization management services, including drug utilization review, the processing of drug prior authorization requests, the adjudication of appeals or grievances related to the prescription drug benefit, contracting with network pharmacies, controlling the cost of covered prescription drugs, or the provision of related services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

