<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24C390BCBD40413CB635ED83783555DA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9053 IH: Water Assurance and Treaty Enforcement for Rio Grande Farmers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9053</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260529">May 29, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000594">Ms. De La Cruz</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure the reliable delivery of water to the United States under the 1944 Water Treaty, to provide a mechanism to compensate United States agricultural producers for economic losses resulting from delivery shortfalls, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B1F663688A44328A88C91D6FD4689C4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAEC563E98EF44D1282FD3700284C8166" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Assurance and Treaty Enforcement for Rio Grande Farmers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>WATER for Farmers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9A3136447DFF425A9C86967C88AAB4EC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0398E781866246479E4E32A394F90486" commented="no">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>The Treaty relating to the Utilization of Waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande, signed at Washington February 3, 1944 (9 Bevans 1166), between the United States and Mexico (in this Act referred to as the <quote>1944 Water Treaty</quote> or the <quote>Treaty</quote>), intends for Mexico to deliver annually to the United States a minimum of 350,000 acre-feet of water from the Rio Grande basin, measured in cycles of 5 consecutive years.</text>
      </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4DF03064A72945F1ADF40F1120B8F2D3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The practice of relying on storm events to comply with the terms of the Treaty, unpredictable yearly deliveries, and accumulating large deficits, create profound uncertainty and have inflicted severe economic harm on United States agricultural producers and communities in South Texas who rely on regular delivery of water under the Treaty.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H596CB0CF3C314514933A27B4BD3281DA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Those annual economic harms have a direct impact on interstate and international commerce, distort agricultural markets, and create unfair competitive conditions for United States agricultural producers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H057E26E746FE44B08F308A80DAED0CA6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recent diplomatic agreements between the United States and Mexico, including Minutes 325 and 331 of the International Boundary and Water Commission, do not contain sufficient enforcement mechanisms to guarantee the reliable delivery of water necessary for agricultural planning and production.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1097196DE8284FBFB5F694887DF7687C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>New enforcement mechanisms are necessary to ensure the benefits of the 1944 Water Treaty are fully realized by the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HEE6A181C57FF41BCA1FEBCA7E099EBF6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of water delivery shortfalls</header> 
<subsection id="H0E5421FFD9E245D696C7D68ADF74FEEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the end of each year of a five-year water delivery cycle under the 1944 Water Treaty, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the United States Commissioner of the International Boundary and Water Commission and the Secretary of Agriculture, shall determine whether Mexico has delivered the quantity of water for that year required under subsection (b). If it is determined that Mexico has not delivered that quantity of water for that year, Mexico shall be considered in a water delivery shortfall for that year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H237C736F938F49B59340006B36AD1CF4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual delivery requirement</header> <paragraph id="HD40D4AA94F344BD8971FBE4A703478F4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The minimum quantity of water required to be delivered by Mexico by the end of each year of a cycle of 5 consecutive years under the 1944 Water Treaty shall be 350,000 acre-feet.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB010FE61FF0243B5818A52A0BCF8A804" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions by Secretary of State</header><text>The Secretary of State shall take such actions as are necessary to formalize the requirement described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H875F14FB2602437BB2D6C0FCF4402783"><enum>4.</enum><header>Imposition of duties during period of water delivery shortfalls</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6EDEEE35F1641D4835228188B5D6474"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The United States Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the United States Commissioner of the International Boundary and Water Commission, shall impose duties with respect to imports of goods from Mexico during the period—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC6C7ECE753CD4307A70FD7D9A09AA4E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beginning on the date that is 90 days after a determination is made under section 3(a) that Mexico is in a water delivery shortfall for a year; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H57182D9248654D29A86E89AC53EAA7F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ending on the date that is 30 days after the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the United States Trade Representative, and the United States Commissioner of the International Boundary and Water Commission, determines and certifies to Congress that Mexico has remedied the water delivery shortfalls for all preceding years.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HED51652785644F608B02A3B4724BB3DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goods subject to duties</header><text>The United States Trade Representative shall determine the goods imported from Mexico to be subject to duties under subsection (a), prioritizing the imposition of such duties with respect to—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB46B68EFEEB84EE39F973F0B31A2F8B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agricultural products or other goods for which such duties are likely to have a significant economic impact on Mexico; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC45B0E25C114D91BC69C28EC27EF763"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">goods produced in areas that use water from—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6BBAA28D3BEC4EE6B1C42E6FEAA0668A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Rio Grande River; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8EB5BA5280594621B5516EF3E754BAF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tributaries that should flow to the Rio Grande River.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H27314629A6F64CAFAC1630DEBC6D4A0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increased duties for shortfall carryovers</header><text>If Mexico is in a water delivery shortfall for a second or subsequent consecutive year, the United States Trade Representative shall increase the duties imposed with respect to imports of goods from Mexico, by—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDC7C8F34CCAF487E8A5F9E4A57090705"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the rates of duty applicable to such goods; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H65805FA4AE964DA0B9ABB24649BA38F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expanding the categories of goods to which such duties apply.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H227DAC61A83A4137AEE2C617E8064882"><enum>5.</enum><header>South Texas Agricultural Compensation Trust Fund</header> 
<subsection id="HB4EDD9680F4F4C2C8BEBB611F86EE0F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund, to be known as the South Texas Agricultural Compensation Trust Fund (in this section referred to as the <quote>Trust Fund</quote>), consisting of—</text> <paragraph id="HBF1BCC78FA3D4D09B78477160753A962"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amounts transferred to the trust fund under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6AD04060EBF4D58A2EA7BD1DC395DAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any amounts that may be credited to the trust fund under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H83254E7B1C0B49AA83438AE83449321C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of amounts</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Trust Fund, from the general fund of the Treasury, an amount equivalent to the amount received into the general fund and attributable to duties collected under section 4.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8D2A78BD07D14A6C89974A295F1072C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Investment of amounts</header> 
<paragraph id="HC600242B140B445C8746EDF8A0BB3C1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investment of amounts</header><text>The Secretary shall invest such portion of the Trust Fund as is not required to meet current withdrawals in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA1D3B7E86E8D4304A9054EBE2446688D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interest and proceeds</header><text>The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Trust Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1845F767CE5140CA8BCF1BB9DA228F40"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Availability of amounts</header><text>Amounts in the Trust Fund shall be available, without further appropriation, to the Secretary of Agriculture to provide direct financial compensation to agricultural producers who have suffered economic losses as determined under section 6.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H42103A59B59D48809EE0179FF55AB4C4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Compensation of United States agricultural producers harmed by water delivery shortfalls</header> <subsection id="H9CFD515E91064E9A8C1CB0E49E88AAC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after a determination is made under section 3(a) that Mexico is in a water delivery shortfall for a year, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the United States Commissioner of the International Boundary and Water Commission, shall calculate the direct economic losses incurred by United States agricultural producers in the Rio Grande Valley as a result of the shortfall.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H147B2118980246F5BAC57027308F6508"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compensation formula</header><text>The Secretary shall calculate direct economic losses under subsection (a) at the amount equal to the product of—</text> <paragraph id="H5FE7190E084C4538B47708102D0F09E7"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text>the shortfall volume in acre-feet, multiplied by</text>
                </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H11044359369D4D01800DDF619CF8D7E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the economic value per acre-foot, multiplied by</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CE0CB5DEC3D4EF9A7EA1CE0958680C6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the impact multiplier.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE9D7E15A924A4E19835E0F851B57B37A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H9B057567CED847BD905D695F6F463E25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Economic value per acre-foot</header><text>The term <term>economic value per acre-foot</term> means the value derived by the Secretary of Agriculture by considering comprehensive and regularly updated studies of South Texas agricultural economics, including direct crop revenue losses, increased costs for alternative water sources, elevated water rates, the higher value and vulnerability of specialty crops, and regional variations in water value.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97095454EABC430289234FB796198816" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Impact multiplier</header><text>The term <term>impact multiplier</term> means the multiplier derived by the Secretary of Agriculture by considering indirect and cascading economic impacts beyond direct farm gate losses, including job losses in agriculture and related sectors, reduced supplies to downstream industries, and closures of agricultural processing businesses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE47C446D38E24BE9AE6CDD11C15CBA1B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Shortfall volume in acre-feet</header><text>The term <term>shortfall volume in acre-feet</term> means the difference between Mexico's required water delivery under section 3(b) for a year and the actual volume of water delivered to the United States in acre-feet during that year.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H493B736AD34F42C39A26CAB3DC5763BC"><enum>7.</enum><header>Data collection and review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States Section of the International Boundary and Water Commission, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of State, shall collect, monitor, and publicly report, on a monthly basis, detailed, real-time data on—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A02B08560294469A8C3A403CC376FDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the delivery of water under the 1944 Water Treaty;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA3A61AD670A45BFA22A56B4C65DB186"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">precise calculations of water delivery shortfalls; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H71E83909859C4C3291C87A9EE0AE347A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the status of compensation payments made under section 6.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H19D3149A43DB424E94A8E9533A8FFB48"><enum>8.</enum><header>Interaction with Treaty and other laws</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H935455D771474D838F2EB6C1A1253475"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Treaty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act is intended to be construed and applied in a manner consistent with the obligations of the United States under the 1944 Water Treaty.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD87EBFF18DF42208C1CD8827B3EBA12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to diminish or impair any right or remedy available under—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1ACAB9D9236E47E086F1AC029A3E721A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other provision of Federal or State law, except as required by this Act; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FC0B7881A3B42D8B8300281B37B5B0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other international agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

