<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-SIL26700-RJY-GK-PW7"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4673 IS: Pathways to a Thriving Household Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4673</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260603">June 3, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S416">Mrs. Britt</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To increase workforce participation by recipients of Federal public housing assistance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="S1"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pathways to a Thriving Household Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PATH Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id6549998d7b1f45c0b639ef0e7fd4e3ed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assisted housing workforce participation</header><subsection id="id7843eeb5e82d4af7afdc836ada34a515"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 16 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437n">42 U.S.C. 1437n</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id85efb791f6054a67a0e5928dff96f558"><subsection id="id64c208d1b61845fca67d0e986c672256"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Minimum work requirements</header><paragraph id="ida880d0bc590a42819e7c797d5b9bc9e3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A public housing agency, in the case of public housing, tenant-based assistance (as defined in section 8(f)), or project-based voucher assistance under section 8(o)(13) or an owner, in the case of project-based assistance (as defined in section 8(f)) excluding project-based voucher assistance under section 8(o)(13), may establish minimum work requirements for individuals or families, which—</text><subparagraph id="id99f63549bbb84555afa57ec9843e7c76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall specify a maximum 40 hour per week work requirement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4eea15b425b42e792a2eb45742c3ff3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not apply to—</text><clause id="ide5cc83cbe8de4aa5b706bb9310483e74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual under 18 years of age or over 62 years of age;</text></clause><clause id="id570bd69fc3714a5a963489827e746fb1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual with a disability;</text></clause><clause id="id135ba1a2668b49ffbc6f8ffeeee861f9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a pregnant woman;</text></clause><clause id="idba6f510780f64119a5079f66b0f72e1d"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the primary parent or caretaker of a dependent child under 6 years of age or for an individual that is temporarily incapacitated;</text></clause><clause id="id1dff830523cd4d83a97f4b5efcb91719"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the primary parent or caretaker of a dependent with a serious medical condition or disability, as determined by the State agency established or designated to administer or supervise the administration of the State plan;</text></clause><clause id="id91ad5d8ebc3e48ee90ec796449b51030"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>an individual who is enrolled as a student in an institution of higher education, as defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfa6c7141479244a682b52b651cd797c6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>A public housing agency or owner under this Act shall determine whether an individual meets the criteria for exemption from the work requirements established under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id711ceeb86f7c4a5fb7d4d686d42323e1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Work activities</header><text>Participation by an individual family member in the following activities shall be considered to fulfill minimum work requirements under paragraph (1), as determined by the public housing agency or owner:</text><subparagraph id="ideb8eeb0f0acd4bc080f1e913b2f8b15b"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Unsubsidized employment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id085496110fff4071ae4b1d042c54494a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Subsidized private sector employment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id144ef7dfb56f41438976a7d73a15e8a8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Subsidized public sector employment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idcbe7fc54093140d18ac90bf9b2e082ee"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Work experience (including work associated with the refurbishing of publicly assisted housing) if sufficient private sector employment is not available.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbaa2a12d17134d9e9e90d4a743eb2f63"><enum>(E)</enum><text>On-the-job training.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id09a074ef82d2420d95c40a51a3b7049a"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Job search and job readiness assistance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida53f4a9f7d36418e96e5740eff2c9054"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Community service programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id43295f9072a54a1b8e5a4e2b16561e49"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Vocational educational training.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ida4c06629149c4a31aae75141e9f16298"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Job skills training directly related to employment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7f2054fe960b48bda002ea223f4f6966"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Education directly related to employment, in the case of a recipient who has not received a high school diploma or a certificate of high school equivalency, or satisfactory attendance at secondary school or in a course of study leading to a certificate of general equivalence, in the case of a recipient who has not completed secondary school or received such a certificate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idca69424d6abd4622929e639f21db7daa"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The provision of child care services to an individual who is participating in a community service program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9458b6cd7eed4ca289aa09d2593c5bfc"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>A public housing agency or owner that establishes minimum work requirements for individuals or families under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="idb17064ecd77d4de499f81297b96767fc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offer supportive services to assist those individuals and families with obtaining employment or otherwise engaging in work activities described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id37992161428c41de9f37d844ea3b5ddb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain uniform minimum work requirements for all applicable tenants within a particular assistance program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="iddfa9fe14d3764e9288c24814082d74c2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include the minimum work requirements policy—</text><clause id="idcc1475a0cc014991bcf8567e7c1a56ad"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of assistance provided under section 9, in the admission and continued occupancy policy of the public housing agency; and</text></clause><clause id="idbfdd28c055a14cc1bc1046f0656bc0de"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of assistance provided under section 8, in the administrative plan of the public housing agency and the tenant selection plan of the public housing agency or owner, as applicable;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idfd9b902b3c054df095a31c486b6e3026"><enum>(D)</enum><text>make a copy of the minimum work requirements policy available to all applicants, tenants, and resident organizations, including—</text><clause id="id14025f218ce9494b905bb096a0233ea4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to tenants at the time a new lease is executed and annually at the time of lease renewal; and</text></clause><clause id="id7ac49911c872483cb6637db9fc23f9be"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>written notice of the policy not later than 3 months before implementation of the policy; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id569f782124ad4c7c815afc7cdf3e82f1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implement a written policy for determining when the work requirement constitutes a hardship for the assisted individual or family and allow for exceptions or exemptions from the work requirement if a hardship determination is made, which shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idff16da717f0c4b28af672624783241c4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">apply to—</text><subclause id="id1f004c078a2549efbacbea41cbeeba7c"><enum>(I)</enum><text>work-eligible adults seeking a determination of disability status;</text></subclause><subclause id="id6aa1045c75b349a2af14f6659d10fa50"><enum>(II)</enum><text>work-eligible adults who are temporarily relocated due to a disaster; and</text></subclause><subclause id="id840c3ede64e34907a1c73eb616b224f5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>work-eligible adults who are actively trying to comply with the work requirement but are having difficulty finding work or engaging in work activity; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2726555440194b348a5ac3aed45cf9e5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include information on how to request a hearing for review of denied hardship requests.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6c7fa3847bd84d62b90674e33e075a44"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The requirements under this section shall apply to—</text><subparagraph id="id12a737361f294919824f41858a57b8d8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of public housing, tenant-based assistance, or project-based assistance, a public housing agency that is not in receivership or designated as a troubled performer under the public housing assessment system, the section 8 management assessment program, or the small rural public housing agency assessment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id04545c31d119434aa1f398d8e6465788"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of project-based assistance, an owner that is not in default of the rental assistance contract and has a current satisfactory management and occupancy review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id17e60cc84dee4e4eaff62936b05425ca"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8261f6bc3a0b4766a37369cbd1196c2d"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A public housing agency or owner that chooses to implement work requirements shall be responsible for verification and enforcement, which—</text><clause id="idf4caa44d2f0047afa750a673aa14bd3f"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be performed not less frequently than annually; and</text></clause><clause id="id9f00c9ef62c74c89b14d3262c5ba62f1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may terminate program assistance to a covered family or family member to whom the work requirement policies apply, if the family member does not comply.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb52e517356094155bddcda5ac9836b61"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Any termination of assistance described in subparagraph (A)(ii) shall comply with the requirements of subpart L of part 982 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="id31b5f8e77be946a8b3d37106ab2641df"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall take effect on January 1, 2027.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

