<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAC545FEF0D1646D29B26861A8AD2EA06" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8787 IH: Servicemember Payment Data Privacy and Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260513">May 13, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001132">Mr. Crane</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001224">Mr. Self</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Defense from contracting with retailers who use covered payment processing equipment, systems, or services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H00DA42A199D642569C26DEAE736B616E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H12D5069C62404532961A463A288C95BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Servicemember Payment Data Privacy and Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBDC92B5840414F54BC00409F59219D92"><enum>2.</enum><header>Elimination of use of certain payment processing equipment, systems, or services</header> <subsection id="HED0A80AB7BCB48069315B0D4B5309856" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Defense shall complete a review of all retailers to determine if such retailers use covered equipment, systems, or services as a substantial or essential component of the performance of a contract to provide payment processing equipment, systems, or services for the Department of Defense.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB8B45CE7D4D4111B8DE1B3EA455B669"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after completing the review required by subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall issue guidance prohibiting the use of covered equipment, systems, or services by a retailer in a contract with the Department of Defense. Such policy and guidance shall direct the modification or termination of such a contract unless the retailer for such contract ceases use of covered equipment, systems, or services in a timely manner.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H6D7C1F1C41534C90A358C972D868E237"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective January 1, 2027, the Secretary of Defense may not enter into a contract for payment processing equipment, systems, or services with a retailer that uses covered equipment, systems, or services as a substantial or essential component of the performance of such contract.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9D15439AC0A4EFB96C98910F4C5C17A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a written report on the implementation on the requirements of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H161C89AF4A7949A6B4F8215B35678692"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H31A690FC1BE345A890E7A03163F1EB8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HDDF22B11E1C2436DAFEBFA6E11749330"><enum>(A)</enum><text>China;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD301C00611BF455CBE59BEA63040D373"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Russia;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1690350683824054A37175FF20FD615C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Islamic Republic of Iran;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4CD3A95224194E8BA20D4C800A2A274D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>North Korea; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB69B7038929B432FAE1739E690485AD0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other country designated by the Secretary of Defense, as posing a significant risk to the national security of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6BCE7D14AED488BB968CBA077687D5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered equipment, system, or service</header><text>The term <term>covered equipment, system, or service</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H23B5C84696AA49AE929FECB9691BC763"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a payment processing equipment, system, or service for which the application processor, source code, secure processor, or secure firmware is directly or indirectly developed, manufactured, provided, owned, controlled, or operated by—</text> 
<clause id="H4F2E17CED70C4B47ABF5952F911BD262"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of a country of concern;</text></clause> <clause id="H63770D73F8CC4D719BD43E3BAB6A051D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity owned or controlled by the government of a country of concern;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5509D891184445C799C0C5BC8E59E66A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an entity subject to the direction, jurisdiction, or control of the government, military, or intelligence services of a country of concern;</text></clause> <clause id="H5CC74D13EF67468B9CA2D85C94511A35"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any subsidiary, affiliate, or successor entity of an entity described in clauses (i) through (iii); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCDBED8CCBCB84BA2A35D26A80B0E4A3F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>an entity that the Secretary of Defense reasonably believes to be an entity owned or controlled by, or otherwise connected entity owned or controlled by a country of concern; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD78FCBB71614F80956DAFDAE728C35A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes payment processing equipment, systems, or services substantially comprised of components, software, or technology supplied by an entity described in any of clauses (i) through (v) of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAB65C4E169BB4683A172014853FF1A42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Electronic fund transfer</header><text>The term <term>electronic fund transfer</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E48077515F3436F95E28BB8B1313631"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any transfer of funds, other than a transaction originated by check, draft, or similar paper instrument, which is initiated through an electronic terminal (as defined in section 903 of the Electronic Fund Transfer Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1693a">15 U.S.C. 1693a</external-xref>)), telephone, or computer or magnetic tape so as to order, instruct, or authorize a financial institution to debit or credit an account; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H945AD78E0AD94BAD8509AB902A9945AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes point-of-sale transfers, automated teller machine transactions, and direct deposits or withdrawals of funds from an account.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB397DF9E9E2D4ABEA47C85EC737F8AFD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Payment processing equipment, system, or service</header><text>The term <term>payment processing equipment, system, or service</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0AF80696FF5E4FD19F89CBE9C4C7C3C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a card, code, or other means of access to a consumer’s account, or any combination thereof, that may be used by the consumer to initiate electronic fund transfers; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14EE51C9B2504FBCB8BFECAAE803FBE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an electronic device, other than a telephone operated by a consumer, through which a consumer may initiate an electronic fund transfer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H826EEF6532474561BDE4BD67FFDF8BF4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Retailer</header><text>The term <term>retailer</term> has the meaning given in section 4664 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

