<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H038EE649AC394C85B09D0E3FDA32C65A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9494 IH: Haitian Refugee Immigration Fairness Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260625">June 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001324">Mr. Bell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000481">Mr. Figures</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000476">Mr. Frost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000309">Mr. Jackson of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for adjustment of status for certain nationals of Haiti, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H66C96CF573E1473F8039D4CA1AF92893" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HED7B6547C58C4B47B2F2E724D82DDEFF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Haitian Refugee Immigration Fairness Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H91BF50FFACC34B499DF77FB3B461C8FA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Haitian refugee immigration fairness</header> 
<subsection id="HCC72444E1547457CB95507CE61DB49B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H48A57360EF7A4F79ADE9CEE62E79C5D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided, any term used in this Act that is used in the immigration laws shall have the meaning given the term in the immigration laws.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCDAD9EDB7F3B4B0F8A0EC70BC045991A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Attorney General</term> includes the Executive Office for Immigration Review and an immigration judge exercising jurisdiction under section 240 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229a">8 U.S.C. 1229a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF22F9B9DD1584832BB40E7F5C793C5EE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Immigration laws</header><text>The term <term>immigration laws</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF151B028E2784B5EBF8F645D7F0835AE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8E877650BE80437F91BB9DD652E3050C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header> <paragraph id="H49A238FD874B4A9799DECEC2CB2BF46F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall adjust the status of an alien described in subsection (c) to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if the alien—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE385D3CB4DF746DD8E7E6D6157BF1229"><enum>(A)</enum><text>applies for adjustment not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H970A9DC65A7D4EB6B682F3BCE1C447E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), is admissible to the United States for permanent residence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54DDE4759C76406089E084BFFF432AB3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of grounds of inadmissibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the admissibility of an alien under paragraph (1)(B), the grounds of inadmissibility specified in paragraphs (4), (5), (6)(A), (7)(A), and (9) of section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) shall not apply.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE77FEA496894F7997F21160B3134950"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>An alien shall not be eligible for adjustment of status under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the alien—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7411A4CDABE140EE942C23197BC4E187"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been convicted of any aggravated felony;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H677F88B5502E43A095068407FF2B6D2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been convicted of two or more crimes involving moral turpitude (other than a purely political offense); or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF541AA78A8A448FD8103FC682FEF8B04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has ordered, incited, assisted, or otherwise participated in the persecution of any person on account of race, religion, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H328185B6CD714D918E59591EE22CE678"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Relationship of application to certain orders</header> <subparagraph id="H1800689DB59D436AA8BE21435821B86F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien present in the United States who has been subject to an order of exclusion, deportation, removal, or voluntary departure under any provision of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) may, notwithstanding such order, submit an application for adjustment of status under this subsection if the alien is otherwise eligible for adjustment of status under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFA10E67B2FD044159D40DC75EC7B7CB8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Separate motion not required</header><text>An alien described in subparagraph (A) shall not be required, as a condition of submitting or granting an application under this subsection, to file a separate motion to reopen, reconsider, or vacate an order described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1AFFE8AFC0C949D78B54AD1F609AEF46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of decision by Secretary</header> <clause id="H77A736A153FE4B45B73C88EC0AB14512"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Grant</header><text>If the Secretary adjusts the status of an alien pursuant to an application under this subsection, the Secretary shall cancel any order described in subparagraph (A) to which the alien has been subject.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H35D50BBCABC94849BF047A7DA82043B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Denial</header><text>If the Secretary makes a final decision to deny such application, any such order shall be effective and enforceable to the same extent that such order would be effective and enforceable if the application had not been made.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCA35D58FEDB84BDAAECD27A1B562FCE3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Aliens eligible for adjustment of status</header> <paragraph id="HD7ECAEF193804F4EBE5D53392D7B6FE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The benefits provided under subsection (b) shall apply to any alien who—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCC5847341CF543889E48D17AB98D1505"><enum>(A)</enum> 
<clause id="HB139453212CC4212B8AE87EB8C07A9AA" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a national of Haiti; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCCB1FFB62D044C6EADC7CFFDA9B78152" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has been continuously present in the United States during the period beginning on June 26, 2024, and ending on the date on which the alien submits an application under subsection (b); or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EE167EE580E40728BE09ABD5CB957A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is the spouse, child, or unmarried son or daughter of an alien described in subparagraph (A).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD206B02AE87488DBBE7943C9D1C6186"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of continuous physical presence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of establishing the period of continuous physical presence referred to in subparagraph (B), an alien shall not be considered to have failed to maintain continuous physical presence as a result of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF9C49675D0F142D482DDE724844BC635"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one or more absences from the United States for one or more periods of time amounting, in the aggregate, to not more than 180 days;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4B6D0FA86CD462AA03C1C380C86C54E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>travel authorized by the Secretary, including travel pursuant to advance parole; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE3E1E49568B141CFB0B78285F603E3CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a departure, removal, or voluntary departure occurring on or after February 3, 2026, or on or after the effective date of any termination of temporary protected status for Haiti under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>), whichever is earlier, and before the date of enactment of this Act, if the alien otherwise satisfied the requirements of this subsection prior to such departure or removal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD68BC323400D42E1A7E7EB51BF406E6C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Stay of removal</header> <paragraph id="HB2A832049AF94695869A4C863A1A4B48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations establishing procedures by which an alien who is subject to a final order of deportation, removal, or exclusion, may seek a stay of such order based on the filing of an application under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H103EB68E1EBE4984A9BE60BDBAFF39EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>During certain proceedings</header> 
<subparagraph id="H93EC90607BC54B77A42A8ACE3B822C13"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), notwithstanding any provision of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary or the Attorney General, as applicable, may not order an alien to be removed from the United States if the alien—</text> <clause id="HD108F405D5044BCBBFF24B233EBA5E65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is in exclusion, deportation, or removal proceedings under any provision of such Act; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4C8B652A131B4B0B8FB2ED1BA7BC76B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has submitted an application for adjustment of status under subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCFC3DB6FBF640CF8D3BEA2942ADAF56"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary or the Attorney General, as applicable, may order an alien described in subparagraph (A) to be removed from the United States if the Secretary has made a final determination to deny the application for adjustment of status under subsection (b) of the alien.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86F0A692529646358BA1B1BEED9CA5C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Work authorization</header> 
<subparagraph id="H7BAB3BF6297B4B7FAF3FC5525D9B7FB3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize an alien who has applied for adjustment of status under subsection (b) to engage in employment in the United States during the period in which a determination on such application is pending.</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H253B90F6BB224F0397A5AFD66ACEDBE3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pending applications</header><text>If an application for adjustment of status under subsection (b) is pending for a period exceeding 180 days and has not been denied, the Secretary shall authorize employment for the applicable alien.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H87BC0C4CD778499D93BEB1B12EB718D4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Record of permanent residence</header><text>On the approval of an application for adjustment of status under subsection (b) of an alien, the Secretary shall establish a record of admission for permanent residence for the alien as of the date of the arrival of the alien in the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H627EAFD171C3440F9875C13982F94D62"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability of administrative review</header><text>The Secretary shall provide applicants for adjustment of status under subsection (b) with the same right to, and procedures for, administrative review as are provided to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H11CD570AE8A149219A91650DF2923E84"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applicants for adjustment of status under section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDF096A834D046F6AE0F940EAC853B90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aliens subject to removal proceedings under section 240 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1229a">8 U.S.C. 1229a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H939AD04E8547464188A1AA43F14C8216"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Judicial review</header> 
<paragraph id="HB7A7B5927B3C41FFAD412AF5A9E9151F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Judicial review of a final order of removal under this section shall be governed by section 242 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1252">8 U.S.C. 1252</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC9D8F710C48413DABA27EA621819054"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to preclude the review of a constitutional claim or a question of law under section 242(a)(2)(D) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1252">8 U.S.C. 1252(a)(2)(D)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HAC5FCE2C3A7040C3AA86DE17CAF8A97E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>No offset in number of visas available</header><text>The Secretary of State shall not be required to reduce the number of immigrant visas authorized to be issued under any provision of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) to offset the adjustment of status of an alien who has been lawfully admitted for permanent residence pursuant to this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA1A2C591424D4662987C5CE298A6DBFF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application of Immigration and Nationality Act provisions</header> <paragraph id="H1C1C6FB0360F4FC8A67E7FEBD83155F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to repeal, amend, alter, modify, effect, or restrict the powers, duties, function, or authority of the Secretary in the administration and enforcement of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other law relating to immigration, nationality, or naturalization.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A56FAEA2C8840BFB862B0ACDE29F234"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of eligibility for adjustment of status</header><text>The eligibility of an alien to be lawfully admitted for permanent residence under this section shall not preclude the alien from seeking any status under any other provision of law for which the alien may otherwise be eligible.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

