<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC51BB4FAD4384E43BF66E88F305D9F81" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8087 IH: Main Street Depositor Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8087</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260325">March 25, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to provide deposit insurance for noninterest-bearing transaction accounts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H25953CE912F84E3EBE016D505D07F596" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H76FA888217F140EAAD4F48F42DF6B1CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Main Street Depositor Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFB7B1F5772A24DB38943A28E2953EF6A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transaction account insurance</header> <subsection id="H80D7524D88F34C6FB9E3D238E326D69C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Depository institutions</header> <paragraph id="HAE8924E7385140D8B45CE9EBEEF0B65A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 11(a)(1) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1821">12 U.S.C. 1821(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C19A476532148A0B395ED9D74983D58"> 
<subparagraph id="HED54446D387A498E98FEB8A684B70557"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Net amount of insured deposit</header> 
<clause id="HCCF2B3F8728447CAA65067C8FC517D82"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The net amount due to any depositor at an insured depository institution shall not exceed the sum of—</text> <subclause id="HA3BF0FEA3CD147F28983674B4987203D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the standard maximum deposit insurance amount as determined in accordance with subparagraphs (C), (D), (E), and (F) and paragraph (3); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4AE40A37B3694918A1661B256BE969AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the net amount under clause (ii).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H80A3316B2344420598088EAE4A8EFD00" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Insurance for noninterest-bearing transaction accounts</header> <subclause id="H6915649B7A76410BA182948F0E81FFC2" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subclause (IV), not later than the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this clause, the Corporation shall insure the net amount that any depositor maintains, in the aggregate, in 1 or more noninterest-bearing transaction accounts at an insured depository institution, in the amount determined under subclause (II).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4FCB8B4F2E574F128D6278248274854C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Insured amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation shall issue a rule to establish the maximum amount for insurance described in subclause (I), which shall be in an amount that is—</text> <item id="H666DC2F6724C4E129F868AE492D40141"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>not less than the standard maximum deposit insurance amount on the date such rule is issued;</text></item> 
<item id="H0313FDE9B45E49CAA1269C63D552A536"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>not more than $5,000,000; and</text></item> <item id="H8B507A62452341DE9A730DAEE0556343"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on considerations of enhancing the financial stability of the banking system, promoting economic growth, and providing for the safety of the Deposit Insurance Fund.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5034E0BDFFFA475B9F0139BBC999F8A0"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Aggregation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of determining the net amount due to any depositor under subclause (I), the Corporation shall aggregate the amounts of all deposits in noninterest-bearing transaction accounts at insured depository institutions that are subsidiaries of a single depository institution holding company.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H50F24ECA227E4630A51770390E181A88" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Exclusion</header> <item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE9B97CC2F3C4D7A8B20B4EDB0566CBE"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subclause, the term <term>foreign bank</term> does not include any bank organized under the laws of any territory of the United States, Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, or the Virgin Islands, the deposits of which are insured by the Corporation pursuant to this Act.</text></item> 
<item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91A894C7BFEE4673B7E80C247B115EAC"><enum>(bb)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation may not insure under subclause (I) amounts maintained at—</text> <subitem id="HB3525D2BE9E042349ED0851BB6F093BE" commented="no"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>any insured depository institution that is a subsidiary of a bank holding company that is identified as a global systemically important BHC under section 217.402 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation); or</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H80AC5F60CC4D454FABDDB2515F2FA60A" commented="no"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>any insured branch of a foreign bank.</text></subitem></item> <item id="HFF5AB0A214F94AC1BE87F352A3124631"><enum>(cc)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subclause may be construed to exclude any insured depository institution described in subitem (AA) from the standard maximum deposit insurance amount described in clause (i)(I).</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD86F4FAD5D48431DB70BA8AF0FE53C0B"><enum>(V)</enum><header>No subsequent adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the Corporation issues a rule pursuant to subclause (II), the amount of insurance provided under subclause (I) may not subsequently be modified or repealed except by an Act of Congress.</text></subclause> </clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E25D1D3D7E44CE9991A7587898BCCA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 3(m) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H29FC1F0B8D534AF79626EAE6E01FA380"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>, including deposits in a noninterest-bearing transaction account,</quote> after <quote>deposits</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B030CF4D43242E1B9656B66ABC8AB18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H264E22A798C244FE83BDB2961CFCEAA2"> 
<paragraph id="H773F420751294044911537645B2ADF83"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Noninterest-bearing transaction account</header><text>The term <term>noninterest-bearing transaction account</term> means a deposit or account maintained at an insured depository institution—</text> <subparagraph id="HBF9D666B55E1412ABD73D7038B033983"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to which interest is neither accrued nor paid;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H374CA89DD4414FA3ADD2B93FF7BC36AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on which the depositor or account holder is permitted to make withdrawals by negotiable or transferable instrument, payment orders of withdrawal, telephone or other electronic media transfers, or other similar items for the purpose of making payments or transfers to third parties or others; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF8134229FCF64031B3D2243CED1D2FBE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on which the insured depository institution does not reserve the right to require advance notice of an intended withdrawal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8EAC2964823F448DB98C71D1E9CEA4D9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assessments</header><text>During the transition period under subsection (c), no insured depository institution with total assets of $10,000,000,000 or less shall be required to pay—</text> <subparagraph id="H1285E493B821424F82DDD38DD29FBCDD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any special assessment under section 7(b)(5) or 13(c)(4)(G) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1817">12 U.S.C. 1817(b)(5)</external-xref>, 1823(c)(4)(G)) as a condition to insurance on a noninterest-bearing transaction account, as defined in paragraph (5) of section 3(m) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(m)</external-xref>), as added by paragraph (2) of this subsection; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H59E3D3817B66464695BBFF84715B31FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any increase in assessments under section 7(b)(2) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1817">12 U.S.C. 1817(b)(2)</external-xref>) solely to offset any impact on the reserve ratio arising out of the extension of insurance to noninterest-bearing transaction accounts in excess of the standard maximum deposit insurance amount as determined in accordance with subparagraphs (C), (D), (E), and (F) of paragraph (1) and paragraph (3) of section 11(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1821">12 U.S.C. 1821(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC3D126289EAE43FA95C324EBAF7D255A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit unions</header> <paragraph id="HCEA2DF29F9DC46D18F880AD4131C2213"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 207(k)(1)(A) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1787">12 U.S.C. 1787(k)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3DB1F7DB6DF94632B1454B96354560A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Subject to the provisions of paragraph (2), the net amount</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H467E0F1700FF44679779215CB91AB921"> <clause id="H17D60E9D4E5044A1878658DE20977BC2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Net amount of insurance payable</header><text>Subject to clause (ii) and the provisions of paragraph (2), the net amount</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCDB9B2BFB8C04CE391F37DB24C100B35"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H54BDC5C008014FB0AC26398868ADA1AE"> <clause id="H5EA1AEF37C0F449B94622E23B7039061"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Insurance for noninterest-bearing transaction accounts</header> <subclause id="H604B651158E2461CB931B733833FEB00"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clause (i), the Board shall insure the net amount that any member, or any person with funds lawfully held in a member account, maintains, in the aggregate, in 1 or more noninterest-bearing transaction accounts at an insured credit union.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE2FD02332655462BB4B3CEE2BC04C1E9"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Insured amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum amount for insurance described in subclause (I) shall be the maximum amount determined in the rule issued by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation pursuant to section 11(a)(1)(B)(ii)(II) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1821">12 U.S.C. 1821(a)(1)(B)(ii)(II)</external-xref>).</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE57D37C75556499BAC01E6B8890056FD"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The amount described in subclause (I) shall not be taken into account when computing the net amount due to a member, or to any person with funds lawfully held in a member account, described in that subclause under clause (i).</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C4E7A5D17E6438082192769CF3156EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H29D879C100F84AE683CC6E623CBD74A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by inserting <quote>such terms mean a noninterest-bearing transaction account,</quote> after <quote>Act,</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFCDF7AD0F35C40068A3EA0D9A1A71F14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE57154E5E4443BD8B3E3DFB936296EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B0DA1CC43C645279DEA64FD306E9EC4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBFD5C13F71E6472A89EA83573FF52BFA"> <paragraph id="H02145209C0DA4BD181879968BBA84082"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The term <term>noninterest-bearing transaction account</term> means an account of a member, or nonmember that is eligible to maintain an insured account, maintained at an insured credit union—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4B534B747F28442784FE5D8D9709D52B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to which interest is neither accrued nor paid;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE08C57C73004724BB5DB92434B4C943"><enum>(B)</enum><text>on which the member or account holder is permitted to make withdrawals by negotiable or transferable instrument, payment orders of withdrawal, telephone or other electronic media transfers, or other similar items for the purpose of making payments or transfers to third parties or others; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2487C2F80D24E6B86B0117EA93726AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>on which the insured credit union does not reserve the right to require advance notice of an intended withdrawal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H37752320478848DFB5AC7E55097FCEE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transition period</header> <paragraph id="HAF46E8B12631471794DFF9B6CADEA7A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Depository institutions</header> <subparagraph id="HC80CF3DDC6814A40B5543CCD028A4728"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, insured deposits in noninterest-bearing transaction accounts, as described in clause (ii) of section 11(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1821">12 U.S.C. 1821(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a)(1) of this section, shall be included in the determination of the value of the estimated insured deposits described in sections 3(y)(3) and 7(b)(3)(B) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813(y)(3)</external-xref>, 1817(b)(3)(B)) in accordance with the plan required under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72B03A36EE584E1CB2D67A0C9920FDB0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall publish in the Federal Register a plan for gradually increasing, during the period ending on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the portion of insured deposits described in subparagraph (A) in the determination described in that subparagraph, reaching 100 percent at the end of the period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1578B4E27DF34EB8A6DA8603DC91B726"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit unions</header> <subparagraph id="H0932BC16E80A48F7B7978B4C306BCAAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, insured shares in noninterest-bearing transaction accounts, as described in clause (ii) of section 207(k)(1)(A) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1787">12 U.S.C. 1787(k)(1)(A)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (b)(1) of this section, shall be included in the determination of the value of the aggregate amount of the insured shares, as defined in section 202(h) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1782">12 U.S.C. 1782(h)</external-xref>), in accordance with the plan required under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EACFF52F7E14EED812EBF259AC64D60"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the National Credit Union Administration Board shall publish in the Federal Register a plan for gradually increasing, during the period ending on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the portion of insured shares described in subparagraph (A) in the determination described in that subparagraph, reaching 100 percent at the end of the period.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA2A8C51464D847E29599353B2462D2C4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The National Credit Union Administration Board may promulgate regulations to ensure that the National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund remains well-capitalized.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0629972BFF0642398820EC7FEB315B4F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and the National Credit Union Administration Board may promulgate regulations carrying out the amendments made by this section, including prohibiting insured depository institutions, as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>), insured credit unions, as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>), and third parties, as applicable, from evading the limitation of insurance established under those amendments to only—</text> <paragraph id="HEDD82151F63F4E8593382FC676CFDDCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>noninterest-bearing transaction accounts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19AB3DFA54C24977A39245FC69D8F48B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deposits or accounts at insured depository institutions not excluded under clause (ii)(IV) of section 11(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1821">12 U.S.C. 1821(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a) of this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45CA6C7BA0F1454F8B81FF81062E651D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shares, deposits, or accounts at insured credit unions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

