<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H304FB52AE1274D99BDE8409494CE636D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7169 IH: Understanding Basic English Requirements Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7169</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260121">January 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001317">Mr. Brecheen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000484">Mr. Fine</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require English proficiency as a prerequisite for eligibility for ride share contracts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC744CA3E919D43C082FFDEF4FFC27A99" style="OLC"><section id="H2B216EDA2B974E66B7270F1006C1DAED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Understanding Basic English Requirements Act of 2026</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>UBER Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H356ED557029040FC8DC45B97A76E242A"><enum>2.</enum><header>English proficiency and other driver requirements for ride share contract eligibility</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H960C04475EE9450BB4F051335778EB46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10FD442D46514D23942D2FFC3C1FF777"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The head of an executive agency may not award an agreement or a contract with any transportation network company or shared-use mobility company for services provided in the continental United States, Alaska, or Hawaii where unless each driver who will be performing work under the agreement or contract—</text><subparagraph id="H1A91BA38222C4D0B961C07212B088446"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is at least 21 years old;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D35D7B9099E4338AD4F93617683C476"><enum>(B)</enum><text>can read and speak English sufficiently to converse with the general public, law enforcement, and other officials, understand highway traffic signs, respond to official inquiries, and make entries on reports and records;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31ECA9831C3E4CF48FA78E337B77E6A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>can, by reason of experience, training, or both, safely operate the type of vehicle the driver drives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6540D89ED91D441F9884D67DDBA7BFCE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has a currently valid driver's license issued only by one State or jurisdiction; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H636F8A4E96BA42F695B473053B6A320A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>has successfully completed a driver's road test.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD2AA6467BAEB4CE79C56BE6912D0BCEA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for American Sign Language</header><text>The requirement under paragraph (1)(B) does not apply to drivers who are deaf or hearing impaired and use American Sign Language.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H626FFD35393B42DEBCC0D6FA8D9122BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Compliance certification and debarment</header><text>A transportation network company or shared-use mobility company shall be required, for purposes of eligibility for an agreement or contract described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a), to certify to the head of the executive agency that all drivers for the company who will be performing work under such agreement or contract meet the requirements set forth in subsection (a)(1). Any company found to not be in compliance with such certification shall be debarred from receiving Federal contracts for a period of 5 years.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC337A9FE2ADB48B09499B5460B8F16D7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEAC4F4144220436B80E667DE3FFD5646"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4145FB369D87424AA68C3E32E41F82D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Shared-use mobility company</header><text>The term <term>shared-use mobility company</term> means a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other licensed and operating entity that provides transportation services that are shared among users, including taxis, limos, bikesharing, ridesharing (such as carpooling and vanpooling), ridesourcing, scooter sharing, or shuttle services.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H28085DC13EAB4C7AACFB33FAA2237D80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transportation network company</header><text>The term <term>transportation network company</term> means a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other licensed and operating entity that uses a digital network to connect a transportation network company (TNC) rider to a TNC driver who provides a prearranged ride. A TNC may not control, direct, or manage the personal vehicle or the TNC driver who connects to its digital network, except where agreed to by written contract.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

