<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5A52C41ED1204498ADCE280B62CD0686" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6072 IH: No Aid for Illegal Entry Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6072</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251117">November 17, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funds by non-governmental organizations and the Department of the Interior for certain immigration-related services, except in the case of a minor.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H12DC4BC058F8460A96AC2EF172E7CA62" style="OLC"><section id="H76D67F27FC6344E2AB5D411233F13D35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Aid for Illegal Entry Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB89316FBED134A54815B48697826C3DF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition of Federal funds for certain immigration-related services</header><subsection id="HBCD95AD75628477E94C47B2E315F844A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds</header><paragraph id="H76FF382CA3B846119FA114FB64625FD8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-Governmental Organizations</header><text>No Federal funds may be awarded, granted, or otherwise made available to any non-governmental organization to—</text><subparagraph id="HBF33901B776640E3ACC0B04AF1CD4861"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide legal services related to immigration proceedings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A32EDC498D448619E6574E1B36A7011"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">house, shelter, or otherwise provide accommodations to any an alien who is present in the United States without lawful status under the immigration laws; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H010A2E017C6B4C6FA73A55CDC60FDF18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transport any individual who entered the United States in violation of the immigration laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H566D42E9BB9341A2A65FC36D1D6811C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply to a non-governmental organization who uses the Federal funds to provide legal services, housing, or transportation to a minor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB9D9DD834874B259FE6C908922F9967"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department of Interior</header><text>The Department of the Interior, including all bureaus, offices, and agencies under its authority, may not administer, manage, or enter into a contract or agreement relating to—</text><subparagraph id="H9857DF0D993545BF9A386966EAD5C357"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provision of services described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1B22F5026414F7BAADF15A7BE136601"><enum>(B)</enum><text>migrant resettlement, immigration enforcement, or immigration legal representation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92B41F0158194120A192C9F88AA56D4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of each Government agency shall take such actions as are reasonably necessary to ensure that a non-governmental organization awarded, granted, or otherwise receiving Federal funds is in compliance with the prohibition under subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="HFCE73012F0E34851BCBE09013B4CE923"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date of enactment and shall apply to any grant, award, contract, or funding agreement entered into on or after such date.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE390075DD70342D3AA9C50D04460F578"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HFE899B0138CB41D2AA2BBC933312CC35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Government agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>government agency</quote> means a subdivision of the executive, legislative, judicial, or other branch of government, including a department, independent establishment, commission, administration, authority, board, and bureau, and a corporation or other legal entity established, and subject to control, by a government or governments for the execution of a governmental or intergovernmental program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4209FFEA4D7478CB153667F78796A34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immigration laws</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>immigration laws</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H039206E28C6C44ABA56E0CDDC60C93A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Legal services related to immigration proceedings</header><text>The term <quote>legal services related to immigration proceedings</quote> includes representation in, advice with respect to, or preparation of documents for any immigration application, petition, removal proceeding, or related process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D3B1099D2394D94A8B00925BB206A72"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minor</header><text>The term <quote>minor</quote> means an alien under the age of 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1BBB4286A404220AC23B9407AC7776E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-governmental organization</header><text>The term <quote>non-governmental organization</quote> means any entity that is not a Federal, State, Tribal, or local government agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

