<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD8A07683FA8D4A32B7AD679B4A0E8CA3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6639 IH: Water Agency and Transparency Enhancement Review (WATER) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6639</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251211">December 11, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000605">Mr. Gray</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify certain sections of Executive Order 14181 relating to emergency measures to provide water resources in California and improve disaster response in certain areas.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA8F6C2E150C94BB1B86F7427017E5D66" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H76BEFFE809F542C0B7685562E60E895D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Agency and Transparency Enhancement Review (WATER) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H103C258611FE4E5FBBC4679DB9CCA831"><enum>2.</enum><header>Plans to address regulatory hurdles for major water-supply and storage projects</header> <subsection id="HB26DBF583E6049799EFD97AC725F6AE2"> <enum>(a)</enum> <header>Identification of major water-Supply and storage projects</header> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce shall identify all ongoing or potential major water-supply and storage projects (including surface and ground water storage projects, aquifer recharge projects, and State conveyance projects) within the State of California for which they have joint responsibility under section 7(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(a)</external-xref>) or individual responsibilities under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text>
      </subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD2E35305CD045608F098448BC6D258B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plans</header> 
<paragraph id="HE7185E5415AC402990FEAB376E151984"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of compliance officials</header><text>With respect to the projects identified under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Commerce shall each designate one Federal official to coordinate each agency’s respective compliance responsibilities under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFDB77C764C644F1BCCD6E8A05BDA713"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification of regulatory hurdles</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, each Federal official designated under paragraph (1) shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5958B829FBE04A57BFFC714DE12B7D84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify any regulatory hurdles that unduly burden each project identified under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B8DCB418F6A47C0A93CD8682FFC4CD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify any recent changes in applicable State or Federal law that may impact such projects from a regulatory perspective, including changes made by the Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/118/5">Public Law 118–5</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0FC57F85CD84ADEB22830CB3A32FDCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop a proposed plan, for review by the Secretaries, to appropriately suspend, revise, or rescind any regulations or procedures that unduly burden such projects and are not necessary to protect the public interest or otherwise comply with the law.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H034A58A4ED234BC48A899C1898D0F3A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (2), each Federal official designated under paragraph (1) shall coordinate and share all appropriate information that will enable improved efficiencies.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D266911B08C4588917EB8D0350E8909" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unduly burden defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>unduly burden</term> means to unnecessarily obstruct, delay, curtail, impede, or otherwise impose significant costs on the permitting, utilization, transmission, delivery, or supply of water resources and water infrastructure.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

