<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-MDM25M09-DLK-NG-YKV"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 S3508 IS: Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2025</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3508</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251216">December 16, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S364">Mr. Murphy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S362">Mr. Kaine</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S369">Mr. Markey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S253">Mr. Durbin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S366">Ms. Warren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To require the transfer of regulatory control of certain munitions exports from the Department of Commerce to the Department of State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H02772B642EAD42EA9D04B87E8A2E8785"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6D49970119AC4E688110DB720A97DDE9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short titles; table of contents</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id68e9f0acd12e4c6eb0ced437d84dd562"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Short titles</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2025</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ARMAS Act of 2025</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id532fb716b20f46528d60790b4d3df7f6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H6D49970119AC4E688110DB720A97DDE9">Sec. 1. Short titles; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H54BCCBFCA10947A8AB49B9DA8AF9FCAA">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HFC17E36029ED46A190BE655E1F5D1AC4">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HFD93EEB20E9044A28574106C8056DFA5">Sec. 4. Transfer of regulatory control of certain munitions exports from the Department of Commerce to the Department of State.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HAFBAFD270CAA44E5BBE861D198C0886B">Sec. 5. Reports and strategy on disruption of illegal export and trafficking of firearms to Mexico and certain Central American and Caribbean countries.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 6. Increasing participation in the eTrace program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 7. Modifications to the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA66DFD3767CB42D2AA6432FA732D2712">Sec. 8. Designation of covered countries.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H30F225EFDFDC4F7BBE10A13B6917D015">Sec. 9. Certification requirements relating to certain munitions exports.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE680CAB8BBD94AFFA333E4E2A5B24325">Sec. 10. Limitation on licenses and other authorizations for export of certain items removed from the Commerce Control List and included on the United States Munitions List.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 11. Prohibitions on promotion of covered munitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H54BCCBFCA10947A8AB49B9DA8AF9FCAA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H31AD2EC65AE640CAA52456597675B156"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Violence in Mexico, Central America, and the Caribbean is exacerbated by firearms originating in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E26783292F5406E8576CBFA6D6DA9FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>While firearms are trafficked to Mexico from a variety of countries, firearms originating in the United States account for 70 percent of the firearms recovered and traced from crimes in Mexico, according to the 2021 Government Accountability Office (referred to in this section as <quote>GAO</quote>) report published by the Comptroller General of the United States and titled <quote>Firearms Trafficking: U.S. Efforts to Disrupt Gun Smuggling into Mexico Would Benefit from Additional Data and Analysis</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H071CF0D329D749778AFEBD6108986596"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States-origin firearm flows contribute to human rights violations, organized crime and gang violence, extrajudicial killings, high homicide rates, domestic violence, and femicides in Mexico, Central America, and the Caribbean.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E710CAA53A7460B97B91387BAB881B0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Firearms trafficking from the United States and firearm violence are key drivers of immigration and asylum claims from Central America.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H392928DFA00247BF99DA712DF7DAFB61"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the United Nations Regional Centre for Peace, Disarmament and Development in Latin America and the Caribbean—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31be8e3e99dd43a298126d541d953074"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">firearms are used in 70 percent of homicides in the Caribbean compared to 30 percent globally; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id54210984a9974c6facc81b69b37aa4c5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">while the Caribbean constitutes less than 1 percent of the global population, 23 percent of all recorded homicides worldwide take place in the Caribbean.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3C8118E07034336A13515A50077B795"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In an August 2022 press conference, Homeland Security Investigations officials reported a <quote>marked uptick in the number of weapons</quote> and an increase in the caliber and type of weapons being illegally trafficked to Haiti and the rest of the Caribbean.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H698EB5E0C26E488194B8BE27721A9CA8"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Caribbean Basin Security Initiative of the Department of State, which commenced in 2009—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc0b38c74343c456f87b6d78f3b4e4fb1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is the regional foreign assistance program of the United States that seeks to reduce illicit weapons trafficking in the Caribbean region and advance public safety and security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4a1f07a273dd49698d928cc1e499c576"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seeks to improve the capacity of Caribbean countries to intercept smuggled weapons at airports and seaports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id790f674dc8224c808d8949c9785acfbd"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides support for forensic ballistics and firearms destruction and stockpile management; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id34b8d2ad2f1b46ae81c29947bc5695e8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has also included support for regional organizations, including—</text><clause id="H8FA47A6E5C4A4C4DB43B0F0384BC0541"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Caribbean Community Implementation Agency for Crime and Security (CARICOM IMPACS), which based in Trinidad and Tobago, and is the lead agency involved in the issue of illicit firearms trafficking and increasing the capacity of member states to detect and prevent firearms trafficking; and</text></clause><clause id="HBF9F8C91887245CBBEC116682877A83D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Eastern Caribbean’s Regional Security System, which is based in Barbados.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C417F2690E74B72922F8E258C02603E"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two GAO reports on firearms trafficking, which were published in 2021 and 2022, respectively, have affirmed that firearms trafficking to Mexico and Central America continues to represent a security concern to the United States, as United States-origin firearms are diverted from legitimate owners and end up in the hands of violent criminals, including drug traffickers and other transnational criminal organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H101BF16AC78C4AB3B64481446604FDD8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In the reports referred to in paragraph (8), the Comptroller General of the United States determined that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8fa816b4423148e3bfa190622dcfc96e"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal departments and agencies lacked information and analysis of the firearms trafficking networks in Mexico and Central America;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id87fff6d46eff4486af0272cbfadc8693"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">few efforts by the United States Government in that region focused on firearms trafficking; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id530d058116ae460ba38595f01b3b0521"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal departments and agencies lack a detailed understanding of the firearms trafficking that fuels violence and arms criminals in Belize, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, and Mexico.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A740EA33C2943909485EE46B787524E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Firearms that were used to kidnap and kill a group of United States citizens traveling in Matamoros, Mexico were illegally smuggled from the United States into Mexico. The suspect in these killings admitted to Federal agents that he purchased firearms in the United States, smuggled them across the United States border, and knowingly provided them to members of the Gulf Cartel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73FB48B245174A7B92F0B631BB86201F"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the incident described in paragraph (10) demonstrates, United States-sourced firearms are being smuggled and diverted to cartels implicated in the supply and flow of illegal fentanyl and other dangerous drugs, which threatens the public health and safety of United States citizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44F22823EF6D471290C7E88BD1F732EA"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the 2022 GAO report titled <quote>Firearms Trafficking: More Information Needed to Inform U.S. Efforts in Central America</quote>, the Comptroller General of the United States—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idde60e238329f476690399a0ede19b241"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reported efforts of the United States Government focused on firearms trafficking in Belize, El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras lacked information about relevant country conditions and performance measures to ensure such efforts were designed and implemented to achieve the intended objectives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8afbc1916141420bb12fe6af9add0a69"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommended the Secretary of State obtain information about the conditions in such countries to support the development of effective programs to reduce the availability of illicit firearms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1797B813B354F33928F90A4F301E517"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As of the date of the publication of the report referred to in paragraph (12), the Secretary of Commerce had not assigned any agents to Central America on permanent assignment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D57FC6472474B759FE5115AD39CFB15"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2021 and 2022, the annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices of the Department of State included <quote>unlawful and arbitrary killings</quote> as a significant human rights issue in Guatemala. Despite such inclusion, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security has authorized approximately 99,270 firearms exports to Guatemala since assuming responsibility for firearms licensing on March 9, 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF6BC4F291F4D6AA1F4D6654482BDB6"><enum>(15)</enum><text>When firearms were controlled under the United States Munitions List and the licensing of firearms for export was the responsibility of the Secretary of State, the average number of firearms licensed for export to Guatemala was approximately 4,000 per year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7E35B40209E4C918204070CF845C9D3"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of firearms recently exported to Guatemala, as specified in paragraph (14), represents an extraordinary increase from the average number of firearms exported to Guatemala before the transfer of licensing responsibility, as specified in paragraph (15). According to the 2022 GAO report titled <quote>Firearms Trafficking: More Information Needed to Inform U.S. Efforts in Central America</quote>, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security has only been able to conduct a very limited number of end-use checks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB2344FB6E894798AC26D9175946D581"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since the Department of Commerce gained jurisdiction over the control of firearm export licensing—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1f37173931df4b588e888bee11a591f5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there has been a 30 percent increase in firearm exports compared to averages for such exports when the control of such exports was under the jurisdiction of the Department of State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id346f3aef060841c786581a298c9ab6d0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Commerce has approved approximately 95 percent of license applications for such exports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CD6596724A8495D86EE1E6E3D487F0B"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the United States Census Bureau, Mexico, Guatemala, and Brazil are among the top 10 destinations for United States-manufactured semiautomatic firearm exports.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1f615d74d5054517924cee137504fc5c"><enum>(19)</enum><text>The Bipartisan Safer Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/159">Public Law 117–159</external-xref>), which was enacted into law on June 25, 2022, implemented key efforts to address firearm trafficking, including by—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id46f2f230424e42e4814ba317ab89db58"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a Federal criminal offense for firearm trafficking; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddbae147b0a8a4e4a92389e79398c8459"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strengthening the capability of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives to interdict firearms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id253f3a5666f34ab1ac1ffe3e591de618"><enum>(20)</enum><text>A growing number of firearms exported by United States manufacturers are involved in violent crimes worldwide, such as the pistol used in a mass shooting of 23 children and 2 teachers in Thailand in October 2022, which was linked to a United States factory.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFC17E36029ED46A190BE655E1F5D1AC4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H07B5FB570B7949F980BE801460701BB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HCC3DC465F3D147B38A5AECBEC7653652"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c65726fdf044f1d94773b03f3429bc7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4bf2b1698eb74732a98d9fe8a07bb376"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4b8f583a15e24825bfe4f3958fb1f9bd"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Covered munition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered munition</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HFAD51563AF644154841770B0BD33319F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any previously covered item; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8125F55D0E3B49B7A029F62FB8A4E3A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any item that, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, is designated for control under Category I, II, or III of the United States Munitions List pursuant to section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778</external-xref>) or otherwise subject to control under any such category.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB184807F43FB41D5ACA006EC0E044D1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>firearm</term> includes covered munitions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D702E0E36C443439D070875888883D2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</term> has the meaning given such term in section 502B(d)(1) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC634F17F21F049039FB14F339AD522E5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Previously covered item</header><text>The term <term>previously covered item</term> means any item that—</text><subparagraph id="HA4A74B9FE3F64356A54268738086894C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as of March 8, 2020, was included in Category I, II, or III of the United States Munitions List; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H325B84D10A1F442D82991014D72B223E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the date of the enactment of this Act, is included on the Commerce Control List.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF209DAF85C654141B8923D0D974DC7D9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Security assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>security assistance</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HD906DE933CA24BD9805A87B5678B9126"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any type of assistance described in section 502B(d)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)(2)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H435796B430E240269F7CA00E607F2D60"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assistance furnished under an international security assistance program of the United States conducted under any other provision of law, including the authorities granted under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5819093EEFD244EBB327EA94946F7BA7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United states munitions list</header><text>The term <term>United States Munitions List</term> means the list maintained pursuant to part 121 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFD93EEB20E9044A28574106C8056DFA5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Transfer of regulatory control of certain munitions exports from Department of Commerce to Department of State</header><subsection id="H9462820119BB4864999048A1AFEF170F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer</header><paragraph id="HDDF8E64C570A4434AB89A7AF5F0D492C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall transfer control over the export of each previously covered item to the jurisdiction of the Department of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ED35F45BA4B4DE58C7AABC0E915BF3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of transfer</header><text>Beginning on the date of the transfer required under paragraph (1), control over the export of any covered munition may not be transferred back to the jurisdiction of the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE115CBFB1E444C7EBD0883D5927C35A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to implement this section by the date specified in subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE044DEE8182D4BBFA41EBC8F3F3E674D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on promotion of certain munitions exports by Department of Commerce</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce may not take any action to promote the export of any previously covered item, including actions before, on, or after the date on which the Secretary transfers the control over the export of the previously covered item to the jurisdiction of the Department State pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1B112634AE642E1BD3B8C8894A107CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed as limiting any authority relating to the designation, control, or removal of items under the United States Munitions List or the Commerce Control List, other than the specific authority to transfer the control of previously covered items in accordance with subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="HAFBAFD270CAA44E5BBE861D198C0886B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports and strategy on disruption of illegal export and trafficking of firearms to Mexico and certain Central American and Caribbean countries</header><subsection id="HBB82829FFE1642CA9B80737B5B6C5703"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H0B875191E9BD46838D7E5F71D090F7D1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of State determines to be relevant, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the efforts of the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies to disrupt—</text><subparagraph id="H9734AB7514294680AE009B9FDCB3B155"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the illegal export or diversion of firearms from the United States to unauthorized recipients in countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a), including through unauthorized third-party transfers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE017011EE454CD886FCBF33DE62AA36"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the illegal trafficking of firearms obtained in the United States to recipients in such countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H573B22770D8F473789EE3B2D3DBF603C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the efforts specified in such paragraph—</text><subparagraph id="H045718068D5D410EA5F8D93FA5CD6DD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the identification of any such efforts, including efforts—</text><clause id="H11A2B9BBF8BB4F33A19DF1D7269AC8BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to track and verify information regarding the end-users of firearms exported from the United States, including by entering into data-sharing agreements—</text><subclause id="HFFFE92C5F8844DECAC55F71B15242D3D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with appropriate counterparts from the governments of such covered countries; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD102368F83A842C8AE5C03408B080635"><enum>(II)</enum><text>between relevant departments and agencies of the United States Government;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H70EC9B173B9F42A9A71107DB5324754F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure the destruction of surplus firearms that have been exported from the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H28BAA85283174336ACD83E72BA833BCD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure that exported firearms are not used to commit extrajudicial killings or other gross violations of internationally recognized human rights;</text></clause><clause id="H28696A90AD5047B6992EA150824D1450"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to build the capacity in such covered countries to prevent the trafficking of illegally imported firearms, including through existing programs supported or implemented by the United States Government;</text></clause><clause id="H55BD3B54E2374804A6EA75E6B3606033"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to track and verify information regarding the end-users of firearms obtained in the United States and illegally trafficked to such covered countries;</text></clause><clause id="HEA68CAB1BB584E6A85C91CA9F33A3EAF"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to combat all forms of cross-border smuggling of firearms from the United States, including firearms smuggled on maritime vessels and aircraft;</text></clause><clause id="H874B5C2D7D48431FA6806B47FB0067E0"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to engage with subnational government officials in such covered countries to effectively implement and enforce agreements relating to the trafficking of firearms that have been concluded between the United States Government and the national government of the respective covered country;</text></clause><clause id="HA6F4F0A661CD43578594E4C9B6EA7D15"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to identify the origin of trafficked firearms, including through the serial numbers on such firearms, and sharing such information with relevant law enforcement agencies of—</text><subclause id="H6EFE0740909841CB9FF84056E69F9079"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="H12456A62758D4E0F8EF66A3BCF1EF88F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the respective covered country; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HCEBBE38E9AFA49F88B155647090B7886"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any other country determined relevant for purposes of such information sharing;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5A6C498A3FFF4BB3A38BCAB181806F60"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to implement—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbe0679e3226346c096233abe3b9f8690"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the <quote>U.S.-Mexico Bicentennial Framework for Security, Public Heath, and Safe Communities</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6834c33824e84d35a772c9ab17742b76"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any successor or subsequent bilateral agreements on combating firearm trafficking, transnational organizations, or fentanyl trafficking; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id370f43fc646f48ac88f4fc85a68e8d55"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to cooperate with other relevant Federal departments and agencies, including the Department of Justice, the Department of Homeland Security, and the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, to combat firearms trafficking and prosecute illegal firearm smugglers;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H952895162615482BA8100B68CE60AC1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the results of the efforts described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f82355a611f49619afce1e00ecbfed9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how homicides, extrajudicial killings, and other gross violations of internationally recognized human rights committed in such covered countries using firearms exported from, or obtained in, the United States have been investigated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C64EE29F9184EB98FFDCEFB7564E8EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency strategy</header><paragraph id="H139017343F804569A2E30F78ABF66DF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce, after taking into account the findings of the report required under subsection (a), shall jointly develop an interagency strategy for the disruption of the trafficking of firearms exported from the United States to recipients in countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9EE249642A94229B15A1A9AF7E54D57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H1A524F7F5E4F445293C3C5124E446E31"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a plan for the United States to accomplish each of the objectives specified in subsection (a)(2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H765170E3B9EB4803BDEF49F9C77C55E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the identification of specific performance measures, targets (including the baselines for such targets), and timelines with respect to such objectives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C681628BC7E4B4C96B87E77D1B22129"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an estimate of the resources and personnel necessary to carry out the strategy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF16041EC20FC4BCAA0FD7DA6DADD14C9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for cooperation between the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and the heads of any other Federal departments or agencies involved in anti-firearm trafficking efforts, including the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CAD336572914D5C8C9029701C14EF94"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for coordination between the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, and department heads referred to in subparagraph (D) regarding efforts in countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a) to combat the trafficking of United States-sourced firearms—</text><clause id="H029FF980A6F04C099C99E9D35EC9140F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>from the United States to such designated countries; and</text></clause><clause id="HDE8F2F95FD67410BA1722EE981A098A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>from such designated countries to other countries in the region surrounding such countries.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B73ECB68A1A489FB42A49FB8B5A2B3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required considerations; consultations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the strategy required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD4247981F42E478EBDB769B3755383B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider how such strategy may support or otherwise align with broader efforts of the Secretary of State relating to security assistance, anti-corruption, and the prevention of organized crime and drug and gang violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CDA9DB3331A49D5BB5E466F9CF3C8AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider whether the placement in the Western Hemisphere of an export control officer of the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, or other personnel of the Department of Commerce or of the Department of State, would support such strategy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA5A2165B5F643ECB57DB9C4FE8D7958"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consult with the appropriate congressional committees; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idebebd692e52c400dbf01c3ebea7f07f3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to consult with appropriate counterparts from the government of each country designated as a covered country pursuant to section 8(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EEF675112AE493F8216979B410112C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit the strategy required under paragraph (1) to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE32DEBE3F7DD4869831F0CBC2E1BB265"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Improved tracking of trafficked firearms</header><paragraph id="HE5CFB862404F42ED9F0FB17571860AFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>forensic information</term>, with respect to a trafficked firearm, includes—</text><subparagraph id="H3F67609EF7CD41D9A2D711B938DD53AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the serial number of the firearm; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48F38376ED3341F4B5C27470B09E4E9E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other information that may be used to identify the origin of the firearm or any person or organization involved in the trafficking of the firearm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD223D9BCB382464E8B53F77A29C16B04"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assessment of data availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which a country is designated (or deemed to be designated) as a covered country pursuant to section 8(a), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of State determines to be relevant, shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7336fa8382224a699138478cca1041e4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an assessment of the extent to which the law enforcement agencies of such covered country make available to the United States Government forensic information of trafficked firearms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6ecffb8c15e3444db663e37bf6617a82"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that contains a summary of the findings of the assessment conducted pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9235D7436B64E62ADEC522038657F31"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Addressing gaps in data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period a country is designated as a covered country pursuant to section 8(a), the Secretary of State shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD3AB6CF983094A1AA5F9B0F3C2535BAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to engage with the foreign counterparts of the government of such covered country to improve the collection and sharing of the forensic information of trafficked firearms confiscated by the law enforcement agencies of such covered country; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83D7A4AF332C45B5B4503DBBAC6AC6EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promptly provide any such forensic information shared pursuant to subparagraph (A) to the relevant Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies for use in criminal or civil investigations into violations of relevant Federal laws, including the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9D63161951342DE85F20D8105AF2A4C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H2CDEBAFEAE004FC297996502D1BE7DDB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>the Secretary or the Secretaries concerned</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1D245947E99D4909A8C8FD15A348FE67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if a single Federal department or agency has jurisdiction over the export control of covered munitions, the head of such Federal department or agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE35A19A592B4D4CA9A6703E61F625A5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if multiple Federal departments or agencies have jurisdiction over the export control of covered munitions, the head of each such Federal department or agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E840CECCF6F44408A34134BB1C09942"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary or the Secretaries concerned, in consultation with the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary or the Secretaries concerned determine to be relevant, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes the export of covered munitions to countries designated as covered countries under section 8(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H82A357FA460046B78BE6ECF995AFC3C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>Each report submitted pursuant to paragraph (2) shall include, with respect to the year for which the report is submitted, and disaggregated by country—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H85E9D8656BA64B51A1B73F134CE36DA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information regarding license applications approved or denied, and previously issued licenses modified or revoked, for the export of covered munitions to proposed recipients in countries that have been designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6DCE8DB9138D4AE6A3AEF707236EF3BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information regarding how evolving country contexts, including with respect to developments in human rights, affected the approval of license applications for such exports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1439B81CA02D41EBA19ADFD16A6D8E18"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of licenses issued for the export of covered munitions to proposed recipients in countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3FE7DAC809DF48978257108CF02F6807"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered munitions exported to recipients in countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2735E3F0618D482183AF4005C2254794"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to end-user checks for covered munitions exported to recipients in covered countries conducted pursuant to section 38(g)(7) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(g)(7)</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Blue Lantern</quote> program), the monitoring program established under the second section 40A of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2785">22 U.S.C. 2785</external-xref>), as added by section 150(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/164">Public Law 104–164</external-xref>, or any other applicable program of the Department of Commerce or the Department of State—</text><clause id="HB2391EEEDE354FA288F7EF7A59D58161"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of such end-user checks requested;</text></clause><clause id="H6A984BFDC3AA4660B6242DB5AAE07474"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of such end-user checks conducted;</text></clause><clause id="HEB4AEC3C9558495C821B6FC4C4A34FE4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the type of such end-user checks conducted; and</text></clause><clause id="HDFA342313C504F2196B7C1AA5082B88E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of such end-user checks;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3F409DD734524EF297351E0F5E066265"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the extent to which the heads of the governments of countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a) shared with the Secretary or the Secretaries concerned and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, such as the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, data relating to the receipt and end-use of covered munitions exported from the United States, and the type of data so shared; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCB68D7B901634D9E8188CB6CD6BCF90A"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each country designated as a covered country pursuant to section 8(a), a description of the United States funding and resources allocated for the purpose of disrupting trafficking of covered munitions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id489bd09fc1874f6989744967a83e053a"><enum>6.</enum><header>Increasing participation in the eTrace Program</header><subsection id="id75ea4a0d90c54351924e58ef9c5cfeeb"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eTrace program</term> means the web-based firearms tracing system of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives that is available to accredited domestic and international law enforcement agencies to assist in the tracing of United States-sourced firearms.</text></subsection><subsection id="idab9f08940d65413ab17ebbb5823d5360"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, shall seek to work with national and subnational law enforcement authorities of countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a) to increase participation by such authorities in the eTrace program.</text></subsection><subsection id="id757e8478e58740119513578647798eea"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbde71aaf59534c5faeac4cc1de8eddd9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the implementation of subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6009924655184de3853f58b88927e6c6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies the number of firearms traced to a purchase or export that resulted in a Federal investigation and prosecution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idc714cb87b8f743c68038c69dae9064a0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Haiti</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives shall ensure the eTrace program is available in the French and Haitian Creole languages to enhance the use of the program by law enforcement authorities in Haiti.</text></subsection><subsection id="idaf6cd1e3d850419181a1976ba3a4fd1e"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated to carry out chapter 8 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2291">22 U.S.C. 2291 et seq.</external-xref>; relating to international narcotics control assistance) are authorized to be made available to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="id1b857ec6f3044421a83f8b08ee622ccd"><enum>7.</enum><header>Modifications to the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall develop an updated Results Framework for the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative that establishes specific indicators relating to the trafficking of firearms.</text></section><section id="HA66DFD3767CB42D2AA6432FA732D2712"><enum>8.</enum><header>Designation of covered countries</header><subsection id="H2D1211AB4A854083B3D6C71440B3159F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall designate each country the Secretary determines meets the requirements described in subsection (b) as a covered country for purposes of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id316b41c7ef674d3296e4861e4fd7f948"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A country meets the requirements described in this subsection if the country—</text><paragraph id="id6bea9d243f7a477884566cef05328355"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is located in North America, South America, or the Caribbean;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id544dc89c31d1418583917753fdd605c4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not a member state of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2514dbe8fde44af693f16255dc03010e"><enum>(3)</enum><text>meets such other requirements as the Secretary may determine appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idd0d925400d374a30abb7ea974af23f8e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial designations</header><text>The Bahamas, Belize, Brazil, Colombia, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, Haiti, Jamaica, and Trinidad and Tobago—</text><paragraph id="idd6f8a2912d81439ca53bdefec437b376"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be deemed to have been designated as covered countries by the Secretary of State as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a7f8dfd4be44cab80e4be4e5b67959f"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall continue to be designated as covered countries during the 5-year period beginning on such date of enactment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id32dfb348bab04b7e953145455d8cb946"><enum>(d)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Termination of designation</header><text>The Secretary of State may terminate the designation of any country as a covered country if, not later than 180 days before such termination, the Secretary submits a notification of such termination to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subsection></section><section id="H30F225EFDFDC4F7BBE10A13B6917D015"><enum>9.</enum><header>Certification requirements relating to certain munitions exports</header><subsection id="H8D61AA81EFD0431CB2C778C328CFCD93"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial certification; prohibition</header><paragraph id="HF971020C000F4AB09D63DCCA10CC54D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), a covered munition may not be transferred to the government of a country designated as a covered country pursuant to section 8(a), or to any organization, citizen, or resident of such covered country, until the Secretary of State submits a written certification to the appropriate congressional committees stating the program required under subsection (c) has been established.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BACEC40E6C84FEDA5CD360CAF47449C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>During the 1-year period beginning on the effective date set forth in subsection (d), the Secretary of State may waive the certification requirement under paragraph (1) with respect to the transfer of a covered munition to the government of a covered country if the Secretary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8611d14c1c46443c9ca1648b5e65d846"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such waiver is in the national security interest of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id198cf00777d84252812926a78e2c43e5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes a written justification for such waiver with such certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52A779254F014D8E9061DBB2C108690F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review and recertification</header><paragraph id="HB46549FC6F7946A8B4828EFE6CACADBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which the Secretary of State submits the certification described in subsection (a)(1) with respect to a covered country, and annually thereafter until the designation of such country as a covered country is terminated pursuant to section 8(d), the Secretary shall review and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a recertification of the establishment of the program required under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7E1979E22524BD19ABE0A40F0337220"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>If the Secretary of State is unable to recertify a covered country in accordance with paragraph (1), no covered munition may be transferred to the government of the covered country, or to any organization, citizen, or resident of such covered country, until the date on which the Secretary submits such recertification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC247CFEDD2734DD9AEFEB6E36792B65B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program</header><paragraph id="HD3B341B2009F4CC0AB3A35FFF081F105"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish and carry out a program under which the Secretary—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide9d058e13bff4168adb02e9158d2967c"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibits the retransfer of covered munitions that were transferred to countries designated as covered countries under section 8(a) without the consent of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ide6b4b719b22d4ed78adcb14273addfdb"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides for the registration and end-use monitoring of such covered munitions in accordance with the requirements described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8ba262d47bc34749be65911166c3a3db"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="HBD88934C87FC42D2AEA209BB2384D3DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Detailed record</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain a detailed record of the origin, shipping, and distribution of covered munitions transferred to countries designated as covered countries pursuant to section 8(a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72785C24BDE7405B8D4785B1B32084E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Registration</header><text>The Secretary shall register the serial numbers of all covered munitions, which shall be provided to the governments of covered countries and to organizations, citizens, and residents within such covered countries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD4D6BBE04224C15A838616FA6BF00E3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>End-use monitoring</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a program for the end-use monitoring of covered munitions transferred to the entities and individuals described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EEA0F6CD9CB409A8275932B6ED4B263"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review of database</header><text>In prohibiting the retransfer of covered munitions without the consent of the United States pursuant to the program required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF5626455B61E4A1198839FB98C3C06C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review the database of the Department of State that maintains records relating to vetting conducted pursuant to section 620M of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378d">22 U.S.C. 2378d</external-xref>) or section 362 of title 10, United States Code, which is known as the <quote>International Vetting and Security Tracking-cloud system</quote> or the <quote>INVEST system</quote> (or any successor database), for any such records relating to the prospective recipients of such a retransfer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H943304528F1F4341B42D939B3D873CAE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the United States does not consent to such retransfer to any such prospective recipient that the Secretary of State determines, after taking into account the findings of the review required under subparagraph (A), is credibly implicated in a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A78374F71E545A3A9D98217FA749885"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Data storage and sharing</header><text>In carrying out the program established pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall—</text><subparagraph id="HB7AF7140EC7F4580A73FBD0577D3B930"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that any data received pursuant to such program is stored and maintained in a database of the Department of State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A60FE1ECE824A0F947442BA158EB1AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, provide for the sharing of such data with the Secretary of Commerce and the heads of other Federal departments or agencies that the Secretary of State determines to be relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H405F9AAB8D4544A5B7082397E2299CE8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date that is 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of Commerce completes the transfer of the control over the export of previously covered items to the jurisdiction of the Department of State pursuant to section 4(a)(1).</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE680CAB8BBD94AFFA333E4E2A5B24325"><enum>10.</enum><header>Limitation on licenses and other authorizations for export of certain items removed from the Commerce Control List and included on the United States Munitions List</header><subsection commented="no" id="H868604A3390749EB977C0601DCCF676B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may not grant an export license or other authorization for the export of a previously covered item unless, before granting such license or other authorization, the Secretary submits a written certification to the appropriate congressional committees with respect to such proposed export license or other authorization that includes—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H125AC5FE4F4940FCBA0293C98A5A1667"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name of the person applying for the license or other authorization;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDEE7F39D2EB44C0B9D72C15B7B5584C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the name of the person who is the proposed recipient of the previously covered item;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H160AA759C1064DDEB91EFABBDCE6CF8D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the name of the country or international organization to which the previously covered item will be made;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H63DEF2269ACF4E1D8C8EC2ACD139A0A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the items proposed to be exported; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6D4A4601FC0447DEAD57AF3512847BFD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the value of the items proposed to be exported.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H68EC11F98EB546669C41AF5898608CE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>Each certification required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, except that information regarding the dollar value and number of items proposed to be exported may be restricted from public disclosure if such disclosure would be detrimental to the security of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H67A94695F5DC463D92337EF9509DC2E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>Each certification required under subsection (a) shall be submitted—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H2CA63569D3F349FF88C094608A3627A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 15 days before a proposed export license or other authorization is granted in the case of a transfer of items to a country that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Israel, or New Zealand; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2851E4AD18CF4870BB342884542EF4C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 30 days before a proposed export license or other authorization is granted in the case of a transfer of items to any country not referred to in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDDA8B59CD51E4BF3B9D4BA66AF5B4B97"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional resolution of disapproval</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb15e4ac637124c27bd25c7d57e6eb4a6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain allied countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposed export license or other authorization described in subsection (c)(1) shall become effective after the end of the 15-day period specified in such subsection if Congress does not enact, within such period, a joint resolution prohibiting the export of the covered item for which the export license or other authorization was proposed.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida898196f61e94a39a796c5e6a04d492c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposed export license or other authorization described in subsection (c)(2) shall become effective after the end of the 30-day period specified in such subsection if Congress does not enact, within such period, a joint resolution prohibiting the export of the covered item for which the export license or other authorization was proposed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idb0d59aaea7594c63a5f755f3b5507b36"><enum>11.</enum><header>Prohibition on promotion of covered munitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce is prohibited from—</text><paragraph id="id0ae215a86bce46cc896247d6a09df31d"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting the sale or export of covered munitions; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id00de483624d44b4ba668ce200f2aa37c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seeking the reduction or removal by any foreign country of restrictions on the marketing of covered munitions.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

