<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0C8C7FE9E0E44348AD438EBB853CD5BE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8161 IH: Expeditionary Diplomacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8161</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260330">March 30, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001322">Mr. Baumgartner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage the practice of expeditionary diplomacy at the Department of State.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H401C4C1A4B674D51A4541A5FBF4D7382" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HACDA0D8B76794B5FACAC49118E3A1413" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expeditionary Diplomacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1768A1E68248449EB98B5B0C2CE4A3F6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition requirement</header> <subsection id="H56F368E8081444A782FB0164694F348B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that includes a definition of the term <quote>expeditionary diplomacy</quote>, and how it relates to diplomacy that is not expeditionary, and an overview of how the Department of State will apply this definition to enhance its ability to conduct expeditionary diplomacy in environments with an elevated security risk, including under the Diplomatic Security Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4801">22 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 9302 of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0B6A48CA9BC245CAA4AFD527B0A8917C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall consult relevant external stakeholders on the formulation of the definition required in subsection (a), which may include the American Academy of Diplomacy and the American Foreign Service Association, as appropriate.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3D6B6D69720C48C0A76022E37B3605A2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on expeditionary diplomacy at the Department of State</header> <subsection id="HD560085FFCEF44958C8922794D99A650"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the submission of the report required by section 2, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on challenges with respect to expeditionary diplomacy at the Department of State and United States embassies and posts and recommendations to address such challenges.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H65E60CE8599144B0BB245067EF519188">
        <enum>(b)</enum>
        <header>Matters To be included</header>
 <text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H160A8AE3ED5C42ADB905851E9E443122"> <enum>(1)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the capacity of regional security officers within the Department of State, including with respect to enabling expeditionary diplomacy, and, if applicable, recommendations to address any challenges in capacity.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="HE461D5EC385D4301BA746CD1E39D21F5">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of other challenges, internal and external to the Department of State, that prevent increased expeditionary diplomacy practiced among Chiefs of Mission and members of the Foreign Service.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0C3B96B47084430BBE0C129E2A6DA10E">
          <enum>(3)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of whether existing Department of State initiatives, and laws and regulations applicable to the Department, including under the Diplomatic Security Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/4801">22 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), as amended by section 9302 of the James M. Inhofe National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2023 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/263">Public Law 117–263</external-xref>), further including the provisions on promotion precepts, training, and the sense of Congress on the establishment of an Expeditionary Diplomacy Award, are being utilized to address such other challenges, to include analysis describing the effectiveness of such initiatives, laws, and regulations in doing so.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H40F3F31D404E49BC82E7DF711B1A1613">
          <enum>(4)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of previous and ongoing efforts to enable expeditionary diplomacy, including in environments with an elevated security risk, that have been successful, and any lessons learned from such efforts, and recommendations as to how, if at all, those lessons learned could be applied more generally across the Department of State.</text>
        </paragraph>
        <paragraph id="H0F890811ADA745CD9AD4DC8972CFF2B6">
          <enum>(5)</enum>
 <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of how personnel policies at diplomatic posts and across the Foreign Service more generally impact members’ of the Foreign Service ability to practice expeditionary diplomacy, complete tours longer than one year in assignments to environments with an elevated security risk, and obtain sufficient country-level expertise (including through developing robust contacts with host country officials, business leaders, civil society groups, and other key stakeholders), and, if applicable, recommendations to improve such policies to incentivize members of the Foreign Service to carry out such work.</text>
        </paragraph>
      </subsection></section> 
<section id="HF557B1CA3F4E4360A2D5685E7B15D064"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the President should include in the <quote>President’s Letters of Instruction</quote> the promotion of appropriate and effective risk management practices to encourage diplomats to regularly and meaningfully engage in expeditionary diplomacy and with populations in the country, including in high security and high threat environments.</text></section> <section id="H4FE26129E7C145C496F46E710C501A10" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Amendments to Chief of Mission Authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 207(a) of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3927">22 U.S.C. 3927(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB952F9BC9C7B4749997C7037D3445D37" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking the <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB1E06B80B9A4AA4A1CC3BD38F88F891" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC99D0000EF5D498EBC86D95D50FCC7D0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB15D48BDC6C2463AB06A847356CF5B07" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H06A49E69866F485CBFD0892AFE8503A5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall exercise appropriate and effective risk management practices to encourage all relevant Government executive branch employees in that country to regularly and meaningfully engage in expeditionary diplomacy and with the populations in such country.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HDA49A60422F445E88C914D009AB924A6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Establishment of expeditionary diplomacy Tiger Team</header> 
<subsection id="HC5F5E263E0DC4D868B919847D75B3EB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall establish a team (commonly known as a <quote>Tiger Team</quote> and referred to in this section as the <quote>Tiger Team</quote>) dedicated to producing recommendations to the Secretary of State to improve the ability and willingness of Chiefs of Mission and Regional Security Officers to approve expeditionary diplomacy and of members of the Foreign Service to regularly practice expeditionary diplomacy. The Tiger Team shall consist of appropriate personnel of the Department of State assigned to the Tiger Team by the Secretary for the purposes of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H355706D52E2B494782C1860CAF0A51E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tiger team leader</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One of the persons assigned to the Tiger Team under subsection (a) shall be a senior-level officer or employee of the Department who shall serve as the lead official of the Tiger Team (in this section referred to as the <quote>Tiger Team Leader</quote>) and who shall be accountable for the activities of the Tiger Team under this section and not serve concurrently in another assignment or position at the Department during the tenure of the Tiger Team.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44BA4D882E2A42CE90358DB6F52CB263"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on composition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report setting forth the names and titles of the personnel of the Department assigned to the Tiger Team pursuant to this subsection, including the positions to which assigned, which shall at minimum include at least one official that reports to the Under Secretary of Political Affairs, an official with international development experience and expertise, and at least one official each from the Bureaus of Diplomatic Security, Administration, Diplomatic Technology, Human Resources, Medical Services, and Overseas Building Operations, respectively. The report shall specify the name of the individual assigned as Tiger Team Leader.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H729463B571E44305927277D0AB3FC8CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header> <paragraph id="HE88EE3556948454F86DB80822A4E14B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Tiger Team shall produce recommendations to the Secretary of State to improve the ability and willingness of Chiefs of Mission and Regional Security Officers to approve expeditionary diplomacy and of members of the Foreign Service to regularly practice expeditionary diplomacy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H30D48DC4AA834F2BA6B7634F6D325667"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In conducting activities under this subsection, the Tiger Team Leader shall identify appropriate external stakeholders with whom the Tiger Team shall work to carry out such activities. Such stakeholders shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H3C19F8ADFE7F423AACE30565AC85950F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>American Academy of Diplomacy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF3D672F62FB4C9489E63D562B616B29"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">American Foreign Service Association.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB63077F089244E9B5518D6A729CAE0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Overseas Security Advisory Council.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80FBDDF254794CBB97B1180386D2B27E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such other stakeholders as the Tiger Team Leader considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89FB8E0693BC4A3EBCB37CFD4B5B50B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a plan on the Tiger Team’s work, to include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF43C0FC996624EAF8C5B7B52A18D6EEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the manner in which the Secretary, working through the Tiger Team and in collaboration with external stakeholders described in paragraph (2), shall—</text> <clause id="H90CFBF52D51F407086ACE76B1F52EDDE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the current state of the Department’s ability and willingness to practice expeditionary diplomacy;</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H3369BEB517004174AEDB59E96A6B9C98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>review previous and current Department of State efforts and historical recommendation reports, external and internal, on expeditionary diplomacy;</text></clause> <clause id="H6EEC15B291BE4BAA8D6891E514BF16EF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the current challenges experienced by the Department, Chiefs of Mission, and members of the Foreign Service in practicing expeditionary diplomacy; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H01EABEEB44EF4F3BB04C85AE87CB36C3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>produce policy, regulations, and legislative recommendations to address such challenges.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCCA159A665E24F9B9CA01379DE3492BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A timeline for the implementation, carrying out, and completion of the plan required under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H27962DF98D9D490B925D930290C505C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of the additional funding, personnel, or other resources of the Department required to carry out the plan required under this paragraph, including any modification of applicable statutory or administrative authorities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F24CCCDD2C043058355314420E50A75"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Implementation of plan</header> <subparagraph id="HB1669984F0314C6FB0B2E55B7EFCC729"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall implement and carry out the plan submitted under paragraph (3) in accordance with the timeline submitted under subparagraph (B) of that paragraph.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE5D1A93B8B248D2ACD5B4BB50AD3A9C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 90 days after the submittal of the report on the plan under paragraph (3), the Tiger Team shall submit to Congress an update on such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H42A7D988AA8749D2A9A6675314C7EC8B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Tiger Team shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a final report on the activities of the Tiger Team under this subsection. The report shall set forth the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0A8F70CBC8224B2BAA62F8F275BE621B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the challenges related to expeditionary diplomacy identified pursuant to paragraph (3)(A)(ii), including challenges identified by the Comptroller General of the United States pursuant to the report in section 3.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H361D07422789415182AF3C7BD61EB29C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of recommendations to address such challenges, including the resources, staffing, authorities, and legislative changes required for implementation, pursuant to paragraph (3)(A)(iii).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F56BC326F8E43638C7FF6155B6BE774"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A timeline for the implementation of such recommendations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0A92FF1B15F4B29BA76F6199559877E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A designation of an office responsible for monitoring the implementation of such recommendations following the termination of the Tiger Team pursuant to paragraph (6).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H195C227A87714D4F98D5E3A692F2A876"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any changes, as appropriate, to the definition required by section 2.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5499E39EC9A2456E9A8A7AAD3DD2F2AF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Monitoring implementation</header><text>For the period of 90 days after the date on which the final report required by paragraph (5) is submitted, the Tiger Team shall oversee and monitor the implementation of recommendations submitted in such report.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7ABD5C3A4C94B7AAF7B1F6BC5BB665A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>On the date that is 90 days after the date on which the final report required by paragraph (5) is submitted, the Secretary shall terminate the Tiger Team.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3191644D5C2749E28B8CA7455437A697"><enum>7.</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8332B85075944332A1CC22CF502E8D6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45FA59ED183F4DE0B59827C77246F743"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>


