<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H994E2FE9ACFD43999985DD9F0E5E749F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8988 IH: Frank Adelmann Manufactured Housing Community Sustainability Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8988</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260521">May 21, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a business credit for gain from the sale of real property for use as a manufactured home community, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBF992CDDE7644324AA756FB933B302AD" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H661D3C7FCB694B67913E2297E2E5F221"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Frank Adelmann Manufactured Housing Community Sustainability Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="HD98CAD3A9313469E81292A0D1CC2681F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="HB2908E6C9A6F4DBAB96F41CA70FD92BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 22,000,000 people live in HUD-code manufactured homes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5B04E09BC404DEB9DBB956AD6030AEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>there are approximately 6,700,000 occupied manufactured homes in the United States, representing about 6 percent of the Nation’s housing stock, 9 percent of the single-family housing stock, and more than 12 percent of all new single-family homes sold in 2021;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56B8ECAC0B994F11BAF0C505190BBFC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>owners of manufactured homes are disproportionately low-income households, and in 2020, the median annual household income for living in manufactured housing was $35,000;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1635EC4C9FC42069D8C9355D019011C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>over one-quarter of manufactured homeowners earn less than $20,000 annually, and two-thirds earn less than $50,000 annually;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC163FC37C5D34DC59393E76212A52035"><enum>(5)</enum><text>more than half of all manufactured homes are located in rural areas around the country, and manufactured homes make up 13 percent of all occupied homes in rural and small-town communities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0AC850B00BC440C9885809897FA0D0D6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the average sales price of a new manufactured home (excluding land) in 2019 was $81,700, and as of December 2023, that average sales price had increased to $121,300, an increase of 48.5 percent over the preceding 5 years;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H512EDCC1CECF4E2F8EB754C730DD8BF8"><enum>(7)</enum><text>despite this sharp increase, the average manufactured home costs roughly half the price per square foot of the average site-built home;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB62EC8649D34465EB1155AC3667B0ABF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>manufactured home communities provide critical affordable housing, but receive very little Federal, State, or local funds to subsidize the cost of manufactured homes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF329F8A18BAE4AA287F3F09FEC5DD219"><enum>(9)</enum><text>an estimated 43,000 manufactured home communities, also referred to as <quote>mobile home parks</quote>, exist throughout the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF4517D3B443429ABD379F0DF6AE4901"><enum>(10)</enum><text>owners of manufactured homes in such communities may own the home, but they do not own the land under the home, which leaves the homeowners vulnerable to rent increases, dis-investment, changes in land use, and community closure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1081182F1B6458EA8C3CA5FE032E25F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>an eviction or closure of a manufactured home community is very disruptive and can be financially devastating to a homeowner who may be unable to pay the thousands of dollars it takes to move the manufactured home or find a new location for the manufactured home;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H51F974244550494E8C431F48F5558D4E"><enum>(12)</enum><text>manufactured housing where the consumer does not own the land generally does not promote wealth-building via homeownership;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EE8D0A610174A14B587C78F0CB4F89F"><enum>(13)</enum><text>for more than a decade, in an effort to preserve a crucial source of affordable housing and aid low-income homeowners, a national network of housing providers has helped residents purchase and own the land under the manufactured home community, and manage the manufactured home community as limited equity cooperatives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H106BB80D103D4174ACA12076FEEB5076"><enum>(14)</enum><text>nationwide, there are more than 1,000 cooperative manufactured home communities, of which more than 360, located in more than 20 States, are permanently preserved as affordable communities through limited equity cooperative or nonprofit ownership;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA104D5E1D3334ABB8738DD85A7D1A7B3"><enum>(15)</enum><text>members of manufactured home community cooperatives continue to own such homes individually, own an equal share of the land beneath the entire manufactured home community, participate in the governing of the community, and elect a board of directors who make major decisions within the manufactured home community by a democratic vote;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBEBC8B31D9B741E682EBE7EE852C4F1F"><enum>(16)</enum><text>site fee increases in limited equity resident-owned communities average just 0.9 percent per year, compared to 5.9 percent per year in commercially-owned communities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCF8ADA8A1A74CB0A6A45E4198656246"><enum>(17)</enum><text>in New Hampshire, more than 40 percent of manufactured home communities are owned by residents;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC31EF1FAE8D244AF92C50C71E3F54EC9"><enum>(18)</enum><text>resident-owned cooperatives and nonprofit owned communities have also flourished in Colorado, Vermont, Massachusetts, Montana, Rhode Island, Washington, Oregon, and Minnesota;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAD8C40F3FEC744069F77C236E1F43EFA"><enum>(19)</enum><text>nationwide, only 2.4 percent of all manufactured home communities are resident or nonprofit-owned;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16CFDCC0A7534C74A4273F9C916E3CD6"><enum>(20)</enum><text>19 States have adopted some protection when a community is sold, and 8 States have strong notification and resident purchase opportunities, which provide homeowners in those States an opportunity to purchase the manufactured home community when it is put up for sale; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C1D96560E8B402EBD91C3C5121162B7"><enum>(21)</enum><text>in order to preserve manufactured home communities and help low-income homeowners live securely, safely, and build wealth through homeownership in the future, a Federal tax benefit should be established to induce manufactured home community owners to sell such properties to the residents when those residents or a nonprofit commits to preserving the community long-term.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H47B04926C73D41BEBEF895FED9C123A2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Tax credit for manufactured home community sale to residents or nonprofit entity</header> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4586DB43F9FD4599B3F443091B8A0950"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to business related credits) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCD357CCD54C749C0919F1DBE040E20B8"> <section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H3EF7DFEEB6054D279D4108CE85078F8C"><enum>45BB.</enum><header>Manufactured home community sale to residents or nonprofit entity</header> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3823B74941E84FCCBFD323D0619BE386"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the manufactured home community sale credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to 75 percent of the qualified gain received by the taxpayer during the taxable year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F93A50656B64CA085DE527BA8C6CA4A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H600CDDA482914BE8A76430573C70EB7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified gain</header><text>The term <term>qualified gain</term> means gain from the sale or exchange of real property to a qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation if—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H70FB29F5CB014B73988C4186A7DCFD5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the real property is acquired for use as a manufactured home community,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H8EFC5FC29E1B4D4C91791957C3A1AFF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the seller (or any related person) owned the property for the entire 2-year period ending on the day before the sale or exchange, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HCA7D547EE7B04BB6BFF8E326678485F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the property is transferred subject to a binding covenant that the property will be used as a manufactured home community for not less than 50 years (or, in the case of a manufactured home community located in a State the laws of which restrict such covenant to a lesser term, the maximum permissible term allowed under such State laws).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H6A8FBFFF3DBC4D189668365D536F0924"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manufactured home community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>manufactured home community</term> means a community comprised primarily of manufactured homes used solely for residential purposes and owned by a manufactured home community cooperative or corporation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E61C1E5943D49F7B160F36E242B6E04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8359B2D5A3BF435AAAE660A0ABBB0049"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation</term> means a cooperative or a nonprofit corporation established pursuant to the laws of the State in which the property used as a manufactured home community is located, and which—</text> <clause id="H95147882214546B2B73BB9E36DB34FE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a community owned by a nonprofit corporation whose membership interests are sold on a nonappreciating basis, has only 1 class of membership and such class consists solely of residents, and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H817EE06A716643F1A10A841C3B5F5D91"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a community owned by a cooperative, has not more than 2 classes of membership, and such classes consist solely of residents and a tax-exempt organization.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6504185D777048DA81ED1E980DB55F51"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Governance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity shall not be treated as a qualified manufactured home community cooperative or corporation unless governance of the entity is carried out by members elected to a board of directors with voting structured equitably among all members.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF81E0F53E51145069952BFD5E9CE9C9F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Member</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>member</term> means—</text> <clause id="H644CDF8257364D04B287F52B60E61969"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an individual who—</text> 
<subclause id="HF3BD0CEC33564E868A79B822165C40B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has attained the age of 18,</text></subclause> <subclause id="H883156AF1F2E4E188BEF2F3AD48197B1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is entitled to be a member by reason of—</text> 
<item id="H618BAB04CE07424F8A030369E7677092"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the membership interest of the individual to execute an occupancy agreement with the manufactured home community cooperative nonprofit with respect to a site in the manufactured home community in order to establish a manufactured home which is owned by the individual, or</text></item> <item id="H6850FA1C57E64E5DA4551274DFAC30A8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>permission from the manufactured community cooperative or corporation, the member’s trust, or other entity, and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H25E3D29CCA214F3DB1704C324B1D225E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is a resident of the manufactured home community, and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H94B1F37659BF4BE38A1128E302A15444"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a tax exempt organization.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFABA71E6A55247EC92B36F0D8709A01A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Membership interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>membership interest</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H65466B0C5A8B460190212C062047499D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an ownership interest in a manufactured home community cooperative or corporation, or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE63471AF19F8488487BE954DD5B1B17A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a membership interest in a manufactured home community nonprofit corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7EABA26C11AC474FAF09EB2ED237DA24"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Manufactured home</header><text>The term <term>manufactured home</term> means a structure which is transportable in one or more sections, which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3C90A37E23F14C86AC91964577FB7C26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in traveling mode, is 8 body feet or more in width and 40 body feet or more in length, or, when erected on site, is 320 square feet or more,</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H263C6F330E274002B12F0E6F85D91549"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is built on a permanent chassis and designed to be used as a dwelling (with or without a permanent foundation when connected to required utilities) and includes plumbing, heating, and electrical heating systems, and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H099BA38E4185451097044C1812B003CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a structure manufactured after June 15, 1976, is certified as meeting the Manufactured Home Construction and Safety Standards issued under the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5401">42 U.S.C. 5401 et seq.</external-xref>) by the Department of Housing and Urban Development and displays a label of such certification on the exterior of each transportable section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HED044D3FBDBF4682AF58940139ECF4C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header> <paragraph id="H34A137C4B51A47D199743274F1E8AD00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Related person</header><text>For purposes of subsection (b)(1)(B), a person is related to the seller if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAF44E21988344E8AA64F5F1642BCE35A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such person bears a relationship to the seller as specified in section 267(b) or 707(b)(1), or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB19DB484850144E6B4C7A744464CB4C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such person and the seller are engaged in trades or businesses under common control within the meanings of subsections (a) and (b) of section 52.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H2E4939615A6A4105A3689C6A520D9EB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election by both seller and buyer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The credit is allowable under this section only if—</text> <subparagraph id="H0BC25B3FACC044BD8001E55F22FC0984"><enum>(A)</enum><text>both the seller and the purchaser of the real property execute an affidavit representing that the sale meets the requirements of subsection (b)(1), and the purchaser acknowledges liability for the recapture of the credit under subsection (d) in case of any violation described in such subsection,</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60623B3757EB4D6DB98E16B86335BB92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the purchaser of the real property records the affidavit, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F1C0F20F92E4AF5B88BE8E82EE2E279"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the affidavit is referenced in the deed to the real property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5514249A51AA4B2FACEBA16D45F29FF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The seller shall include a copy of the affidavit representing the sale with the return of tax.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H6CEBB17808BB47ED9A20A3A38F21499A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax upon violation of covenant</header><text>There is imposed a tax on the buyer for a violation of the covenant specified in subsection (b)(1)(C). The amount of such tax shall be 20 percent of the net proceeds after settlement for the sale or exchange of the real property referred to in subsection (b)(1). For purposes of section 501(a), the tax imposed by this subsection shall not be treated as a tax imposed by this subtitle.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8CCBFBA51FD541ECA57EF7D18FA77F96"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out this section, including the recapture under subsection (d).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD3B37751389C4EFFA441C810670799A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit allowed as part of general business credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/38">Section 38(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD38AE8CFBF474F53B9AFCF10C0858DC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (40);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45B0F2286E404B48B0BB5579BCFFF8F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (41) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E9355A14E524DF79E55EFADDA7A4D37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA228DB13E4B0458E9793487BFBDD26B3"> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FAB154C56984313B5F848A9053ADD22"><enum>(42)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufactured home community sale credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0F5B87011BE4037AC0702D2AA75DB4C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header> 
<paragraph id="H730164785DEA4A368C5E3061CB4AA15E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/196">section 196</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H3CD1B5A3FF8E4B2C9C46A5D852617534"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (13);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8EB032426214C408E82FA23C1021423"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (14) and inserting <quote>, and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB31D06E68D254052A60F9E0515BBEB0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H799B9468DDF44315A1BA4D9BE3E3A85F"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4B7B3E3B6FA47D8B93B0A2A9DCE11AE"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufactured home community sale credit determined under section 45BB(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBA00AC24DB054D8CBC5C7C4058807D87"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23C8457F52CB460597C5E7CCAB402DE6"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry idref="H3EF7DFEEB6054D279D4108CE85078F8C" level="section">Sec. 45BB. Manufactured home community sale to residents or nonprofit entity.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE5AEE8EC2FA54A199DB46531EAD13B79"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2026.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

