<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-type="olc" bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HEN25E63-80G-XR-42T"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3577 IS: Auto Theft Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>1st Session</session><legis-num>S. 3577</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20251218">December 18, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S337">Mr. Coons</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S434">Mr. Moreno</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S402">Ms. Rosen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To provide funding to State and local law enforcement agencies to combat auto theft and stolen automobile trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="HA3364C61A9E5400E83C5F87793B039DE"><section section-type="section-one" id="H8FC86310BAB54D699C95878EDA62FFEE"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Auto Theft Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF021127A57FD436482104C8647F6AF26"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idcae38ae9e20e4d4b859fee1169d37cdc"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc82fee89b0b44476bdb55545ccf3edd9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant year</header><text>The term <term>grant year</term> means the year during which the applicable grant is to be disbursed under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BEE3F7F13F147CF93B5B6752AE32E1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Local law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <term>local law enforcement agency</term> means any entity administered by a locality that exists primarily to prevent and detect crime and enforce criminal laws.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC797413DFC374D289A14E74D0041BD6B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Locality</header><text>The term <term>locality</term> means any city, county, township, town, borough, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id42da4958714f443d98f91817f6c4eafa"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the auto theft prevention grant program established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb08592fc61fe4502889ad414d60c051b"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Recipient State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recipient State</term> means a State that is awarded a grant under the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF4049D2A73C424AAF19B88704DD7257"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF239CD9F3B20405F9C7B60AFE2A8230A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State law enforcement agency</header><text>The term <term>State law enforcement agency</term> means any State entity that exists primarily to prevent and detect crime and enforce criminal laws.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4559695D6A0E44F4A4FD1EA140F01C72"><enum>3.</enum><header>Auto theft prevention grant program</header><subsection id="HC1125F8D927346A0AA23138F47B00403"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish an auto theft prevention grant program to provide funding to State law enforcement agencies and local law enforcement agencies to combat auto theft and stolen vehicle trafficking.</text></subsection><subsection id="id5985f62298df4f56a4f4c46dda0f7bba"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State desiring a grant under the Program shall submit to the Director an application that includes—</text><paragraph id="id59590d540b414461b370450d45bb62f0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evidentiary or other materials, including, as appropriate, State-specific police reports, budget documents, plans, or other documents, demonstrating that the State needs Federal assistance to combat auto theft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf937f43dc2f401cb7ac2a8ed13867ea"><enum>(2)</enum><text>documentation of the actions taken by the State during the year before the grant year, based on the information in such evidentiary or other materials, to reduce the instances of auto theft in the State; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf55dbd2b38674c64afbbd06326df4e4a"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan indicating how the State will—</text><subparagraph id="idd2a0ce0cc4a64f748d6c82784ba999b8"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>use amounts received under the Program to implement auto theft prevention activities in accordance with subsections (d) and (e); and</text>
 </subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ae09f5de6004defb0146d2760e401cd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate the success of the activities carried out using amounts received under the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id98286deb0055468c8bc566959d599f69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Awards</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd52871a15c6f48c0b2d107208f68cdc3"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Director may make a grant under the Program to the Attorney General of any State which has submitted an application that complies with the requirements under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id89a434c51d214acfa3aa1237a2ac12cd"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether to make a grant to a State under the Program and the amount of a grant under the Program, the Director shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida11513d8557749eea12f020a310d223f"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the information provided in the application of the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5f491d6858bb404abc3c9a0e524b7e92"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">endeavor to prioritize States with a higher overall level of auto thefts during the year before the grant year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H293F8ED9183D438689F9BFF00BA982D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><paragraph id="HB8BA5E8B771C4A9C926D5B56CE3CE3BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local law enforcement agencies</header><text>The Attorney General of a recipient State shall make not less than 50 percent of the amount of a grant awarded under the Program available as competitive subgrants to local law enforcement agencies within the recipient State to combat auto theft, with the amount awarded determined by prioritizing localities with a higher overall level of auto thefts during the year before the grant year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H330B93C47040432AB58A4EBDC4F84566"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State law enforcement agencies</header><text>The Attorney General of a recipient State shall make not less than 25 percent of the amount of a grant awarded under the Program available to State law enforcement agencies of the recipient State to combat auto theft.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FA48626866F44448FDFFE24C73D4C2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other amounts</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb9d83cde2171468399e403cb2b883e46"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>The Attorney General of a recipient State shall make any amounts received under a grant under the Program that are not allocated under paragraph (1) or (2) available as competitive subgrants to local law enforcement agencies or to State law enforcement agencies of the recipient State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ided7ade84a6f544498652561bd2d5ac96"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prioritization for localities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of any subgrant made under this paragraph to a local law enforcement agency shall follow the prioritization under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD26E6B519BD84A13A818224385A8FEDB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>Amounts received under a grant under the Program may only be used for the purpose of combating auto theft and combating stolen automobile trafficking, including—</text><paragraph id="HB73AFE4A7CC0473EA60BBE0788217DB4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>purchasing equipment used to combat auto theft, such as law enforcement vehicles and license plate readers;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddc05038d99ac45dd97bf0b2048b0ddaf"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funding costs associated with equipment described in paragraph (1), such as subscription fees and data storage fees for license plate readers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29F09F7A20F542AE83304886BFC0E12A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hiring additional law enforcement officers and support staff to combat auto theft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A4D434F2C1E4A3E8A8534EF8602DE1B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>funding overtime costs and additional compensation for law enforcement officers and support staff involved in combating auto theft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FB12646B47F4ED6B1E423B459546D5D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing training for law enforcement officers and support staff to combat auto theft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H765454386F5C42958958D13A1333BB43"><enum>(6)</enum><text>providing resources for joint task forces established to combat auto theft;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE96FEF3F2ED443D189D7D7E6BEF61DC4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>funding law enforcement data collection, data storage, or research activities related to combating auto theft; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFD66FEA33F84C50BFA791F99D47675A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>funding for the administrative costs of applying for and implementing the grant, which shall not exceed 5 percent of the grant amount.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA7AAE3A268274DFFADFFB44E43DA06E1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 to carry out the Program.</text></subsection></section><section id="H59BAD5198755436FA99783C6C4899124"><enum>4.</enum><header>Additional authorized uses of COPS grant program funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1701(b) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFA2A0F9FA8704483A099CBD5E566B806"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (23) and (24) as paragraphs (24) and (25), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93219473821D4C2D8D00CB021A470B95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (22), the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H50E802F34F9146C6BAAEB163A0D7E7EA"><paragraph id="H1567A7563658453C85450841204F700C"><enum>(23)</enum><text>to combat auto thefts and stolen automobile trafficking by purchasing equipment, hiring law enforcement officers and support staff, funding overtime and officer compensation costs, expanding access to training initiatives, funding joint task forces, and funding law enforcement data collection or research activities related to auto thefts;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H56D58124374E4128B8656E3F3888AF2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (24), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>(22)</quote> and inserting <quote>(23)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>

