<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C6B1CBF630047C4989CD891521F932F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8289 IH: BIS Licensing Efficiency Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8289</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260415">April 15, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to ensure expeditious processing of license applications, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCA430F3421BF4AC0824383C1C72D54B5" style="OLC"><section id="H8009915F2B844CA5BE6A596E9B537F3C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>BIS Licensing Efficiency Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6C04E6E7BB7C46C0815093682F723A0E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H8650F4320CFC4DC899DB69DD101EAD8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 1756(a)(2) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4815">50 U.S.C. 4815(a)(2)</external-xref>) requires the Secretary of Commerce to ensure that <quote>licensing decisions are made in an expeditious manner, with transparency to applicants on the status of license and other authorization processing and the reason for denying any license or request for authorization</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD15056C153B428BB8AF166004AFDF90"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1756(b) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4815">50 U.S.C. 4815(b)</external-xref>) expresses the sense of Congress that <quote>the Secretary should make best efforts to ensure that an accurate, consistent, and timely evaluation and processing of licenses or other requests for authorization to export, reexport, or in-country transfer items controlled under this subchapter is generally accomplished within 30 days from the date of such license request</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84148E4676AB443E81FBE38834A54960"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 12981 (61 Fed. Reg. 54079; relating to administration of export controls), which was codified in Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>), stipulates that <quote>all license applications submitted under the Act and the Regulations or any renewal of, or successor to, the Export Administration Act and the Regulations, shall be resolved or referred to the President no later than 90 calendar days</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05857E13C4A448EEBE193A52C641D12E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Export Administration Regulations (parts 730–774 of title 15, Code of Federal Regulations) stipulate that license applications should be <quote>resolved or referred to the President no later than 90 calendar days from the date of BIS’s registration of the license application</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEA25A38ABB1F4374A25CD0D4A16F8E1A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HD445866E0960410DB509A964CE8EAADF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">long license delays at the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce create uncertainty for United States exporters and domestic manufacturers and can lead to the loss of business to foreign companies, harming the United States economy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29EE3846EC424BBAB4D4173B3D50FD1A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efficient and predictable processing of export licenses is critical to the competitiveness of United States technology companies and the stability of global supply chains;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0849C648B30146038DA50B5340331EF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>United States technology and economic leadership requires that the export controls system functions efficiently and that license decisions are made in an expeditious manner; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD01E07CDB13E46648C1025B0A088354D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>transparency regarding the efficiency and timeliness of license reviews is necessary for effective Congressional oversight of the export control system.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD21CFABD163D42B9A91D352364B9493A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Licensing timeline; licensing reviews</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1756 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4815">50 U.S.C. 4815</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2801A3FCE2D14818AF3B9266BF54E50A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (g);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC55B28F9CC204CA39365C0C42960CC95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g), as so redesignated, in the header, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Report</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">Annual report on end use checks</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72FE4CC8DF1042998505F504CD95D37F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H928B422637A847149B2620020548D754"><subsection id="H5C81962AA788459B8B8E0AE8670DAF44"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Licensing timeline</header><paragraph id="HB583990DDE1F47C1A19017772DA9ADF8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which an application for a license under this section is submitted, the Secretary should make a licensing decision and notify the applicant of such decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40F560D4B61A45A8BB7852407FDBF35B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delayed application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If no licensing decision is made not later than 120 days after the date on which an application for a license under this section was submitted, the Secretary shall notify the applicant of the status of such application, the reason such a decision has not been made, and request any additional information necessary to make such a decision.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC92FAF8230D24906A7CD60C7F0CC95AD" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Licensing reviews</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Licensing officers with relevant subject matter expertise shall play an essential role in conducting license reviews of all applications for a license under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HCA37F208042949059FCC7094201CB9B5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Quarterly report on license processing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1756 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4815">50 U.S.C. 4815</external-xref>), as amended by section 1, is further amended by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0537AE69161E49AE99EFA60B1BAEAF03" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H6A5185EED3B3457A9B0EED55968486D8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Quarterly report on license processing</header><paragraph id="H2D1DC8911F244AF193F5C57ACAB23471"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and not less frequently than quarterly thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report detailing the processing of license applications and other requests for authorization for the export, reexport, release, and in-country transfer of items controlled under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74706A2952514075A3C03794BF01D299"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><subparagraph id="HBCC6BD122AA549BE9AE79FABE728A95D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>The first report required by paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the preceding one-year period, the following:</text><clause id="H330BC8C31AEB49F1832F674A85BA2716"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The total number of license applications submitted.</text></clause><clause id="H198406C330E845AFBCCFEF29109A4C99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>On the date on which such report is submitted, the total number of license applications in the below statuses on the:</text><subclause id="HFBC981EA9E574C7FA83D5ADC143A4052"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Received.</text></subclause><subclause id="H08DABD5194D34BFC9DC8A67140E81A5E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>On hold (i.e., on hold without action).</text></subclause><subclause id="H21FFBC1486B849D4AA22B2E3CE91A004"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Referred to another department or agency.</text></subclause><subclause id="H4AAFB6DF198540D497A0DCD8591F3F2A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Signed off by a Licensing Officer.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD95C0DD8B5F748919F3EAB9ECF67A29B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Countersigned.</text></subclause><subclause id="H8CFAFEB214694990A1D8C66A2F989F16"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Validated.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2A1ADD32E2234B07B9E17CDAD873E396"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A breakdown of the total number of licenses approved, denied, and returned without action.</text></clause><clause id="H72663179B4FF424E904A5272852B4489"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The average and median processing time for all license applications, in calendar days from the date on which an application is first submitted to the date on which a decision on an application is communicated to the applicant.</text></clause><clause id="H3FB8496F08C8423D85126134B8F03C8F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The average and median processing time of license applications broken out by—</text><subclause id="HF7E7727C69C64F4E9BE160394F90E006"><enum>(I)</enum><text>end-user country (for license applications with multiple end-user countries listed, such applications shall be included in the calculation of each country);</text></subclause><subclause id="HC3E9A6499BCA4A9DA145943C36748103" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Export Control Classification Number (<quote>ECCN</quote>) (for license applications with multiple ECCNs listed, such applications shall be included in the calculation of each ECCN); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5BA3DF55E1764051B2DF33C095B7A07F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whether the license application was for an export, re-export, deemed export, or in-country transfer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA350FEE4401E4D2A971F2E1669AB1EDD"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The total number of license applications referred to—</text><subclause id="HBD5248363C05464893F38D2C1D96458C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of State;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2389605072E04F61AB4121E87A7A8AFE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Department of Defense; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB0667911961B4954BC656CA6EE723DFC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the Department of Energy.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H016065EB936346A29C85CAD856C39C37"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The number of license applications that remained pending for not less than 90 calendar days and a summary of the reasons for such delays, including interagency referral, pre-license check, or administrative backlog.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBA47AEF626A4E368C5FFF0C14514E69"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each subsequent report required by paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the preceding quarter, the information described in subparagraph (A)(i) through (A)(vii). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA92905839BE4235BCA8362CC7413C55"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H13CDA0CBC4F3476AAD3368DB3318E4E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><clause id="HE83778F96A33459CA9911CD7C7581825"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="H7DCAEFF08EDB4EAEB82833F1419465D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HF46702D6D760499F9BC7D4C3D2715EC9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Audit and report by Comptroller General of the United States</header><subsection id="HBD1AE3069AB84E9DBA10BA6723565A11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall commence an audit of the license review process of the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEE30E8AD9849436FA73E7C34CF381C02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The audit required under subsection (a) should analyze whether licensing decisions under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4801">50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.</external-xref>) have been made in an expeditious manner in the preceding calendar year consistent with the procedures and timelines mandated by such Act and identify any bottlenecks that may impact the timing of licensing decisions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6A0508BE0958428282D6DFF7B482812F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="H33DB9484D8704405BCBAE7DA760748A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit a report with the findings from the audit required by subsection (a) to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66AC3A61E51242C086FF795107F0313C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>post the report on a publicly available website of the United States Government Accountability Office.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

