<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA01E8F9398F4FD0AF1977C46163E1CF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 7643 IH: Veteran Technology Employment Success Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7643</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260223">February 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000831">Mr. Walkinshaw</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001220">Mr. McGarvey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the manner in which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs calculates the average employment rate of veterans participating in the VET TEC high technology program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6245089991F240FA81FE07D0A5053566" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3553401574A14E1AB25B0E4FE133540B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Technology Employment Success Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H09AF524A0C24443DA9B9C1913ABD9050">
      <enum>2.</enum>
      <header>Employment rate calculation for VET-TEC high technology program<editorial/></header>
 <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3699C of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text>
      <paragraph id="HD2ECBD60ED34429AB6F49871D6AB4063">
        <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (f)—</text> <subparagraph id="H6BA21A0872E545AA9BB3A9B868D192D3"> <enum>(A)</enum> <text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1) by inserting after <quote>House of Representatives</quote> the following: <quote>, and make available to the public,</quote>; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
        <subparagraph id="H4BDAAC7B0B20409B844D687C4507001E">
          <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>in paragraph (3) by adding at the end the following: <quote>Such rate shall be calculated as a fraction, the denominator of which is the number of covered individuals who completed such a program during such year and the numerator of which is the number of individuals counted in the denominator who are employed on the date that is 180 days after the date on which the individual completed the program, and expressed as a percentage. Notwithstanding the previous sentence, the numerator shall not count a case in which the individual is employed by the same organization that was the provider of the individual’s program of education or a case in which the individual is employed, by a parent or affiliate of such organization, as an instructor for a substantially similar program of education. To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall also report the rates of full-time employment, part-time employment, and self-employment.</quote>; and</text>
        </subparagraph>
      </paragraph>
      <paragraph id="H6D012F4DE1AD48BE83E1A1BD2F3CE5D2">
        <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>in subsection (g) by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H2CA0F930E67C445FA14A48EEE828ABAF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H716952A979FC4F04857F3F06CF83A0CB" indent="up1"> <enum>(3)</enum> <text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary on an ongoing basis shall solicit, collect, and analyze feedback about the program from covered individuals who participate in the program and from the GI Bill School Feedback Tool. The Secretary shall use such feedback to evaluate and improve the implementation of the program.</text>
          </paragraph>
          <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block>
        </quoted-block>
      </paragraph>
    </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

