<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB6DE02A0CCF841658F954E0525A60F71" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 6326 IH: To accelerate accreditation and access to sensitive compartmented information facilities for industry, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2025-11-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">1st Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6326</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20251128">November 28, 2025</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000579">Mr. Ryan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To accelerate accreditation and access to sensitive compartmented information facilities for industry, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H12344BE389284B618559F888784DED32" style="OLC"><section id="HE3E15AD6F5A6469780F2124DAD68D9CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Acceleration of accreditation and access to sensitive compartmented information facilities for industry</header><subsection id="H05F5C6013C014FBBA0CFFD8676D2FEF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after enactment of this act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with other appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government, shall submit to the congressional defense committees a plan to accelerate the accreditation, construction, and operational use of commercial sensitive compartmented information facilities accessible to private-sector entities in support of national security innovation, manufacturing, and mission-critical classified activities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7FF2C6E1A4AB4D7EA9C0AF66FE081620"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H283983D4432A4FCCB89739DE7AF8386F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Recommendation of policies to authorize the parallel processing of construction security plans, construction, and information technology deployment to reduce accreditation and approval timelines.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60D840FCAFF2494A8D0BAE20E4AB3769"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the feasibility of adopting architecture and construction templates to allow for shortening or eliminating portions of the construction security plan review and approval process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF58D65F878A401BA180E20D82FE873C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An evaluation of current policies regarding the use of mobile Secret Internet Protocol Router Network and Joint Worldwide Intelligence Communications System systems within accredited contractor sensitive compartmented information facilities, including a review of Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff Instruction 6211.02D.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H182167435C4E4C35AC801710BBBE882D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the feasibility of delegating the authority to review construction security plans and associated 30, 60, and 90 percent technical drawings to appropriately trained sponsor-approved personnel within the Armed Forces, subject to applicable security standards and oversight.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6017A4208B7D4DA79E08F9ABABB72D0E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A proposal to designate shared commercial classified facilities as valid places to work for all types of classified work authorized by the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H143F463C52FC4F51BA5C214C51640DB1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A proposal to develop and establish a secure, centralized, digital platform for the management of sensitive compartmented information facility lifecycle processes, including—</text><subparagraph id="H0149086A78C04F859E9E101E6EC62922"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submission and tracking of construction security plans, requests for information, fixed facility checklists, and co-use authorizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D0B37D947E04C81AD9B0E15201DFAB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilization of artificial intelligence and machine-learning tools for construction security plan validation, interagency compliance, and document version control.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15C738C9734A48E3BC116A976B1922B4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A list of any additional authorities, appropriations, or other resources necessary to implement the plan required by this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

