<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-HLA26167-YCS-LG-6X2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S3899 IS: Maverick Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 3899</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260224">February 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S435">Mr. Sheehy</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To authorize the transfer by the Secretary of the Navy to the U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama, of certain F–14 Tomcat aircraft.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section section-type="section-one" id="idbedb7c725fea452d8991dc3e3035d775"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Maverick Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id2d695e7ea02640139ae121a2511fa4a0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of certain aircraft from the Navy to the U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama</header><subsection id="idf8d16bf40da34df39d11fc828a812cc5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary of the Navy (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) may transfer (by sale, gift, or otherwise, including by loan) to the U.S. Space and Rocket Center Commission in Huntsville, Alabama (in this section referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>), all right, title, and interest of the United States in one or more F–14 Tomcat aircraft currently in the custody of the Department of the Navy or the Department of Defense, on such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers appropriate, which may include requirements for demilitarization and indemnification and may restrict further disposition or use.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id67a34ce7737e4e769803d3e3b3b1cfd9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreements for restoration and operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may authorize the Commission to enter into agreements with qualified nonprofit organizations for the purpose of restoring and operating aircraft transferred under subsection (a) for public display, airshows, and commemorative events to preserve naval aviation heritage.</text></subsection><subsection id="id04f0c403524f42928d83a57f98591a4a"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conveyance at no cost to the United States</header><text>The conveyance of an aircraft under subsection (a) shall be made at no cost to the United States. Any costs associated with such conveyance, costs of determining compliance with terms of the conveyance, and costs of operation and maintenance of the aircraft conveyed shall be borne by the Commission.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill>

