<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6C30C9CC659B4310B85CA1BFB3D25A79" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>110 HR 7834 IH: Safe Cloud Storage Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7834</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000597">Ms. Lee of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000405">Mr. Knott</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit liability for certain entities storing child sexual abuse material for law enforcement agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7C555C30746C461AB676E0CCF43718DE" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA0D734FB71464C71BE56016A2FFBCCE4"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Cloud Storage Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="HC8C3BB067CC94C20BB0A1B8FA99A78AB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Storage of child pornography and child obscenity</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB65C735496B74A19ABF6F571A1DF0D45"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title II of the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/21101">34 U.S.C. 21101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 201 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07037A8BD314456DB9B3F93F06321EFB"><section id="HE6BFE2B04AF74F1696E503CF042333E3"><enum>202.</enum><header>Modernizing law enforcement's ability to store child pornography and child obscenity and limited liability for approved vendors</header><subsection id="HEED0982019924054AEB453C2E2E79A1F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE67D12796CA24CC5A0F4728C3865A21D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Approved vendor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>approved vendor</term> means an organization, corporation, or entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H3790C8CD18AF410EBFCD33A2E5498658"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offers digital storage services, including remote or cloud-based storage, and analytical and forensic tool processing support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4552E0AD6464B7F8C73412A2C3F8012"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been contractually retained by a covered agency to support the duties of such agency by—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4805C593A7AF47828EC3F335165DACB1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>storing digital child pornography or child obscenity;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE55ACB18A3694D708CAC1679C575791D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making such child pornography or child obscenity available to the contracting agency, or any law enforcement or prosecutorial agency designated by the contracting agency, upon request; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD909FC8BD53B4331B08887444BF39DB7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing maintenance, technical and analytical assistance, and forensic tool processing support upon request by the contracting agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5395DED886A46EEBAA52EA1F94A6F8B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Child pornography</header><text>The term <term>child pornography</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2256(8) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H020427E77CFF41BA9BEF5AB93C58E568"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Child obscenity</header><text>The term <term>child obscenity</term> has the meaning given that term in section 21101(2) of title 34, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H833E9A4A5D2C48EF93713F4F79ABF3F1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text>The term <term>covered agency</term> means a United States Federal, State, or local law enforcement or prosecutorial agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F17451B37C84CBA8A51EAD46394AB15"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Local</header><text>The term <term>local</term> means any political subdivision of a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A3563E1763F499791C920A14FADEFD9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any of the 50 States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, Guam, American Samoa, or the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0673D26F54AE464C99809ED9BC8ABEB0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limited liability for approved vendors</header><paragraph id="H29E008B207E245959AF24CF0CB55F174"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limited liability for law enforcement approved vendors</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a civil claim or criminal charge may not be brought in any Federal or State court against an approved vendor relating to the approved vendor's performance of any contractual obligation or service described in subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D0B48DC73A0470FB605F9BB58B2EBCB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intentional, reckless, or other misconduct</header><text>A civil claim or criminal charge may be brought in any Federal or State court against an approved vendor if the approved vendor—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H539278E1D8BE44FE97E84C094EC19D6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engaged in—</text><clause id="H6292194571C243099290F5F55EC8B6CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intentional misconduct; or</text></clause><clause id="HDB9F53235D9E41788346A5BCF16BD661"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>negligent conduct; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF09C56130974458BA15743F9E286F70F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>acted, or failed to act—</text><clause id="HAFACAAB020A24019BCFCCA84624CA7DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with actual malice;</text></clause><clause id="H35FD2582CC62466C852D719DC9BEB29D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with reckless disregard to a substantial risk of causing injury without legal justification; or</text></clause><clause id="H2DC980B2F3CE4778928D9BAADB659A95"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for a purpose unrelated to the performance of any responsibility or function described in subsection (a)(1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H989CB236CE144382A5B3C0BCB36405A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vendor cybersecurity requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any child pornography or child obscenity stored, maintained, or processed by an approved vendor, such approved vendor shall—</text><paragraph id="H507296689FD24C13B3531797BA21CDEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>secure such child pornography or child obscenity in a manner that is consistent with the most recent version of the Cybersecurity Framework developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology, or any successor thereto;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66894C25BF094D7D975C6BD2C475DC5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>only access the child pornography or child obscenity upon consent of the law enforcement or prosecutorial agency contracting the service and for the purpose of providing maintenance, technical assistance, and forensic tool processing support in the cloud;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2BB52AB0BCA468E9F9C0CF771927162"><enum>(3)</enum><text>minimize the number of employees that may be able to obtain access to such child pornography or child obscenity and maintain a list of employees who have obtained such access;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC685699C51BA4840911CF98797AFEFEA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>employ end-to-end encryption for data storage and transfer functions, or an equivalent technological standard;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5143545A386C4FEBAE464331C50A662E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>undergo an independent annual cybersecurity audit to determine whether such child pornography or child obscenity is secured as required by paragraph (1), including by assessing compliance with the National Institute of Standards and Technology Special Publication 800–53, Revision 5 (relating to security and privacy controls for information systems and organizations) or any successor documents or revisions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB17431DBB9C45BA9A51554586B0AE33"><enum>(6)</enum><text>promptly address all issues identified by an audit described in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8A67F6428364E51B7C35D90488A8D5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evidence storage</header><text>Any covered agency that stores child pornography and child obscenity pursuant to a contract with an approved vendor shall retain such evidence—</text><paragraph id="HDF0D783F2EE949028CB9CB87C31A9363"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in compliance with the security policy of the Criminal Justice Information Services Division of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, or any other similar and appropriate division within the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05E111556B734B2E9A83E3E3B6674C9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for a period consistent with the evidence retention requirements applicable to the investigating or prosecuting covered agency under the relevant Federal, State, or local law, rule of criminal procedure, or prosecutorial policy; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63E7ACFAA9E94C3AB4E10D9B20E01BE3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the absence of such law, rule, or policy, for a period not less than the applicable statute of limitations or the duration of any sentence imposed, including the period of post-conviction review.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8ACD55D414C04A0E875B488BFEE23F71"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional requirements for approved vendors</header><paragraph id="H3E991505FEF24910BF42696815607B10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Location of data</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6EE6A1F42BE84F249BA23EF8679254F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each approved vendor shall ensure that child pornography and child obscenity stored pursuant to this section remains in the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9CCFAE55E5824EAB8C177D54FBF0BE1B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Child pornography and child obscenity under this section may be transferred outside the United States only with the express consent of the contracting covered agency if such agency deems the transfer necessary for investigative purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0315A3715674EA4A195F512CDEC39B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification letter</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3960CB65925A47B3AE7CEE8E9CEF72C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Approved vendors shall file a notification letter with the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice not later than 30 days after entering into a contract described in subsection (a)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3207A1B1E3EF4B0FB6D00C0F4FB4FB0D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notification letter described in subparagraph (A) shall include the entity name and point of contact information of the approved vendor, the name of the contracting covered agency, the period of performance of the contract, and an acknowledgment by the approved vendor that the approved vendor will notify the Child Exploitation and Obscenity Section of the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice of any changes to the information in the letter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB687B5BFB16B4EC3BC2C285374EC1B1E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Breach of contract</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA2D4453ED914FC0BB0009A2F1253B4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a covered agency fails to make required payment under a contract, breaches any material term of such contract, or otherwise terminates such contract without establishing lawful transfer of the evidence, the approved vendor shall, not later than 30 days after the failure, breach, or termination, notify the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice in the case of a breach by a Federal agency, or the appropriate State attorney general in the case of a breach by a State or local agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7410D3D98E3F48E699E2AABE1CA27B5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maintenance of evidence</header><text>Upon making a notification under subparagraph (A), the approved vendor shall continue to preserve and maintain the integrity of the evidence until a prompt and lawful transfer of custody occurs to the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice or another Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency with jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52CE4841900749DA8476FDC775E189C8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit—</text><paragraph id="H4F8A226D59434BD98ACAF4D1202BD899"><enum>(1)</enum><text>bona fide use by the contracting covered agency of child pornography or child obscenity being stored by the approved vendor, which includes providing such child pornography or child obscenity to any other party as necessary for an investigation or prosecution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53A9A3DFEB5249DEBA079071B423E765"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the obligation of the contracting covered agency to comply with a constitutional or statutory obligation, court order, or request from a victim made pursuant to section 3509(m)(3) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB670256224E742898025DC0BB224C47D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>Section 1(b) of the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/401">Public Law 110–401</external-xref>; 122 Stat. 4229) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 201 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DB5A7B63C8D4434ABE73C89E1E511EF"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">Sec. 202. Modernizing law enforcement's ability to store child pornography and child obscenity and limited liability for approved vendors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

