<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H92031B90B21C4C76B604DE2391A84B66" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8107 : Government Audit and Accountability of Federally Funded State-Administered Programs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8107</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260609">June 9, 2026</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the establishment of a list identifying program areas and administrative practices presenting the greatest risk to the integrity of Federal funds administered by States and local governments.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6EF399BCD744322B106F1D3329BEB43" style="OLC"><section id="HA8B747D0DA524032A5D095AC3B631733" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Government Audit and Accountability of Federally Funded State-Administered Programs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H70D8FFCA83C444ADA64A9ACC27A3E58D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federally-funded State-administered programs vulnerability assessment</header><subsection id="H6610F43A4CB14EE0A41C5BFD1F7CB588"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and periodically thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress an assessment of program areas and administrative practices that present the greatest risk to the integrity of Federal funds administered by State and local governments and pass-through entities subject to audit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C856094455946B89D1259838ADF5E14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each assessment required by subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HCFCF72AC3A0448128F98595CF28C8512"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify program areas and administrative practices at the Federal, State, and local level that present systematic vulnerabilities in the administration of Federal funds by State and local governments, including practices that are more susceptible to waste, fraud, abuse, and improper payments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80AEA85604904C3EB32A6A3D1DD6C9E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess evidence-based best practices and strategies that have strengthened the integrity of Federal funds administered by State and local governments and reduced waste, fraud, and abuse in Federally-funded programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76A12044ADE5492799521296CE7260BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess program areas and administrative practices at the Federal, State, and local level that—</text><subparagraph id="HAF613505B46242E6A7F6A8554C581619"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have demonstrated effectiveness in mitigating waste, fraud, abuse, and improper payments; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CC5E38799354630B7C0E0AD450BA018"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have shown limited effectiveness in reducing such risks;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2DD4BD44EF848E9A04E991CF60A525B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify Federal tools, resources, and technical assistance available to State and local governments and how such tools may be improved to prevent and mitigate the systemic vulnerabilities identified under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BBB23F467A24488BD5E39DCF29569A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include recommendations to Federal agencies and matters for consideration to Congress to address and improve the program areas and administrative practices identified under paragraph (1), including recommendations to improve eligibility determination and enrollment processes to mitigate risks.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AF7DE0688CF41BB88CC8484FA0B3DA7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sources</header><paragraph id="H7C02ABCE0FDB45D68149C8197F48E21E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Audit and related materials</header><text>In carrying out the preparation of the assessment under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall rely, to the extent practicable, on existing oversight, audit, and investigative materials to conduct an analysis of Federal funds administrated by State and local governments, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HB572C401A63C43FEB066983C7A2806CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any finding of a Federal, State, or local auditor, comptroller, treasurer, inspector general, attorney general, or any other similar official with respect to the administration of such funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98C0DA1FC3FA446581487CD8A3B89C91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any audit required under section 7502 of title 31, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74A8E02D51EB441AACC625D000946063"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other publicly available Federal, State, or local oversight and program integrity data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE76961F1740141F585367E690BAF071A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing each assessment required by subsection (a), the Comptroller General may supplement the materials described in paragraph (1) with additional analysis and new audit work, including by drawing on prior and ongoing work, where such materials are insufficient to assess the program areas and administrative practices identified under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DDD07EE28094E6894AAD7FED6E8BC3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form and methodology</header><text>The Comptroller General shall determine the appropriate form and methodology for preparing and submitting each assessment required by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H606A862DD8B342E7A2213CFAA2473E84"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA90A6955BD6445729658D6B371FBAFE9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Improper payment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>improper payment</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3351(4) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76B24D7BC00444C1A6F4697D5F87B168"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 6720(a)(4) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20260608" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 8, 2026.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

