<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H92031B90B21C4C76B604DE2391A84B66" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 8107 IH: Government Audit and Accountability of Federally Funded State-Administered Programs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8107</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260326">March 26, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Government Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the establishment of a list identifying program areas and administrative practices presenting the greatest risk to the integrity of Federal funds administered by States and local governments.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6EF399BCD744322B106F1D3329BEB43" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5F17212A79524BFDA2D8988A3D3ECE97" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Government Audit and Accountability of Federally Funded State-Administered Programs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE405500806A847658550100808E67486"><enum>2.</enum><header>High Risk List for federally-funded State-administered programs</header> <subsection id="HF7B00A651E8A4F21967051D0B6C66496"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and periodically thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a High Risk List identifying program areas and administrative practices presenting the greatest risk to the integrity of Federal funds administered by States and local governments, including Federal pass through programs subject to audit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC65B1F88D8294534B7DF270BAC5FBE58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The High Risk List required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H283B25C2508240178687488BC3C48E93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify high-risk program areas and administrative practices presenting systematic vulnerability the administration of Federal funds by State and local governments;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0481E5DA3E8E42F6AD4859FE96BC1AB1">
          <enum>(2)</enum>
 <text>assess best practices that have strengthened the integrity of Federal funds administered by State and local governments and reduced waste, fraud, and abuse in federally funded programs;</text>
        </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H292BF8A6BE7D4DE4810E7108262A0005"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify Federal tools, resources, and technical assistance available to address the vulnerability patterns under paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEEDC8F3629464374B4F9FDE724310FEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include recommendations to Congress for addressing the high risk program areas and administrative practices identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H53F0B198BD604A56A0985741D1140C86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sources</header> 
<paragraph id="H75840441658A43AB80898113CA4F4BE3">
          <enum>(1)</enum>
 <text>In carrying out the preparation of the High Risk List under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall primarily rely on existing publicly available oversight, audit and investigative materials, to conduct an analysis of federally funded State-administered programs, which may include—</text>
          <subparagraph id="HBA2A2B3F7CC443578839BFC45FFEE255">
            <enum>(A)</enum>
 <text>findings of Federal and State auditors, inspectors general, and attorneys general with respect to the administration of Federal funds by State and local governments;</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H42D82DCA1BF4481EA3C4A7C84243B1E1">
            <enum>(B)</enum>
 <text>single audit reports required under section 7502 of title 31, United States Code; and</text>
          </subparagraph>
          <subparagraph id="H79B84278D83B4AC296D3935A2743588F">
            <enum>(C)</enum>
 <text>and other publicly available Federal oversight and program integrity data.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CE74781F2E04A6D93EF3248841ED80F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the High Risk List, the Comptroller General shall apply professional auditing and evaluation standards in analyzing such materials. The Comptroller General may supplement such materials with independent analysis of publicly available Federal program data where existing oversight materials are insufficient to identify high-risk program areas or administrative practices, provided that nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Comptroller General to compel the production of information from States or local governments or to conduct independent audits of State or local programs.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCDE7AEE734C947B08025B03A4A2A59C1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form and methodology</header><text>The Comptroller General shall determine the appropriate form and methodology for preparing and presenting the High Risk List required under this section, consistent with Government Auditing Standards and the requirements of subsection (c).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

