<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD34448F16F6491C88888E7304C12A9E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 HR 9409 IH: Remote Control Locomotives Safety Improvement Act of 2026</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9409</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260623">June 23, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000402">Mr. Kennedy of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000599">Mr. Lawler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain operations of remote control locomotives, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H24C9DB2EE9754CFF8567D66909D07B33" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5592239C35744D8BB5B4880F22FA8399" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Remote Control Locomotives Safety Improvement Act of 2026</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HADCF6AF3AAEA4F1A959E131641FD9455"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitations on remote control locomotives</header> <subsection id="H093130EA28694755B6B33335BDB07A41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>A railroad carrier may not—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFD8CAF81279F4863A55B64772B3F2C63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operate a train outside a yard without a human locomotive engineer physically located inside the cab of the lead locomotive who has the ability to take control of the operation of the train; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3CAAAB7D21F40B1815962AD19178E3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operate a remote control locomotive on a main line.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEBE5740118F447F0B905A775A7D08364"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for operation on a main line</header> 
<paragraph id="HB184D1ABE427480A85EDFD28162242CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certified locomotive engineer</header><text>A railroad carrier may not operate a train on a main line unless such train has a lead locomotive with a locomotive cab operated by a locomotive engineer certified under part 240 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, who is physically located inside the locomotive cab.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FE8E5A1804F49E3AFF05016F2D0AD0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statutory construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to allow a locomotive engineer or conductor solely certified under part 240 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, as a remote-control operator to operate a train described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0768A2E4DA04AD8AA461280110540CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver process</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law or regulation, the Secretary may not waive the requirements of this section for—</text> <paragraph id="HFAE73CEB3C8C406DAB973B719B0E273B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a class I railroad;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H759212D315AF4AE5A545BC40776138A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a class II railroad; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75F8072CC12A4B49B133AA7A1AD2BF4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any train operating on track classified as class 1 or above, as described in part 213 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H513D44C5C7974DBD8447C416E13CDC50"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header> 
<paragraph id="H4E17467265074249989166AB6D2F5086"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Rulemaking requirements</header><text>The requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H143FD9362FA241CAB9B1D0F8776F7880"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3CFBF1AB3DFC409E861BF39647D996F2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Audits and inspections</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6091A76037FB406A804C9869C805D5A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H91858CEA22B54F628422BE097CEEF7F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out an audit and inspection of each class I railroad; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7FC0D1370474C2F967D0F51DEC9FDB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>take any necessary actions to ensure each such class I railroad is complying with the requirements of this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC5FCA29BDB7E4C5EAF403647F5620E05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, carry out unscheduled audits and inspections, as necessary, on any rail carrier covered by this Act that is not a class I railroad to ensure compliance with the requirements of this Act.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H134F0C4BF15144D09640F7BDE96E3D11"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as provided for in section 2(d), the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this Act, including any updates or conforming changes to part 229.15 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></section> 
<section id="HEBCE11EFEB7140FC88C0D17DFC94C516"><enum>5.</enum><header>Fines for violations</header> 
<subsection id="HF48D09827CBC40FA8D362E2E00B6C93B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Subject to section 21304 of title 49, United States Code, a person violating this Act or a regulation or an order issued by the Secretary pursuant to this Act is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty. A separate violation occurs for each day the violation continues.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1C854A6EE4A4418DAD08BD624BA04196" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of the penalty shall be the greater of 1 percent of the person’s annual income or annual operating income or $1,000,000.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H43795ED0E1FE47C386810F2B0D7AECF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The requirements in subsections (a)(3), (a)(4), (b), and (c) of section 21301 of title 49, United States Code, shall apply to any penalty imposed by the Secretary pursuant to this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H1C455606AEEF4165B8535A28AD793D27"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H62D9A02CA8AB4C01A00F360239002A39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Class I, II, and III railroads; railroad carrier</header><text>The terms <term>class I railroad</term>, <term>class II railroad</term>, <term>class III railroad</term>, and <quote>railroad carrier</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 20102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68BE06C472F34C0EB83D89D48031B2DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lead locomotive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lead locomotive</term> means the first locomotive proceeding in the direction of movement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H280EBFF0CA944A3E8F04DD6DBF58BCCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Locomotive cab</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>locomotive cab</term> means the compartment or space on board a locomotive where the control stand is located and which is normally occupied by the engineer when the locomotive is operated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H72CF6324D47F4FC4857CEBDD419E9EFA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Main line</header><text>The term <term>main line</term> means a segment or route of railroad tracks over which 5,000,000 or more gross tons of railroad traffic is transported annually.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6FCCCEFDC8648518325F4A58F41C2E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Remote control locomotive</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>remote control locomotive</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H7E6FEB532E074B9EB2BBE5A1E371805B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a remote control locomotive that, through use of a radio link, can be operated by a person not physically within the locomotive cab; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7C0A952330484D4C9A286E1CE1FF7CA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a locomotive or group of locomotives remotely controlled from the lead locomotive of a train, as in a distributed power arrangement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H870E392FEFBE4841A747B3749132EEC8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Remote control operator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>remote control operator</quote> means a locomotive engineer, as defined in section 240.7 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, certified by a railroad to operate remote control locomotives pursuant to section 240.107 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA110A296B8B746CF9F966CA1B9A2F243"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Train</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>train</term> means 1 or more locomotives coupled with or without cars, except during switching service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCF838B345FA484581E194E17AE4EDE9"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Yard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>yard</term> means a system of tracks, not including main tracks and sidings, used for classifying cars, making-up and inspecting trains, or storing cars and equipment.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

