<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" dms-id="A1" public-private="public" slc-id="S1-KEN26393-223-L0-16N"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 S4927 IS: Rural Hospital Emergency Room Guarantee Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>119th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>S. 4927</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20260624">June 24, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S399">Mr. Hawley</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S388">Ms. Hassan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title>To establish a guaranteed funding stream to keep existing emergency rooms at America's rural hospitals open, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="S1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Rural Hospital Emergency Room Guarantee Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida31d712df89041849497b13af21da86a"><enum>2.</enum><header>Rural Hospital Emergency Room Guarantee Fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id768297fbf06e4dbb931f4948154dec36"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="id7b3560463d3b4afcbb745330d1aac215"><enum>399V–8.</enum><header>Rural Hospital Emergency Room Guarantee Fund</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id51321e06b1454d9e87a6e8f4b25d7f4c"><enum>(a)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the <term>Rural Hospital Emergency Room Guarantee Fund</term> (referred to in this section as the <term>Fund</term>), consisting of—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id908d6c3d1b114a3b9b4c7ae4ad672482"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such amounts as are appropriated to the fund pursuant to subsection (i); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id64b1bb57b4324750bebdf196b9a5449e"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amounts collected as civil monetary penalties under subsection (g)(2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5bebcef2e17340d68651cd50f5d39af7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Fund shall be administered by the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id79036ab3f4d64c308f387d6ff7d9c07d"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id1b794352f9ea40ed8a4ba09fdab21cc1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in the Fund shall be available, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation, to the Secretary to make payments under the program established under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f2df3695ff84b0db8eff3ebb36a74ba"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="ida9d4f3f02599479c9866cfecfd946482"><enum>(A)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Rural Hospital Emergency Room Guarantee Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish, and solicit applications for, a 10-year program (referred to in this section as the <term>program</term>) to make payments to eligible entities for the authorized uses described in subsection (e).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idac8f92a5508446058f63b1df1488a90e"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each year of the program, the Secretary shall—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id6dc53476aae249ff99cdbafc692abbc8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make a payment—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idbb8a3c8061c443b49934403f3ba8da30"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first year of the program, in the amount of $1,000,000 (to be distributed in equal payments on a quarterly basis) to each eligible entity with an approved application under subsection (d)(2); and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc577078ed3824ee08a99159e0da118da"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in each subsequent year of the program, in an amount equal to the amount of the payment for the preceding year, as adjusted to reflect changes for the 12-month period ending the preceding November 30 in the Consumer Price Index for Medical Care Services published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor; and</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id16371b69fdbd4f4aa462efac58ad7d9f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make an additional payment to each such eligible entity in an amount not greater than 50 percent of the amount of the payment made to such eligible entity under clause (i) for that year, to be determined by the Secretary with respect to each such eligible entity pursuant to a formula established by the Secretary by rulemaking based on, with respect to an eligible entity—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb69e018101940e48f33370881892299"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the payor mix of the eligible entity;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3765b8dc461a452d91f2714d35ec0227"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the injury need of patients within the immediate geographical area in which the eligible entity is located;</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id004b39c5a5c84311be3bf291e0e452e6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the economic conditions in the geographic area in which such eligible entity is located; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idb3d497beaaf2494492990318949d8cc0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>past financial history of such eligible entity.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idc4b7111d7c7346178d85a5531b7345fb"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Emergency payments</header><text>The Secretary may make an additional payment, in an amount not to exceed $250,000, to an eligible entity with an approved application under subsection (d)(2) in any year of the program if the Secretary determines that the emergency department of such eligible entity is in danger of closing in the next 14 days, on the condition that no eligible entity may receive more than 1 such payment in any year of the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5c4251422fa34015857d4b493f75755d"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications; approval; eligibility</header><paragraph id="idfa64cbe18b724f518793c35dc846a4a2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each entity desiring to receive payments under the program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id612e776987f548ac9aacfa4251d56b65"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id39e73ab8e02042769b556ead896628f6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after receiving an application under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall approve such application if the Secretary determines that such entity meets the eligibility criteria described in paragraph (3). Such approval shall apply with respect to such an entity for the duration of the program, except as provided in paragraph (4).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc8d7fb4362d0481bbba9bcb70a139837"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>If the Secretary does not approve an application under subparagraph (A), as soon as practicable after such disapproval, the Secretary shall provide to the applicant—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id14452c0f85cb452f9a5a37bcf472f310"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of the reason for the disapproval; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id50a2083910374c44833bc22534746971"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an expedited process for curing any deficiencies in the application and reapplying.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2c438040df004ffabed97983943c2f65"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a payment under the program, an entity—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id81b24463e4374223bab8276fb094aea4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be a rural health facility (as defined in section 2105(h)(3)(D) of the Social Security Act), other than an entity described in clause (i)(II) of such section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd7d1f3b7416c40f6a6aa945ebdd0f68a"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall participate in a Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B(f) of such Act); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id74f937a7d55147a3b62fdffe661791ea" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall operate a 24-hour emergency department of a hospital (as defined in section 2799A–1(a)(3)) or a 24-hour independent freestanding emergency department (as so defined).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id739a86ec4aed450fab7200e8c2402ff5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Condition of participation</header><text>After the date on which the application of an eligible entity is approved under paragraph (2)(A), if such eligible entity is acquired, in whole or in part, by a private-equity, venture-capital, or similarly purposed ownership fund, such eligible entity may not continue to participate in the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id302be3f95f944a9f85e3ade8e4db8bc5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header><text>An eligible entity receiving payments under the program—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idd39d970200e0463e9760649a5eac75c6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only use the funds to pay for the normal operating expenses, including for staffing, of the emergency department of such eligible entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id9665c9d868c74dbe9fe42e68413be737"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7af060854e33447886bf999a0b49ecb7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use the funds—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id21b43325379f4209b02e6c9cf4d2163a"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop projects that do not directly impact the existing operations of such eligible entity; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id3a2ee5c0e64d424ab30152770c4ba6cc"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to make payments to executives, executive staff, or members of the board of directors of such eligible entity; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id2328fc3a6bab40eb80697c5e4c1e4afa"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transfer the funds to other facilities, including other facilities of such eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id378ab9bba2e042819f991de9a0ff5506"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible entity receiving payments under the program shall submit to the Secretary an annual report describing the financial condition and continued need of such eligible entity and the impact of such payments received during the preceding year on such eligible entity. The Secretary may not use such reported information to disqualify such eligible entity from participation in the program.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id8f877641c9d3439698438f5332d0c3e8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Compliance</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="iddb6f211debfd4ed181ba085771237f08"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct random audits of eligible entities receiving payments under the program to ensure the compliance of such eligible entities with the requirements of the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3b0ee14ba9dc4feb83f09d4b5a37d9ac"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Violations</header><text>If the Secretary determines that an eligible entity has violated a requirement of the program, the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idf54552473a4d409bac4cd4955fd9ce91"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impose civil penalties, including civil monetary penalties, against such eligible entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id37477cfde0584b2898fd52cf5cdedb12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>remove such eligible entity from participation in the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7c7f2962e15045f7a7a6ad433ab88e98"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations for reporting</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Rural Hospital Emergency Room Guarantee Act</short-title>, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, shall promulgate regulations—</text><paragraph id="id47c9d73dc53f4bc591e916c48d95d998"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establishing a reporting methodology for eligible entities enrolled in the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act under section 1866(j) of such Act to disclose for informational purposes on any required cost reports under such title XVIII all payments received under the program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id225c9f3943ff40348f82805e045dd5bc"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allowing an eligible entity to exclude all payments received under the program from cost settlement calculations and expense offsets.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id77164bbbf9374acba16a4145ccca58c3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Mandatory funding</header><text>Out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is authorized to be appropriated, and there is appropriated, to the Fund such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2036.</text></subsection><subsection id="id7c91b7f7d9894e09a0d47f762f842e62" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Participation in the program shall not be taken into account in determining eligibility of an eligible entity under any other Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B(f) of the Social Security Act) and any payment under the program shall be in addition to any payment such eligible entity is eligible to receive under any other Federal health care program (as so defined).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill>

