<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE resolution PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/res.dtd//EN" "res.dtd">
<resolution public-private="public" resolution-stage="Introduced-in-Senate" resolution-type="senate-resolution" star-print="no-star-print" slc-id="S1-RIL26179-YP4-D2-7LG"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>119 SRES 627 IS: Designating March 5, 2026, as “National Slam the Scam Day” to raise awareness about pervasive scams and to prevent government imposter scams and other types of scams by promoting education about such scams.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. Senate</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2026-03-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">III</distribution-code><congress display="yes">119th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num>S. RES. 627</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20260305">March 5, 2026</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S404">Mr. Scott of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S406">Mr. Kelly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S331">Mrs. Gillibrand</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S415">Mr. Warnock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S341">Mr. Blumenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S252">Ms. Collins</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S396">Mrs. Blackburn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S381">Mr. Rounds</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S439">Mrs. Moody</cosponsor>) submitted the following resolution; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>RESOLUTION</legis-type><official-title display="yes">Designating March 5, 2026, as <quote>National Slam the Scam Day</quote> to raise awareness about pervasive scams and to prevent government imposter scams and other types of scams by promoting education about such scams.</official-title></form><preamble><whereas><text>Whereas hundreds of thousands of individuals in the United States are targeted by government imposter scams each year, including government imposter scams related to Social Security, Medicare, the Federal Trade Commission, the United States Postal Service, and the Internal Revenue Service;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas scams cost United States consumers billions of dollars annually, disproportionately affecting older adults;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, in the first 3 quarters of 2025, the Federal Trade Commission reported that fraud losses totaled over $12,000,000,000, with over $700,000,000 reported as imposter scams;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas 1 in 4 people in the United States reported losing money to scams, with a median loss of $500 per person;</text></whereas><whereas commented="no"><text>Whereas, according to the Federal Trade Commission, since 2020 there has been more than a four-fold increase in older adults reporting losses of $10,000 or more, and at times they have lost their entire life savings; </text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, since 2013, the fraud hotline of the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate has received more than 12,685 complaints from individuals in all 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico regarding possible government imposter scams;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas, according to the Federal Trade Commission, in 2025, older adults reported larger median individual losses as a result of government imposter scams than younger adults;</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas government imposter scams involve scammers contacting individuals in the United States and claiming to resolve a government-related problem or impersonating employees of government agencies, such as the Social Security Administration, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Federal Trade Commission, the United States Postal Service, and the Internal Revenue Service, to demand payment or personal information, which defrauds the people of the United States and erodes trust in the government agencies that the scammers impersonate; and</text></whereas><whereas><text>Whereas increased awareness of, and education about, government imposter scams help to thwart government imposter scammers: Now, therefore, be it</text></whereas></preamble><resolution-body><section id="S1" display-inline="yes-display-inline" section-type="undesignated-section"><text>That the Senate—</text><paragraph id="id02a85a5f1eb948d9916467169847bc76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designates March 5, 2026, as <quote>National Slam the Scam Day</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id021ea0a9c0044672902de87641c2a057"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognizes National Slam the Scam Day as an opportunity to raise awareness and amplify the messaging about scams that involve individuals impersonating government employees by any means, including by mail, telephone, text message, email, social media, or internet websites (referred to in this resolution as <quote>government imposter scams</quote>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8f7182af6d8043949d26f5677af3ea06"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes that law enforcement agencies, consumer protection groups, telephone companies, area agencies on aging, and financial institutions all play vital roles in—</text><subparagraph id="idb60cce3e17274b5b876e06439c6510cc"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preventing government imposter scams from targeting the people of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5fb44b854dc24ab994cc605cefbfdb2f"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educating the people of the United States about government imposter scams;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id14b86d0c05cf4066a53e090bec60a86d"><enum>(4)</enum><text>encourages—</text><subparagraph id="idbf7002df4f8e413395b522d82f7d1be5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the implementation of policies and programs to prevent government imposter scams; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26d4822f55f84c8497046416bf6b1488"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the improvement of measures to protect the people of the United States from government imposter scams;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id43c037ece45a4d05983e5d1f96056dec"><enum>(5)</enum><text>encourages members of the public to—</text><subparagraph id="idc165704cc4b24e478b044c1f65e92750"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ignore solicitations from individuals falsely claiming to represent government agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idaca3326ec85e4189b9c0e8c99b6412ef"><enum>(B)</enum><text>share information about government imposter scams with family and friends; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5b0c1a2cc0f64fc8808fb32b0c5c2508"><enum>(C)</enum><text>report government imposter scams to the corresponding agency, such as—</text><clause id="id67741daa40da44b9b980889f57d3ac77"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Office of the Inspector General of the Social Security Administration;</text></clause><clause id="id56539ef2522345fe955961461b3dc20f"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Treasury Inspector General for Tax Administration; or</text></clause><clause id="ideec282382d3f481eb6deafaeea30087d"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Federal Trade Commission; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2d2db61f155740e18784d991e827c1cc"><enum>(6)</enum><text>honors the commitment and dedication of the individuals and organizations that work tirelessly to fight against government imposter scams.</text></paragraph></section></resolution-body></resolution> 

